Chapter 9

Draco thought Rigel must be either very brave or very stupid. When he and Pansy had offered to escort their friend to Professor Snape's office that morning, they expected to witness a dressing down of epic proportions; what they hadn't expected was their soft-spoken friend's vehement, unequivocal resistance.

"—stupid, arrogant boy—"

"You forgot reckless," Rigel's disgruntled tone made Draco wince just imagining the look it must have inspired on their Head of House's face.

"I'm only working up to it, you impetuous fool!"

Pansy gave a sigh of exasperation from the other side of Snape's closed office door. Even the thick, insular wood couldn't muffle their professor's ire. Draco hoped no one happened down this hallway before Snape and Rigel were finished…talking. It was one thing for Pansy and him to overhear such an argument—they were Rigel's friends. Other people were not meant to witness Rigel's belligerence, however; it was a side he only showed to people he trusted. Just as well they were there to guard the door, really.

"He could at least try not to antagonize the professor," Pansy said quietly.

"He's become noticeably more self-asserting of late," Draco huffed, sotto voce, "Not yet sure if it's a good thing or not."

"I think not, at least from Professor Snape's perspective," Pansy commented, leaning shamelessly toward the office door as the voices within dipped in volume.

"It wasn't impetuous or reckless, Professor," Rigel argued, sounding perfectly reasonable in a way Draco knew drove his godfather mad. His father used such a tone on Uncle Severus to embarrassing effect, after all. "Please give me a little credit. I did take a moment to come up with a plan before rushing into danger."

"Exactly: rushing into danger," Snape snarled, "With no thought for your own wellbeing or anything except your insatiable need to involve yourself in affairs far above your pay-grade."

"I just told you I did think before I went after Remus," Rigel said, ever patient. Draco personally thought he'd get further with their Head of House by apologizing profusely and claiming to not have been thinking clearly. Telling Snape he'd purposely done something stupid wasn't exactly a good defense.

"And what thoughts, pray tell, did your puny, prepubescent brain come up with that justified so foolhardy and ill-advised a course of action, Mr. Black?"

"He's getting sarcastic with his rhetorical questions," Pansy noted.

"Not a good sign," Draco agreed.

"I thought that any perceived danger to my own person was greatly outweighed in this case by the potential danger to every other inhabitant of this castle should Remus truly have become lost to the wolf." Rigel's voice was definitely getting testier. "And I thought that the danger to my fellow students and professors was even then greatly outweighed by the potential catastrophe for creature rights that any incident involving Remus attacking Hogwarts personnel was sure to provoke. You act like my actions were unnecessary, Professor, but they weren't. The alternative to someone stopping Remus from biting Professor Pettigrew is unthinkable."

There was a short pause, in which Draco and Pansy exchanged raised eyebrows. That wasn't exactly the argument Rigel had given them the night before. Did their friend really care so much about the politics of creature rights? Or was he playing up the bigger-picture angle in an appeal to Snape's mercenary, objective nature? Draco thought he'd missed the mark, were that the case. There was nothing objective about the way his godfather favored Rigel.

"Even if you disregard all that," Rigel went on, "Even if you tell me that other people's safety and wellbeing somehow shouldn't matter as much to me as my own, it still makes sense for me to have done what I did."

"Is that so." Snape didn't sound at all curious.

"Remus means enough to me personally that any injury to him would be an injury to me," Rigel said. This was the argument Draco recognized. He wondered if it would be so compelling the second time. "I won't argue that my intervention might have saved Remus his hearing, since I admittedly didn't know that when I decided to help. I know Remus, though, and I know that if he'd even scratched someone in that uncontrolled state he would never forgive himself. It would kill him to have harmed another person, no matter that it wasn't his fault. He would feel that him being here in a school full of innocents at this time of the month was culpable enough."

"And he'd be right," Snape growled. Pansy silently put her hand to her head in dismay. Draco had to concur, that was not the right thing to say to Rigel.

"You don't mean that," Rigel said, sounding shocked.

"Don't tell me what I mean, boy," Snape spat.

"But you…your Wolfsbane is the reason Remus is here. It's because of your breakthrough that we know he's not dangerous at the full moon," Rigel said, "It's why I was able to confront and contain him so easily, even though I'm just a third-year. Sir…you can't think that your potion failed last night. It didn't! Something else just overrode it for a little while and confused Remus! Please, Professor, if you don't believe in its effectiveness, how are other people to trust its effects?"

"Why should I care?" Draco could picture Snape flinging his hand dismissively as he said that.

"Because it's your name on the line too, you know," Rigel snapped, seemingly fed up, "If people distrust the New Wolfsbane and think it doesn't do what you said it does, your credibility will be shot to pieces. It will throw your entire body of work into question in the eyes of some. Surely you care about the effect a werewolf incident at Hogwarts would have on your career, since you obviously don't care about anyone else who could have been hurt last night." The last was said with a tone bordering on disapproval.

"I care about how you could have been hurt last night, you stupid child!" Snape was roaring now, and Draco couldn't help but flinch back from the door a bit at the sudden shout. "Everyone else can go to hell as far as I'm concerned. You're the one I put two and a half years of time and attention into! You're the one who begged to be taken under my wing! The one I gave advanced potions lessons to far before most Masters would have given a student the time of day. The one I agreed to make my apprentice in January at only thirteen years of age—or had you forgotten that the trial period we agreed on would be up in just a few short months? I must say your latest behavior does not give me much reassurance in the matter of your good sense, Mr. Black. Perhaps I've wasted my time, after all, and you'd prefer to throw your life away at the first opportunity instead of dedicating it to any work of true import."

"I—you—that's not fair," Rigel got out, but it was clear the heat was entirely extinguished from his voice. "Of course I still want to be your apprentice. I just—you can't make me choose potions over everything else. I would choose it over most things, you know that, but…when someone I care about is in trouble I can't refuse to help them by claiming to be saving my own life to help other people later on. That's nonsensical."

"It certainly isn't—"

"You're saying that if someone you cared about was in danger—Draco, say he was kidnapped by ransomers—and for some reason Mr. and Mrs. Malfoy were unable to do anything, you would just, what? Shrug your shoulders? Ask someone who wasn't as good at potions as you are to risk their life to save Draco?"

"I am a grown wizard, Rigel," Snape said. He sounded weary all of a sudden. "When I need to enter a dangerous situation I do so fully prepared to handle whatever lies ahead."

"Why can't you see that I was prepared to handle this?" Rigel asked, "Potions isn't the only thing I'm good for, you know."

Draco was startled to hear Snape let out a bitter laugh, "What I would have given to hear you say that at any other time."

"I live to aggravate, Sir," Rigel said, a wryly amused tone entering his voice as well.

"I hope you give equal amounts of frustration to everyone you know, Mr. Black," Snape shot back, "I should be highly put out to discover that you'd reserved an uneven share of it for me."

"Ask Draco sometime how often I drive him to gritted teeth, Professor," Rigel said, a bit of sheepishness in his voice.

"Perhaps I shall ask him now—if he and Miss Parkinson are finished eavesdropping at the door, that is."

Draco and Pansy both winced, but caught was caught. There'd be no sneaking off surreptitiously now.

The door swung open and Draco hoped he looked perfectly at ease as he sauntered into the small office. "Finished if you are, Sir," he said, grinning up at his godfather in the same impish way he'd used to great effect at a much younger age.

"You guys waited for me?" Rigel looked utterly surprised to see them still there.

"Just in case we needed to rush in and silence you before you said something really idiotic, Rigel," Pansy said, smiling in a helpful way.

"In that case, you missed your cue, Miss Parkinson," Snape snorted, "Several times."

"My apologies, Professor Snape." Pansy dipped a small curtsey that Draco was sure none of the other girls their age could pull off so thoughtlessly. "It's so difficult to hear anything through antique oak."

"Salazar Slytherin designed the acoustics in the adjacent hallway specifically so that students awaiting their punishment would be able to hear clearly the cries of the student being disciplined before them," Snape informed her.

"How interesting," Pansy murmured, face full of guile.

"Are you going to give me detention?" Rigel asked suddenly.

Draco tried valiantly not to gape. What kind of idiot tempted their Head of House so blatantly? Why was he cursed with such embarrassingly unsubtle friends?

"What I'm going to give you is a chance to convince me that these past two years have not been in vain," Snape sneered. "There are six weeks until the end of term. That is how long you have to assure me that you've the proper temperament for the responsibilities and expectations any apprentice of mine must meet."

Draco mentally groaned. He could tell by the fervent determination that was suddenly radiating on his empathic radar that his friend was planning to barricade himself in his lab until winter break.

"I won't let you down, Sir," Rigel said, his calm, assured expression betraying none of the desperate conviction that was bubbling underneath. It amazed Draco sometimes that other people thought Rigel cold.

"He won't be starting until tomorrow, unfortunately," Draco cut in, placing his hand on Rigel's shoulder proprietarily, "Today Rigel's atonement allotment had been booked by his friends in payment for scaring the life out of us yesterday."

"Oh, has it?" Rigel asked, amused.

"Certainly," Pansy sniffed, "You apologized to us first, after all, so our vengeance… ah. penance, that is, must come before Professor Snape's."

"What will we be doing today?" Rigel asked, looking with trepidation between Draco and Pansy, seeming to have forgotten Snape was still standing there. Good, Draco thought with a smirk, let him recognize who he should really be paying attention to.

"Dueling," Draco said, crossing his arms, "If you think you're up for it, that is. I know a real wizard is leagues beyond your usual prey—I promise, we won't be as easy to take down as some old werewolf."

His friend affected a fearful expression, glancing up at Professor Snape with nervous hesitation. "I really shouldn't just rush into danger like that, Draco. My life is more important than a duel with you and Pansy, after all—"

"Get out," Snape scowled, sweeping his robes around him imperiously, "I don't want to see any of you until the school week resumes."

"Yes, Professor," they chorused, hurrying out the door without further delay.

"Are we really going to duel?" Rigel asked once they'd traversed a far enough difference from Snape's office, "Or did you just say that to diffuse the tension?"

"Are you accusing us of lying to a teacher?" Pansy asked, pressing a hand to her heart in dismay.

"Never." Rigel shook his head. "Don't know what I was thinking. Shall we go and change, then?"

They turned toward the Slytherin common room at the next intersection. Upon reaching the dorms, Pansy peeled off into the room she shared with Millicent, and Rigel and Draco continued on to their own.

When they entered, Draco immediately bit back a curse. A cloying, insistent emotion was battering at his empathy, and he wanted nothing to do with it. He hastily tried muting his sense with the Occlumency he'd been practicing, but he wasn't yet good enough to block it out completely. Resigning himself to feeling slightly nauseated, Draco hurried toward his trunk as quickly and quietly as he could.

He grabbed his loose training attire and began changing as swiftly as he was able, pointedly not looking in the direction of his roommate's hangings. After he shrugged on his lightweight tunic he realized Rigel, the blessed idiot, was taking his sweet time gathering up his clothing and looked to be planning on changing in the bathroom.

Draco threw a pair of socks at Rigel with impeccable aim. As they bounced off his friend's head, Rigel whipped around and frowned at him like he was the idiot.

"What?" Rigel said, standing.

Draco motioned frantically at the four-poster bed across the room, where the hangings were drawn shut rather pointedly.

"Oh, is Theo sleeping?" Rigel whispered, looking and feeling apologetic.

"Sleep—" Draco bit back a groan of disbelief. Only Rigel. Shaking his head, Draco left the room posthaste, unable to stand another moment of the clenching, twisting sweetness that was trying to invade his head.

It was a few long minutes before his friend joined him in the hallway. Rigel's raised eyebrow as he asked why Draco hadn't gone ahead to the common room was the straw that did it.

"Because I didn't want Pansy to hear me tell you what a complete idiot you are!" Draco whisper-shouted as he glanced about to make sure no one would overhear them.

"What have I done now?" Rigel asked, genuinely nonplussed.

"Rigel, when a bloke has his hangings drawn in the middle of the day, what do you think that means?" Draco said, rubbing his forehead.

Rigel actually blinked in confusion. "I…thought he was napping. You think he was studying or something? I wasn't making that much…noise…oh. It—he—oh."

Draco sighed. At least he didn't have to spell it out.

"Really?" Rigel wrinkled his nose as though completely put-off by the very idea.

Draco snorted. As though Rigel had never—he cut the thought off. It was…no. Just no.

"I've never noticed him—I mean—" It was almost amusing to see his stoic friend so flustered. "He didn't used to do that, did he?"

What did Rigel want, a timeline? Embarrassed, Draco shrugged. "Guess he discovered himself this summer. Can we not talk about it anymore? Just…be more aware, okay?"

Rigel nodded seriously, every plane of his face a study in carefully disguised horror. It was have been hilarious, if it weren't so odd. Surely Rigel had—no, no, still not going there.

Draco shook his head to clear it. Maybe his empathy was getting stronger if he was still getting echoes of a strange curiosity all the way in the hall.

"Pansy must be waiting," he muttered, turning to lead the way out into the common room before things got any more weird.

Is was a bit surreal, meeting in the middle of the day all dressed in their running clothes. The common room was bustling with students attempting to rush through their Sunday homework, and it was several moments before they spotted Pansy being clucked over by two upperclassmen Draco definitely could have gone without seeing.

"But it doesn't suit you at all, Pansy," Rosier was saying mournfully, "The color is positively drab, my dear."

"It's built for functionality, not appearance, Aldon," Pansy said chidingly, "And there, you see? Draco and Rigel are wearing just the same."

Rosier turned to eye their plain, somewhat worn attire with equal parts confusion and distaste. Before he could issue whatever scathing comment Draco could see floating behind his sharp, oddly-colored eyes, Rookwood, with his usual aptitude for blunting his friend's razor wit, cut in. "Are you going to play Quidditch, then?"

"They could play Quidditch in sensible clothing," Rosier sniffed. No doubt his definition of 'sensible' was uncannily close to the actual definition of 'flattering.'

"We're exercising, I already told you," Pansy sighed, "It would be entirely wasteful to muck about in the dirt in my dress robes, don't you agree?"

"I'm sure I wouldn't know," Rosier frowned, "What sort of exercise involves getting dirty, anyway? Are you gardening for Professor Sprout, or something?"

Draco could feel the disbelief coming from Rigel, who was gazing at Rosier is something like wonderment, but the sad truth was that Rosier likely couldn't fathom any appropriate physical activity that involved soiling one's clothing. His idea of exercise was likely limited to Quidditch, abraxan-riding, and indoor stage dueling. Draco doubted he'd ever even seen someone doing sit-ups or push-ups, much less the wide variety of calisthenics and stretches that Rigel had somewhat sadistically incorporated into their daily regimen. The only people Draco knew who did any sort of exercise, in fact, were all members of their House Quidditch teams.

"We're going running," Draco said, restraining the eye-roll he could feel building up only because before Draco made Flint's team roster he hadn't done any actual exercise, either.

"Then we stretch and build our muscle groups before practicing our footwork, then our wandwork," Pansy added, smiling.

"I knew you enjoyed the outdoors, Pansy, but I admit I didn't realize the three of you were such…enthusiasts," Rosier said, still looking a bit confused, but also radiating more interest by the second. Draco sighed inwardly. The worst thing about Rosier was his damnable curiosity.

"Oh yes, though we usually go out much earlier," Pansy said, a bit of pride showing through her smile, "It's remarkably refreshing, and energizing, as counterintuitive as it sounds. It was difficult at first, but I'd say Draco and I have come a long way since we started, haven't we?"

Draco smiled back, nodding in agreement. They weren't quite caught up to Rigel's level in terms of the strength or speed of their repetitions, but they were leaps from where they'd begun.

"Has Rigel not improved, then?" Rookwood asked, a curious light to his expression. This was why he and Rosier made such good friends, Draco decided.

Pansy laughed lightly, but Draco could feel the edge of a more pointed emotion than amusement as she said, "Rigel is leagues ahead of the two of us, I'm afraid—he's been at it much longer, after all."

As Rosier and Rookwood gazed with interest at Rigel, who was doing his best impression of an embarrassed clam, Draco tried to figure out what emotion he was getting from Pansy, exactly. It wasn't anything like jealousy or dislike. It was more like the feeling of sharp satisfaction you'd get if you were doing well at a game you particularly enjoyed playing. He didn't know why revealing that Rigel was good at exercising should bring Pansy so much enjoyment, but there it was.

He'd been getting similar feelings from Pansy all year, and he wasn't quite sure what to do about it. He'd always known Pansy was smart and good at reading people, but lately she seemed more…manipulative, almost. She gave off flashes of dark amusement when her face showed polite concern, or sometimes Draco would sense a deep, scornful boredom that clashed jarringly with her earnestly fascinated expression as she listened to an upperclassman's anecdote. Before this year, Draco would have said Pansy was like a particularly quick-witted flower: amusing but soft. Was she growing into something sharper? Or had this facet of her character always been there, and he was only now becoming aware of her thorns?

Rosier suddenly clapped his hands together. "This is so fascinating. Can we watch?"

Now Pansy was definitely feeling smug, but her words were perfectly demure. "It won't be very exciting to see. Surely you have more important things to occupy your time?"

"What could be more important than broadening our horizons?" Rosier asked, spreading his arms grandly, "We're ever so curious about this sort of exertion. Aren't we, Rookwood? And who knows? With you three fine, upcoming scions promoting it, I'm sure it'll be all the rage in no time."

"Perhaps you should participate," Rigel suggested. Draco had to hold back a laugh at the innocent expression on his friend's face. "It's a lot of fun, once you get used to sweating."

Rosier could not stop the curl that tugged his lip upwards in instinctive disgust. "Ah, no thank you, Rigel. I'm sure we'll be content to watch."

"But perhaps we will participate next time, if it does look as fun as you say," Rookwood said, a small smirk tugging at his otherwise stony features.

"Hmm, yes, who knows?" Rosier said, looking extremely unhappy at such a prospect.

Draco decided then that Rookwood was an all right sort, despite the company he kept. At least he knew when to take his partner down a peg.

"Shall we, then?" Pansy lead their little party across the common room. Draco didn't know if this was going to be a disaster or a lark, but he did know that whatever Rosier claimed about their clothing's unsuitability, Pansy looked all kinds of…suitable in her jogging trousers.

Even though it was chilly, the lawn was still populated by a fair few students. Suddenly Draco wasn't so sure that making a spectacle of themselves was going to be as fun as it had sounded when he suggested it. After a moment, however, he straightened his shoulders and shrugged all thoughts of the other students to the back of his mind. Malfoys did not change their plans simply because others became witness to them. If it was worth doing privately, he should not be embarrassed to do it publically. His reasons remained the same, after all, and a Malfoy's reasoning was beyond contestation.

Ignoring the curious looks they were receiving, Draco began stretching alongside Rigel and Pansy as though it were any other morning. He had to reflect that there had probably never been three people better at collectively pretending not to notice something than he, Rigel, and Pansy in that moment of calm, unruffled stretching.

The moment was broken, of course, when Rosier said, "What does that one do?"

Rigel paused mid-twist and said, "Lower-back stretch."

"Ah," Rosier said, nodding seriously.

Draco dutifully suppressed a scoff. He was nearly certain at this point that Rosier was exaggerating his ignorant fascination on purpose. The git.

They left the two upperclassman to their own devices while they made a circuit around the lake. People seemed generally content to ignore them once it was clear they weren't doing anything more interesting than going for a jog. That disregard evaporated, of course, when they returned to their starting point and Draco began leading them through their footwork drills.

Before they'd even gotten through all of them, they were interrupted by a pair of inquisitive Gryffindors who apparently weren't raised to mind their own business.

"Are those the exercises from Dueling class, Malfoy?" Weasley sidled into their space like a homeless dog sniffing for scraps. "We weren't assigned any practice, were we?"

"Some people have the dedication of character learn without being forced to, Weasley," Draco told him, not pausing in his complex shuffle even once.

"Is that why Parkinson and Rigel are following along?" the redhead asked, scratching his nose in the most plebian way Draco had ever seen. "Only they aren't even in Dueling."

"Yes," he sniffed, "In life there's this thing called taking advantage of all your resources—not that you have any resources—and that means Rigel and Pansy don't need to be enrolled in a class to reap the benefits of instruction."

"So you're tutoring your friends in what Professor Lupin teaches us," Weasley said, scowling a bit as he attempted to ignore the insult Draco had given at his expense.

"Very clever of you to figure that out," Draco drawled.

"All right, you prat, I was just making conversation—" Weasley started, but Longbottom, of all people, cut across him.

"I think it's nice, what Malfoy's doing," the lump of porridge masquerading as a pureblood scion even seemed to mean it.

"It isn't nice; it's practical," Draco corrected him, wondering why all of a sudden people thought Slytherins were going soft. It was all Rigel's fault, he concluded. If not for his mushy reputation Draco wouldn't have to be twice as acerbic to make up for it.

"Well either way…" Longbottom visibly steeled himself, hands shaking slightly. "Would it be all right if we joined in? I don't know m-much about Dueling, but maybe I could try," he trailed off in confidence at the end, looking down at his feet as though wondering how they'd brought him here.

Draco actually had to stop and stare at the Longbottom heir for a moment he was so perplexed. When had he ever been inviting to this kid? Did he think that just because he was vague acquaintances with Rigel meant Draco was by proxy his friend as well? He opened his mouth to disabuse the poor, disturbed young man of this notion, but predictably Rigel seized the moment for his own misguided sense of fairness.

"That's a great idea, Neville," the dark-haired boy said, "We practice so often together, our moves are becoming predictable. A little new blood will be just the thing, won't it, guys?"

Pansy tilted her head in that politely calculating way of hers and nodded slowly. "Why not? It would be a good chance to diversify our range of tactics."

Draco had to pause at that. It would be nice to go up against new opponents; it would be nice seeing Rigel trounce somebody else for a change, at that. Draco didn't know how his friend was improving so quickly, but he'd shot ahead of Draco and Pansy in terms of fluidity and speed in the last few weeks. Draco would accuse him of sneaking in extra practices if he didn't spend most of every single day with Rigel. He supposed some people just had a knack for certain things.

"It might not be fair." Draco couldn't resist the small smirk that slid into place as he eyed Longbottom and Weasley in their weekend robes. "We practice daily, and keep in good condition." The unspoken 'unlike you' did not go unscowled upon by the more freckled of the Gryffindor duo.

"Everyone starts somewhere," Rigel said evenly, "And Ron is in Dueling with you, right? So he can help Neville with the steps. They'll be at our pace in no time."

Draco shot Rigel an annoyed look—surely he was not suggesting they start including Weasley and Longbottom in their morning practices. That was their time.

"We could make it a weekly thing," Pansy jumped in, sending Draco a reassuring glance. At least one of his friends could be counted upon to read his mind, then. "If it goes well, that is."

Rookwood stepped forward from where he and Rosier had been keeping a respectful distance. "In that case, why don't we join now as well? From what I've witnessed, you three do seem to know what you're doing."

"The more the merrier," Rigel said, and Draco doubted he was even being ironic.

"How will it work, then?" Weasley said, eyeing the five Slytherins with a mildly flattering amount of caution, "Should we starting doing all those jumping things and push-up exercises?"

"You can join in those next week," Pansy said briskly, "For now you should stretch, focusing on your legs, arms, and wrists."

As Pansy lead the four newcomers through a beginners stretching routine, Draco pulled Rigel aside and asked, "Are we really doing this? It's going to slow down our training."

"Only for a short while," Rigel said, smiling a bit, "And we still have our weekday practices. This is just some extra inter-house cooperation."

Draco snorted, "More like an inter-house charity project."

"You can put it on your resume," Rigel said blithely.

He had to laugh at that. Wait until he told his parents he'd started a dueling charity for the tragically under-trained at Hogwarts. "What shall we call it?" he asked, grinning, "I need an appropriately impressive title to put after 'President and CEO' on the business cards."

Rigel thought for a moment, "How about the Slytherin Association of Defense?"

"You want people to call it 'SAD?'" Draco lifted an eyebrow at Rigel's innocuous expression. He could feel the amusement flitting through Rigel's mind as easily as the sun shining through the clouds.

"Then how about the Defense Association For Teens?" Rigel smirked.

"'DAFT' is worse than 'SAD.'" Draco rolled his eyes.

"Then what about Draco's Ultimate Life Lessons?" Rigel suggested.

"Now you're just being ridiculous," Draco laughed. How did Rigel come up with this stuff? "It has to be simple, easy to remember, and explicit. Let's call it the Dueling Club."

Rigel winced, "Remember the dueling club from last year?"

"Oh. Well, we don't want it associated with Lockhart." Draco frowned. "Should we just call it the Defense Association, then?"

Rigel tilted his head in exaggerated thoughtfulness. "That's perfect. And we can call it the DA for short, and when anyone asks what the DA stands for, you know what we'll tell them?"

Draco was almost afraid to ask.

"We'll say it stands for Draco's Army," Rigel said, nodding sagely.

He groaned at the utter cheesiness of that idea. "Just go back to stretching, Rigel, and leave the thinking to me."

"Yes, sir!" Rigel saluted him with a jaunty wink and quickstepped over to the others before Draco had a chance to reply. Honestly, his friends were quite ridiculous sometimes. Draco's Army indeed.

Rigel was inundated with mail on Monday morning. The perfunctory post-Halloween 'are-you-alive?' letter from Archie was expected, as was the short, concerned-yet-proud note from Sirius, who'd apparently heard the story from Remus already. At least her uncle's timeliness saved her the trouble of telling Sirius herself, though Rigel knew her reply would have to be at once apologetic and self-deprecating in order to properly downplay the whole ordeal.

The missives attached to Archie's letter were a bit less expected, though not unwelcome. Leo had written yet another long, somewhat rambling letter by the looks of it. Rigel found herself more and more often becoming an ear to his troubles, and wondered if he was becoming a bit overwhelmed by his position. On the other hand, he might just be a remarkably poor letter-writer.

The last letter was from Caelum Lestrange, and Rigel had to suppress an incredulous laugh as she hastily tucked it away with the others to read later in the day. The curiosity burned at her all through her first two classes, though, and when she finally time-turned back to Advanced Potions after lunch, she stepped into the first unassuming alcove and ripped the letters open with the tip of her wand.

Harry,

Tired of America yet? When are you coming back to the alleys? It's rather dull here without you. I haven't beat anyone into the dirt in ages—I do hope you're practicing, and not just that stuffy exhibition style they teach in schools these days, otherwise I may be obliged to remind you how ineffectual that ridged nonsense is in real life. We'll have to find a new practice spot, though. The Phoenix opened its courtyard to the folk who lost housing units in the latest Ministry raid, so it'll be a bit crowded until at least the new year, I'd wager. Maybe you can come to my house for our lessons—that's right! I've got my own digs now. Da has been pestering me to get out of the house and find a job for ages. I haven't time for what he calls 'gainful employment,' of course, but my unofficial full-time gig does come with certain benefits, at least in the homestead arena.

Da talks about you often, and wants to know what your summer plans are—I wouldn't mind knowing myself, to tell the truth. Will you be wrapped up in another of your potions projects? Or maybe you'd like to do something more fun. There's a tournament in the lower alleys mid-July, and the organizers aren't exactly meticulous about the names that appear on the entrance forms. Might be a good chance to test your progress. If you do end up working with my Da again, be a sport and tell him I'm working at Ma's clinic. She's covering for me, keeping the lectures on 'wasting time with those ragtag friends of yours' to a minimum. I'm not complaining or anything; I brought it on myself when I decided not to tell him. He doesn't understand the lower alleys. He tries not to think about how many of Ma's relatives are in the court of rogues, and his station wouldn't let him approve of the work I do even if he were to know of it. I guess I don't need to tell you what it's like to keep secrets from your family—sometimes I think you know more than I do, on that account.

Well, I won't bore you with more maudlin musings at the moment. Plenty of time to wear your ears out when you come home. Time enough to wear your feet out, too! You'd better not have gone soft at your prissy American school, Harry. I'll set Marek on you if you have—he's been dying to teach you proper knife-fighting.

With those pleasant prospects to look forward to, stay safe, and I'll see you soon.

-Leo

Rigel shook her head as she folded the letter neatly and tucked it away. Definitely a terrible letter-writer. Leo sounded incredibly bored, and she wasn't sure if that was an improvement over his tired, somewhat bogged down tone in the previous letter or not. She didn't want her friend to be overly troubled, but a bored Lionel Hurst could not possibly be a good thing.

Lestrange's letter was, if anything, at least a refreshing change from her usual correspondence.

Potter,

What have you been doing all semester? I haven't heard a lick of news about that tacky brewing technique you droned on about at the showcase. If you think you can keep the research all hush-hush now that you're not interning at the Guild anymore you've got another thing coming. That process you published was completely nonsensical, and if you don't send me your actual notes on the subject I shall tout you as a fraud to every influential Potions Master my parents are acquainted with—which is quite a lot, in case your feeble American education doesn't teach you about important things like Society.

What are you doing this winter? Wasting away in some mediocre lab, no doubt. The labs here at Durmstrang are state of the art, and it's almost a shame I'll have to leave them when I graduate this spring, but of course I'll be moving on to bigger and better things. Everyone here is scrambling to pick a specialty before they graduate, but naturally I've already secured a proper apprenticeship for the summer. Master Whitaker clearly recognizes talent when he sees it, as he's requested I accompany him on a research trip to Chile this June. If I show merit he promises to keep me on until I've taken my Mastery. I'll have my credentials before my nineteenth birthday, I don't doubt. Not as impressive as Master Snape's record, but I don't think they should let candidates take the Mastery exam before they've even had a real apprenticeship. What good is a seventeen-year-old Master without any experience? No doubt you're one of those arrogant twits who thinks you can pass your examinations right after you graduate school, as Snape did. Well forget that nonsense right now and resign yourself to an apprenticeship like everyone else, you self-centered novice. Maybe if you're very good I'll let you be my apprentice once I have my Mastery. You can clean my cauldrons. If you haven't blown yourself up with your ridiculous tinkering before then.

Are you coming to the gala? Mother is letting me go again this year. I was politely asked not to show my face last year, something about an unfortunate incident involving your stupid cousin at the previous year's gala. I need someone to insult besides your dratted 'relative,' though. The twerp makes it entirely too easy.

You'd better send me those notes! And if you have any new breakthroughs I better be the first to hear about them. What's the point of pretending to be your friend, otherwise?

Don't take all month about it.

Your future Master,

-C. Lestrange

Rigel allowed herself an incredulous laugh before tucking that letter away as well. Only Lestrange would be such an obnoxious jerk and still manage to make himself sound desperate for attention. She would have to tell him that, when she wrote back to inform him that she wouldn't be his apprentice if he were the last Potions Master alive. She'd start her own Guild before that happened, in fact.

Reading the letters hadn't taken nearly as long as she thought it would, so she was significantly early for her Advanced Potions lesson. She didn't have anything better to do, however, and she certainly shouldn't be showing her face anywhere else in the castle while she was ostensibly attending Transfigurations, so she slipped down to Lab One under her invisibility cloak. She could at least get some studying done in the hallway before Professor Snape got there to unlock the door.

When she quietly arrived in the corridor leading to the Lab, however, she saw the door standing wide open, with stark, unforgiving light flooding out into the hallway. She slowed her approach, wondering what Snape was doing there so early—he had a class, didn't he? She was about to take her cloak off and step into the light when she heard a cultured voice that was definitely not Snape's acerbic drawl say, "Are you going to ignore me all morning, then?"

"As long as I am able." That was certainly Snape's resigned reverberation.

"It wasn't my idea to come here, Severus." Rigel recognized the other voice by its deceptively light remonstration, and had to wonder what Lucius Malfoy was doing at Hogwarts in the middle of the school day.

"It was your idea to cancel my morning classes in the guise of securing my opinion on the state of Hogwarts' wards, though, was it not, Lucius?"

"Ah, but I have come to entreat your opinion on the matter. In any case, I thought you'd enjoy a break from your tedious duties. Do not tell me you've begun to suddenly enjoy teaching after all these years."

Rigel kept her cloak firmly around her and crept silently closer to the door. She really shouldn't be eavesdropping, and she had no actual reason to be suspicious of two old friends having a casual conversation in the dungeons, but there was something screaming at her instincts that this wasn't all it seemed. It was too convenient that Malfoy happened to stop by Snape's domain just after a mysterious force caused a creature attack at Hogwarts. Something suspicious in her gut nudged her closer to the doorway, insisting that she pay close attention to whatever came next.

"My opinion is that the wards are just fine, and that the incident on Halloween had absolutely nothing to do with the age of the castle's magic, as you very well know. I do not have time to indulge this fiction today, and would appreciate if you could make your fake report to the other governors and leave." Snape was moving briskly back and forth across the lab, taking ingredients from various cupboards and pulling out equipment according to some mental checklist only he was privy to.

Malfoy was leaning against one of the spotless workspaces, watching Snape circle the room lazily as he said, "I'm sure I don't know what you mean. As a member of the Board of Education I have a vested interest in ensuring the security at Hogwarts remains unmatched in the world."

"And as his representative you have a vested interest in making my life more difficult than it needs to be," Snape scoffed.

"Not more than necessary," Malfoy gently stressed, "You must agree that getting to the bottom of this incident is in everyone's best interest right now. Dumbledore doesn't need any more bad press, and we certainly don't need traitors running about willy-nilly, sparking phenomena of national curiosity and living untouched by the vengeance they've so unwisely earned."

"I told you I don't know that it's him," Snape said with the air of someone repeating something for the umpteenth time, "Any number of things could have caused the madness we witnessed on Hallows Eve."

"If he had but a moment to explain to our lord what he thinks he's doing here, I'm sure we could clear up this little mystery in no time," Malfoy said, a venom behind his mild words belying the innocent nature of his suggestion. Who were they talking about? Someone at Hogwarts who shouldn't be?

"I can't touch him while he's holed up in this school." Snape had stopped gathering ingredients and stood, scowling, at an angle that let him view both Malfoy and the door. It would have been the perfect position to watch for eavesdroppers—if an eavesdropper hadn't been under an invisibility cloak, at least. "You know that. He knows that. Even the rat knows that, which is why he's made his bed here in the first place. He's only hiding in plain sight because he knows the Party has no power here. Dumbledore swallowed some half-spun tale about repentance and redemption, no doubt. I argued against his placement, but I have limited sway over the appointments—obviously, or the wolf would not be begging at our door, either."

Rigel rolled her eyes at Snape's callous reduction of Remus to his condition, but largely ignored that comment in focusing on the rest of what he'd said. The only person she could think of at Hogwarts that was a Party member besides Snape was Pettigrew. At least, he was the only new addition to the staff that fit the description. It sounded very much like Peter Pettigrew had come to Hogwarts not as a spy for Riddle, as she'd half-assumed, but rather to find refuge from the powerful statesman. And Riddle suspected Pettigrew had something to do with what happened on Halloween, apparently.

"He must leave sometime," Malfoy said, an annoyed frown crossing his elegant features, "Perhaps over the holidays we can catch him out."

"I doubt it," Snape sneered, "For all his utter ineptitude, he is not careless. He's too cowardly to make a foolhardy mistake. I watch him carefully, but of course he knows I am watching. He may well remain on the premises over break, as well."

Malfoy rubbed his temples delicately, "Well he will want a full report, in any case. Your eyewitness account of the Halloween debacle as well, I don't doubt. Can you get away?"

"Not before the holiday," Snape flicked a hand dismissively, resuming his collection of materials.

"You must come to the gala, then," Malfoy said, relaxing a bit as the conversation moved away from serious waters.

"If I must," Snape snorted, "Who's hosting, again?"

"The Parkinsons," Malfoy said, sounding amused for some reason.

"Salazar save me from that woman's incessant matchmaking attempts," Snape muttered into the standard size three beaker he was inspecting for dust.

"Take a date, then." Malfoy's grin was unrelenting.

"Don't be absurd." Snape's face twisted in distaste. "I won't be staying long enough to entertain a guest."

"You're never any fun, Severus," Malfoy sighed.

"You forget how dangerous it is for your health when I have fun, Lucius." Snape straightened his shoulders somewhat predatorily. "Perhaps you'd like to remember at the end of term."

Malfoy grimaced, but Rigel thought it was good-natured. "I remember just fine, old friend. No need to emasculate me in the ring again—once was more than enough, and Narcissa still laughs anytime someone mentions peacocks."

"A common occurrence, I'd imagine, as you keep a herd of the beasts on your property," Snape smirked.

"A reminder." Malfoy shrugged unconcernedly. "I shall not forget the lesson in humility you dealt me that day. What callow youths we were, Severus."

"Speak for yourself, Sir Peacock," Snape said, drawing his wand to check the time. "I have an appointment at ten. I trust you can see your way to the gates without antagonizing anyone else?"

"Oh I don't know." Malfoy pretended to consider. "Perhaps I'll stop by McGonagall's classroom and tell her I'm doing a surprise quality of education audit while I'm in the neighborhood."

"Do as you wish, but recall that if you do antagonize her into transfiguring you, Narcissa is not here to change you back."

That was argument enough for Malfoy, it seemed, who began to move toward the door. Rigel scrambled backwards as quietly as she was able, but she still could have sworn Snape's eyes shot to exactly the spot she had been standing in for a few agonizing seconds. He didn't say anything, however, and Rigel could only hope he hadn't thought it necessary to use Occlumency to scan the area. She ducked around the corner in time to avoid colliding with Mr. Malfoy as he swept toward the nearest staircase, and waited an agonizing ten whole minutes before carefully stowing her invisibility cloak in an expanded pocket and making her way as casually as possible back toward Lab One.

It was a good thing they were going over a potion she'd already studied that day, as Rigel's mind was not as focused on brewing as it should have been. There were too many interesting implications to consider. Pettigrew had somehow betrayed the SOW Party and sought asylum at Hogwarts where Riddle's vengeance couldn't reach him. Whatever he'd done must have been pretty bad, to make him think running to Dumbledore was his best option.

She wondered if she should tell someone—Remus, maybe—that Pettigrew had potentially switched sides again, and might be in trouble. They weren't exactly friends anymore, but as Rigel understood it that was because when Pettigrew chose the SOW Party he discontinued his associations with the Marauders. There must be something left of the friendly Gryffindor boy her parents had once described, though. No one betrayed the Party; it was a for-life sort of commitment. To try and back out was social and economic suicide. Plenty of examples had been made to that effect in the early days of the Party's ascendance, including some of what used to be the most powerful, wealthy families in Wizarding society.

Then again, was it really her business? A part of her said no, nothing was her business unless it directly related to her family or her potions work. A different, blossoming part of her hesitated to be so indifferent, however. If Pettigrew did have something to do with Halloween, then he was at least indirectly a threat to Remus, and possibly a problem with the potential to impact thousands of people all over the country, if his influence on the creatures of Hogwarts was any indication. She had no proof that this was the case, but…perhaps she could acquire some? Riddle must know something about whatever was going on. He was presumably going to discuss said happenings at the gala with Professor Snape, in fact. Since she already knew the meeting was to take place perhaps she could simply…keep an eye out that night for anything of interest. It couldn't hurt to listen in for a short while—if only to make sure Riddle was keeping his promise about not interfering at Hogwarts. That was undeniably her business…right?

Rigel put Malfoy's visit out of her mind until two weeks later, when its consequences unceremoniously marched through the front doors.

"Who're they?" Millicent asked from across the table.

Rigel looked up with the others to see a group of adult witches and wizards gathered at the entrance to the Great Hall.

"Ward experts," Draco said knowledgably, "They're here to inspect the Hogwarts defenses by order of the Board of Governors. My father commissioned them personally after that mess on Halloween."

"And the goblins?" Theo asked, raising an eyebrow.

Draco frowned and stood in his seat a little to peer over the heads of his peers, "Oh. I don't know. My father didn't say anything about goblins in his letter."

"Perhaps they know something about what happened that night," Pansy said, tilting her head consideringly.

"No need for them to come all this way to provide information," Blaise said, frowning, "Goblins don't trouble themselves for wizards very often, and certainly never without a vested interest of their own."

"Yeah, not like they care if a bunch of wizard kids get eaten by spiders," Theo said, shuddering a bit.

"Hogwarts is home to tons of really rare and valuable magical objects, though," Pansy pointed out, "Some of them are probably goblin-made. Maybe they want to personally see that those objects are well-protected."

Rigel thought that argument sounded a bit weak. If Goblins cared about goblin-made artifacts in that way, they were just as likely to be glad if those objects became vulnerable. Treasures that were well guarded by wizards weren't any use to goblins, after all.

She gazed thoughtfully at the group that was now milling about the Great Hall freely, looking up and around at infrastructure and wards that were presumably visible to their experienced eyes. Was it all an act? A ploy to excuse Malfoy's presence in the school those weeks ago? Looking at the goblins' fierce expressions, she doubted it. There was a deadly earnestness to their focus as they swept the hall, clawed hands firmly clasped around strange looking devices that beeped in low increments.

One passed by their table, and Rigel felt her stomach drop with alarm as its little device began beeping like mad just as it drew abreast of her seat. The goblin swung toward her in a move almost too fast to track, one hand leaving the device to seize the front of her robes and yank her bodily out of her seat.

Up close its face was arresting in its snarling suspicion. She brought both hands up automatically in a move drilled into her by Leo, one on the goblin's wrist and one on the outside of its elbow. The arm attached to the hand holding her robes was thin, but strong. The joint below her right hand was just brittle. It wouldn't take too much pressure to snap it backwards, should it come to that. All of this information went through her head in an instant, but Rigel was nothing if not infinitely cautious. Instead of devolving into sudden violence, she braced her feet and lifted her chin, using her height in a weak attempt at intimidation as she said, "What?"

"You have an artifact of power on you," the goblin ground out, the words sounding like gears grinding without oil to slick them.

"So?" Rigel said, more calm than she felt. Inside she was trying to figure out what had set the little device off. Her time-turner? Her invisibility cloak? The Marauder's Map? She had all three on her at the moment. Depending on what the device was designed to detect, it could be any of them, or the combination of all three.

"Let's have a look," the goblin grinned nastily, raising the device with his other hand and pointing it at her person.

It began to beep faster and faster as it approached her sternum, where the time-turner nestled safely beneath her clothes. The goblin tossed the device aside and reached greedily for the neck of her robes, but his fingers had barely grazed her collar when a pale, long-fingered hand clamped down on its wrist and jerked the goblin back. She just remembered to let go of the creature's bony joint before it was thrown several feet away from her.

Professor Snape stepped menacingly between Rigel and the goblin, his tall, black-draped form more comforting than she would like to admit.

"You are here to search the castle, not its inhabitants," Snape said. His voice was soft, but his words carried in the utter silence that Rigel now noticed ruled the hall.

"It takes a wizard to use the artifact," the goblin spat, its device now back in its hands, "The boy lit up the magometer. He's guilty."

This, Rigel thought as whispers began to travel the hall, was not going to be good PR. Perhaps she would take up the Weasley twins on their personal image offer after all.

"My student carries a Ministry-sanctioned magical device on his person that has nothing to do with your ineffectual investigation," Snape said, his tone entirely dismissive. "I suggest you move on with your task if you don't want to be hauled in front of an inter-species relations committee to answer for the brutality you displayed toward this child of thirteen."

She could not see the goblin around Snape's torso, but she could hear the frustration in its voice when it growled, "Not until I see the artifact. You could be protecting—"

"Protecting the very thing that is a danger to my students? Do not insult me again, goblin." Rigel could see the shiver go through the crowd at those words, and imagined the fury on Snape's face must be something to behold.

"I must ascertain its purpose," the goblin insisted, though it certainly sounded less eager to cross her Head of House now.

"Its purpose is to keep my student alive," Snape sneered, "By all means, remove it from his person for your little inspection and explain to your superiors how you broke the Goblin Peace Accords by murdering a wizard child in cold blood in front of a thousand witnesses."

The goblin spluttered, and she could see its feet slid back in clear panic. Rigel could feel the heaviness of the stares now leveled at her, and while she applauded Snape for defending her education so thoroughly, she wondered if claiming she needed some kind of life-sustaining medical device was really the only way to distract from her time-turner. She was going to have a lot of explaining to do, at this rate.

Professor Dumbledore finally stepped down from the dais and began serenely leading the group of ward-inspectors out of the hall, the goblins following grudgingly after.

Professor Snape turned to Rigel and inspected her person quickly before giving her a satisfied nod and a gesture to regain her seat. She sat down slowly, still trying to catch up to everything that had just happened. The goblins were looking for something specific, an artifact of significant magical power, and they had good reason to suspect it was at Hogwarts, being used by a wizard in a way that presumably had something to do with driving magical creatures mad. She could see why that might concern the goblins, but she wondered vaguely how they knew about such an artifact before her mind jerked her back to the most vital of present concerns.

If Pettigrew was indeed involved in the Halloween debacle as Snape and Malfoy suspected, then he had the artifact, and he was sitting right there at the Head Table—no don't look! Time for that later. Focus, Rigel. The goblins had left the hall to search the rest of the castle, which meant they might not find the artifact if Pettigrew had it on him, which meant it might be all her fault if something awful happened because the goblins had left because of her—no, that's not right, concentrate! Professor Snape had dramatically stepped in to shield her from the goblin but in doing so had essentially prevented the goblins from continuing their search in the Great Hall, effectively protecting Pettigrew as well. Why. Theory one: her Head of House valued her education so highly that is was more important than stopping a potential uprising of magical creatures—false. Theory two: Professor Snape had his own, secret reasons for not wanting Pettigrew found out right there in the hall in front of everyone. Possible. He wanted the artifact for himself? No—Riddle wants it. Rigel felt her eyes grow wide as all the pieces came together at once.

Riddle had tasked Pettigrew with finding or retrieving some kind of artifact. Pettigrew had found it, and, instead of returning to Riddle, had gotten it into his head to run to Hogwarts instead. Maybe he was power-hungry. Maybe he was an idiot. Probably he was both, Rigel decided. This artifact meant something to the goblins, but it was important enough that the Ministry was (maybe, likely) conducting raids on the lower alleys in an attempt to track it down. All this started only a few months ago, however, which means it was an artifact that hadn't been discovered until recently, or at least had gone missing from its usual location recently.

A stolen artifact…Rigel's mind flashed to that summer, a redheaded curse-breaker casually mentioning a break in at a high-profile archeological site. It flashed again to the night of Halloween, the sight of a pudgy professor startled out of his reverie, something round catching the light as it rolled out of sight. A niggling memory dug at her mind until, with a burst of realization, she saw a panicked-face Pettigrew rooting around in the alley dust for a grubby paper sack, looking apoplectic despite being barely bruised by her clumsy collision. She was whirling with newfound knowledge, dizzy as the strands of chance and circumstances pulled tight in sudden irrefutability, settling into a picture that staggered even as it awed.

A hand on her shoulder jerked her violently back to the present, and her brain finally grasped the most immediate and insistent of concerns. Her time-turner secret was safe, but now everyone thought she was on magical life-support. Right. On the bright side, no one thought she was responsible for the mess on Halloween, which is how things could have gone without Snape's timely (if ultimately self-serving) assistance.

"Are you okay, Rigel?" Pansy asked quietly from her left.

Rigel told her head to nod evenly, but only managed a half-coordinated jerk that she doubted reassured anyone. Trying again, she cleared her throat. "I'm fine. Thanks. Sorry. That was…weird, wasn't it?"

"Uh…yeah," Theo said, leaning across the table in a parody of discretion, "No offense, Rigel, but what on earth is going on? What was Snape talking about?"

"I'd…rather not talk about it." It came out more as a plea than a statement, but her friends—her amazing, too-nice friends—settled back as though it had been a command.

The rest of the meal, they casually shielded her from the curious and mildly horrified inquiries of their fellow students, and despite her gratitude all Rigel could think about was how she was going to lie to them when the numbness wore off. Whatever Snape's intentions, he had played into her hands rather efficiently, if cruelly. Draco already thought Rigel Black sickly, plagued with some sort of chronic illness that kept him from feeling comfortable in his own skin. If a few others thought Rigel was fragile, vulnerable in some way that healthy children would find difficult to conceptualize, it might be for the best. Perhaps some of them would keep their distance, would bow to the instinctual defense mechanism that tells the brain not to get attached to wilting flowers and old people.

And maybe, if everything went terribly wrong one day and she and Archie lost control of their artifice, Rigel Black could quietly succumb to an undescribed malady that everyone had sort of seen coming for a while. She tried not to think about the coldness it would take to slowly, methodically break her friends' hearts. She tried, but she couldn't flinch away from the despairing look in Draco's eyes, nor the trembling fear in Pansy's elegant fingers. It had only been five minutes, and already she could not bear to watch their pained confusion. Years of this…it could not be. She would have to explain it some other way, at least for those who were already too attached to keep their distance.

They made it as far as the common room before her friends rounded on her in denial and desperation.

"Rigel, what—"

"Your not, please say you're not—"

"—can't do this to us, Rigel, you can't—"

"Stop." Rigel took two deep breaths as her friends all visibly fought to control themselves. "Sorry. I just—sorry." She blew out a breath. "I'm doing this wrong. I'm fine, you guys. Just fine, I'm not—not dying, I promise."

"How can you say that?" Draco snapped, "What in Merlin's name qualifies as fine on your sociopathic planet?"

"I am," Rigel insisted, quietly but firmly, "I mean it. I'm not—whatever you're thinking, I'm not."

"Professor Snape said—" Pansy cut herself off with a hollow laugh, "Well, we all heard what he said. What did he mean?"

"He was just exaggerating to get the goblin to leave me alone," Rigel said, running a shaking hand through her hair, "I do have a magical device on me. But it's not—it's not life-sustaining, or anything. Professor Snape was protecting me, is all. He knew I didn't want to show it to the goblin."

"Why not?" Blaise said, a dark frown on his face, "What could be worth such an extreme claim?"

"I'm not supposed to show people my device," Rigel said, honest in that at least, "Not supposed to have it, really. It's…experimental. It's something only I have, and to let news of it leak out would be…a bad idea."

It sounded incredibly lame to her ears, too vague to be believable, but perhaps she had underestimated her mysteriousness in the eyes of her friends, because they slowly began to relax before her eyes.

"So you're okay—or as okay as you usually are," Draco clarified, blowing out a slow breath. "Good. That's good. Don't ever scare us like that again."

"Blame Professor Snape this time," Rigel said, shrugging uncomfortably.

"Is that device why you never change in front of us?" Theo asked suddenly, a look of guilty realization on his face.

"Part of the reason, yes," Rigel said. At least, it was part of the reason this year.

"I am a terrible person." Theo's face screwed up in dismay. "I take back all the things I said about you being cock-shy—"

"THEODORE!" Pansy and Millicent shrieked in unified shock and disgust.

"Well I just meant—" he attempted to backpedal as Draco and Blaise groaned in shared embarrassment.

"It's okay," Rigel said, relaxing into a smile and shaking her head, "I don't really mind. If it was someone else, I'd think they were odd, too."

"Yeah, but…" Theo attempted an awkward smile. "I'll get you an awesome Yule present, okay? The best ever, I promise."

"Ah, you don't have to get me anything," Rigel blinked, taken aback. She really didn't deserve to get presents out of this mess.

"Not get you—Rigel, you cheapskate! You weren't going to get me anything, were you?" Theo exclaimed, forgetting his embarrassment in favor of outrage.

"No, I was! Am, I mean," Rigel said quickly, holding back a laugh, "I just haven't decided what, yet."

"Well it better be good," Theo said suspiciously.

The others laughed, and Rigel sent the sandy-haired boy a grateful smile. For all his indelicacy, he certainly knew how to diffuse an emotionally difficult situation with style.

She went to bed that night with her friendships intact, and despite the compounding difficulties she'd had dumped on her head that evening, she couldn't bring herself to regret how things had turned out, at least. Additional complications were nothing novel, for her, and if the alternative was a clear-cut tragedy, she'd take an ambiguous artifice any day.

The next morning saw the ward inspectors back in the Great Hall, though there didn't seem to be any goblins this time. Rigel, Draco, and Pansy were in good spirits after their morning workout and tucked into breakfast with brisk efficiency, ignoring the wizards milling about.

"Recon you scared off those gold-munchers," Theo said, grinning at Rigel from across the table.

"You shouldn't call them that," Blaise said absently as he scanned the morning's post.

"I'll call them whatever I want after they assaulted my friend," Theo said, lifting his nose in half-joking superiority.

"The goblin army hasn't declared war on Rigel," Millicent snorted, "It was one goblin who got a little carried away doing his job. Let's not sensationalize—"

"Too late." Blaise lifted the front cover of the Prophet for everyone to see.

HOGWARTS STUDENT ATTACKED BY VICIOUS MAGIC-HUNGRY GOBLIN!

"That's a bit much for a headline, isn't it?" Rigel asked faintly, wondering how she was supposed to explain this one to her family.

"It sort of wraps around the page awkwardly," Pansy agreed, "And that picture of you isn't even recent."

"They got a picture of me?" Now that was disturbing, seeing as she hadn't posed for a picture in all the time she'd spent as Rigel.

"Not really. Looks like they acquired a picture taken during one of last-year's Quidditch matches," Theo said, examining the page with interest.

"It doesn't say anything too specific," Blaise said in what was probably meant to be a reassuring tone, "Just that the goblin attempted to confiscate a magical item you had on your person against your wishes. It phrases it more like 'steal' than 'confiscate' and more like 'attempted murder' than 'against your wishes,' of course."

Rigel was already drafting the letter to Sirius in her head. She would have to intimate that she'd had the Marauder's Map on her at the time, and hadn't wanted to reveal it. He'd probably think the whole thing a laugh, once she explained that she hadn't been in any real danger.

"On the bright side, no more slimy goblins," Theo said cheerfully, piling another helping of eggs onto his plate.

"Think they'll give up the search, then?" Millicent asked, frowning, "Only whatever they were searching for must have been pretty dangerous, and probably valuable, too."

"Goblins never give up on treasure," Blaise said, "They can be pretty sly in their pursuit, however."

"How do you mean?" Pansy asked, eyes sharp.

"Look at the wizards inspecting the wards," Blaise said knowingly, "They aren't all the same as the ones here last night, are they?"

They all surreptitiously looked about, though Rigel wasn't sure how Blaise expected them to remember what all the ward experts had looked like. Then Rigel caught sight of flaming red hair standing by the Gryffindor table and abruptly ducked back down in disbelieving panic. What were the blasted odds of him being here?

Draco flinched next to her and dropped a demanding glare her direction, "What?"

Trying to stem the anxiety that was probably flooding his senses at the moment, Rigel shrugged, "Nothing."

Draco rolled his eyes, "I already saw your panicked face. What is it?"

In deference to Millicent, Blaise, and Theo, none of whom knew about Draco's empathy yet, Rigel refrained from arguing Draco's claim. Instead, she affected nonchalance and said, "Blaise is right, that's all. There's at least one inspector here who definitely wasn't last night."

"You know him," Pansy guessed suddenly, "That's why you were so surprised, right?"

Rigel really wished her friends were less perceptive sometimes. "Not very well," she said, "I met him this summer. He's Ron Weasley's older brother, William Weasley."

"A Weasley?" Draco wrinkled his nose slightly, "There's no way my father hired a Weasley to inspect the wards."

"He works for Gringotts," Rigel corrected.

"The goblins sent him to finish the search," Millicent hummed in an impressed way, "Very clever, since most people don't remember that the goblins employ wizards and witches in certain departments."

"Curse-breaking departments," Theo shuddered, "You think Hogwarts is cursed?"

"Just the Defense position," Draco said, smirking.

"Maybe the artifact they're looking for is cursed," Blaise suggested, eyes alight at the prospect of an interesting mystery.

"Why don't you ask Mr. Weasley?" Pansy said, smiling suddenly, "He appears to be headed this way."

Rigel contained her dread, she knew she did, and yet Draco still shot her a concerned look as the tall redheaded wizard loped toward the Slytherin table. She resisted the urge to slouch, knowing it was too late for that as the curse-breaker stopped in the isle beside them.

"Mr. Black?"

Looking up at the freckle-faced, blue-eyed wizard, listening to the familiar cadence of his voice, she recognized him immediately as 'Will' of the lower alleys. There was no way he didn't recognize her as Harry, but there was also no way she could acknowledge that connection despite what would look like overwhelming evidence. She would just have to bluff her way through it.

"Hello, Mr. Weasley," she said, smiling politely as she turned outward in her seat, "How have you been of late? Are your parents well?"

He seemed a bit taken aback to see her there, acting so normally, but shrugged casually nonetheless. "They're great. Mum mentioned you last time I was home."

"She's a lovely woman," Rigel said, "Will you give her my regards?"

"Of course," he said, somewhat slower than was perfectly polite. She could see the suspicion all over his face as he traced her features, but she knew that he couldn't say anything here, unless he wanted to advertise his own dalliances in the alley to all and sundry. "I'm here in official capacity on behalf on Gringotts, as you may have guessed."

Rigel inclined her head. "I'm very sorry for my part in that incident last night," she said, "Please extend my deepest apologies and understanding to your employers. It was not my intention to cause any difficulties in your search."

"Thank you," Weasley said, blinking in wary surprise, "Though that sentiment was essentially what I was meant to convey to you. The goblins want you to know that they would never harm a wizard unwarranted, and that Stonetoe simply got a bit carried away with excitement last night. Everyone at Gringotts is very eager to recover the object of our search."

"It must be an important magical object to warrant such intense scrutiny of even young students," Pansy spoke up, "Perhaps we could help you search. What does it look like?"

"That's classified," the redhead said, flashing his teeth in a winning grin, "Sorry."

"Of course," Pansy smiled back, just as winning, "How silly of me. We'll leave the search to your capable expertise, then, Mr. Weasley."

"I'm honored by your esteem," the curse-breaker leaned closer in a half-bow, "Though between you and me, we could use more pretty girls on the team."

Pansy giggled obligingly, and Weasley rose once more with a nod to Rigel. "Drop by the Burrow sometime, Black. Mother would love to see you again, and I'm sure you and I could find a lot of things to talk about."

Rigel tried very hard not to gulp, even though her polite agreement was entirely ruined by the fact that Draco could feel her uneasy trepidation and was giving her a very measuring look as she attempted to turn calmly back to her food.

"That's interesting," Blaise said, his eyes lowering to half-lid as the curse-breaker wandered off, "I wonder how classified it is, exactly. Is Gringotts keeping the information among its own personnel?"

"Can't be," Rigel said, eager for the distraction, "The Ministry has been conducting raids in search of just such an artifact. The Aurors must know what they're looking for."

"I haven't heard anything about raids," Draco said, frowning, "Father always keeps an ear out for that sort of thing."

"Not on prominent wizards," Rigel said, trying not to roll her eyes. Sometimes she wondered if her friends struggled to remember that there were people other than rich purebloods in their Wizarding community. "They've been raiding the lower alleys in London."

"The what?" Millicent raised an eyebrow, "You mean that collection of slums tucked into the Wizarding space around Diagon? It'd be a good place to hide something, I suppose."

"It isn't just slums," Rigel said, a bit defensively. She caught herself and moderated her tone a bit before adding, "There are some nice neighborhoods back there, reputable merchants, too."

"Apothecaries, you mean," Blaise smirked, "We might have known you'd trek through even a place like that for good ingredients, Rigel."

"Don't knock it until you've tried it, eh?" Theo laughed, "Get it? 'Knock' like Knockturn Alley?"

The others shook their heads or rolled their eyes in various shows of exasperation.

"Returning to the point—are you sure the Ministry is searching for the same artifact?" Pansy asked Rigel.

"What are the odds there are two mysterious missing artifacts?" Rigel said.

"The Ministry might be using the missing goblin treasure as an excuse to conduct more raids," Draco pointed out, "It's the sort of thing they'd—" he cut himself off with a cough, probably in response to the offense Rigel couldn't help but feel at his words.

Her father wouldn't sanction raids against innocent people for no real reason. She was sure he was using his personnel to sweep the alleys for clues to the whereabouts of the missing object. Leo had made the efforts sound crude and clumsy, true, but she supposed it was natural for Leo to be a bit biased about people coming into his 'jurisdiction' to exercise the law.

The conversation picked back up after an awkward pause, but Rigel didn't hear much of it. She spent the rest of breakfast lost in thought, and vowed to spend some time-turned hours over the next week looking into the practices of Aurors and their relationship with various sectors of the British magical community. She was tired of having questions about things she ought to be well versed in, having grown up in close proximity to them. It was past time she stopped taking certain things for granted.

November marched onward and snow began piling up on branches as the lake tried to freeze in fits and starts. Some mornings it was simply too cold to run outside, and Pansy, Draco, and Rigel had taken to huffing and puffing their way up the numerous staircases in the castle to keep things interesting.

It was on one of these idyllic mornings, high in the divination tower, that they stopped to catch their breath in a spacious reading alcove off the spiraling staircase.

"This… is so much worse… than jogging," Draco panted, hands on his knees, "My calves are going to mutiny and send me tumbling down this staircase to my doom."

"On the bright side, your arse will look amazing in your burial trousers," Pansy laughed breathlessly.

Rigel and Draco were momentarily too taken aback by the word 'arse' coming out of their blonde friend's mouth to share her amusement.

"What?" Pansy blinked at them. "Oh. Sorry."

"Don't apologize," Draco said suddenly, straightening. He opened his mouth again. Closed it. Cleared his throat uncertainly.

"Just say it," Pansy said, frowning.

"Sometimes it feels like you're not being honest with us," Draco blurted.

Pansy raised both eyebrows and looked from Draco to Rigel and back, as if to say, who's dishonest?

"Okay fair enough," Draco conceded, "And I did apologize about keeping the empathy thing from you but it was a difficult time for me—"

"It's all right, Drake," Pansy smirked, "I forgave you for that already, remember? After you groveled and promised to wear a bow-tie to the gala this year."

Draco winced, "Yes. I remember. I—well, never mind, I guess. Sorry I said anything."

He made as if to start climbing steps again, but Pansy abruptly said, "No. Wait."

Rigel felt as if she was watching something critical unfold but didn't know what.

Draco and Pansy stared at each other for a long moment before Pansy sighed. "Let's sit," she said, "I suppose it's time I fessed up to something."

Wondering if Pansy, too, had come into a mysterious gift on her thirteenth birthday, Rigel was taken aback when her petite friend said, "I'm not a very honest person, by nature."

"That's not true," Rigel said, patting her friend's hand gently, "You're the most open, generous person I know, Pan."

Rather than smiling and accepting the compliment as her due as Rigel had expected, Pansy grimaced a bit awkwardly. "That's the thing, I'm really…not. I just…" she seemed at a loss for what to say.

"I've noticed that often your emotions don't really match up with that you do or say," Draco said tentatively, "At first I thought I was reading you wrong, but lately I've been thinking maybe I don't know you as well as I thought. And that's not something you should feel bad about," he rushed on, "So please, please stop feeling bad about it, because it's making me feel queasy." Pansy laughed, though it was a bit hollow, and Draco continued in a softer voice, "I think it reflects badly on me, Pan, not you. I'm the one who should have been paying closer attention, I think."

"Don't say that," Pansy frowned, "It isn't like I've been dropping hints—quite the opposite. You're not responsible for this confusion. I am."

"I'm confused, too," Rigel put in, feeling that she may as well be honest if they were, "Mostly about what we're talking about right now."

Draco and Pansy both laughed at that, and Pansy even smiled wryly. "You know I really thought you'd be the first to notice, Rigel. I knew as soon as I met you that if anyone had enough experience with social deception to sniff out my subterfuge, it would be you."

"Me?" Rigel tilted her head, "I've never been any good at reading other people. That's your area of expertise."

"So it is," Pansy said, sobering a bit, "I'm very good at figuring out other people. I can find out their likes, dislikes, wants, needs, fears, anything, really, with just a few short conversations."

Rigel was suddenly looking at the long, get-to-know you conversations she'd shared with Pansy back in first-year very differently. "It's an impressive ability," she offered weakly.

"More impressive when you combine it with my talent for dissembling," Pansy said, "You're good at that part of it, Rigel. For a while I thought you were like me, except then I realized you didn't understand other people at all. You only knew how to present yourself in a certain light, not how to see the ways other people were presenting themselves. I think you've gotten better at it, over the last few years, but I was born good at it. I've told you guys I didn't have many friends before you two, haven't I? The truth is, I couldn't stand playing nice as a child. I could read all the petty undercurrents in every simpering, fake conversation and it drove me mad to have to sit still and listen to hours of meaningless drivel and smile prettily while people patronized me and—" she broke off with a sound of acute vexation. "Well, you get it."

"I sort of remember you as a child," Draco said, nodding slowly, "I can't remember specifics, but I do recall asking my mother once why I had to keep going on play dates with you when you didn't want to play. She told me you were refreshing company. I didn't really understand that at the time, I just knew your house was boring."

"I was a rotten child," Pansy freely admitted, "Spoiled and headstrong. And it took a long time for me to deign to participate in social moors. When I finally did, though, well, I was good at it. I am good at it, aren't I?"

"You are," Draco smiled, and it was as much admiring as reassuring, "I doubted my assessment for months, and I could actually feel your true emotions. That's some serious skill, Pans."

Pansy smiled demurely, and even knowing now that it was put on, Rigel couldn't see any artifice in it. "Does it bother you, though?" Pansy asked after a moment, "Because I'm not sure I could stop now, even if I wanted to. I've come to enjoy it. It's like a game, you see?"

"I would never deny you your entertainment," Draco said, smirking suddenly, "I just want to play on your side. If you'll have a poor player like me in your corner."

Pansy lit up with surprised pleasure, and Rigel wasn't even going to try and guess if it was real or not. If it was what Pansy wanted her to see, then that's what she would see. Rigel could hardly extend any less than the courtesy she wished from others for herself, could she? The only difference was that Pansy played at duplicity, while Rigel was actually duplicitous. If Rigel could not forgive Pansy her manipulations, then how could she ever forgive herself for what she was doing, when it was exponentially worse?

"Can I ask what your true character is?" Draco asked after a moment of thought, "Is that even a valid question?"

"That's hard to say," Pansy said, sighing a bit, "Everyone manipulates their own character to a certain degree. To decide how much of what you purposely put on comes from a place of genuine feeling—it's difficult, you know? Some of what you see is my own personality exaggerated. Some of it is reactions and responses I make up depending on my mood which may or may not be similar to the mood I'm trying to portray. Sometimes I feign an emotion so well I forget whether or not I felt it to begin with. I feel it by the end, so it's true in a way. In another way it's just a form of self-manipulation, to match the manipulation of others in a way that makes it hard to distinguish between authenticity and artifice. I try not to over-think it, to be honest."

"I think everyone self-manipulates," Rigel shrugged, "I mean, if someone wishes they were braver or kinder or more patient and they emulate those qualities for long enough, don't they become a real part of their personality? The only difference is that most people don't even realize it's a pretense—they imagine it more along the lines of personal development. Your personality is just a little more fluid, Pan. There are lots of people like you out there, I bet." A few ladies from the court of the rogue came immediately to mind, in fact.

"The three of us are quite the deceptive bunch," Draco said at last, "It's no wonder they call us the Sneaky Snakes."

"Wasn't it the Slimy Snakes?" Pansy asked, smiling slightly.

"The Surreptitious Snakes, for certain," Rigel laughed.

"The Sly Snakes."

"The Scheming Snakes."

"The Stealthy Snakes."

"The Secretive Snakes."

"The Shifty Snakes."

"The… Shady Snakes?" Rigel frowned, "I should have said Suspicious Snakes."

"Too late, your lame answer shall live forever in infamy," Draco sighed, "You know there are people in this school who think you're cool, Rigel?"

"None that know me, surely," Rigel smiled.

"Adrian thinks you're cool, actually," Pansy said, "And… I think that Chang girl has a bit of a tendresse for you."

"It's pronounced 'tendre,'" Rigel corrected automatically.

"You speak French now?" Pansy asked archly.

"He does, actually," Draco said, shaking his head, "Caught him practicing with a house elf not long ago."

"You have the most diverting hobbies, Rigel," Pansy said. Then she grinned, suddenly, "Actually that's excellent! You can help me prepare phrases for my miai."

"You're what?" Rigel asked at the same time that Draco bit off a surprised exclamation.

"Already?" Draco was scowling in open dislike.

"I'm fourteen," Pansy shrugged, "It's within propriety."

"It's customary to wait until after OWL's," Draco scoffed, "You could be a complete idiot for all they know."

"Come again?" Pansy said, a dangerous glint in her eyes.

"Obviously you aren't," Draco backtracked easily, "But they're taking quite a risk. Who is it, anyway?"

"One of the Duval boys, I gather," Pansy said, seeming largely disinterested.

"Practically paupers," Draco said disapprovingly, "What is your father thinking?"

"Of course I'm not going to marry a Duval," Pansy rolled her eyes, "You're missing the point. If I start meeting men on the continent now, word of my beauty and charm will be already disseminated by the time I start seriously looking for prospects. The Duvals may be in hard straights now, but they still know everyone who's anyone in Paris."

"That's a lot of forethought to put into engagement prospects," Rigel commented.

"Not an unusual amount," Pansy said, smiling slightly, "Don't tell me your family hasn't even begun discussions on the subject."

Rigel realized abruptly that she was about to come off rather hypocritical. "I'm already engaged, actually. To Harry."

"What!?" Draco and Pansy could not have looked more shocked.

"Yeah, we…signed the paperwork last summer," Rigel said, affecting a sheepish expression, "I thought I mentioned it."

"You certainly did not mention anything of the sort," Pansy choked out, "Why—how could you make such a decision out of the blue like that. Early engagements are generally planned from birth, but you made it quite clear you'd never entertained even the idea of being engaged to Miss Potter when you last spoke of such things. What changed, Rigel?"

"And why didn't you tell us?" Draco added, still looking appalled.

She wasn't even going to guess how Pansy knew about the conversation she'd had with Rosier and Rookwood almost two years ago. "We changed our minds, that's all. It's going to be a very long engagement, in any case, so it isn't as though anything's set in stone. I didn't realize it would interest you so much."

"Not interest—it's only the rest of your life, Rigel!" Draco threw up his hands, utterly irate, "We haven't even met her yet. What if she hates us?"

Rigel felt an acute stab of guilt that wasn't softened at all by the pang of remorse that accompanied it. That Draco would consider Rigel's potential future partner to be something that would intimately affect his life…she hadn't really properly faced the fact that Pansy and Draco fully expected them to be friends forever, but now that reality was staring her down accusingly. "I—I know she'll love you both," Rigel said, swallowing tightly, "How could she not?"

If Draco had feathers, Rigel would have been able to watch them settle in proud appeasement. "Still," he said, "She probably isn't good enough for you."

Rigel laughed and tried to convince herself that it was not at all hysterical. "She'd likely agree with you on that."

"I'm sure she's wonderful," Pansy said, though her voice was a bit strained, "Rigel is an excellent judge of character, after all."

"Oh he isn't, either," Draco grumbled, "He's probably marrying her so he doesn't have to put any effort into thinking about it."

"Guilty," Rigel said, amused once more.

"Don't admit to it," Pansy admonished her exasperatedly, "You'll ruin Miss Potter's consequence before she's even been out."

"Out of what?" Rigel asked, grinning.

"Out in society," Pansy rolled her eyes.

"I'm not sure she's coming out in society," Rigel told her, "At least not anytime soon."

Pansy blinked, looking crestfallen for a moment. "Isn't she…coming to the gala this year?"

"Why would she—" Rigel cut herself off abruptly. Hadn't Mr. Malfoy mentioned the Parkinsons were hosting the gala that year? "Did you…send her an invitation, Pan?"

Pansy lifted her chin stubbornly, "Yes, I did. She would have been invited anyway, with her father the head Auror at the DMLE. I just included an invitation for her…separately, as well. In case her family doesn't want to come."

"Harry isn't really a party person," Rigel said, trying not to get her friend's hopes up. How could she possibly go as Harry? Unless Archie wanted to go as her, of course. She stifled a smile at the image of Archie in a dress. She rather thought he could pull it off, for some reason.

"You must simply convince her to come," Pansy said firmly, "If you're going to marry this girl some day, Draco and I deserve to meet her at least, don't we?"

"I'll see what I can do," Rigel said, intending to do no such thing.

"Tell her we don't bite," Draco suggested, smirking.

"I try not to lie to my cousin," Rigel said. Everyone else, on the other hand…well, a girl had to do what she had to do.

"Now that that's settled, we really ought to get moving again if we want to make breakfast," Pansy said, jogging in place for a moment, "And on the way down, you can help me with my phrases for when I meet Duval, Rigel."

"I live to serve," Rigel said, affecting a snooty French accent as she began the trek down the long spiral staircase.

"Ooh, that's a good one," Pansy grinned, "How do you say that in French?"

As winter break approached, their classes became steadily more challenging, in preparation for midterm examinations. Even Rigel's unofficial electives began issuing more complex and time-consuming assignments as her mastery over the basics became apparent.

Dumbledore's Alchemy class was as laid-back as ever, even as the material they covered gained momentum, and her Magical Theory class, while fascinating, didn't give her much to stress over, either. Her Healing classes, on the other hand, had recently taken a rather sobering turn.

"It's best if you don't overthink it," Pomfrey said gently.

Rigel wasn't sure what there was to overthink about killing an innocent animal. It seemed pretty clear to her that she had erred grievously and the cat laying on the tiny operating table had paid the price.

They had moved on from studying things like lacerations and broken bones and into the territory of life-threatening injuries and conditions. She had practiced on animals before, of course, both in Madam Pomfrey's lessons and on her own, in the woods. This wasn't the first time an animal she'd been trying to save had died, either—sometimes she got to them in the forest too late. This was the first time an animal had died of wounds she was responsible for giving it, however, and the difference seemed appreciable.

"I thought I could do it," she said, a bit numbly. She had studied the process thoroughly before attempting a limb-restoration, and she had successfully re-attached several fingers and toes on other animals in the weeks leading up to this. Somehow, though, she hadn't been able to move quickly enough this time, hadn't properly appreciated how time-consuming the reconnection of severed nerves and muscle fibers would be, or how quickly the blood would seep out of the cat's tiny body.

"I know you did," Pomfrey sighed, "I did, too. The first is always the hardest, Mr. Black.

"I don't want there to be any more," she said, "I didn't—why didn't you save it, when it became clear I was failing?"

"It's a lesson you need to learn," Madam Pomfrey said regretfully, "It's the worst part of Healer training, and some don't have the stomach for it. This won't be the last mammal you lose on the table, and it certainly won't be the last time you feel wracking guilt for failing a patient. You can't always save them, though. I know it sounds awful, but it's the hard truth. If you are serious about this career, it's better to learn now how to distance yourself from the lives you touch. You're always going to do more good than bad as a Healer, in the grand balance of things, but you won't be perfect for every single patient you treat."

"It's different," Rigel argued, gazing down at the mutilated feline, "If I fail to save someone who comes to me for Healing, it's different from being the one to hurt them in the first place. If I'd known the cat would die, I wouldn't have wanted to practice on it, Madam Pomfrey."

The older witch sighed again, "I know how you feel. If there was another way to reliably teach our craft I would use it, Mr. Black. In some schools they let students practice on real people, taking the young adepts to clinics and research hospitals to heal the cases that chance sends their way that day. They get plenty of practice with everyday hurts. They don't take those students to the emergency rooms, though. In a life-or-death situation there's no time to practice—you either know how to save the patient or you don't. If you've never practiced the procedure before, chances are you won't. If you wait for a guiltless opportunity like the one you describe to arise, you might be practicing your first serious Healing on your best friend."

"So I should just ignore it, then?" she asked, sick to her stomach, "Just focus on the people I might save one day and forget about the creatures I'm hurting now?"

"No," the mediwitch shook her head firmly, "Do not forget. Heal, child, as much as you're able. Heal all you can, to make up for the ones you cant, and the ones you hurt. Make this training mean something, and if it makes you feel better, send a prayer for their souls to the Great Mother Goddess."

Rigel didn't observe the old religions, but she did take a moment to make a promise to herself. She would keep careful track of the animals that died by her hand, and she would repay that debt tenfold with her Healing gifts, even if she never became a real Healer like Archie would. Even if their whole ruse ended tomorrow and she never needed to pretend to have Healing abilities again, she would still use the gift as often as she could. It was the only thing she could do, in light of the cost its learning demanded.

"Are you ready to go again?" Madam Pomfrey asked after a long moment.

"Perhaps I should study more first," Rigel said, reluctant to see a repeat of the last half-hour.

"You already know what you did wrong," Pomfrey said sternly, "Shying away from the dirty work is a disservice to your teachings."

And my victims, Rigel added with a sickened lurch. Nevertheless, she gently prepared the dead cat for disposal and turned her attention to the next specimen.

The tabby had long fur, probably just recently grown out in deference to the winter cold. It slept peacefully under the machinations of a Deep Sleep Charm, and although Rigel knew the cat had been given copious amounts of numbing solutions, she still felt like the worst of beasts as she intoned the Severing Charm and watched its leg detach itself at the upper-thigh.

Moving faster than she had last time, Rigel raced against the cat's own circulatory system to stymie the bleeding while at the same time reattaching the fragile tissues before necrosis could take hold. Some cell death at the site of separation was unavoidable, but if she worked fast enough the cat wouldn't even know the difference when it awoke. If it awoke.

She was doing better this time, she realized as the bone fused seamlessly and the ligaments were sewn back together under her watchful gaze. Her wand moved back and forth in a flurry, and this time she attached the blood vessels before bothering with the muscles or nerves. Once blood could circulate normally throughout the leg without spilling out onto the table, she rapidly built up enough muscle tissue to keep the leg stable at the joining, then set her attention to the nerve damage. This was by far the most difficult part, concentration wise, as nerves were exceedingly complicated to deal with even using magic. Her mistake last time had been in attempting to simultaneously deal with the nerves and other damage. Now, with the life-threatening issues dealt with, she was free to devote her entire focus to delicately repairing the synapses and receptors.

Almost before she knew it, she was lacing the epidermal together and finishing up with an expertly finessed hair-growth charm. She admired her handiwork for just a moment, flush with success and the knowledge of how far she'd come in the last months.

Madam Pomfrey took out her wand with a satisfied nod. The nurse enervated the sleeping feline, who stumbled to its feet with a twitchy shake of its head. It looked disoriented for a moment, then leapt from the table to the floor with only a slight spasm in the leg muscle to show where the neurons were reasserting themselves.

Pomfrey herded the cat into a traveling case with a bit of food and water, and Rigel cleaned up the operating area, wiping down all the surfaces and disposing of everything into a bright red litterbin that Pomfrey assured her the elves were very careful about handling.

Before she left for lunch, though she wasn't sure she'd be able to eat a thing, she said, "Madam Pomfrey?"

"Yes, Mr. Black?" the mediwitch said absently, scribbling away in a notebook that Rigel presumed kept tack of her academic progress.

"Do you think it would be possible from now on to practice on different animals?" she asked.

"Cats are very good examples of mammalian systems," Pomfrey said.

"Yes, but do you think we could use, well, useful animals from now on?" Rigel pressed, "The cat that I killed…it's just a waste, you see? If I could use some of its parts in a potion, I think I'd feel better about it. Animals have to be killed for certain potions ingredients anyway. Perhaps we could contact an ingredient collection company and ask for specimens that are slotted to be euthanized already. They could have the ingredients when we're finished. I'll harvest them myself."

"I suppose that would be good practice for your anatomy lessons, too," Pomfrey said slowly, "Yes. I'll get in touch with some people right away."

"Thank you, Madam," Rigel said, feeling a little better about the grisly business already.

"Thank you, Mr. Black," Pomfrey smiled softly, "You're a good student. You did very well today, and it's always a good sign when a Healer cares about the animals he practices on. I think you will make a fine, compassionate addition to our field one day."

"You're too kind, Madam," Rigel fingered her bangs self-consciously.

"One can never be too kind, Mr. Black."

Rigel supposed, as words to live by went, that those were as good as any.

Amidst all the diligent studying and cramming for the end of semester, Rigel did have one admittedly frivolous project to keep her creativity occupied when the rest of her brain was strained from what sometimes felt like constant abuse.

She hadn't forgotten what she owed the Weasley Twins after the paper flower prank, and her vengeance would be as poetic as it was sweet.

A pouch full of pink powder sat on her workstation beside a large bag of Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans and a small cauldron of simmering slime. The 'potion' was completely colorless and stuck to the sides of the cauldron belligerently despite Rigel's frequent stirring. Its recipe was of her own design, though it was really a bastardized version of a toxin-expulsion draught.

Once ingested, the actual toxin-expulsion draught would bind to any ingested poison and expel it as expediently as possible. It was a rather gruesome solution for internal poisoning, as the potion tended to expulse itself through any and all convenient orifices, including nose, mouth, eyes, and pores. Most people preferred to take a bezoar. The Weasley Twins, unfortunately for them, would not be given the choice.

Rigel had removed the binding agent from the potion's design, as she wasn't planning on actually poisoning her redheaded friends. This time. She'd also swapped out most of the ingredients for similar ones that lacked significant pigment and had less offenses tastes. She'd then used a bleaching agent to sap the color from the potion entirely, and the result was an expulsion solution that would be neigh-undetectable prior to ingestion.

The potion would be painstakingly painted over the beans (a Weasley favorite, she had observed) and set on a drying rack until the coating was smooth and transparent. It would probably take hours, but Rigel had all the time in the world. She tried not to laugh maniacally as that thought crossed her mind. She wasn't entirely beholden to her father's genetics, after all. Lily always had a sense of dignified grace when she was enacting vengeance upon an unsuspecting fool, and there was no reason Rigel couldn't emulate that half of her upbringing, too.

The pouch of powder was originally just the Marauders' standard colored sneezing powder. She had bought it with the idea to send it to Archie as a thank-you for working so hard, but she would have to postpone that care package until the next Hogsmeade trip. Her cousin would agree that teaching a lesson was more important.

The powder was designed with the intention of making the victim sneeze uncontrollably until they washed the powder off—except the powder turned to goo upon contact with liquid, making it impossible to wash off. The Weasley Twins would, of course, know to vanish the powder instead of washing it, but that was why Rigel had modified it, as well. She had painstakingly sifted out the sneeze-inducing component to the powder, leaving behind a tinted dust that would turn invisible upon contact with skin, making it rather easy to ignore once past the initial encounter. To that, she'd added a large supply of craft glitter, obtained with the help of her generous friend Binny, who she gathered had simply raided the school's Yule decorating supplies.

The glitter was a red herring. It would pull the attention from the innocuous-seeming dust it was mixed with, and with a little luck Rigel would have an epic, impossible-to-see-coming yet painfully-obvious-in-retrospect revenge prank.

It was a shame the Weasley Twins forgot who they were pranking when they set Rigel Black in their sights. Once a Marauder, always a Marauder; they would not be making that mistake again.

She decided to strike on a Friday morning, partly in deference to the narrative portion of her prank, and partly because people were more alert and upbeat as the weekend approached. She didn't want anyone to miss the show.

The owls swooped down from the rafters in what Rigel had to say was her most anticipated mail time ever. A nondescript barn owl floated down like an avenging angel to alight righteously before the eyes of two sinners—okay, Rigel shook her head, that was probably enough poetry for one prank.

From her carefully selected seat she had a perfect view of the Weasley Twins' slightly bemused expressions. She had addressed one letter to each of them, and personalized the font enough to make the envelopes look inviting and official rather than suspicious. The twins shrugged and tore into the letters simultaneously. The explosion of glitter that followed could only have been explained by the rather strong localized pressure charm she had painstakingly cast on the envelopes' contents the night before.

Twin disco balls blinked amidst the glittering fallout in the moment of stunned silence before the hall burst into appreciative laughter.

Rigel allowed herself a modest chuckle. Draco's elbow tapped hers discretely, however, and she realized he could probably feel the utter glee she was suppressing. She spared him a winsome grin, then focused her attention back on the Gryffindor table. The Weasley Twins were laughing along good-naturedly, digging around in the piles of sparkling dust to find the cards she'd also included in the letter bombs.

Knowing what they said (sorry, not sorry in advance), she was ready with a toast from her water goblet as they swung their heads in her direction with identical smirks. They dusted themselves off dramatically, Fred even going so far as to shake his head over Angelina Johnson's eggs, and sauntered over to the Slytherin table to friendly catcalls and whistles.

"Oh, Fred, what are we going to do with our disobedient pup?" George asked mournfully, scratching his glitter-infested hair with the air of a put upon parent.

"Discipline, George, that's what today's youth is lacking," Fred sighed, wistfully clasping his hands together in despair.

"Out with the old, in with the new," Rigel said airily.

Fred snickered, "I'm not sure I'd go that far, little pup."

"It was only a glitter bomb," George added, looking both amused and apologetic as he informed Rigel she wasn't the second coming of pranking legend.

"But it was good, right?" She widened her eyes a tad, making sure to smile just like a child showing his parents his first magic trick. "It took forever to get all the glitter in the envelopes."

"It was great, Rigel," George said, definitely hiding amusement now, "I take it we're even for the flower prank now?"

"Of course!" Rigel leaned forward earnestly, "I was a little worried I took things too far, actually. I didn't want to tip the scales back the other way. I just couldn't resist doing two envelopes of glitter." She added a guilty little smile for maximum effect, ignoring the muffled choking going on beside her. Draco should really work on his subtlety.

"We won't take it too personally," Fred promised her, leaning in to ruffle her hair. She quickly ducked back with an indignant look, narrowly avoiding the powder clinging amongst the glitter getting in her hair.

"It washes off really easy under water," she informed them, affecting a serious expression, "So you can get rid of it all tonight."

"Ah, no offense, pup, but we'll probably just evanesco it if it's all the same to you," George said apologetically.

She gazed in mild horror at them, "Oh, no! Whatever you do, don't try and vanish it. I nicked it from my dad's experimental supply, and his notes were pretty clear about the kind of reaction that might produce." At Fred and George's uneasy expressions, she scratched the back of her neck nervously, "It's okay though, right? One day isn't too bad. I mean it's not like you have Snape today or anything."

They did have Snape, in fact, first thing that morning, in a double block that would last until noon. She knew that when she planned the prank, of course, but it was a simple matter to fake distraught realization as she gazed back and forth between their awkward expressions.

"Oh, no," she said again, "I didn't—you're going to lose points, and it's all my fault!"

"It's okay, pup," Fred said, putting on a smile, "We lose points all the time. Don't feel bad. It was a good prank."

"No, I feel awful," Rigel moaned, her shoulders slumping forward, "I'm so sorry, you guys."

"Rigel, it's fine," George said firmly, "You can't always predict how a prank will turn out. It's our fault for getting caught in it, right?"

Rigel sniffed, blinking rapidly to give the impression that she was fighting tears. "I don't know. It seems so wrong." Before they could contradict her again, she lifted her head brightly, saying, "Wait, I know!" She made a show of digging around in her bag until she pulled out the bag of Bertie Bott's Beans. "Here, take these. I know it doesn't make up for the points, but they're your favorite, too, right? I only have one bag…but you could share?"

"Oh, you really don't have to," George said, though he was certainly eyeing the bag with interest.

"I want to," Rigel insisted, pressing the bag into Fred's hands, "Take it as my apology for going too far. I clearly shouldn't be trusted with this much responsibility."

She thought she was laying it on a bit thick by that point, but Fred and George took the bag with big, grateful smiles. She held onto her innocently apologetic expression as long as she possibly could, but once the twins had each taken a handful of the beans and tipped them into their mouths she really couldn't hold back a pleased smirk any longer.

"Done being an idiot, now?" Draco asked mildly.

"Just about," Rigel said calmly, watching the twins glance at each other, then her with growing suspicion.

"Puppy," Fred said slowly, "You haven't gone and done something unnecessary, have you?"

"What's necessity got to do with cold-served revenge, Draco?"

"Nothing that I can think of, Rigel," Draco said obligingly.

"What's in the beans, Rigel?" George asked, groaning a bit at what Rigel assumed was his own stupidity.

"I'm sure I don't know," Rigel inspected her nails with forced cruelty, "I heard they're trying a new poison flavor for the holidays, though. Gee, what are the odds one would make its way into this bag?"

Fred appeared to be contemplating the merits of self-induced regurgitation, but George put a hand on his brother's arm reassuringly. "Rigel wouldn't actually poison us," he said confidently, "Monstrously deceive us, and lead us on for a humiliating ten minutes, maybe, but not poison us."

"You sound pretty sure," Rigel noted, trying to look as unmerciful and cold as her young, smooth cheeks would allow.

"I don't think you want to be rid of us just yet," George smirked. The effect was somewhat dashing, at least until a narrow stream of clear liquid began to dribble out of his nose. It rolled down to his lip, collecting the heretofore ignored modified sneezing powder and ballooning out into a glob of pink goo. "What?" he touched his hand to his face and pulled it away incredulously. "Oh, no."

Fred, meanwhile, was attempting to stem the flow of pink slime that was running down his cheeks as his eyes leaked expulsion draught in a process that, while painless, looked absolutely disgusting. "What have you done, Rigel?" he asked, voice rising a bit in carefully controlled panic.

"I just thought people should know who the real piles of goo behind the paper flower prank are," Rigel said, though she kept her voice low enough that only Fred and George and a couple of her friends could really hear her. The point was to get the elegance of the prank across to the twins, not undermine their work with the original prank, after all.

By now the toxin-expulsion draught they'd ingested had started to ooze out their pores, and everywhere the powder on their skin and clothes came into contact with the oozing liquid it blossomed into rivulets of fluorescent, sticky goop, until soon it looked like Fred and George were giant pink popsicles that had been left out in the sun too long.

The hall was roaring with laughter as people stood on their seats to get a better look at the walking piles of sparkly slime that were the Weasley Twins.

Rigel had to school her expression into one of sober concern as Professor Snape made his way past their spectacle on his way out of the hall.

"You appear to have liquefied these two Gryffindors, Mr. Black," the professor said with supreme unconcern. She could read the appreciation in his eye, however, and flattered herself that he seemed ever so slightly curious as to how she'd done it.

"They're just a little melted, Professor," she said, smiling modestly.

"In your opinion, will they re-solidify before their morning block?" Snape asked, professional courtesy oozing in his voice.

"They might be a bit soft in the head still," she said, faking concern.

"Back to normal, then," Snape's smirk was positively cutting as he strode away, "Good."

The Slytherins sitting near enough to hear that exchange gave a healthy laugh in his wake.

"I suppose now you're going to tell us not to evanesco this, either?" Fred said, his voice muffled by the layer of slime that coated his face.

"No, go ahead," she said, smiling too-innocently.

He hesitated visibly, goo-covered hand poised on his wand but clearly expecting another trick.

George groaned in sudden realization, "We could have evanescoed the glitter in the first place, couldn't we?"

"That probably would have be the wisest course, yes," Rigel allowed.

"You realize we can never trust you again," Fred said morosely, clenching his eyes shut and muttering the vanishing spell with extreme trepidation.

"You say that, but…" Rigel trailed off with a winsome smile as Draco and Pansy chuckled appreciatively.

Once satisfied that Fred's goo had vanished without obvious side effects, George followed suit. Rigel thought the incident might teach them not to always do things at the same time. If there'd been any delay between the two in opening their letters or eating the spiked beans, she might have only caught one of them.

"Well, I can honestly say I've never seen a prank like that before," George said, after inspecting himself for any lingering goo, of course.

"What he said." Fred leaned toward Rigel conspiratorially. "Only how did you get the goo to come out of our, ahem…" he waggled his eyebrows in a way that Rigel really couldn't help but flush at. She had been trying not to think about that aspect of the expulsion draught.

"A true master never divulges his secrets," she managed to choke out as her ears turned red.

"Probably for the best." George grimaced good-naturedly. "Some things should be left to the imagination."

Secretly relieved that Fred and George weren't actually all that upset about her getting one over on them, Rigel readily agreed that the finer aspects of her prank should not be available to the masses.

"I think we've entertained those masses enough for one day, in any event." Fred glanced about at the raptly interested students around the hall and waved to signal that the show was over. People went back to their breakfasts readily enough, though she could hear speculation about what exactly had happened threading through most of the conversations around them.

"Though Rigel did most of the entertainment." George shook his head admiringly. "Clearly we need to talk about your pathological acting skills, little pup."

"I employ them mainly in self-defense," Rigel said.

Draco snorted in an entirely obvious way. "I'm sorry. What?"

Rigel shot him a betrayed look, "I do. It's not my fault I'm surrounded by aggressively nosy people who also happen to be incredibly gullible."

"You're aware that you shouldn't have said that out loud, right?" Pansy sighed.

"You're aware that that's only what I want you to think, right?" Rigel said.

"I'm not sure that makes any sense," George felt compelled to point out.

"I'm not sure that anything makes sense, anymore," Fred added, looking a bit glum.

"As long as no one is certain of anything we can all go about our lives in peace," Rigel said, shrugging.

Everyone was certain they had nothing to say to that.

The end of first semester wound down rather anticlimactically, in Rigel's opinion. Slytherin scraped a win in their Quidditch match with Gryffindor, lending good spirits to the last couple weeks of classes despite the numerous tests and assignments coming due. Rigel was just polishing off the very last of Flint's essays when Draco poked his head into their dorm room and said, "Nearly ready?"

She tucked the parchment rolls away in her bag and slipped off the bed with a grin, "Lost track of time. I'll change now."

It was the last Sunday before break, and the sixth meeting of their unofficial defense association. After the initial couple weeks of awkwardness, Draco had taken to teaching like a fish dropped in an unfamiliar, but not altogether unpleasant new pond. Draco claimed he just enjoyed bossing other people around, but Rigel suspected he found real satisfaction in the way the others looked to him for information and direction.

They collected Pansy, Rosier, and Rookwood in the common room, waving cheerfully to Pucey, who had taken to ribbing them about their little rendezvous with the Gryffindors every chance he got.

"Another play date?" the fifth-year called across the room.

"You're welcome to come if you're feeling left out," Rosier smirked, "We've more than enough toys for everyone."

"Ask me again in the spring, when my arse doesn't hurt so much from Flint's training!" Pucey laughed. Bole and Derrick, who sat close together on an adjacent couch, joined in a moment later.

"It's going to hurt worse in the spring, I promise," Flint spoke up ominously from a chair nearby.

Amidst playful groans and complaints, their group exited the common room with anticipatory energy in their steps. After a few weeks to settle into the rhythm of things, they'd all grown to greatly enjoy the weekend dueling practice. It was engaging and challenging to face off against different people, and as it wasn't for class credit or marks, it was fun and largely free of pressure, too.

That wasn't to say it was lacking intensity, of course.

"Bout time you lot showed up," Ron yawned, stretching his not-quite-noticeable-yet biceps as they approached their usual spot on the lawn. Neville, who seemed to be practicing a complicated wrist exercise, glanced up with a smile as they drew near.

"We wanted to give you as much extra preparation time as possible," Pansy said, smiling sharply, "You're going to need it this week."

"That's what you said last week." Ron allowed a confident eyebrow to quirk upwards.

"It was true then, too." Pansy lowered her lashes coyly. "Or have you forgot who won?"

"I hope you're up for a rematch, then?" Ron smirked.

"If you think you'd like to lose again," Pansy said, beginning to idly hop from foot to foot in an effort to warm her muscles in the cold December air.

Those two, Rigel reflected, had certainly managed to bring out the competitive spirit in one another. While most of them changed dueling partners regularly, Pansy and Ron had fallen into a weekly rivalry. She supposed they were a good match on the dueling pitch—Ron had a strategist's mind, from what she'd gleaned over the weeks, and Pansy was by far the most devious of their dueling circle. They matched wits as much as wands when they squared off, and Rigel was glad someone seemed willing to take Pansy seriously besides Draco and her. Rosier had refused on principle to duel the blonde girl, and Rookwood had seemed out of his element the one time he'd tried. Neville…well, he seemed scared to death of Pansy for some reason, which Rigel supposed meant he was the only one with any good sense in the group.

"Enough posturing," Draco rolled his eyes, "We've got a lot to do before you two get another go at each other."

"Yes, Grand Dueler Draco," Pansy dipped an elegant curtsey despite wearing loose-fitting running pants.

"Of course, Magnanimous Master Malfoy," Ron parroted, doing his own wobbly approximation of a bow.

It was a testament to six weeks of practice that Draco restrained himself to a mild scowl in the face of Ron's obvious facetiousness.

They started with an easy jog that didn't take them too far along the banks of the lake. The four newcomers still weren't in the same league of conditioning that Pansy, Draco, and Rigel were, probably because they only really exercised once a week, so Draco tended to focus their efforts on exercises and moves that would help their dueling specifically, instead of the full-body fitness that the third-year Slytherins worked toward in their early morning practices.

Footwork drills and combination exercises took up the next twenty minutes or so, and once Draco was satisfied everyone had warmed up diligently, they broke into pairs. Rigel had dueled Neville last week, and Rosier the week before, so she squared off with Rookwood this time, a slow-simmering excitement laying low in her gut.

Rookwood was by far her most challenging opponent. Neville wasn't at all aggressive, Rosier was cunning but lacked ruthlessness, and Draco preferred coaching to dueling most weeks. Rookwood, though, was level headed, efficient, and difficult to read because his movements were so minimalist. His impressive repertoire of spells didn't hurt, either. Anyone who didn't know better would think it an unfair match up, a small third-year against a mountain-like sixth-year. Rigel didn't flatter herself when she acknowledged her own skill, however. The three and a half months since the beginning of the school year had been more like eight for her; she had as many hours to go over foot-drills and practice the maneuvers Leo had shown her as she could motivate herself to take.

It wasn't cheating, she told herself, since they weren't in any sort of competition, but it did give her a little guilty start every time one of her friends mentioned how scarily fast she was improving. Her quick progress, coupled with the fact that she didn't have to worry about her magic acting without her permission now that it was suppressed all the time, meant Rigel had grown into her instincts at last. She wouldn't call herself dangerous, or anything, but her skillset was certainly impressive for a thirteen-year-old.

They spread out a good distance from one another, with Pansy and Ron the farthest from Rigel and Rookwood. Neville and Rosier were the least likely to go overboard in their practice, so they were in between the more serious pairs.

"The usual rules apply," Draco announced, "Only this time let's try not to noticeably disfigure anyone—I'm looking at you, Pansy. If Weasley gets sent to the Hospital Wing one more time he's going to set a record."

"I thought the boils gave him character," Pansy twirled her wand carelessly.

"Detention builds character, too, and that's what we're all going to get if you keep getting carried away," Draco said. Rigel thought the amusement in his tone rather undermined the bark to his words. "All right. Ready? Set? Begin."

Rigel darted sideways to avoid an oncoming orange-colored hex she didn't recognize and threw up a shield a heartbeat later to intercept a fast-moving incarcerous that Rookwood had neatly placed in her path. That's what I get for being predictable, Rigel thought as she muttered the words for the tripping jinx under her breathe while sliding to avoid the concussion of a shield-smasher colliding with her protego a moment later.

Rookwood's dueling style was hard and fast. His impressive stamina meant there was very little pause between spells, which left his opponent feeling overwhelmed with the need to defend against the constant pressure. Rigel's best skill by far was dodging, however, and her on-the-go offense neatly avoided the issue of getting bogged down on defense altogether. With a sprinkling of shield charms thrown in as a nod to the 'pick-your-battles' philosophy, Rigel had a flexible style all her own that tended to dominate the dueling space just through its sheer mobility. Rookwood didn't seem to mind, of course, since Rigel almost never saw him move during a duel. She sometimes wondered if he did the footwork drills at the beginning of their sessions just to humor Draco.

She mentally thanked Remus for all his work with her that summer as she ducked and dove around spells with comfortable agility. Rookwood's expression never faltered, for all that not a single one of his spells came close to hitting. If it was to be a game of attrition, Rigel rather thought her physical stamina could outlast Rookwood's core reserves.

To make sure of this, she randomly began increasing the power behind some of her spells, forcing the upperclassman to hurriedly reinforce his shields every time one threatened to break through. She jumped high over a tarantallegra placed at her kneecaps, then mentally cursed when she saw Rookwood use her slow jump to break his usual fast-paced rhythm and begin a complicated series of wand-movements that she just knew spelled trouble.

As soon as her feet touched down, she leapt backwards to put space between her and whatever was coming next. Not a moment too soon, as the earth between them swiftly transitioned from dry, brittle grass to smooth, slick ice. Wondering how on earth Rookwood had managed to transfigure so much ground so quickly, Rigel cast an underpowered sticking charm to her feet and began factoring in twice as much necessary time in avoiding spells.

It was a stopgap measure at best, as proven when one of her feet stuck just a second too long and she was forced she shield a spell she ought to have been able to hop right over. Curse Rookwood for thinking to aim for her feet, now the slowest-moving part of her. She tried to distract him with a couple of closely timed stupefys, but Rookwood swatted them away like flies and sent back a vertigo jinx that she just managed to recognize in time to prepare the counter-charm as it approached.

The vertigo-jinx was one of the annoying ones you couldn't shield against. All one could do was prepare defense ahead of time and cancel it quickly. Although she lost perception for a moment, she had already sent her muscles diving to the side as the jinx connected, and so when she reoriented herself it was some feet to the right of where Rookwood's follow-up incarcerous had attempted to snare her.

One trail of rope has wrapped itself around her left ankle, however, and even as she cast a finite at the conjured binding she knew she should have gone with relashio. Finite was an area-effect cancelling spell and so the sticking charm on her left foot was now gone as well. Rookwood had already sent another spell in her direction, and she didn't recognize it. Shielding would be ill advised, but dodging now would be likely result in a windmill maneuver that left her exposed as her left foot undermined her right.

The spell was too low to duck, but not too high to leap over in a last-ditch effort at surprise. She cast a severely over-powered lumos charm as she squeezed her eyes shut and pushed hard off her right foot, tucking herself into a dive-roll that, if she timed it right, would take her right over the incoming spell and much closer to Rookwood himself.

She came out of the roll a mere three feet from her opponent, and a mirror shield at precisely the right angle prevented Rookwood from firing any spells he wouldn't want to dodge at close range. The momentum from her roll was still carrying her forward, her left foot and right knee sliding across the ice easily as she kept in a crouch to minimize the target she presented.

Rookwood was blinking rapidly at what Rigel assumed was a great big black spot across his vision, but he wasn't done yet. He canceled her mirror shield with a projected mirror shield of his own that destabilized hers into collapsing, and his wand began to move in swift patterns as his brow knit with the concentration his next spell demanded. Before he could complete it, though, Rigel was already within his guard, propelling her momentum abruptly upwards with the sticking charm on her right foot and chopping her left hand down on his right forearm in a move that targeted the muscles he used to keep a good grip on his wand. Her knees dug into Rookwood's chest at the same time, and while any other boy his age would likely be completely winded, Rookwood merely stumbled backwards at her added weight.

It was enough. Rigel tumbled to the ground on top of the larger boy, wand at his throat even as his own wand fell to the dirt from a forcibly lax grip.

"Concede?" Rigel smiled from her seat upon his chest, panting through her triumph even as she inspected her opponent for any real damage.

"I'm not sure that counts," Rookwood grumbled, looking a little put out as he gazed up at the sky.

She gently pressed her wand into the thick muscle of his neck. "Would you like me to stupefy you?"

"No," he decided, sighing deeply in a way that dislodged Rigel from her perch and sent her laughing to the ground.

They both sat up and shared an easy grin. Rookwood was never a poor sport, though Rigel thought she was the only one he'd actually lost to so far.

"Rigel won again?" Draco shook his head as he made his way over, "How many weeks it that running, now?"

"Rigel always wins," Rookwood said genially, "Except once when he dueled you."

"Draco can read my moves too easily," Rigel complained. She didn't understand how a little empathy could give him such an advantage in their duels. It wasn't like her emotions could tell him what sort of spells she was going to use. Perhaps it was simply that she couldn't take him by surprise when he could tell if she was about to do something devious. She did tend to win a lot of her duels on the grounds of creative surprises, come to think of it.

"I've been dueling you longer," Draco said, "Still, it was a good duel, from both of you. Edmund, you've finally figured out that stopping Rigel from dodging is the only way to gain advantage over the pacing, and Rigel…I can't tell if you planned all that or just panicked at the end, but it did work, and Professor Lupin says that results are undeniable."

An expression he'd picked up from Sirius, if Rigel didn't miss her guess. It sounded like the sort of argument he would use to get his way.

Rigel and Rookwood nodded their thanks at the roundabout praise, and Rookwood asked, "How did the others do?"

"Neville lasted a whole five minutes against Rosier," Draco said, smiling. Rigel decided not to let him know how proud he looked of the Gryffindor he would have said six weeks ago was a waste of good oxygen. "They dueled a couple of times before tiring out. Aldon has no stamina, I swear."

Rigel could barely comprehend Draco referring to Rosier by his first name, but something had certainly changed between the two of them over the last couple of months. They were friendlier, now, and sometimes when Rigel came across them she got the weird feeling they'd been talking about her. She shook her head. It was probably her suspicious imagination.

"Did Ron finally beat Pansy?" Rigel asked, looking over at where her blonde-haired friend seemed in deep conspiracy with the redhead. It was not an uncommon sight, as both were the type to go over their duel with a fine-toothed comb afterwards. Pansy had an analytical streak that Rigel could only assume came from her father, Mr. Parkinson, and Ron never missed a chance to break a maneuver down to its basic elements. Too much exposure to Quidditch as a child, she thought.

"Pansy thinks not, but Weasley is calling it a draw," Draco said, smirking, "All I know is that Pansy snapped when Weasley tried to get a hair-removal charm to connect and it's lucky the poor bastard made it out alive, frankly.

Upon closer inspection, Ron did look a bit worse for wear. Pansy had a thing about hair, as Draco and Rigel could personally attest, having spent endless hours the victim of her over-zealous braiding habits more times than they cared to remember.

"Well, let's huddle up, since everyone's done, now," Draco said, clapping his hands together smartly.

They gathered with the others, passing around congratulations and encouragement where appropriate as they all stretched out muscles carefully to avoid injury.

"Great work today!" Draco said. He looked pleased as punch, and Rigel thought again what a good thing this odd habit had become. It gave him an outlet apart from Quidditch to focus his energy on when wrangling with his empathy left him annoyed and feeling stifled. "Rigel, Edmund, that was some very fast-paced dueling. Neville, you've gotten a real hang of the rhythm of spell-exchange, now. Next you should work on purposely disrupting that rhythm periodically so your opponent doesn't get too comfortable. Aldon, you should practice casting the higher-level spells until your core bulks up a bit—you were flagging at the end of the second duel. Also, try to find a little killer instinct. I know Neville doesn't exactly inspire it, but I think a bit of drive will really take your dueling to the next level. Pansy, I wish you had a bit less killer instinct, to be honest. You're going to emotionally scar Weasley for life if you aren't careful, and then we'll have to replace him, and just when he's starting to not look like a complete clown in the ring." Everyone laughed good-naturedly at the scowling redhead. "If you all want, we can plan to meet up again the first Sunday after break."

They all agreed, and then Ron spoke up. "First of all, I'd like to say it's bogus that I'm the only one you still call by my last name, Draco. And secondly, I think we should make this a proper club."

"Remember the disaster at last year's 'dueling club?'" Rosier reminded him.

"This'll be different," Ron said, waving a hand vaguely, "Run by students. I've had several people ask about what I'm doing with a bunch of snakes every week, you know. I think they're interested, but they feel like they can't intrude as long as it's a private thing."

"We'd have to get permission," Draco said, not looking entirely put out at the idea.

"Percy can use his Head Boy magic for something useful, then," Ron said, grinning, "He knows the Head Girl real well, too, so between the two of them, it shouldn't be a problem."

"We can start advertising in common rooms after the new year, then," Pansy said, looking excited at the prospect of organizing something, "We'll have to make it clear we're only accepting dedicated members serious about improving their skills. I expect some will drop out once they understand the physical demands. We might get enough to do a tournament, though, by the end of the school year."

Neville looked slightly intimidated at the prospect of new members, but he said, "I'll ask Professor Sprout if she'll put a flyer in the Hufflepuff common room."

"Good idea, Nev," Rosier said, smiling. He seemed to have taken a bit of a liking to the slightly timid Gryffindor. "It should definitely be open to all Houses."

"Professor Flitwick likes me," Rookwood said. She supposed that was as good as an offer to talk to the Ravenclaw Head of House about it as well.

"It's settled, then," Draco said, "I'll draw up a charter of some kind over the holidays. Stay in shape, now, and don't forget to practice your drills. We don't want to look like a bunch of fools in front of our new members, right?"

"What could be foolish about learning Dueling from a third-year?" Rigel asked, smiling as Draco narrowed his eyes at her.

"I'm sure I can find a willing assistant couch among the upper years, provided we do get any new members," Draco sniffed, "You just worry about not knocking people over in your next duel, Rigel. We don't want to be banned for free-dueling, after all."

The others laughed at that, and Rigel quickly stifled a grimace. She really shouldn't have knocked Rookwood's wand from his hand bodily like that. It was, strictly speaking, bad form. It had just seemed like the most obvious thing to do at the time. Those sorts of instincts were the ones Leo would be pounding into her head over the break, too, so she would have to be doubly careful when their club resumed in the spring. No sense advertising herself to her peers as a violent brute, even if it was a more effectual style of dueling.

By far the hardest thing she did before catching the train home that year wasn't packing, saying goodbye to her friends, or deciding which books to keep with her and which to leave in her dorm room. The hardest thing was surrendering her time-turner to Professor Snape's care the last day of term.

"I trust you've already completed your holiday assignments?" Snape asked, once the Ministry-required end-of-semester mental health checklist had been completed.

"Yes, sir," she said with no small amount of regret. What she would give to be able to take the innocuous golden necklace with her over the break. She had abused it terribly in the last two weeks, of course, to make up for all the time she would not be able to steal over the holiday, but just imagine what she could do with a time-turner at her parent's house! She could be at home with her family and in the alleys with Leo and studying in a library somewhere with Archie. For that matter, Archie could use it to—

She caught herself before the thought fully manifested. Maybe a break from the time-turner was for the best, after all. She didn't put a lot of stock in rules as a rule, but there were some lines she probably shouldn't cross. Like revealing the existence of a secret time-turner to her cousin and letting him use it to catch up on his studies. It pained her, leaving it at Hogwarts, but that very pain was a warning sign, she thought. It was time to resume a normal pace of living, perhaps.

"The two years is almost up," Snape said suddenly, breaking her from her reverie.

"They are," she agreed, a bit nervous, "Have you…made your decision?"

Snape inclined his head, his lips twisting in a way she found odd until he said, "I shall speak to your father upon the new year."

"My—why?" Rigel swallowed thickly. "Isn't it my choice?"

"It would be, if you were of age, as most apprentices are," Snape said, "As it is…he does have the power to gainsay this, Rigel."

He was not speaking to her as a student, she understood, but as a mentor. "I will speak to him when I get home," she said, thinking hard, "If he is warmed up to the idea…perhaps it will not be so difficult to acquire his permission. I think if it comes down to it, and I insist…well, he's never actually refused me anything." Archie had never asked to be apprenticed to the son of Sirius' hated rival, of course, but perhaps she could phrase it somewhat differently.

"You will both be attending the gala at the Parkinsons', will you not?" Snape asked, clear signs of plotting in his expression.

"I…suppose so," she said carefully, "I haven't heard from Si—my dad either way, but we went last year at the Rosiers'."

"Good," Snape nodded, "I am required to attend in any case, so that will be as good a place as any." With a sudden flick of his fingers, he added, "Your cousin, Miss Potter. She will also be there?"

"I'm really not sure," Rigel said, dread pooling in her stomach. She hadn't forgotten Snape had wanted to meet Harry—her—sometime over the break, but she hadn't thought he would suggest a place so public. Nor a place where Rigel was already supposed to be. "She doesn't go to parties."

"She will attend this one, if she wants to continue benefiting from my second-hand tutelage," Snape said sharply, "Tell her to seek me out, and I will judge whether or not such an arrangement is fit go on."

"I will tell her," she said quietly, "Thank you, Sir. Is there anything else?"

"Nothing that cannot wait for the new term," Snape said, leaning back in his office chair, "You may go, Mr. Black."

"Have a good holiday, Professor," she said, forcing a smile. All she could think as she made her way back to her dorm was that she really, really wished she could have kept the time-turner over winter break. How on earth was she going to be in two places at once without it? She just hoped Archie made good on his promise of a new plan for their disguises. Between Remus, Snape, her friends, and their families, they needed a miracle to make it through the holiday undiscovered.

Chapter 10

When Rigel stepped off the train at platform 9 ¾, she'd barely taken three steps when she was scooped up in a fierce hug that stole her breath and tugged her off-balance completely. Laughing a bit, she hugged Sirius back, saying, "Miss me, Dad?"

"More than ever," Sirius said, leaning back to get a look at her. "You haven't grown much, Sport. Been eating your vegetables?"

"I'm saving up my growth spurts for the summer," she said, grinning easily, "That way I don't risk getting new robes for Yule."

"Wouldn't want that," Sirius agreed, "Then I'd have to keep that new sneakoscope for myself."

"Dad!" she affected an appalled look. "Don't ruin the surprise!" Archie had a thing about surprises and people who spoiled them prematurely.

"I'm just kidding," Sirius said, slinging an arm over her shoulders and steering her toward the porthole, "Sneakoscopes are for people with enemies. Everyone loves the Black boys."

"Does uncle Regulus know you call us that?" she asked.

"Reggie doesn't have room in his head for such trivial details," Sirius said, "Too crowded as it is up there."

"What with its being stuffed full of his own consequence," she said, raising one eyebrow.

"What a caustic young man you've grown into." Sirius sighed dramatically. "It's my fault, really. I let you spend too much time with Harry as a child. Should have sent you to play with that Longbottom boy, instead. I hear he's very nice."

"Harry's not that bad," she said, "She's never mean to anyone."

"Not to their faces anyway," Sirius laughed, "I love our Harry, but you have to admit she's got a critical streak a mile wide."

Did she? Perhaps she used to, before it had become so difficult to live up to her own standards. These days, no matter the internal critiques her mind sometimes offered, she didn't have the hypocritical gumption to level any true condemnation at other people when her own life was such a mess.

"I think she's gaining some compassion in her old age," she said after a moment's contemplation.

"More like gaining some control over her tongue," Sirius said with a short bark of laughter.

"That too," she agreed. Looking for a change of subject, she asked, "Why didn't you send me to play with Neville as a child? Aunt Lily is good friends with Mrs. Longbottom. Did you just think Harry was enough of a playmate for me?"

Sirius gave her an odd look. "We did have the Longbottom kid over once. Don't you remember?"

She blinked, completely taken aback. Archie had had a play date with Neville once? Why hadn't he mentioned that? After the Flint disaster, she would have thought he'd mention any other distant pre-Hogwarts acquaintances who might expect her to recognize them.

"I don't really…" she trailed off, wondering how she was going to explain this one.

To her surprise, however, Sirius dropped it immediately with a somewhat awkward, "Never mind, Arch. I'm probably misremembering."

They walked in slightly strained silence until the apparition point, each lost in their own thoughts. Eventually she decided to just ask Archie about Neville and see if there was anything important for her to know.

Sirius offered to get started on dinner when they reached number twelve, and she gratefully took the chance to retreat to her room and 'unpack.' In reality she simply un-shrunk her trunk and opened it up on the bed to give the impression of unpacking and settled in to mentally review everything she had to tell Archie about the last semester before they officially switched back.

It was half an hour before the door to Archie's bedroom whooshed open and Archie darted in, nearly slamming the door behind him in his hurry. She had to laugh when she took in his appearance—he was bundled up like a nomad fresh from the tundra, knit hat pulled low over his brow and a thick scarf pulled up over his nose and cheeks.

"Cold?" she asked, chuckling as he struggled to unwrap himself.

"No," Archie huffed, "Unless Lily asks, and then yes, you were very cold on the way here."

"They're going to see our faces eventually," she said, perplexed by Archie's strange and unnecessary maneuver.

"Not until I fix mine," Archie said, grinning with more mischief than she was ready to deal with so soon after coming home.

"You said you had a plan for our disguises," she said slowly, "You going to tell me what it is, now? I was sort of thinking we'd have to just pretend not to grow at all this year, and then somehow arrange to go away at the beginning of the summer and take the Polyjuice before we get back, or…something."

"Don't worry another moment," Archie said, nearly bouncing with excitement, "I've got a solution and you're going to be so impressed, because I worked really hard on it all semester."

"What is it?" she asked, more than a little curious now. How on earth did Archie have time to research new disguise methods on top of everything else he had to do that semester? Maybe AIM gave time-turners to its students, too?

"It's a surprise!" he said, "So close your eyes."

She did so, trying not to smile too fondly. It would only encourage her playful cousin to keep her in suspense. What felt like several minutes later, Archie gave her the go ahead to open her eyes again. She blinked, and found herself looking into a mirror. It wasn't the first time she'd used that expression to describe how eerily alike she and Archie looked, but it was the first time she hadn't been exaggerating.

"Is it an illusion?" she asked, turning her head this way and that to admire the angles of Archie's new look. It was uncannily accurate, though there was something…off about it. "I think it's on backwards."

"What?" Archie lost his smug little smirk with a disheartened slump. "It's symmetrical," he whined.

"Not perfectly," she pointed out, "Come look at the mirror with me." She dragged him over to the bathroom and gestured to their reflection. "See? It's flipped, because you were picturing what I look like when you look at me, weren't you? But when you see the slight quirk in my right eyebrow, it looks to you like it's on the left."

"Oh, duh," Archie groaned. Looking in the mirror between their images, he furrowed his brows and pressed his lips together in concentration. A moment later, without any noticeable wand-work that she could see, the faces in the mirror matched perfectly.

"How are you doing that?" she asked, frankly astonished, "It's much more solid than any illusion I've ever seen."

"Thank you," Archie said, smirking again, "That was the level of amazement I was looking for the first time."

"Maybe if you'd gotten it right—"

"Anyway! Remember when you gave me a Potentialis potion after our birthdays?" Archie said, grinning widely.

"Oh, no," she blanched. Not Archie, too. Draco's gift might have been a coincidence, but two gifts conveniently unlocked after two Potentialis potions? Unlikely. She would have to seriously look into what she was doing wrong with that recipe.

"Oh, yes!" Archie actually jumped in excitement, "I mean, I knew the metamorphmagus ability ran in the Black line, but the only case in the last two generations was Andromeda's daughter."

"The only documented case," she said.

"You think there were others that hid their gift? Why?" Archie's brain caught up with his voice abruptly and he said, "Oh. I guess for the same kind of reasons my ability will be undocumented, too."

He looked a bit down at the prospect of hiding such a major magical development from his father, so she said quickly, "It's really amazing, Archie. This is…beyond anything I imagined. Our ruse is going to be nearly indestructible, now. We can never be caught out as one another, because there's no way to be sure—" she broke off with an embarrassed laugh, "Well, only one way to be sure, I guess."

"Actually, I can become a girl now," Archie said seriously.

She leveled an amused stare at him. "Been practicing?" Her cousin flushed pink from ears to cheeks. "I bet your anatomy scores have really improved," she pressed, fighting a laugh at the mortified expression on his face, "Does Hermione help you practice?"

"Don't talk about Hermione like that!" Archie blurted, "It's not—I don't—stop laughing, Harry!"

"Sorry, sorry," she said, wiping one of her eyes discretely, "It's good, Archie. Really. I mean, now they really can't prove anything on your end. Me…" She sobered up quickly. "Well…maybe it's time I started considering taking the male version of the Modified Polyjuice. The older we get, the bigger the risk of someone realizing my hips are just a tad too wide becomes, right?"

"You said it was dangerous to suppress the reproductive organs' natural shape over a long period of time," Archie said, frowning.

"In theory," Harry shrugged, "I don't have any concrete data on it. Anyway, this whole thing is dangerous. It might be unavoidable at some point. This summer, maybe—I'm growing a lot this year, Archie. I can feel it, underneath the Polyjuice, growing pains all across my ribs and lower back."

"It'll be suspicious for different reasons to your parents if you suddenly turn into a boy, though," Archie argued worriedly, "I mean, what if Sirius throws another swimming pool party? What if your mom wants to come into the changing room with you at Madam Malkin's? It's too big a risk."

"I suppose there's time to figure something out," she said, trying to lighten the mood a bit, "Anyway, I'm really proud of all the work you must have done this semester. Coming into a new gift isn't easy."

"It was a lot of fun, actually," Archie said, shrugging, "I can turn my hair pink. Want to see?"

"Maybe tomorrow," she said, smiling at the mental picture, "Our parents will be expecting us for dinner soon. We need to hurry and change clothes, and I've still got to put my contacts in."

"Sucks to be you," Archie said, smirking, "I never have to wear contacts again."

"You might have to wear a bra, though," she smirked, "Maybe you should go as me to the gala—you can look more like a girl than I can right now."

Archie shot her an unimpressed look, "Yeah, like Harriet Potter would go to the gal—why are you looking at me like that?"

Grimacing, she wondered how she could have forgotten that she had tons of explaining to do. Now she would have to rush through it before Sirius came up to get them. "Change first," she sighed, "Then I'll explain everything."

"First you might want to drop that voice-changing spell," Archie suggested, "And undo whatever thickening charm you've been using on your eyebrows, or James and Lily may have a few concerns about the direction your adolescence is taking."

"They'll have a few questions, anyway." Harry rolled her eyes as she performed the cancellations. "I look like someone cast a stretching charm a ten-year-old boy."

"Your shoulders are much wider than a ten-year-old's," Archie said.

"Oh, good," she smiled, "Then it won't be suspicious when I start growing facial hair."

"You aren't going to grow facial hair," Archie laughed, "You'll have to pretend to, though. I recommend cutting your jaw a bit and then dabbing at it embarrassedly when your roommates are looking."

"Somehow, when I envisioned the future of our deception so long ago, this wasn't what came immediately to mind," Harry sighed. She changed quickly from Archie's familiar robes to her own somewhat alien outfit. Her clothes always felt too small the first few days after switching roles. Archie's male-cut robes were just so much more comfortable than the snug-fitting swaths that passed for feminine ensembles. At least she would be back in her brewing robes soon.

"So what's the scoop?" Archie asked once they were both suitably attired.

"It's complicated, but the long and short of it is that both Rigel Black and Harry Potter need to attend the New Year's Gala this year," Harry said. She launched into an explanation about Snape's demanding to meet her as Harriet at the gala as well as his plan to confront Sirius about Rigel's apprenticeship, then segued into her friends wanting to meet Harriet as Rigel's betrothed, and finally her fear that it wasn't going to be enough if she went alone that year. "I mean, you could in theory pretend to get violently ill the night of the gala and leave me to go as Harry—myself, I mean—with Sirius, but without using the Modified Polyjuice, Harriet is going to look exactly like Rigel. It'll be a bit suspicious, don't you think, if Rigel just happens to be sick and Harriet shows up looking and acting uncannily like him? I'm afraid Professor Snape will assume that Rigel is pretending to be Harriet in order to convince Snape to let Rigel keep helping Harriet with potions, which of course is going to make Snape think Harriet isn't actually any good at potions and Rigel has actually been covering for Harriet this whole time and—"

"Whoa." Archie held up his hands with a confused look on his face. "First of all, stop talking about yourself in two different third-persons—it's freaking me out."

"Sorry," she said, taking a breath.

"That's okay," Archie said, "I think I understood most of it. I'm just thinking—and bear with me here because this is going to sound crazy, but—why don't we both just go as…ourselves?"

Harry blinked slowly, "You think? I was going to research mind magics and see if there's a way to mentally connect our surface thoughts temporarily so we could feed each other information about credible responses to awkward situations in real time."

"That…sounds awesome," Archie admitted, "But I think in this case, the simple answer is better. You be you, and dazzle your Snape with a galore of potions expertise, and I'll be me, and dazzle everyone with my stunning good looks and charm."

"Except for the part where you look like me," Harry said.

"Our good looks, then," Archie waved a hand dismissively, "The point is, all 'Rigel' really needs to do at the gala is introduce Harriet—I mean, you, damn this is complicated—to people and not blurt out any terrible secrets in front on the entire Wizarding ton. Piece of cake."

"I'm not sure you can pretend to be me for so many hours, though," Harry said, biting her lip, "My friends are pretty observant. One of them can feel your very emotions, now, so you'll have to be convincing on more than just the surface level."

"Because you're so unique," Archie said, voice thick with irony. She had said something similar to him once, she thought, and maybe he had a point. There weren't many things, she had come to realize in the last few years, that couldn't be faked. "Besides, I'm pretending to be me, remember? It would literally be impossible for anyone to call me out on not being Arcturus Rigel Black."

"True," she conceded. Still… "What about your aura? Snape, Malfoy, and Riddle can all read them, and they all know I don't have one. I can fake one as Harriet, but you don't know how to suppress yours."

"I'll learn." Archie shrugged. "We've nearly two and a half weeks until New Year's. If I put all my time into studying aura-suppression, I'm bound to get somewhere."

Harry frowned at his confidence, but agreed that it was possible. She'd have to do something about her aura, as well. Now that she knew her diminished magical core wasn't strong enough to support shaped imbuing in practice, it would be incredibly foolish to appear in front of Snape with an aura that contradicted the words that would be coming out of her mouth.

"Kids! Food!" came echoing down the hall, and they wrapped up their plans for the moment.

"You remember all the topics I told you Remus covered in his lessons?" Harry asked Archie as they headed for the stairs.

"Got 'em," Archie said, "You read over all those letters Aunt Lily and Uncle James sent?"

"Twice," she said, grimacing. She would not be slipping up in that department ever again. Being held at wand-point by her own father had had a strong motivating influence on her ability to memorize those letters' contents.

"Let's go reclaim our rightful identities, then," Archie said cheerfully, bounding toward the smell of dinner with a look of hedonic ambition on his face.

Harry followed close behind, ready to get the looks of bewildered amusement that would blossom in the wake of she and Archie's stunning similitude out of the way, at least. Then she would lay claim to a large helping of what smelled like her mother's vegetarian lasagna. That conquest, at least, wouldn't leave a sour taste in her mouth.

The next day saw Harry and Archie holed up in the lab beneath Potter Place, pouring over the dark disguise book. She'd read the chapter on auras before, but as her aura had already been suppressed at the time, she hadn't paid very close attention to the details in that section.

"This sounds like Occlumency," Archie said, frowning.

"It is, basically," Harry said, "You'll need to access your mental landscape, then essentially use your magic to construct something that conceals the main portion of it from the mists. Near as I can tell, what's on the first level of your mindscape is what people can read from your aura."

"So it's like putting your things inside a house, so people can't see them when they drive by," Archie said.

"Yes," Harry agreed, "And Occlumency is the process of building and defending that house, while Legilimency is the art of breaking into other people's houses."

"Sounds fun," Archie said, "Only how do I access my mindscape?"

"It usually takes a lot of meditation," Harry said slowly, "But I have an idea…I don't know if it will work, but it might be a huge shortcut."

"Is this like the time you had an idea to raise a baby fox in my closet without telling me?" Archie asked warily.

"I told you," Harry protested.

"After it ate the aloe plant on my windowsill and got sick all over my blankets," Archie reminded her.

"If Mum hadn't started wondering where all our milk was going it wouldn't have been so hungry," Harry said, feeling rather guilty about the blasé sense of responsibility she'd had as a child.

Archie sighed, "The point, though, is…are you sure your idea is a good one?"

"Not entirely," Harry said, "But I don't think it's going to hurt you."

"Has anyone ever told you how terrible you are at reassuring people?" Archie rubbed his jaw. "Okay, shoot."

"Remember when I showed you your magical core?" Harry said at once, actually a bit excited to see if her idea was going to work.

"You mean when your magical core tried to roast me? Yeah, I remember," Archie didn't look impressed.

"Well, I told you about how during the Sleeping Sickness I could access people's mindscapes through their cores, right?" she said, leaning forward, "Even though accessing other people's cores is somehow something only I can do, everyone should be able to access their own cores without a problem. So in theory I can pull you through your core into your mind."

"And you'll be able to direct me in constructing some kind of aura-containment field," Archie said, eyes widening.

"I could probably even help you," Harry said, "I think anything I made in your mind with my magic probably wouldn't last very long, but I might be able to direct your magic to help you create something."

"That actually sounds worth a shot," Archie said, starting to grin, "Can we try it now?"

Harry nodded, smiling back, "Sit with your back against something so you don't fall over. Then we'll begin."

They got into a comfortable meditation position, then focused their attention inwards.

"Do you remember how to project your consciousness toward your core?" she asked, eyes closed.

"I think so," Archie said. After a long moment of silence, he sighed happily, "Found it."

"I'll meet you there," Harry said. She focused on the secondary layer of her core, the writhing coils of fire that snapped out, whip-like in reflex, in answer to her focusing attention. As her avatar fully materialized beside the core, she fought a flinch of unease. It looked for lack of a better term denser than she remembered. She supposed that was the suppressor, compacting her magic as it locked the deepest parts of it away. She expected the core to look smaller, though, if it was being compressed by the suppressor. Instead it merely seemed darker, wilder, and hotter. She felt a frisson of fear as she stretched her hand toward the outer coils. Was she still welcome here? But no, this was her core. It couldn't resent her for suppressing it—magic didn't think that way. Everyone said so.

She coaxed a coil forward, wrestling a bit to get it to go in the direction of Archie's core. Once she felt the twang of connection, she followed the line with confidence. Projecting her consciousness got easier each time, and she hadn't lost the knack for it, despite not having occasion to practice since the Chamber of Secrets.

Archie's magic was as she remembered, wrapped in soft, swirling mist that seemed to invite even as it concealed. She followed her cousin through the gentle wafts of magic, parting the mists before them until they reached the babbling river of cheerful blue that made up his primary core. It flowed in a whimsical circle, uniform yet free. What a contrast it made to her own disgruntled and repressed core.

"Do I have to swim upstream?" Archie asked, letting his fingers dangle in the current.

"Only if you want to lay eggs and then die on the upper banks," Harry said, reaching out her own hand to dip in the stream, "We just need to push through the center. I guess in this case we dive in and swim until we hit the other side."

"Do we hold our breath?" Archie asked.

"Have you been breathing?" Harry smirked.

"Oh," Archie blinked as he realized that as a projected consciousness he didn't, in fact, need to breathe, "Weird."

She guided him forward, plunging them both into the rushing blue. When they emerged on the other side, Harry had to pause for a moment and stare at the world she'd just stepped into.

If she hadn't swam through his core herself, she might have assumed Archie had an air core, so full of light and atmosphere was his mindscape. There was no clear light source, yet everything she saw was bathed in a golden glow that offset brilliantly against the intensely blue sky that seemed to swallow up most of the horizon. She and Archie had emerged on a sandy bank littered with glass-like pebbles that sparkled in the light. The river in Archie's mind mirrored that of his primary core, flowing in one large, continuous circle that dominated the center of his mental landscape.

"What are those?" Archie asked, pointing upwards.

She craned her neck and couldn't believe she hadn't noticed them before. Filling the sky above their heads were bubbles—not filled with air, but with water. They skimmed along in an invisible breeze, large and small, each a self-contained pocket of crystal-clear river water that sloshed and swirled as it floated around.

"They must be your manifestations," Harry said, running a hand through her long hair thoughtfully. How were they supposed to even access those things, much less suppress them beneath a layer of secondary Occlumency?

"My mind is awesome," Archie declared, grinning proudly, "I bet nobody in the world has a mind this cool."

"And to think we haven't even done anything with it yet," Harry chuckled.

"Why mess with perfection?" Archie said airily.

"Because you have to pretend to be me, and my mind is considerably less…open," Harry said, gesturing at the blinding expanse of sky.

"Right," Archie said, rubbing his hands together, "Where do we start? Can we just gather all the bubbles in one place?"

"I think we have to cover them with something," Harry said, "The idea is to veil them from the first layer of your mind, from the 'view' of the mists. Anyone using aura-sensing or non-invasive Legilimency essentially scans the primary layer of your mind, so anything out in the open is 'visible' to them. Make sense?"

"Yeah, but… how are we supposed to cover a whole river?" Archie asked.

Harry looked at the expanse of water flowing peacefully. "It is pretty big." Her miniature sun seemed positively portable in comparison, in fact. "We have to cover the bubbles, too."

"We could build something to put them in, I guess," Archie said, looking around, "Right in the middle of the river-circle-thing. A dome or something…" He scrunched up his nose. "That would be pretty out of place, though."

"It doesn't have to be aesthetic," Harry laughed.

"Why shouldn't it be?" Archie asked, looking offended, "It's my mind. I want it to be all tranquil and stuff. Maybe it'll help me think."

"Occlumency does make your thought patterns more efficient," Harry agreed, "It's a side-effect of a well-organized mind."

"Well let's organize mine, then!" Archie looked excited to get started, but utterly unsure where to begin, exactly. "What if we just put, like, a privacy screen up along the outer border of my mind?"

"That's a lot of surface area to cover," Harry frowned, "And the mists extend pretty far up along the edges of your mind. But maybe we could grow some sort of…privacy vegetation. The ground along the banks looks pretty solid. I think it would take roots."

"Trees!" Archie gushed, "Yes, that's perfect! We'll plant trees all along both banks and the canopy will block out the river!"

"And we can attach the bubbles of water to the branches," Harry said, "So they can't be seen from outside either."

"They're so…free, though," Archie sighed, "Do we have to tie them down? What if we just moved them into the river, instead? Then they could flow freely, but still be hidden by the canopy."

"That could work," Harry said slowly. She wasn't sure if you could put aspect Manifestations inside the representation of your core, but she didn't think there was any harm in trying. Archie's magic couldn't harm his own mind. "Let's try it."

They stood for a moment, just staring up at the many globes of watery whimsy. "How do we get them down, again?"

"You should have some control over them, since it's your mind," she told him, thinking of how she managed her own mindscape. "Just focus on a bubble and think of what you want it to do."

Archie turned his attention to the nearest sphere, a small bubble about the size of his fist that wobbled in the air like a bobber in choppy waters. He lifted a hand coaxingly toward the little blue ball, then slowly retracted it like he was reeling in an invisible line. The bubble swerved through the air almost curiously to hover at Archie's nose. He laughed and caught it between his hands carefully.

The moment it was clasped between his fingers a peculiar look came over his face. "It's a memory," he said, sounding a bit breathless, "It's—I can feel it, like I'm really there. Remember when we made those snow-ghosts?"

"In Mrs. Bagshot's yard?" Harry smiled, "We surrounded her house with them. The glow-powder we sprinkled in their eyes lasted over a week, I think."

"Yeah." Archie smiled down at the memory bubble fondly. "That was a good prank. Even though Aunt Lily made us apologize when she found out."

"I think old Bathilda enjoyed it," Harry said.

"She did leave them up until they melted," Archie agreed. He walked to the bank of the river and knelt down. Gently, he released the ball of memory into the stream. The bubble seemed to slip into the river almost delicately, not sinking to the bottom like a stone but winding its way through the water easily of its own accord, matching the current, yet outside of it, clearly making its own path.

Archie turned his attention to the next bubble, and Harry took a moment to consider how she could best help. She didn't really want to handle Archie's Manifestations. It was a very personal part of the mind, and even though she knew almost everything about her cousin, it still didn't feel right to interact with his memories in that way.

She moved a short distance away, instead, and bent her will toward the water in Archie's river. In theory she could use her own magic to build something, but there was no telling how long it would persist in Archie's mind, or what it might do once she stopped concentrating on it. Better to ground his defenses in his own magic.

The water flowed at her command, as though eager to be useful. She directed a small trickle away from the stream with a thought, drilling it down into the sandy bank as though she were planting a liquid seed. Another moment of concentration, and the water hardened and darkened, sticking fast below the sparkling pebbles and shooting upwards in a fountain that solidified even as it blossomed toward the sky. She fed it more bits of magic as needed, guiding the offshoots into trunks and branches that burst into brilliant green at their edges. In a short time, a supple river birch stood before her, several distinct trunks together spreading a multitude of cheerful leaves whose shade gave another dimension to the babbling stream it overlooked.

Harry rand a hand over the curled bark with a satisfied smile. Archie's mind was going to be lovely, by the time they finished.

"That's great, Harry!" Archie called from where he was herding a string of memories along in a strange parody of follow-the-leader.

Harry waved back in acknowledgement, then got to work on the next tree. They still had a long way to go.

She didn't know how long they worked, but eventually, when about a third of the circular bank was covered in canopy, Harry noticed that the water level in the river was significantly depleted. She jogged to where Archie was still ferrying bubbles into the river and said, "I think we should stop here for today."

Archie nodded. "The river is starting to get a bit crowded," he said, gesturing to where entire schools of memory orbs were swimming around one another even as they floated along with the current around them. "I feel tired, too, like after I practice a spell too many times. Only I haven't done any magic—it's kind of scary that you can use my magic like that without my input."

Harry blinked. "I think you could forbid me…probably."

"No need." Archie shook his head, amused. "Could you access my core without being in my mind, though? I mean, could you tap into someone else's core just by being near them?"

Harry recoiled from the idea. "Surely not. That would be…" Well, she couldn't call it impossible. Magic seemed to make most things possible. Still, it was the sort of idea that made her feel slightly ill. Using someone else's magic to help them was one thing. Using someone's magic against their will was unthinkable. Magic always answered to the will of its owner. To even think that she might be able to circumvent that will was… "Dangerous."

Archie shrugged, but she thought it seemed a bit forced.

"Let's get back to our bodies," Harry said, eager to change the subject. "Do you think you could find this place again with meditation, if you need to work on it while I'm not around?"

"I think so," Archie said, looking around as though to cement the view of his mindscape in his imagination. "Yeah. Let's go."

They dove back into one of the rivers and let the current carry them out.

The first thing Harry heard upon opening her eyes was a loud "ouch!" from Archie. She opened her eyes to find him clutching at his neck and wincing. "Cramp," he whined, grasping for his wand with his other hand. A moment later he was muttering a muscle relaxant charm under his breath and sighing with relief.

Harry smiled. "Wish I'd known that spell back when I started meditating. It took forever to figure out how to hold my head so it didn't kink."

"Someday your trials will inspire Rita Skeeter to write a biography," Archie said solemnly.

She considered throwing something at him, but everything in reach was something she needed undamaged for her lab.

They stretched out their muscles and climbed the stairs to the kitchen. "Please let Aunt Lily have left sandwiches from lunch," Archie prayed under his breath as they poked their way into the fridge.

"Lunch?" Lily breezed into the kitchen from the other room, "Archie, it's nearly five—they're setting the table at Grimmauld as we speak."

"Did you come to collect us, Mom?" Harry asked, shutting the fridge sheepishly.

"Of course," Lily said, "You've been in the lab all day. I got a little worried that it was too quiet down there, but when I checked you guys were just meditating. Have you been at it all day?"

"I read that meditation can help you learn things faster," Harry said, "The study said that meditating for an hour every week can cut down the time a student spends studying by as much as two hours a day."

"So you two thought if you spent a whole day meditating you'd learn at the speed of light?" Lily guessed, smiling, "I'm not sure it works like that."

"Can't hurt to try," Archie said, grinning impishly.

"Just warn me if you decide to take up Legilimency," Lily sighed, "I'll have to Obliviate the knowledge of where your Yule presents are hidden."

"We'd never use our powers for evil!" Archie said, looking aghast at the very prospect.

Harry wondered how Archie could possibly classify 'peeking at presents' as 'evil.' Especially compared to some of the other things they'd done. She supposed Archie just didn't think of their deception as something bad, in the grand scheme of things. Neither did she, of course, but she did feel nearly constantly guilty about it all the same.

She and Archie flooed over to Grimmauld Place and were met with the glorious smell of food cooking as they wandered in from the floo-room. Before they reached the kitchen, however, Sirius intercepted them.

"I need a word with Arch, Harry," he said, looking determinedly cheerful in a way that only made her feel a bit uncomfortable.

"I'll help Remus finish up," she offered, scooting past her uncle in the hallway and wondering what had Sirius so awkward-looking. She didn't think he'd ever met a conversation he couldn't gracefully skate his way through.

Archie watched Harry slink away toward the kitchen with nary a look back and wondered if she knew how utterly unconcerned she often seemed.

His dad gestured him toward the library, so Archie followed, taking a seat in one of the terribly old upholstered chairs and wrinkling his nose at the smell coming off the fabric. They really should update the decorating sometime.

"What's up, Dad?" he asked, tilting is head to invite his father to say whatever was on his mind.

"Son," Sirius said, his eyes roaming Archie's face restlessly, "Lately I've been thinking."

"About?" Archie prompted when his dad lapsed into silence once more.

"You look a lot like Harry," Sirius said slowly, "I mean, before there was a bit of a difference, sometimes, but now…you look almost exactly the same."

Archie nodded, knowing it would be absurd to deny the obvious. "I've noticed. I accused Harry of playing a prank on me last night, actually, but I checked and she definitely goes longer than an hour between drinking something so I know it isn't Polyjuice—"

"I don't think it's Harry," Sirius said, grimacing a bit. "I think…you may have inherited some latent metamorphmagus abilities."

"Me?" Archie chuckled in disbelief, absolutely stunned that his dad had put that together so quickly. Too bad he could never know how right he was. "But I can't change my appearance, Dad. And if I could, I'd definitely use it to look like the keeper for the Abbleby Arrows, not…Harry." He tried to make it sound as thought the very notion were amusing, but Sirius didn't laugh.

"I don't think it's a conscious ability," Sirius said, frowning a little, "It's rare, because usually magic genetics is an all-or-nothing deal, but sometimes an ability can manifest passively. I can't think of any other explanation for why you and Harry continue to grow more similar instead of less."

"Why would it fixate on Harry?" Archie asked, thinking quickly. Maybe he could use this. If Sirius set upon a plausible explanation that didn't endanger the ruse, well, why not let him? It would stop his dad wondering about the strangeness of it, at least.

Sirius shrugged a bit helplessly. "I suppose, since you spent so much time together as children, you might be a bit…attached to Harry. Perhaps your latent ability has latched onto her as a sort of model for your own growth."

"What does that mean for me?" Archie asked, trying to look as though he were considering the possibility.

"Maybe nothing," Sirius said, "Maybe…well, it depends on whether it bothers you, I suppose, that your appearance might be shifting to match hers."

"You calling me ugly?" Archie squinted at his dad until Sirius let out a bark of laughter.

"No, and don't let Harry catch you implying she is, either," Sirius said ruefully.

"She wouldn't care." Archie waved his hand dismissively, then paused. "Do you care? I mean, does it bother you that I might end up looking like James instead of you?"

Though to be honest Archie rather thought Harry and he looked more like Sirius than James.

"It doesn't bother me," Sirius said, and Archie thought he was probably being honest, "I just worry it may not be healthy. I'm not saying you depend on Harry, because you're both very independent, strong-willed young adults. It might be that you need some…distance, though. For both your sakes."

"Distance?" Archie scrunched up his nose. He wasn't sure he liked that idea. Harry and he were a team.

"You spend a lot of time together," Sirius said, "Which isn't bad necessarily, but you also sacrifice a lot for one another. Harry studies Healing for you, you study Potions with…Snape….for her. It's just—you're very committed to one anther, for being so young."

"Neither of us is doing anything we don't want to," Archie pointed out.

"That may be true, but you're still doing a lot for one another," Sirius said. He rubbed his chin. "I just think you need something for you, Archie. Harry had her internship last summer. Maybe this summer…you can do something by yourself?"

He said it more as a question than a suggestion, but Archie nodded easily, growing excited as the implications turned over in his mind. "If you think it's best, I'll start looking into opportunities. It could be really fun to have a project of my own next summer." In fact, Archie thought, maybe he could find an internship abroad. Without the chance to update their Polyjuice over the winter break, there would be a very noticeable difference in looks when they next took it. Harry's sudden change could be explained by a growth spurt while she was in America, but with Remus at Hogwarts…maybe a little time away from his family was just what he needed. Or what their artifice needed, rather.

"Good." Sirius looked quite relived, and Archie concluded that his supposed passive metamorphic talent must have been bothering him more than he let on. "So. Dinner?"

"Race you," Archie grinned, taking off like a shot. It was only partly to escape the awkwardness of ending that heavy conversation; he was also really hungry.

It took the rest of that week, working on and off, to get her and Archie's mindscapes straightened out. In addition to suppressing all the Manifestations of Archie's mind, she'd helped him set up a few rudimentary defenses to casual prying. She doubted anyone would try to Legilimens him at the gala, but she'd found that you never actually knew, with purebloods.

Once Archie's mind was shored up, Harry turned her attention to herself. She really needed to flesh out her projected aura a bit, just enough that it wouldn't be obviously fake to anyone familiar with reading them. Toward that end, she convinced Archie that it would be in their best interest to visit Frein's shop in the Lower Alleys. She had followed the instructions in the dark disguise book as best she could, but as she had no way of sensing her aura for herself, she didn't know if it would pass muster or not.

Frein had read her aura easily last summer. He would be the perfect, innocuous candidate to test her new, improved aura on. Archie's too. She thought the canopy they'd built would be very effective as a suppressant, but she wanted to double check before they showed up at the Parkinsons' on New Year's Eve.

"How much further in is it?" Archie asked, looking very uncomfortable as they turned onto yet another side alley.

"Not much further," Harry said, "See that fountain? It's just down the alley that opens alongside it."

"You know your way pretty well down here," Archie said, voice carefully neutral. "Last time I came to Knockturn with you we stayed on the beaten path."

"It's been two summers since I started working with Krait," Harry said, smiling a bit, "I know the alleys much better, now."

"I thought you meant the craftsman alleys," Archie said quietly, "Or maybe the more questionable retailer alleys off of Knockturn. I didn't know you'd been running around…way back here, Harry."

"This is where my apartment is," Harry pointed out.

"Really?" Archie looked dubiously at the ramshackle buildings around them.

"Not here," Harry rolled her eyes, "It's further in, in one of the residential districts: certainly not in the commercial areas close to Diagon."

"Is it nice, at least?" Archie asked, looking as though he wasn't sure he was allowed to ask that question.

"It is." Harry smiled. "Want to see it?"

"That's okay," Archie said, "I'll take your word for it."

She supposed he was even less comfortable in the lower alleys than he seemed. She couldn't blame him—she still remembered getting hopelessly lost the first time she'd ventured beyond Kyprioth Court.

They turned one last time and found themselves in front of a familiar sign reading "Custom Metalwork and Repair."

She opened the door to the shop and ushered Archie inside. It was as fantastically cluttered as she remembered, walls of miniscule boxes organized according to some mysterious schema. "Mr. Frein?" she called, stepping up to the counter, "Are you here?"

"Be right with you!" came a cheerful voice from the back of the shop.

"Are those fairy rings?" Archie asked, awe in his voice as he took in a glass display case under the counter.

"He works with all kinds of materials," Harry said, "Leo says he's a genius."

"Leo is too free with praise," Frein said, finally stepping out from the back room. His face was lightly lined with signs of frequent mirth, and he hardly had to stoop to scoot under the counter's divide, so short was he.

"He simply has excellent taste in the people he chooses to speak about," Harry said, "How have you been, Frein?"

"Very well, young miss, thank you." He gave a little bow that gave them a full view of his bright red hair. "What can I do for you today? Trouble with that ring of yours?"

"No, although I wouldn't mind if you had time to tweak it this week," Harry said, smiling a bit sheepishly, "I was thinking I'd like to have access to just a bit more of my magic—there's a brewing technique that's very hard to achieve without sufficient magical reserves."

"It shouldn't be too much trouble," Frein said, "May I have a look?"

Harry pulled off her glove with only slight hesitation. She could easily hand it over for a few days—she just wouldn't do any magic in the meantime. As long as she didn't use her magic, she could contain it just fine on her own.

He turned the ring over in his fingers once she'd pried it off and hummed a bit under his breath. "I can have it adjusted by four this afternoon, does that work?"

"Are you sure?" Harry frowned, not intending to inconvenience the man. "I don't want to rush you."

"If I say I'm sure will you wipe that ridiculous half-guilty expression off your face?" Frein laughed. "You honestly look very pitiful like that, child."

Harry's face relaxed in open surprise. Archie hooted with laughter. "He's got you there, Harry. Just let the man do his job when he wants to do it."

"All right. Four, then," Harry said, shaking her head.

"Was there anything else?" Frein asked, pocketing the jade ring.

"Yes," Harry said, wondering how exactly she could phrase her request.

"Can you read our auras?" Archie blurted, leaning forward excitedly.

Frein nodded easily, not even questioning their motive as he took a step back and squinted at them each in turn. "Interesting," he said, smiling widely, "Very interesting. You, young lady, have no aura at all! Have you suppressed it intentionally?"

Archie exchanged a look with Harry, then said, "I'm…a guy."

Frein looked acutely surprised. "Ah, I've done it again. I'm terribly sorry, young man, but I assumed the two of you were twins—you are identical, are you not?"

Harry and Archie both laughed, a bit uneasily. "We're related, but not twins," Harry said, "Though people do confuse us quite often. So you can't see his aura at all? Not even a little bit?"

"Nothing," Frein agreed, still smiling. "I'm guessing that is good news?"

Harry smiled enigmatically, but didn't answer. "What about my aura?"

"It's matured since I saw it in August," Frein said, raising a bushy brow knowingly, "Been working on it?"

"A little," Harry said, smiling back. In fact she'd added quite a few more of the supplementary Manifestations to her outer mindscape, and very carefully siphoned a bit more magic to the torch-like manifestation that sat atop her mountain. People would expect for her core to have expanded after her thirteenth birthday, and she felt her aura should reflect that. Even if nobody had probably been paying attention to it at the showcase, anyway. "Is there anything noticeably off about it? I'd like it to be as natural as possible—in the interest of academic curiosity, of course."

"Of course," Frein said, face serious. He squinted at her some more, but eventually shrugged. "I see nothing wrong with it. It's a little on the uncomplicated side, but not everyone has a complicated aura. Some say a simple aura is the sign of a simple mind, but in truth it is only the sign of a very clear-thinker. It will pass muster, I think, whatever you're preparing it for."

Harry had to try very hard not to laugh maniacally. It was all falling together. For once. With their auras in check, no one who could read them (i.e. all the most dangerous people she knew) would associate Harriet Potter with Rigel Black.

"Thank you, Frein," Harry settled on saying, "We really appreciate it."

"Come by anytime," Frein said jovially, waving off her thanks, "Four o'clock, in fact."

"Will do," Harry said, bowing her head once again in thanks as she and Archie made their way out onto the street.

They exchanged triumphant looks as they set off toward home. "I think we might actually pull this off," Archie said, looking like he wasn't sure whether to relax or keep an eye out for something to go wrong.

It was a little after two and they'd had an early breakfast, so Harry asked Archie if he wanted to stop at the Dancing Phoenix for lunch. "It's much closer to the main alleys," Harry said, "And you might be able to meet some of my friends, if they're here."

"Oh, sounds fun," Archie said, managing to summon a genuine-looking smile for a moment. "Do they take well to strangers around here?"

"You aren't a stranger," Harry laughed, tugging him along, "You're with me."

Archie looked like he wasn't sure what to say to that, but he followed her to Kyprioth Court nevertheless. He seemed to relax into the idea the longer they walked, and by the time they approached the Dancing Phoenix Archie seemed almost excited at the prospect.

"What kind of food do they have here?" he asked, rubbing his stomach exaggeratedly, "I'm starved."

"Solom makes the best shepherd's pie," Harry bragged as they ducked through the front door, "And since it's cold out he'll probably have lamb stew on today—it's to die for."

"Ain't a one died on me yet, though," Solom called from where he was wiping down a table by the stairs.

"He says," Rispah, sitting with her feet up in a chair before the fire, laughed softly.

They seemed to be the only people about at the moment, so Harry waved a greeting to Solom, then steered Archie to the table closest to where Rispah was sitting and said, "Sit. I'll put our orders in to the kitchen staff." No sense in making one of the serving boys traipse all the way out to the dining area when it was just them. "Rispah, this is my cousin Archie. Archie, this is Rispah, Lady of the Rogue."

"You didn't tell me you had a brother, Harry," the older woman said, setting a cup of something hot aside.

"He's not my brother," Harry said, shaking her head amusedly as she ambled out of the room.

She saw Rispah gracefully gain her feet and saunter over to Archie's table. She wondered if it was okay to leave Archie alone for a moment, then mentally shrugged—he'd be fine. Rispah was perfectly nice.

She chatted with a few of the cooks she'd grown familiar with over the summer, then collected a couple cups of milk and headed back to the dining room. She had to hold back a snort when she saw Archie sitting several feet closer to the end of the bench than when she'd left him. Rispah was sitting beside him, leaning on the table in a way that angled her body almost threateningly toward her poor cousin. It didn't help that Rispah, despite the winter chill, wore a supremely flattering but barely-there bodice that caught the eye with dozens of carefully embroidered sequins half-hidden among the laces.

"I hope you're playing nice, Rispah," Harry said, taking a seat across from them.

"She's not," Archie said, clearing his throat in the general direction of the tabletop.

Rispah chuckled, low and calculated, "This is nice, lad."

"My name's Archie," her cousin sighed, "Harry, I don't think your friends like me."

Harry was startled into a laugh at Archie's bald statement. "You've only met the one so far, and I'm sure Rispah's just teasing you. She likes most people."

"I don't either," Rispah smiled, shaking her pretty head of curls ruefully, "But I make exceptions for Leo's friends. And I suppose friends of Leo's friends—if they're nice to me." She said the last with a smile that Harry thought should be put on a list somewhere for unexpectedly lethal things. "What brings you and your friend this way today, Harry?"

"We're picking up an item I ordered later, so I thought we'd lunch here," Harry said, not too concerned with whatever was provoking Rispah's slight hostility. She probably just needed to get to know Archie. "I wanted Archie to see where I spend so much time, too. The Phoenix was sort of my home away from home last summer."

"I thought she was holed up in the Guild all those afternoons," Archie put in, looking determined to participate.

"How do you feel, knowing Harry was here, with us?" Rispah asked. Her voice seemed just a tad too sweet, and Harry wondered if Rispah was actually feeling defensive for a moment. She tried to see Archie from an outsider's perspective. His winter robes were finely made, the silver chain of a watch dangling from one pocket. His face, like hers, was aristocratically cast, for all its somewhat odd androgyny. He looked like a young Lord, from his carefully arranged hair to his upscale shoes, and Harry wondered how she hadn't realized he'd stick out. She'd just grown so comfortable in the lower alleys, she forgot sometimes that other purebloods usually didn't trespass these streets, and generally weren't welcomed anyway.

"I feel I ought to have guessed," Archie said, smiling in an unconsciously affable way, "I mean, Harry was always the adventurous one when we were kids. If anyone could find a gem like this in all these twists and turns, it'd be him. I'd have gotten hopelessly lost."

Rispah looked intrigued despite herself, "You two grew up together?"

"Of course," Archie said, grinning, "Harry really hasn't mentioned me? I'm wounded. We're cousins, but we grew up closer than siblings—it's like he's ashamed of me!"

"I am," Harry said, completely deadpan.

"Cousins?" Something in Rispah's face relaxed minutely.

"Of a sort," Harry shrugged, "Our families are very close. And we are related a couple of generations back."

"It's like that in most of the old families, I hear," Rispah said, gazing at Archie shrewdly.

"Some more than others," Archie said, a bit of embarrassment creeping into his voice, "My family is infamous for interbreeding. And lunacy. And those things probably aren't related if you ask my grandmother's portrait."

Rispah let out a full-throated laugh. "Does anyone ask her?"

"Actually, we put her in the attic," Archie said, ducking his head as though ashamed, "There's just no respect for the elders anymore."

Rispah laughed again, this time slapping her skirts heartily. "Aye, you'll do fine here, lad."

"Course he will," Harry said, smirking a bit, "He's related to me."

"You fit in too well here," Rispah said, flicking her curls and pinning her with a serious look, "It's not safe here in the alleys of late."

"You mean the raids?" Harry asked, sobering quickly.

"Raids are just the Ministry's way of pretending their law means anything down here," Rispah said, leaning closer, "It's the reaction to the raids that's the problem. Folk are getting restless. Angry. Shopkeepers are growing bitter over all the disruptions, threatening to take their business underground. The vampire covens are organizing. And Leo hasn't been getting challenges."

"Isn't that last one good?" Harry asked, frowning. If Leo wasn't being challenged for his title of King of Thieves, it must mean people were satisfied with the way he was running things.

Rispah shook her head. "There's always challenges, except when someone's plotting foul play. If no one's trying to take Leo's crown in the open, you can bet there's something sinister a foot behind closed doors."

"Like Claw?" Harry asked, blanching a bit.

"Mayhap," Rispah muttered, "Mayhap not. Difficult to tell. A lot of people are upset 'round here—one more might not attract the attention it ought."

"Is there anything we can do?" Harry asked, unconsciously including Archie as a matter of course.

"Be a little more careful than you usually would," Rispah advised, "Stay to the alleys you know, the ones close to the clinic or the Rogue. And don't traipse about after dark. Especially if you're gonna be traipsing with outsiders—no offense, young lad."

"None taken," Archie said, eyebrows raised. He didn't seem to know what to make of such a serious conversation. "How long until I'm…an insider?"

"Well, you'll have to meet Leo, first," Rispah said, smiling a little once more, "He's in charge of these parts."

"We've met," Archie said, scrunching up his face to remember, "I think…I was helping Harry with her crates, and—"

"Her?" Rispah broke across him sharply, turning to look at Harry with new eyes.

Harry's eyes cut to Archie's frozen, apologetic look. "I suppose it was bound to happen. It's not a big secret, really."

"You're a…" Rispah dissolved into a fit of laughter, clutching at her stomach as though trying to physically hold herself to the bench. "Oh, Goddess, that's a pretty trick, young miss! To think that I missed it—but you do look very boyish, Harry, if you'll forgive my saying so."

"It's true," Harry said, shrugging, "I look like my parents kidnapped Archie's twin and adopted him."

"Except you were born first," Archie pointed out, still looking very sheepish.

"Does Leo know?" Rispah was suddenly grinning like a cat with a mouthful of cream.

"He does," Harry admitted, sorry to disappoint the older woman. "I told him shortly after we met, in the interest of honesty."

Rispah nodded. "Good lad—lass, that is. Never lie to a King if you can help it."

"Easier to tell them to mind their own business," Harry agreed.

"What's he king of, again?" Archie asked, looking a little lost.

"Anything I want to be." Leo appeared from practically nowhere at the end of the table. She was sure she hadn't seen him walk through the front door.

Archie visibly twitched in response to her bright-eyed friend's sudden appearance. "That's rather convenient," he said after a moment.

"It's actually a lot of work," Leo said, not looking too torn up about it. He slid onto Harry's side of the bench, obliging her to move over or sit in awkward proximity to him. "Archie, right?"

"Good memory," Archie said, nodding amiably, "It's been a while."

"It's good practice for a King to remember the people he meets," Leo said, grinning wolfishly, "No matter how seemingly insignificant."

"No seeming about it," Archie said, not put off in the least. Her cousin could always rise to a conversational challenge. "I'm about as uninteresting as they come."

"Really?" Leo picked at one of his nails off-handedly, "I heard you kill basilisks in your free time."

Archie choked. "That was once," he protested, "And how do you even know?"

"I know everything," Leo said, "About everyone who steps foot in these alleys."

"That must take up a lot of your time," Archie said, nodding seriously, "Or do you employ spies?"

"Looking for a job?" Leo asked, head cocked in interest.

"Employment doesn't suit the men of my family," Archie said, leaning back in his chair with a relaxed grin, "But we do enjoy a number of eccentric hobbies."

"Maybe I'll make an ear out of you," Leo said, grinning now, "I always need more in the upper echelons of the social crop."

"A friend of Harry's is a friend of mine," Archie said.

"Likewise," Leo smirked.

Harry honestly couldn't tell if they were serious or not. "Now that we're all friends…" Harry trailed off as a serving boy came trotting out from the kitchens with she and Archie's lunch. She pulled out of a couple of coins and tossed them his direction, smoothly pushing Archie's bowl to his side of the table. "How have you been, Leo? Your last letter seemed a bit rushed."

"Lots to do before the snows get bad," Leo shrugged, gesturing to the large stack of pallets stacked neatly on the far side of the large dining room. He stole her cup and sniffed at its contents before wrinkling his nose. "Milk, again?"

"It's good for you," Archie and Harry said simultaneously.

Leo and Rispah laughed. "Now we know you two are related," Rispah said.

"Lots of people drink milk," Harry rolled her eyes.

"Not around here," Leo informed her, "Ale keeps you warmer."

"So do warming charms," Harry said.

"Too many squibs," Rispah said bluntly, "Ale's easier."

There was a moment of silence, in which Harry felt like an utter cad. Archie cleared his throat uncomfortably. "Do you need blankets, or…" he seemed at a loss for what to say.

"We can take care of our own, young Mr. Black." Leo tipped an imaginary hat. "I thank you though. There's not many would even offer."

Archie shrugged in a way that was grace and humility combined. "Well I'm around, if circumstances change."

"I know where to find you," Leo said, nodding agreeably.

Harry was certain that he did, however uneasy that might make her.

"You going to be around for training this holiday?" Leo asked Harry after a few minutes of letting her and Archie eat.

Harry swallowed. "Sure. Do you have time though?"

"Some afternoons are good," Leo said.

"Some afternoons it is," Harry smiled, "Should I bring a knife?"

Archie noticeably refrained from choking again.

"Do you have a knife?" Leo laughed, "No, don't bother—those cleavers you keep in your potions kit don't hardly count."

Harry tilted her head, "They do well enough for their purpose."

"Don't we all?" Rispah said, tracing a small ring idly on the wooden tabletop, "Don't we all."

They lapsed into pensive silence after that, finishing up their lunches quickly. Leo ambled off to talk to Solom about some 'court business,' and Rispah spent the rest of the meal casually trying to make Archie blush. She was well into her eighth or so pose, this one an artful lounge back on her hands that thrust her chest out rather coquettishly, when Harry stood. "We should be getting back to Frein's," she said, "It's a long walk there."

"It was nice to meet you, Lady Rispah," Archie said, even managing to sound sincere despite how utterly nonplussed he must be after her obvious attempts to fluster him.

Rispah sighed playfully. "One thing to say about you nobles—I do like your manners."

"See you around, my lady," Harry grinned, bowing in a movement that was echoed by Archie not half a beat later on their way out.

"I hope so, little lass," Rispah chuckled low, "The alleys could use a player like you."

Harry was sure that the alleys had plenty of players already, and said so. Rispah only smiled enigmatically, giving a little wave as the door swung shut behind them.

"Your friends are…interesting, Harry," Archie said after they'd walked a short distance.

"You've met Marek," Harry said, "What did you expect?"

"I'd somehow convinced myself he was the exception," Archie said.

"They're great, once they warm up to you," Harry promised.

"I somehow doubt I'll spend enough time here to merit it," Archie said, "But I suppose it's nice to have goals in life."

"I don't think we need anymore goals," Harry said, "The last time we got ambitious things sort of spiraled out of control."

"I don't know." Archie pretended to think. "You think we've lost control?"

"If we haven't, I'd like to see what out of control really looks like," Harry huffed.

"Careful what you wish for," Archie teased.

As they made their way through thinly-disguised slums to pick up a ring that would re-suppress the majority of her magic, Harry rather thought that advice was a bit overdue.

It was a few days before Yule that Archie received a letter from Ron Weasley, quietly begging Rigel to come to the Burrow for an afternoon visit. After a brief discussion with Archie over whether it would be better to decline or for Archie to try and be Harry all day at home, they settled on an ingenious alternative.

Archie sent a letter accepting Ron's invitation, but inquiring if it would be all right if Rigel brought his cousin Harry to visit, as well. It would be a test run, of sorts, for the New Year's gala. If Archie could pull off being Rigel around the Weasleys, several of whom knew Rigel's personality fairly well, he could probably skate through the gala all right.

The weather was foul that day, rain sleeting down into slush that collected on the windowsills, so after securing permission from their parents to go, she and Archie bundled up in their warmest cloaks, bringing along gloves and scarves on the off chance the Weasleys wanted to go outside.

Before they left, Harry had one more thing to do. She ducked into the downstairs bathroom and eyed her hair in the mirror. It was exactly the same cut and style as Archie's, usually, but she felt as long as they were intending to lead people's thoughts, Harry's hair ought to be at least nominally different. It would draw attention away from their similarities, and give people and easy feature to fix on when deciding which was which.

She very carefully put a tiny amount of power into a hair-growth charm, waving her wand back and forth over her head until the ends began inching slowly toward her ears, avoiding her bangs completely. She knew the trick was to go slowly, if you wanted the hair to appear at least semi-healthy, so she bit back her impatience and kept up her concentration as her locks crawled downwards. She grew it out several inches until, instead of resembling an unruly halo, her hair curled up under her chin in a restless bob.

She looked incredibly tousled, she thought critically, fingering the waves that always prevented her tresses from lying flat. The extra hair framed her face effectively, though, further disguising the uncanny similarity to Archie's features. It would be enough, she decided, to differentiate them in her friends' eyes.

Archie blinked when she emerged, tilting his head like a bird who'd come across a new species that might not be entirely friendly. "You look like a girl. Sort of."

"Now you know what you'd look like with long hair," Harry smiled.

Archie laughed. "I already know what I look like with long hair—it was one of the first things I tried."

"Of course it was." Harry rolled her eyes. "Are you ready to go?"

"Yes," Archie said. A determined look crept into his eyes.

"Run through them again," Harry prompted.

"Arthur, dad, works at the Ministry in the Misuse of Muggle Artifacts office," Archie said, ticking a finger, "Molly, mom, housewife with an impressive tolerance for chaos. Bill, the eldest, works at Gringotts in the curse-breaker division and he's the one who came to Hogwarts after that goblin attacked you—me."

"And he's the one we have to convince the most with our act," Harry put in, "He knows Harry from the lower alleys, and he thinks Rigel might be Harry, which we need to change."

"Even though technically he's right," Archie teased.

"Especially because technically he's right," Harry said, "I'll reveal myself as Harry, throwing the suspicion off of you."

"Right." Archie nodded, beginning his ticking of fingers once more. "Charlie is the one I haven't met, and he works with dragons in Romania. Percy is a seventh year, wants to be a barrister, and helps me with Transfiguration study. He's also Head Boy. The twins are Fred and George, fifth years, pranksters and all around jokers. They swap identities a lot so I shouldn't directly address one of them if I'm not sure which is which. Ron is in my year, in the Defense club with me, has a rivalry with Pansy, has a good mind for puzzles and is best friends with Neville Longbottom. Ginny is a second-year, very short tempered, rather sharp tongued, and she's the one who got possessed last year."

"Which you should never ever mention," Harry said.

"Which I should never ever mention," Archie agreed, "Is that everything?"

"I think so," Harry said, "Just be really polite to Mrs. Weasley, don't get upset at anything Ginny says, even if it seems confrontational, be sure to defend Percy if he gets ribbed too much, and don't let the twins bulldoze you in a conversation."

"And avoid talking to Bill," Archie added.

Harry smirked. "Yes. Leave William Weasley to me."

"Should I be worried for him?" Archie raised his eyebrows at what was probably a predatory look on her face.

"Worry about yourself, cuz," Harry said lightly, "This is your dress rehearsal, and I will be watching closely."

"It'll be like looking in a mirror," he promised, stilling his normally expressive features with eerie ease. "After all, I am the real Rigel Black."

"Keep telling yourself that." Harry ushered him toward the floo. "I might even start to believe it."

Archie flooed through first, leaving Harry to rather predictably stumble through the grate after him. She really hated the floo. She blinked the soot from her eyes and looked up to see a familiar gaggle of redheads staring curiously in her direction. She affected a nervous, harmlessly distant look in place of the fond smile that fought to grace her lips.

"This is my cousin, Harry," Archie said, waving a casual hand her direction.

"It's nice to meet all of you," Harry said, stepping forward to address Mr. and Mrs. Weasley in particular. "Thank you very much for having me over."

"What manners," Mrs. Weasley sighed happily.

"We're very glad to have you," Mr. Weasley added.

"Harry was bored stiff at home," Archie put in, looking sympathetic, "Poor thing doesn't have any friends, and I couldn't just leave her there to collect dust in the library."

Harry's eye twitched, but before she could defend herself Mrs. Weasley bustled forward to engulf her in a warm hug.

"Poor dear." The housewitch patted her head gently. "I suppose all your school mates are in America?"

"Uh, yes," Harry mumbled into the other woman's shoulder.

"Well, my boys are very friendly, and I'm sure Ginny would love to make a new female friend," she said, smiling as though she truly believed it. Harry saw Ginny roll her eyes over Mrs. Weasley's shoulder.

"Oh yes, very friendly," Ron coughed after beat of silence and a stern look from his mother.

"I'm sure they are, Ma'am," Harry said, "Is this everyone?"

She knew it wasn't. At the kitchen table sat Mr. Weasley, Ginny, Percy, and Ron. The eldest two were presumably working, and the twins were nowhere to be seen. She tried not to read anything ominous into that observation.

"Oh, no, just my two youngest and Percy, our Head Boy," Mrs. Weasley said, beaming fondly at said boy as she made her way back to the table, where Harry could see she'd been darning a pair of thick winter socks. "Come to think of it, where are the—"

"Missing us, Mum?"

"We've only been gone five minutes."

The Weasley twins slunk into the kitchen with all the air of people who were trying very hard to appear completely innocuous.

"What have you done?" Mrs. Weasley frowned suspiciously.

"Done?" Fred pretended to think about it. "Nothing terribly interesting."

"In the last five minutes, anyway," George grinned.

"These are my two fifth-years," Mrs. Weasley sighed.

They turned as one to where Harry and Archie stood closer to the fireplace.

"Hey Rigel—woah." They swiveled heads of red hair back and forth between she and Archie with slightly awed expressions.

"Rigel," George said, turning a serious expression toward Archie, "How in Merlin's name—"

"—did you forget to mention—"

"—that you had a twin!"

Harry was surrounded by overly curious fifteen-year-olds before she knew what had happened. Hands poked at her face and ruffled her hair experimentally as Fred and George fired rapid questions over her head excitedly.

"It's a girl Rigel!"

"She's even got the same chin—"

"—and the same unimpressed expression!"

"How cute," they sighed simultaneously.

"She's not my twin," Archie said, long-suffering, "She's my cousin, Harry Potter, and stop poking her, please. She's easily provoked."

Harry snapped playfully at the nearest twin's freckled finger.

"Woah, this one bites!" Fred said, cowering behind his twin.

"Can we keep it?" George asked Archie, widening his blue eyes in a desperate plea.

"She's mine," Archie said firmly, "Don't you have enough toys, anyway?" He gestured to Ron and Ginny with an idle smirk.

"But we want a new one," Fred pouted.

"I think I'm offended," Ginny frowned.

"You're always offended," Ron informed her.

"Fred. George. Stop intimidating our guest," Mrs. Weasley snapped, "Honestly. First young lady we've had over in ages and you two can't help but traumatize her."

"She doesn't look traumatized," George said, peering into Harry's blank expression curiously.

"Not like that girl Charlie brought last holiday, anyway," Fred put in.

"The one whose eyebrows you lengthened into curtains?" Mrs. Weasley scowled.

"We were doing her a favor," Fred shrugged, unconcerned, "Poor thing had plucked them nearly all away."

"She never did come back," Mrs. Weasley said, looking disappointed now, "What fine young babies they might have had."

"Mum," five mortified voices echoed around the kitchen.

"A mother can dream," Mrs. Weasley sniffed.

"Anyway…" Fred said, intentionally awkward, "Rigel, we've got a surprise for you—come see?"

Archie grinned, but she could tell he was restraining it to match Harry's personality as best he could. "Sure. Ron, do you want to…?"

"Better not," Ron grimaced, "I'll catch up with you in a bit."

"Great." George took Archie's arm and towed him off into another room. Soon footsteps sounded on the stairs and Fred waved a goodbye to the general assembly, adding, "Nice to meet you, girl-Rigel," as he followed the other two.

"Don't blow anything up," Mr. Weasley muttered. Harry waited for the others to laugh, but apparently the man wasn't joking.

"So, Head Boy? That's very impressive," Harry said, smiling in what she hoped was a friendly way as she stood there, unsure what to do. "There's only one Head Boy for the whole school, right?"

Percy nodded, his ears a little pink. "That's right. Do you have prefects and the like at your American school?"

Harry shook her head. "Not exactly. They separate us into tracts, and each tract has upperclassmen that act as monitors. Their duties include things like making sure the younger students don't get too out of line, checking the dorms after curfew, and tutoring those who need help. They have no authority outside of their own tract, though, so as a Healing tract student I wouldn't have to heed a monitor from the Charms tract, for example."

"Interesting." Percy adjusted his glasses and waved her over to the seat next to him. "So there's no one that represents the whole student body like a Head Boy or Girl would?"

"No," Harry said, "But school unity in general is different at AIM than it is at Hogwarts, I think. The tracts mostly keep to themselves, even in the general classes, and there's no inter-tract rivalries or anything, so a student that represents the whole school wouldn't have much to do, I think."

"No Quidditch, right?" Ron asked, looking sad for her.

"There's a sort of pickup league of intramural teams." Harry shrugged. "But they don't draw a big crowd, and they aren't affiliated with any particular tract."

"What do you do for fun, then?" Ron frowned.

"Same things that students who don't play Quidditch at Hogwarts do, I guess," Harry said, smiling a bit. "We hang out with our friends, go to club meetings, or work on extracurricular projects."

"I'm in a Defense club," Ron said, perking up, "With Rigel."

"I heard," Harry said, "How's it going? That Malfoy kid is leading it, right?"

"I guess," Ron said, avoiding the odd look his parents were giving him. Maybe he hadn't mentioned that most of the members were Slytherins so far.

"Rigel says you're really good at strategizing," Harry offered, "Did you learn that, or is it a natural gift?"

Ginny snorted, "Oh it's definitely unnatural. Ron's a wiz at chess—kicks even dad's butt all over the board, and has since he was about eight."

"Not my game, chess," Mr. Weasley said mildly, perusing a magazine article rather absently.

"Have you ever entered a tournament?" Harry asked, "My uncle, Remus, entered one last year and almost won. He lost to this hundred year old vampire, who I guess had been studying the game for several decades at that point."

"Professor Lupin?" Ron blinked a bit. "I didn't know he played."

"He's got a prodigious mind," Harry said, "He just hides it behind mild mannerisms. How are classes with him?"

"Terrifying," Ginny said flatly, "Your uncle is a sadist."

"That's true," Harry agreed easily, startling a laugh out of the other girl. "It part of what makes him a great teacher. He's not afraid to be cruel to be kind, you know? He'll push you when even you don't really want to keep going."

"He is a great Defense teacher," Ron said, "I've got him for Dueling, too—wicked fast with a wand, he is."

"He was a prefect when he went to Hogwarts," Harry said, "Even got an honorable mention on his Defense NEWT, I think."

"He went to Hogwarts?" Percy frowned, "But he's…"

"That was back when they allowed Halfbloods," Mr. Weasley said sharply, "And before Mr. Lupin's condition was more or less public knowledge."

There was a moment of silence before Ginny said, "Do you wish you could have gone to Hogwarts, Harriet?"

"Just Harry is fine," she said, smiling despite the somewhat rude nature of the question. Ginny was always refreshing, at least. "And yes, sometimes I do. The Healing tract at AIM is wonderful, as are the facilities and a lot of other things, but to be honest our Potions Master isn't much to write home about. Potions are sort of a passion of mind, so I envy Rigel being able to study under Master Snape—he's the best, right now."

"You wish you could come to Hogwarts…to study under Professor Snape?" Ron looked like he was trying to paste a polite expression over a horrified one, but failing.

Harry nodded, hiding her amusement. "Oh, yes. You're so lucky to have access to such a renowned expert in the field. A lot of places have reputable Charms or Transfiguration Masters, but truly excellent potions professors are few and far between, even at the major schools."

"Why is that?" Percy asked, looking perplexed, "There are a number of very well-known Potions Masters throughout Europe, after all. They're not like Defense Masters, who are rather hard to come by."

"The talented Potions Masters don't become professors," Mr. Weasley said knowledgably, "There's more esteem to be had working directly for a guild, or going the inventor's route and selling your own line of potions. More gold, too. Spell crafters rarely patent a spell with any success—it's just too easy to pass on the incantation, so those talented at wand work often go into teaching instead. Potion-makers can charge exorbitant fees for crafting and brewing difficult potions, though. Too many regular witches and wizards never bother to learn the art properly."

"That's right," Harry said, glad to see that others appreciated how important potion-brewing really was to society, "Master Snape is a rare exception—someone who contributes inestimable amounts of research to the field while also passing on his expertise to the next generation. He's really admirable."

"Admirable," Ron repeated, looking very dubious, "Right."

"I never realized." Percy, on the other hand, looked very impressed with his Potions professor. "I shall have to take better advantage of his expertise in the future."

"I'm sure he'll appreciate that," Harry lied, smiling. Professor Snape did deserve to be thanked and appreciated for his work, whatever noises he made to the contrary.

"So if you and Rigel are both obsessed with potions, do you, like, spend all your holidays locked in a dimly-lit lab together, sweating over a pair or putrid cauldrons, or what?" Ginny was really looking for a button to push, Harry noted with a bit of amusement.

Undeterred, Harry tilted her head, "Only if mom doesn't let us open a window."

Ron laughed. "Good one. Leave her alone, Ginny. She seems nice."

"No such thing," Ginny said, leaning back in her chair.

"You wouldn't say that if you met my friend, Hermione Granger," Harry said, "She's the nicest person in the whole world."

"Never heard of her," Ginny said, one eyebrow raised, "She from America?"

"No, she's British. Muggleborn."

"And winner of planet-wide nice awards, huh?" Ginny didn't seem terribly convinced.

"That's right," Harry said. Ron snorted. "She's also a genius," she added, smiling.

"You're making her up," Ginny guessed, "No one is smart and nice. What's the point?"

"Why was I cursed with such cynical children?" Mrs. Weasley quietly despaired.

"Hermione would say that intelligent people have more responsibility to the people around them, not less," Harry said.

"She sounds like a lovely young lady," Mr. Weasley said, nodding in approval.

"Maybe you'll meet her one day, Mr. Weasley," Harry said, "I think she's going to do great things."

"Talking about your one friend again?" Archie and the twins came bounding back into the room.

"Hermione's worth all of your Slytherin friends put together," Harry said, quoting something Archie had once said to her. "Why do you look like you've been breaking into your dad's coffee cabinet again?" Harry added, eyeing his jubilant posture.

Archie noticeably stilled, laughing a bit sheepishly. "I only had a few cups this morning. I think I lost all my tolerance for the stuff when I went to Hogwarts—they don't serve it to us kids there." Harry refrained from nodding in approval, but it was times like these she appreciated how quick Archie was on the uptake. Now any excess energy on Archie's behalf could be attributed to caffeine. "Besides, you should have seen what Fred and George came up with this time. It's amazing, Harry, even our dads would freak."

As Fred and George preened under the praise, Harry held up a hand. "Plausible deniability. I know want to know."

"It's like she knows us," Fred stage whispered, looking awed.

"Didn't you know?" Harry blinked as innocently as she could, "Rigel tells me everything. Poor kid just can't keep a secret."

Fred was not the only one to smother incredulous laughter at that.

"Why don't you kids go outside for a bit," Mr. Weasley suggested. "It's stopped sleeting, by the sound of it."

"It's cold," Ginny complained, even while she trudged over to the kitchen door to pull on a pair of somewhat oversized boots.

"Too cold for the brooms," Ron agreed, also reaching for a coat from one of the many hooks by the window.

"Ice skating!" Fred and George crowed, racing each other to a cupboard under the coat rack that seemed overflowing with shoes of every different kind.

"We didn't bring our skates," Harry said, apologetic.

Ron laughed. "That's okay. Mum can make them."

Sure enough, Ginny was presenting her booted feet to her mother's wand, which twitched in a comfortable pattern almost lazily, as though she'd done such a thing countless times before. Twin blades of ice sprouted along their soles, curling elegantly at each end.

"What do you guys do?" Ginny asked, taking in her and Archie's impressed looks.

"We have a pair of never-melting skates from about a hundred years ago," Archie said, "They look like something out of a historical play, but they work all right. We just take turns."

"They smell like uncle Sirius' feet, though," Harry said, wrinkling her nose, "For some reason he never wore socks as a child."

Mr. Weasley's eyebrows rose at that statement. "I'm not sure Lord Black would want you telling us that."

"Dad would freely admit to it," Archie said, grinning, "He thinks embarrassing stories are the best kind."

"Sounds like a Marauder to me," Fred said.

"Your family sounds awesome," George agreed.

"I think your family is awesome," Archie said, smiling genuinely, "Besides, you haven't heard about all of them—Aunt Lily is down right terrifying."

"She isn't either," Mrs. Weasley tutted.

"Do you know my mother?" Harry asked, curious. Lily hadn't really mentioned Mrs. Weasley, except in passing relation to the Weasleys as an example of good, wholesome light-leaning wizard stock.

"I see her at Dumbledore's little soirée in the spring, most years," Mrs. Weasley said, referring to a gathering of Light politicking wizards who usually met around the Easter holiday. "Not last year, of course, with her being on home rest with her newborn. Ooh, I can't wait to meet little Adriana at the next one. I do adore babies. How's she coming along? Healthy?"

"Very," Harry said, "She's a lot like my mom, actually. Red curls and somewhat easily exasperated."

"Harry just says that because Addy hates her," Archie gloated.

Harry ignored the jab, taking her turn in front of Mrs. Weasley instead of answering, holding each of her booted feet up in turn.

"Who could hate our Harry?" George asked, coming up behind her to pat her head consolingly, "She's like a cuddlier version of Rigel."

"You've known me about ten minutes," Harry said, flicking his hand away, "And if you try to cuddle me, I'll give you an extra toe. On your face."

"Promise?" Fred waggled his brows.

"Boys." Mrs. Weasley glared.

The twins headed out into the backyard, Ginny and Ron following. Archie's skates were almost finished, but Percy made no move to stand. At Harry's questioning look, the older boy cleared his throat uncomfortably, saying, "I don't skate."

"We'll see you when we get back, then," Harry said, trying another friendly smile.

"Thanks for the skates, Mrs. Weasley," Archie said, admiring his new blades, "That's a wicked cool charm."

"It'll only last a couple of hours," Mrs. Weasley said, "After that come on back inside and I'll have cocoa waiting."

With heartfelt thanks, they followed the Weasley children out into the cold. It was very awkward tiptoeing across the big backyard on blades of magic, but the sounds of whooping and laughing egged them on toward the pond. The ground sloped downward toward the water's edge, and while Harry carefully picked her way along the incline, Archie impulsively dropped to his bottom and slid the rest of the way, sprawling onto the ice with a carefree cry of warning to the others.

"Rigel!" Ron cursed and spun away from a collision with the black-haired boy.

"Sorry!" Archie called as he slid past, his momentum carrying him close to the center of the little pond before friction reeled him to a stop. "That was more graceful in my head."

"Story of his life," Harry remarked to Ginny, who had stopped at the bank to readjust her laces.

"You wouldn't know it, with how he's perceived at Hogwarts," Ginny told her. Her eyes followed Archie's relaxed form as it stumbled upright and set off on a circuit with confident glides. "I almost never see him this relaxed at school. He's just another calm, collected Slytherin, there."

"Rigel is many things to many people," Harry said, turning to watch her cousin as well. "Sometimes he's the perfect pureblood Heir of Black. Sometimes he's the potions prodigy, other times an amateur healer. Sometimes he's a Marauder, other times a studious shut-in. But these times, when he's just himself—they're rare."

"Why so many different faces?" Ginny asked, equal parts curious and confused.

"I think of it more as his different potentials," Harry said, "They're all a true reflection of what he could be. Rigel hasn't settled into a single path yet."

"Maybe he has, and just doesn't know it," Ginny said.

"I don't think so." Harry smiled slightly. "When Rigel Black chooses a path, the whole world will know it."

"You think a lot of him," Ginny remarked, slanting her eyes toward Harry even as her face stayed facing the pond.

"He's my brother in all but blood." Harry shrugged, sticking her hands in her cloak pockets and pushing off on one skate gently. Looking back she tilted her head at Ginny inquiringly. "It's a sister's job to expect a lot of our brothers, isn't it?"

Ginny followed, catching up easily and falling into a lazy glide beside her. "I think I had high expectations of my brothers once," the redhead said, putting on a moue of sardonic contemplation, "I can't remember much besides a crushing sense of disillusionment, though."

"If you were really disillusioned, you'd be inside with Percy," Harry pointed out.

Ginny glanced over sharply at her words, long fiery strands crossing her face in the breeze. "That's a very good observation, for having known us all of twenty minutes," Ginny said. Her tone wasn't suspicious, exactly. More testing.

"Some things are easier for an outsider to see," Harry said, looking away on the pretext of watching her footwork.

"You remind me of Rigel," Ginny sighed, stretching her arms out as they turned to follow the rounded edges of the pond.

"We did grow up together," Harry smiled, "You'd be surprised how many of our mannerisms are shared."

"Like an innate ability to deflect questions?" Ginny's grin was edged.

"Sure," Harry laughed, "But I was more talking about things like our competitive spirit—want to race?"

Ginny's smile turned feral. "Three laps around the circumference starting—go!"

Harry, easily anticipating the redhead's underhanded move, didn't even blink as she burst ahead. She was too busy pumping her own legs across the ice as fast as she safely could to rib the other girl for lack of sportsmanship anyway.

They flew over the frozen water, waving the three Weasley brothers and Archie out of their way as their rhythms settled in and their strokes evened out. Harry's world narrowed to the ice in front of her and the flash of red in her periphery that marked Ginny's position in relation to her own. Ginny claimed the inside curve, but Harry simply leaned further into the turns to compensate, building as much momentum as she could through the arc so that she rocketed like a sling-shot into the straightaways. Her thighs were burning and her toes aching at being dug into the ice like picks at every corner, but she barreled into the third lap with a huge grin across her face. Racing was something she and Archie had never been able to do with only one pair of skates. It wasn't quite like flying on a broom, but it was much more physically satisfying, she thought. Like a foot race, only faster.

The twins had set up a makeshift finish line using one of their knitted scarves held between them. Ron and Archie cheered good-naturedly from the sidelines. She could hear Ginny's breath beginning to come in fast pants, but weeks of running in the cold winter air had conditioned her lungs to its thinness, and Harry pushed forward even faster, using her hard-earned muscles to pull away from her opponent in the final stretch. She lifted her hands triumphantly as she crossed the 'finish line,' expecting one of the twins to let go as she approached the stretched out scarf.

Why she expected such a reasonable thing to occur, she didn't know. It must have been the exertion making her loopy, because in retrospect it was perfectly obvious that the twins were never planning on letting go of the scarf as she hit it.

Instead, they held tight to the ends, using the transferred momentum of her impact to swing themselves in a circle around her, just barely avoiding a collision and managing to completely entangle her in the knitted fabric. She landed on her butt, squirming uselessly as she slid across the ice like a punch-drunk, color-blind mummy.

The others roared with laughter, and she could see at least Ron was having trouble staying upright as he cackled, clutching Archie's arm for balance as he pressed his other hand to his ribs. Ginny slid to a stop near where Harry had stopped, sending chips of ice all across her legs. "Should have ducked under the scarf," the younger girl said sagely.

"I see what you mean about disillusioned expectations," Harry mumbled through a mouthful of soft knit.

Ginny bent down and grabbed one end of the scarf with a mischievous smile. Before Harry could beg her not to, she'd yanked with all her might and sent Harry rolling across the ice toward the bank, unraveling from the scarf as she went.

She slid to a stop on her back, blinking up at Archie, who was grinning down at her with a brilliant twinkle in his grey eyes. "All right there, cuz?"

"You said your friends were nice," Harry complained, climbing to her feet with the help of Ron's hand and dusting herself off fastidiously.

"I didn't, actually," Archie said, "Mrs. Weasley is the one who said her kids were nice."

"Mum lies a lot," Ron said, only looking vaguely apologetic.

Harry let out a low laugh as she shook the ice from her hair. "At least there's honesty about the lying, I guess."

"Not until it's too late to turn back, though," George commented, gliding over with his reclaimed scarf tied around his waist in deference to its icy wetness.

"Now that you're one of us, though, cat's out of the bag," Fred added, ruffling a few more ice chips from her bangs helpfully.

"Or at least in a different, slightly less opaque-y bag," George mused.

"Still beats sitting at home, right?" Archie asked, nudging her ribs good-naturedly.

Harry nodded, still smiling. "Of course. This is a lot of fun, actually. Makes me wish there'd been more of us, growing up."

"Neither of our houses would still be standing, were that the case," Archie said, "And anyway, that's what friends are for, right guys?"

"Thanks again for having us over," Harry said, looking around at the four Weasleys with earnest enjoyment in her expression.

"Thanks for coming on such short notice," Ron said, his smile slipping a bit. "You might not believe it, but things were pretty down around here this morning."

"What's up?" Archie asked, adopting a more intent expression that, in Harry's opinion, put his face much closer to Rigel's usual demeanor.

"Our brother Charlie just found out he can't come home for the holidays after all," Fred said, disappointment clear on his face.

"He works abroad, right?" Archie said, guessing, "Did his international floo license expire?"

George grimaced. "Nothing so harmless. A bunch of dragons escaped a reserve in northern France last night. All the dragon tamers that can be spared are being pulled from colonies across Europe and re-assigned to tracking them down and moving them back to the reserve before the muggles notice."

"How many escaped?" Harry asked, alarmed. A rouge dragon was a natural disaster in its own right, never mind more than one.

"Five," Ron said, looking a bit sick at the thought.

"Five," Archie breathed, completely taken aback.

"Maybe they didn't go far," Harry said, trying to brace the mood a bit, "Maybe they'll get them rounded up before Yule, and Charlie can make the second half of the holidays."

"Or maybe they'll go on a rampage and cause a huge international incident and public outrage will turn on the dragon keepers and their families and we'll all be stoned in the streets," Ginny said, arms crossed as though to keep off the chill.

"Or…that could happen," Archie said, struggling to maintain composure, "It's always good to have a clear idea of the worst case scenario, anyway."

Ginny snorted. "The worst case scenario is the dragons kills hundreds of muggles and expose our existence to the world and wizards get hunted into extinction—"

"Okay!" Fred clapped a gloved hand over Ginny's mouth with false cheer. "Don't mind her. Too many ghost stories as a child. Prejudiced her imagination rather negatively."

"Whose faul' is tha'?" Ginny mumbled through the glove, rolling her eyes.

Ron turned flat eyes on the twins, who exchanged wounded glances before bursting into laughter. "Yeah, it probably was our doing," Fred admitted.

"But Bill told us the stories first," George pointed out.

"And you turned out just fine?" Archie's tone made it clear he doubted the accuracy of that logic.

"So critical," Fred wrapped an arm around Archie's shoulders plaintively.

George followed suit on his other side. "Our pup just doesn't love us the way we love each other, brother mine."

"Thank Merlin for that," Ron muttered. He lifted a shoe to examine his skate. "We've only got forty minutes left on these, you guys. Let's skate."

Fred and George hefted Archie underneath his arms and hauled him bodily back onto the ice. Ron, Ginny, and Harry followed at a more sedate pace.

"Your cousin's a good sport with them," Ron said idly, "Most people only tolerate the twins until the first time they get pranked, and then it's all offended pride and how-could-you lectures."

"People think being a pair or pranksters' friend means they won't prank you?" Harry's eyebrows rose.

"I know, it's crazy," Ron said, huffing a laugh, "If anything it's the opposite."

"It's like that at our house," Harry said, smiling fondly, "The Marauders love to target people they love. Drives my mom crazy—she's always walking into a pie, it seems."

"She sounds very tolerant," Ginny remarked.

"I think she just feels very lucky," Harry said slowly, "Mom never takes anything for granted. She's got a temper like an avenging angel, but her heart is bigger than anything. She's secretly mischievous, anyway—some of the most memorable pranks around our houses are ones my mom came up with."

"Sounds like a good match," Ron offered.

"It is," Harry agreed.

"Maybe the twins will meet someone like your mom, then," Ginny said, flicking a sly glance Harry's direction before striding off toward the other side of the pond on her skates.

Harry tilted her head a bit, confused at what exactly the redhead was implying.

"Ignore her," Ron sighed, "I wish I could say it was you, but Ginny is always like that."

"She seems very forthright," Harry said, smiling, "It's not unpleasant. Only surprising, on occasion."

"I revise my earlier statement," Ron shook his head, shooting her a bewildered look. "You and your cousin are good sports. When Rigel said he wanted to bring a friend, I was worried, cause my family can be a bit much, but all my siblings seem to like you. Even Percy likes you, and he's aloof around new people at first."

Harry thought guiltily that it wasn't that difficult to get along with Ron's siblings after knowing them for two years. Archie was the one who had met everyone today and simply dived right into the friendships, no hesitation at all. Harry wasn't nearly that graceful in social situations. She somehow always came off either stiflingly polite or somewhat disinterested at first glance.

"I think it's just that your siblings are a lot like people I know at home or from my other school." Harry shrugged modestly. "And it helps that they're so great. I think it's wonderful how close you all are—strong sibling relationships are a rarity among wizarding families, in case you haven't noticed. Take my uncle—he never talks to his brother Regulus unless they meet unexpectedly at formal events. Sirius' cousins have a strained relationship as well: Narcissa Malfoy rarely converses long with her sister Bellatrix even at intimate social gatherings, and neither of them acknowledges their third sister exists at all without someone else bringing her up first. Then there are the Lestrange brothers; rumor is their animosity in the workplace is tearing their company apart from the inside."

"Really?" Ron's eyes were wide, "How do you know all this?"

"Some of it Rigel's mentioned," Harry said quickly, "And the rest is just stuff I picked up hearing Uncle Sirius complain about his relatives."

"I guess…" Ron's mouth twisted into a grimace, "Well, they aren't perfect, but I wouldn't trade 'em."

"You sure?" Harry teased, "I'd trade you Rigel if you give me Percy—I hear he's a Transfiguration wiz, and that's far and away my worst subject."

"You're just getting sick of looking at yourself all day," Ron said, a lopsided grin on his face, "Admit it."

"It is rather surreal." Harry wrinkled her nose a bit.

"Why do you look so similar?" Ron asked suddenly, ducking his head a bit as though afraid the question was going to inspire an offended response.

Harry instead pretended to a thoughtful expression, "We're not actually sure. Sirius thinks maybe…hey, don't spread this around too much, ok?"

Ron blinked, then nodded solemnly. She suppressed a smile, knowing that she had given him just enough leeway to tell a few select people, who would then go on to tell a few other people, until eventually the fact that the Black Heir had some kind of passive metamorphism would be the sort of common knowledge that everyone had but no one was sure how they knew.

Harry dithered ostensibly for a moment, then leaned close to say, "Sirius thinks Rigel inherited a kind of passive metamorphic ability from the Black side of his family. Rigel can't actually control his features or anything, but Sirius thinks maybe his magic is unconsciously shaping his appearance to mimic mine."

"Weird," Ron said, one eyebrow lifting, "I've heard of passive gifts before, but it's usually stuff like a natural Occlumency shield or an affinity for creatures. I think Neville might have a passive plant affinity, actually. A passive metamorphmagus, though…well, it's Family Magic, I guess, so anything is possible."

"Especially with a family like the Blacks," Harry said, nodding along, "So many of their ancestors were secretive types—what records they kept might not even be accurate, so there could be close to anything in their blood."

That was the story she and Archie had decided to roll with after his talk with Sirius. It worked, as long as they made it clear to people that Archie/Rigel had no actual ability to morph his features consciously. The innocence of the ruse hung on it being uncontrollable circumstance that the two of them looked so much alike.

They eventually joined the others in seeing who could do the most outlandish trick on the ice. The prize, a reverently plucked pinecone, went to Ron, who was just gearing up for an attempt at a two-handed toe grab when the ice disappeared from beneath his skates and he went sprawling arse over teakettle. He slid into an overhanging tree at the bank and came up with a face-full of slush and a very irritated squirrel who attempted to scalp him in retaliation for the disruption done to a certain acorn stash.

Cold, tired, but in good spirits, they all six sloshed back to the kitchen door and surrendered themselves to Mrs. Weasley's tender mercies. Cloaks, scarves, and gloves were whisked away to a drying rack while shoes were relegated to a place by the hearth in the den. Harry barely managed to keep her under-gloves on, hiding the suppressor ring from sight. Hot cocoa made the rounds, warming their fingers and stinging their numb lips as they huddled under afghans around the kitchen table.

Once they'd drained their mugs, Mrs. Weasley shooed them out of the kitchen so she could get started on dinner. At Archie's offer to help, the witch simply laughed and shooed him out all the quicker.

"Mum doesn't really trust us in the kitchen," Fred whispered conspiratorially.

"Can't imagine why," Ginny rolled her eyes, "You only blew up her favorite cauldron twice."

"After the first time it wasn't exactly her favorite anymore," George scoffed, "So that only counts once, I think."

"Once was enough," Ron said, grimacing in remembrance "Everything she cooked tasted like sulfur for a week."

"Oh, that was the week we put sulfur on your toothbrush, actually," Fred sniggered.

"Hardy-har," Ron sighed half-heartedly.

"What should we do now?" Archie said, turning the conversation toward more present difficulties.

"Is it okay with your parents if we keep you for dinner?" Fred asked, looking hopeful.

"Did we mention dinner?" Harry asked Archie; he'd been the one to ask permission, after all.

"I said we'd be home sometime later," Archie shrugged, "So I guess we could. If it's not too much trouble."

"Mum's already cooking extra," George guessed with a fond smile.

"She better be making extra dessert, too," Ginny said, shooting Harry a speculative look, "Harry looks like she eats a lot."

Ron, Fred, and George all choked. Harry looked down at herself, wondering if there was some sort of sign that said 'insert pie here' that she hadn't noticed Archie putting on her that morning. Archie just chuckled. "She really does," her cousin said.

"I'm a growing person," Harry said, only a bit defensive. She led a very active lifestyle, and that meant she had to pack away a certain amount of food to keep herself healthy.

"She kicked my butt in that race," Ginny said, still eyeing her frame speculatively, "I bet there's a serious amount of muscle under there."

Harry fought a blush. She wasn't used to people presuming to guess what was beneath her clothing—at least not to her face.

"Does she exercise with you, Rigel?" Ron asked, looking interested.

"More like I exercise with her," Archie said, looking a bit uncomfortable, "Harry trains with our Uncle Remus when she has time. She's the one who got me into, uh, physical activity, I guess you could say."

Harry fought a wince, and thanked the weather for being too cold to encourage dueling practice out on the lawn. The truth was, Archie had little to no conditioning, and no real Defense training at all. That was one glaring hole in their ruse that they simply hadn't had the time to correct yet.

"Play Quidditch, too?" Fred asked eagerly.

"Of course she does," Archie said, smirking, "She's a beater."

"Like you?" Ron said, surprised, "How do you play with just two beaters?"

"Well, we…hit the ball back and forth," Archie said, faltering a bit, "And at home I'm really more of a chaser, anyway. I just played beater on the House team last year because that was the open position."

"Rigel's a great Chaser," Harry said, picking up the thread of the story when Archie seemed inclined to trail off, "My dad plays chaser, too, and my uncle Sirius is our other beater. Mum and Remus play keeper when we do three-v-three in the summer. They taught us all the positions, though, to keep things interesting. You guys don't just stick to one position, right?"

"True," George said, "When Charlie's here he always gets seeker, but the rest of us like to mix it up now and again. Dad's a surprisingly good seeker, actually—very focused. Sometimes I think he forgets the rest of the game is even going on."

The others laughed, and a short silence fell over the den. "What were we going to do?" Ron asked, scratching his head.

"Let's go bother Percy!" Fred said, bouncing on his toes a bit, "He's already done all his holiday work, so he can't ban us from his room anymore."

"Because holidays are about family," George said, his tone that of someone misappropriating a quote for their own less than earnest purposes, "And family doesn't stay shut up in a room."

"Unless it's crazy Aunt Muriel," Ron said, "In which case, it stays locked up in a room."

"Was that you?" Fred affected a scandalized expression.

"You believed the story about the latch getting stuck?" Ginny's face was full of incredulous pity.

"Reminds you of home, doesn't it?" Archie asked sotto voce.

"It's sad how I used to think our family was unique," Harry said.

"But also comforting to know that we don't have the only patent on lunacy," Archie said, philosophically.

"Oh yes," Harry snorted, "There's nothing more comforting than more lunacy in the world."

"That's the spirit," Archie grinned. Raising his voice, he added, "So are we going to appropriate Percy's time, or what?"

With Fred and George leading they way, they traipsed up the stairs to Percy's room, the door to which was only very reluctantly opened after a long and convoluted argument through it. They all squeezed onto the floor between the bed and the bookcases, and eventually Percy produced a pack of exploding snap cards with a remark that since a certain level of chaos was inevitable at that point, he may as well control the outlet as best his could.

It was a merry hour later that Mrs. Weasley's resounding voice echoed up the stairs to draw them back down for supper.

The kitchen table had been transformed from a cluttered family workspace to a scene from one of her mother's Magical Mansions magazines. Matching plates were squeezed up and down its length end to end, with a few placed at the corners in front of stools. Cutlery was stacked somewhat elegantly on top of the plates, leaving all available room in the center of the table to be filled with food. Bowls of rolls and stacks of crackers with various spreads tucked into the nooks between. Beautiful spiral-cut ham sprawled on a platter, glazed with a maple sauce she could smell from the stairs. Carrots and yams fought for space beside green beans, mashed potatoes, and pitchers of berry-red juice.

Mrs. Weasley was bustling between the stove and the table, but Mr. Weasley was already seated at the head of the table next to a very relaxed-looking Bill Weasley.

"Grab a chair, everyone," Mrs. Weasley said over her shoulder, one hand on her wand and the other in an oven mitt. "The pie will be out any moment."

The Weasley twins grabbed Archie and hauled him between their seats on Bill's side of the table while Percy and Ginny exchanged knowing looks and seated themselves as far from the twins as possible on the other side. Ron claimed a corner stool for himself between Fred and the end chair that Mrs. Weasley likely used, leaving Harry to take the chair on Mr. Weasley's other side, next to Ginny and across from Bill.

Mr. Weasley, ever conscious of social proprieties, took the liberty of introducing her. "This is my eldest son, William. Son, this is Rigel's cousin, Harriett Potter. Rigel very thoughtfully brought her to visit this afternoon."

Bill looked much too perplexed to form a coherent sentence, merely nodding absently as his eyes roamed her features, flicked to Rigel down the table, then settled back on her with a frown. He lingered on the round lenses that adorned her nose, and she knew he recognized them as the ones Harry from the lower alleys wore. She could only imagine what he must be thinking—seeing her, looking like Harry but undeniably female, sitting there in his kitchen as a distinct yet similar entity from Rigel Black, unable to say anything because of the explanations that would be required to even begin to suss out the truth.

"It's very nice to meet you, Will," Harry said, allowing the tiniest of ironic smiles to bend itself in his direction.

"It's Bill," the young man said sharply. Clearing his throat, he eyed her somewhat intently. "Just Bill."

"My mistake." Harry allowed her eyes to crease apologetically. "You can call me Harry—everyone does."

His eyes widened almost imperceptivity, and she could see the moment he squashed a rush of panic and decided to pretend ignorance. Good. The best-case scenario would be him becoming so confused he decided to say nothing in order to hide his own lack of knowledge. "All right. Nice to meet you. You'd be James Potter's daughter, then?"

"That's right," Harry said, "His eldest."

Bill's head tilted curiously, sending his fang earring into a swinging motion that made it catch on a lock of shocking red hair. He idly untangled it as his mother piped up, "I just can't wait to meet the new baby," as she deposited the pie in the only semi-open space on the table and took her seat.

"Boy or girl?" Bill asked, pouring himself a cup of something that steamed.

For a half-second Harry was put off by the question, thinking he was referring to her, but a heartbeat later her brain caught up and realized he was talking about Addy. "Girl," Harry said, smiling a bit, "She's cute." Mrs. Weasley seemed to be hanging on her every word, but Harry really wasn't sure what else she could say about Addy. She was a baby. They were all pretty much the same, right?

"Takes after her mother, then," Mrs. Weasley sighed, adjusting her napkin in her lap, "Always been known for her charms, Lady Potter has."

There was an awkward pause in which Harry could almost see the kind woman trying to find something of her mother's to compliment her on as well. Harry wished her luck—there was really no comparison, at this point. She'd taken mostly after James even before she started using the Modified Polyjuice Potion to fuse her looks with Archie's. Even her eyes, once the bright, startling green that had stood out even in rumor among the social elite, were now an average semblance of their former color, just cheap contacts dulled further by the false glasses she wore to keep up appearances.

"These potatoes are amazing, Mrs. Weasley," Archie spoke up from between the twins. Harry thanked him silently for moving the conversation away from her.

"It's an old family recipe," the matronly witch said, smiling proudly.

"All our old family recipes are poisonous," Archie said, looking very impressed at the idea of family cooking in general. "Before I was born we had a house elf who made all the food in the house, so Dad didn't even know how to wash dishes, much less fill them with something edible."

"Did your elf die or something?" Ginny asked, her voice as blunt as the spoon she was using to dump carrots on her plate.

"Dad had to give it clothes," Archie said, seemingly unaware of how awkward a topic house elves might be for a family who probably couldn't afford their own. "He says he caught it looming weirdly over my crib at night a few times. Creeped him out. Thought it might try and baptize me in the Dark Arts when he wasn't looking."

After a beat of mildly horrified silence, in which Mrs. Weasley looked like a witch who was suddenly quite glad she'd never had a house elf, Archie added, "That last bit was a joke. I don't think you can actually baptize someone in Dark Magic."

"Though if you could, the Blacks would have found a way," Harry said, forcing a light laugh in an effort to include the Weasleys in the joke. Archie forgot at times that even though he didn't take the Black legacy seriously, it was still a semi-respected mostly-feared name in Wizarding Society. Others didn't poke fun at the traditionally dark family quite as readily as they did. In fact, Harry had only ever heard the Malfoys, arguably the Blacks' social equals, makes jokes at the family's expense.

"What was it like, growing up in a traditionally Dark home?" Percy asked, his curiosity more pressing than Harry's weak attempt at humor, apparently.

"It's all I knew, so I can't really compare, but I wouldn't say I grew up in a Dark household—not in the way you mean, at least," Archie said, the honesty clear in his tone, "There were a few cursed artifacts packed into the attic, and I did run across a boggart by accident in the library once, but my dad did his best to keep me away from any overt influences. I never really saw my extended family growing up, and all the particularly macabre literature was put up out of my reach. Dad is…not like other Dark wizards. And my mum was Light through and through when she…when she was…" Archie swallowed a bit dryly, then reached for his water glass with a subtle flush of embarrassed upset.

"I didn't mean to bring up…" Percy looked equally upset and embarrassed.

"It's all right." Archie's smile was back in action a scant moment later, one hand fingering the hair at his nape in a nervous gesture that Harry doubted anyone else recognized. "My childhood was a lot of fun, actually. Especially with Harry there—she's got those wild Potter genes, you know."

Many pairs of eyes turned to Harry, who blinked and summoned up a playfully innocent expression, as though to say 'who, me?'

"She did beat Ginny in a skate-race," Ron acknowledged after a moment of thought.

"Really?" Bill grinned, "Thought only Charlie could do that."

"He can race her next time," Ginny mumbled, rolling her eyes.

"We'll be sure to invite you two back when my other son can get away from his work," Mrs. Weasley said, smiling despite the clear regret in her eyes.

"We'd like that," Archie said, smiling in a barely-reserved way. He really was going to have to practice more before the gala.

Harry nodded in agreement, and Mrs. Weasley positively beamed with the happiness that comes to a hostess when her guests are genuinely enjoying themselves. Conversation turned to other things, and before she knew it Harry had eaten more in one sitting than she knew was possible. With compliments dripping from their lips, she and Archie gathered their things and prepared to floo home before their parents worried they'd overstayed their welcome.

"Thanks for having us, Mr. and Mrs. Weasley," Archie said for probably the fourth time that evening.

"Do come back," Mr. Weasley said, a warm smile on his face to back up his words.

"See you at school, Ron, Ginny, Percy—and you two as well, I guess," Archie ducked under a two-sided hug from the twins and waved to them all one last time before reaching for the floo powder.

Harry bid everyone a last goodbye, taking note of the way Bill's assessing gaze never strayed too far from her person as she, too, ducked into the hearth. She didn't doubt she'd be seeing him in the alleys very soon. The curiosity in his eyes meant he would let her explain, at least, before he jumped to any conclusions. That was the best she could have hoped for, considering; as she and Archie divested themselves of their outer layers in the floo room to Grimmauld Place, she considered the day overall positive in terms of their ruse. The fact that she got to spend an enjoyable afternoon with her friends from school (even though they didn't know she was their friend) only added to the feeling of satisfaction.

The feeling only lasted until the following morning, when the precariousness of their position came swinging into focus once more, but it had been there, and that had to count for something.

"You need to see this." Archie made his way into Harry's lab at a startling eight-o-clock in the morning, a letter clasped gingerly between his fingers.

"You're up early," Harry said, eyebrows raised, "What's the emergency?"

Her cousin held out the letter with a grimace. "It's from Flint. I thought it was for me, but…well, read it."

Harry took the parchment and sat on a nearby stool to peruse it.

Archie,

I write in haste. I need you to contact 'Rigel' without delay—whoever he is, wherever he is, I don't care. He and I have an agreement, and I'm calling it in. The Leaky Cauldron, three nights hence.

Marcus

"He's calling in the favor now?" Harry sighed, "I guess the timing could be worse."

"What do you think he wants?" Archie asked, looking incredibly out of sorts.

"Only one way to find out," Harry said, musing over the implications of sneaking out without her parents knowing after dinner.

"Harry—aren't you at least a little suspicious? He wants to meet you—or Rigel, whatever—in a pub. past dark, without even telling you why." Archie frowned. "I mean, Flint seemed an all right sort back when I saw him at Quidditch games, but…he's been blackmailing us for two and a half years now. What if he's changed his mind and wants to expose you?"

Harry shook her head slowly. "Flint knows me—or thinks he does. He even sort of likes me now, I think. There's also the vow we agreed upon: he can't expose me. It wouldn't be in his best interest to try, either. He gets more out of keeping quiet, especially if he does want to call in this favor. In fact…" Harry smiled suddenly. "This is a good thing, Arch. If I fulfill the terms of our vow now, then at the end of the school year when he graduates I'll be free of it. He'll have to keep our secret forever, but we won't owe him anything else in exchange."

"What if it's something you can't do, though?" Archie said, not looking convinced, "Maybe I should come with you."

"No, I need you to cover for me," Harry said, shaking her head, "I'm going to have to play sick, I think, and leave the house before dinner. Then I'll just sneak back in before the curfew wards go up."

"You will be careful though, won't you?" Archie checked. At Harry's droll look, he waved a hand impatiently. "I know, you wander the alleys all the time, but it's different at night. Your friend Leo said so himself, and he's the rat king or whatever."

"I'm just going to the Leaky Cauldron," Harry said, smiling reassuringly, "I'll floo straight there and straight back after talking to Flint. Nothing bad will happen."

"It will now that you've said that," Archie groaned, "Harry, how many times do I have to tell you about tempting Fate?"

Harry rolled her eyes, "The situation is dramatic enough without Fate stepping in this time, I think. Don't worry so much."

"I never used to worry," Archie sighed, "That used to be an other-people thing. Then we started this hare-brained scheme and suddenly my cholesterol is through the roof."

"Really?" Harry gave him a skeptical look.

"Well, no. We checked it this semester, actually—but it should be!" Archie exclaimed.

"I'll make a note," Harry said, turning back to her ingredient table, "Can I get back to work, Arch? I'll have to speed up my production a bit if I'm to take that evening off to meet with Flint."

"I'm going back to bed," Archie said, heading for the stairs, "I'll pretend all of this was a dream and we're not in way over our heads."

Harry frowned down at her tools for a moment. "Do you regret it?" she called after him.

"Not yet," came the tired reply. "Not yet, Harry."

The next couple of days were spent subtly indicating she might be coming down with a cold. A cough here, an irritated throat-rub there, and by the third day Lily was suggesting she step away from the cauldron for an evening and relax for the sake of her health.

Her mum brought a glass of ice water up to her room, where she was re-reading one of the Guild's older special editions just to pass the time.

"How's your throat, Harry?" Lily asked, sitting on the side of her bed to run a hand through her bangs sympathetically.

"A bit worse than this morning," Harry said, huffing in disgruntlement for effect. She'd never been a very docile patient. "I think I'm going to take a sleeping potion and just let my body fight it off overnight."

Lily frowned slightly, "Don't you want dinner first?"

"My stomach is all achy," Harry said, "I'd rather just eat a big breakfast tomorrow."

"I'll make your favorite, then," Lily smiled fondly down at her. Harry waited for her to get up, but her mother seemed content to simply watch her for a moment longer. "You're growing so fast," she said, seemingly out of no where, "Some days it feels like I hardly recognize you as the little girl that was afraid of wands."

"I wasn't afraid." Harry flushed in remembrance. She'd been a strong advocate of wand safety at age six.

"You used to cry when Sirius put his in his back pocket," Lily said smiling.

"It's unsafe," Harry mumbled, chagrined.

"That it is," Lily agreed. "I admit I snapped at him the other day myself—he left his wand in Addy's cradle, if you can believe it."

Harry snorted, "Not surprising. Uncle Sirius is a scatterbrain sometimes. Just like Archie."

"They are very alike," Lily agreed. She seemed to hesitate, then said, "Harry, speaking of Archie, I've been talking to Sirius and I wonder if anyone has mentioned—well, explained, really, why the two of you look so much—"

"Archie talked to me after he talked to Sirius," Harry said quickly, "Passive metamorphism, right? Nothing to be worried about. I know you didn't really separate us at birth."

"Some separation that would be," Lily laughed. Harry joined her, adding in a fake cough at the last minute. Lily stroked a hand through her hair again. "I just wanted to make sure you knew that the similarity was on Archie's end. I noticed you grew your hair out the other day—though you seem to have cut it again, huh?"

She fingered the blunt ends of her re-cut hair awkwardly. "I just…wanted to try something different for a day."

"It's okay to want to be different from Archie," Lily said softly, "I know you two have a solidarity thing going with the hair-cutting, and I hope you're not both still upset at not getting to go to the schools you wanted—"

"We aren't," Harry promised, "It was just a way to…remember each other. If we had the same haircut, we thought we'd remind ourselves every time we passed a mirror that the other one was thinking about us, too, probably."

"That's lovely," Lily said, "If you wanted to do something a bit more feminine with yours, though, I'm sure Archie would understand. You're a young lady, for all that we seem to forget that at times. You're entitled to want to feel like one, at this age."

"I know," Harry said, stumbling over her words a little as she tried to get her head around where her mother was coming from. What did she want Harry to say? "I just wanted to look a little different from Archie when we went to the Weasleys, that's all. So they'd be able to tell us apart without too much trouble. I might do the same for the New Year's gala—we are still going, right?"

"Well, we've no reason to refuse this year," Lily said carefully. She tucked a strand of her long red hair behind an ear. "Addy is old enough to put up with a few hours of people poking her, at least, and James is of course running security again—not to mention you were invited specifically by the young Miss Parkinson, for some reason."

"Archie says Pansy really wants to meet me," Harry said, grimacing a bit, "I guess Archie talks about me at school a lot."

"Well, why don't I help you with your hair that night?" Lily offered, "I'm quite handy with smoothing and curling charms, you know—I've even tamed your father's hair, a time or two."

"I'll have to see that to believe it," Harry chuckled.

"It's a date, then," Lily said, patting Harry's head once more. "Get some sleep, all right? I'll leave a few pieces of toast in the warmer if you wake in the night hungry."

Harry murmured her thanks and made a show of pulling a vial of sleeping draught from her potions kit as her mother left the room. She dumped the contents in her bathroom sink and left the empty bottle by her bedside as she slipped out of her pajamas and into clothes suitable for the cold night air. She waited until everyone had flooed over to Sirius' house for dinner (mentally thanking Archie for somehow managing to make it happen there even though it was technically the Potters' night to host) before slipping into her shoes and closing her bedroom door firmly behind her, heading for the floo.

The Leaky Cauldron had a decent crowd for the dinner rush, though Rigel knew it would taper off fairly quickly as the sun went down and the temperature dropped. People were always traveling through the pub from one world to the other, which was great for providing a steady flow of customers, but brought frequent frigid gusts of wind shooting from one end of the dining area to the other.

It took her a good minute to spot Flint, who had chosen one of the dimmest sections to sit in. He'd also pulled his hood up for good measure, and Harry wondered how he thought he'd be inconspicuous while trying so hard to avoid notice.

She slid into the booth across from him and signaled a passing waitress to bring them two butterbeers. Nothing was more suspicious than people who came to a bar and didn't drink anything. Flint looked up from under his cloak and blinked at her, seeming taken aback.

"You—Rigel?"

"Who else?" she said, settling into the persona of Rigel Black with barely a thought to mark the transition.

"I thought you'd look different," he grunted, keeping his voice low.

"Why?" she frowned.

"No need to look like Archie over the break," he shrugged.

"It's a permanent body alteration," Rigel huffed, "Not worth undoing it for a few weeks."

"Hn." Flint's eyes darted around the room edgily and they lapsed into silence as the waitress deposited their drinks and held her hand out for the fare. Apparently they looked like the sort of sketchy people who might skip out on a tab.

Rigel dropped a generous amount of coin into her manicured fist and flashed a hand-signal she'd picked up at the Phoenix. It was technically a thief-sign, conveying a need to conduct private business without being interrupted, but Rigel didn't think Leo would mind her appropriation of it in this instance. Whatever Flint needed had to be important, to have him looking so out of sorts. The waitress gave a sharp nod and left them in peace readily enough, so Rigel supposed she was at least passingly familiar with the Court's people.

"What's going on, Flint?" Rigel finally asked, pushing one of the drinks his way so that it would at least look like he belonged there. "Your letter seemed fairly urgent."

"I'm glad Archie could contact you in time," Flint said, moving his hands up to cup the pint glass like it was an unexpected lifeline. "Wasn't sure how far away you live."

"Archie and I have ways of fast communication while we're away from school," Rigel said vaguely.

"Good. I need you to come here again soon—I need your help, Rigel." He looked neither pleased nor unnerved by this admission—merely resigned to it. "I'm calling in the favor you owe me. The big one."

"I gathered," Rigel said shortly, unwilling to be reassuring until she knew what he needed. If he wanted something like a kidney, it was going to be a very inconvenient week. "What do you want?"

"Not want," Flint growled, almost to himself, "Need. It's my mother. She's…she needs help. I don't have anyone else to go to."

Rigel let a frown crawl across her brow. "Is she in trouble?" A moment later she cursed her foolish mouth—of course she was in trouble. Probably the kind of trouble that involved Flint's father, if Pansy's account of the upperclassman's home life could be believed.

"She needs a safe place to go," Flint said roughly, "I need you to—to take her to the muggle world. You can move about in that circle, right?"

"What makes you think that?" she asked cautiously.

"It makes sense." Flint jerked one shoulder in a brusque shrug. "It'd be harder to track you down, if you got found out and had to flee. You must have a back-up plan—a safe place to hide if you ever need to run. I need you to take my mother there. Just for a little while. Just keep her safe until I graduate; once I've got my NEWT's, I can help her start over. I just need time—" he blew out a frustrated breath. "I thought it would be okay until I graduated. I thought we could just wait it out. I was wrong."

He lapsed into a defeated silence, and Rigel took a moment to appreciate the monumental task that was now before her. It was a sign of Flint's desperation, rather than any true trust on his part, that he came to her with this. Still, she would do what she could—the vow, and her sense of decency, demanded no less. The only problem was…she didn't actually know anyone in the muggle world besides her mother's hateful relatives.

"What's your end goal?" she asked him, a spur-of-the-moment plan beginning to make itself known in the depths of her mind. "Do you think your father will look for her? Does she just need a place to stay, or an entirely new identity?"

Flint blinked slowly, "I…yeah, he'll probably look. If only to make sure she isn't gallivanting around in society bringing shame to the Flint name." The last was said with acute bitterness, and Rigel had to wonder how often such sentiments had been drilled into him.

"What kind of life does she want to live?" Rigel asked, taking a sip of her butterbeer to distract from the paths her imagination wanted to walk. "Does she want to work? Or live at home?"

Flint looked a bit incredulous. "Rigel…whoever you are…I don't care. Just get her somewhere safe, and I'll work the rest out this summer."

"She might object to being locked away for so many months," Rigel said, frowning once more.

"She's been locked away her whole life," Flint snapped, eyes hard.

"Then maybe it's time for a change," Rigel said softly.

Flint stared at her. "You have an idea."

Rigel nodded tentatively. "I can't settle her in the muggle world. I can take her somewhere safe, though. Somewhere close. She won't have to assimilate to a foreign culture this way. And I can find her employment, if you give me a few days."

"Days?" Flint scoffed. "Don't be ridiculous. That kind of thing—to do it without drawing the attention of my father would be impossible. He has contacts in the Ministry, contacts he'll be able to take advantage of even considering he'll be trying to avoid a scandal. Any move you make in the Wizarding World will reveal her to him." He leaned forward to pin her with a serious look. "This isn't a game. Can you help me or not, Rigel?"

"You came to me because some part of you thought I could help—and I can, you just have to trust me. The Ministry will never hear a whisper of her. I can hide her away here, in London. She'll be safe. In a nice house, with nice neighbors she doesn't ever have to talk to if she doesn't want. Far from the reach of men like your father—I promise, Flint. I can make this work." She poured every ounce of sincerity she could into her face. She was about to take a serious risk, but Flint was already sworn to secrecy. It wasn't a significant increase when compared to the risks she'd already taken, and for once the risk would be taken on behalf of someone else—not selfishly. Maybe it was the holiday spirit making itself known in the air, but Rigel was tired of feeling like all her efforts benefited no one but herself.

"How?" Flint's voice was flat, but there was a look in his eyes that hadn't been there before. She thought it might be hope.

"I don't have a safe house myself," she said carefully, "But I know someone who does. It's sitting empty, fully furnished, not fifteen minutes from where we sit. It's not big—just a single bedroom, kitchen, living room, and bath, but it's perfectly livable. My friend will let your mother live there as long as she likes."

"Your friend," Flint repeated, looking skeptical. "I'm just supposed to trust some other person with my mother's keeping? I don't think so. The deal is for you to pay back the favor, not foist it off on someone else."

"Well this is the only way I can help you," Rigel scowled, "And my friend is just as trustworthy as I am—more, in fact. She's—"

"She?" Flint openly sneered. "I see how it is. You think my mother's going to sleep on the couch in your love shack like a common—"

"Will you shut up?" Rigel snapped, thoroughly exasperated. "First of all, I'm thirteen. I don't have a bloody love house or whatever. It's not like that at all. The girl is Archie's cousin—I know she's trustworthy because I've worked with her."

"Archie's cousin?" Flint's eyebrows rose, "The Potter chit? She's in on this mess, too?"

"Yes," Rigel said, rolling her eyes.

"I suppose I have to keep her secrets, too, now?" Flint huffed, looking disgruntled.

"It's no harder to keep your mouth shut on three people's secret than two," Rigel pointed out, "And stop complaining—you're getting your favor."

"So you say," Flint said, taking another swig of his drink. "I want to see this so-called livable house. Won't have my mum living in a slum. She's accustomed to better, no matter that our house was more like a cage most days."

"You can see it tomorrow," she said.

"Why not now?" Flint challenged.

"It's late," she sighed, "And my parents will wonder where I am if I stay out all night."

Flint's expression was one of open surprise. "Your…parents?"

"Yes, of course," Rigel said, frowning a bit, "What, you thought…I was an orphan or something?"

"Well yeah, kind of," Flint said, looking uncomfortable and a bit confused.

"Well, I'm not," she grimaced, "So…tomorrow?"

Flint nodded. "How soon can my mother move in, provide it isn't a hovel?"

"You can bring her with you tomorrow for all I care," Rigel said, rubbing her eyes.

Flint eyed her with something approaching gratitude. "If this works out, I owe you one."

"You really don't," Rigel said, "That's the point. But, uh…Flint, you know that…even if there wasn't the whole debt thing between us…I mean, I'd still want to help. You know that, right? And Pansy would, too. Probably even Draco. Not to mention Adrian and the others on the team. I just—you should know that you do have people to turn to. People who would help you if they could. It's not just me."

Flint actually laughed, a barking, grating sound that made her ear twitch. "You are priceless, little snakelet. You really think Draco has the resources to help me—without Lord Malfoy getting wind of the scheme and turning my mother right back to my father's clutches? That's what pureblooded culture means, Rigel. It means the law is on his side, not hers. She has no rights as a squib. No recourse in civil society. She married him, and that subjugates her to him forever. For all the power my pureblooded friends pretend to wield as scions of their houses, they could do nothing for my mother that wouldn't undermine their own positions in society. But you can."

It was not the first time Rigel had considered that in some instances it was easier to maneuver around the purported 'power channels' of the Ministry and the upper-crust of pureblooded society than to try and wade through them, but it was the first time she had heard the argument pertain to someone else. It brought home to her in that moment how limited many of her pureblooded friends were, in terms of real freedom, when compared to some of the denizens of the lower alleys.

She took a long breath, then nodded. "You're right. I can. I'll—are you even free tomorrow? I can be here any time of day." She would have to fake a rather miraculous recovery, but it wouldn't be too much of a stretch.

Flint was quiet for a minute, then seemed to come to a decision. "If you say it's a nice house, I believe you. I'll bring my mother tomorrow morning—she doesn't need to spend one more moment in that house. Is seven too early? My father will sleep until noon, at least. I can make as though I had no idea she'd gone when he wakes."

"Seven is fine," Rigel said, wincing internally. It would be a very miraculous recovery. "I'll meet you here?"

Flint nodded sharply. "Yeah. Tomorrow. Good."

"Go home, get some sleep, and I'll see you back here early," Rigel said, taking another big gulp of her drink.

Flint made to stand, then stopped and stared at her once more. "Thanks, Rigel."

"I'm glad to do it," she said, her eyes softening slightly at his obvious relief.

He made his way to the floo without a backwards glance. Rigel checked the time, not wanting to floo home before her parents went to bed. Luckily, they zonked out shortly after Addy these days. Poor, tired, dears. She thought she'd better finish her butterbeer, just to be on the safe side. She still had a couple of hours before the curfew wards would auto-set, so she relaxed back into the booth, taking her time to think out all the relevant details to this latest plot.

She would have to talk to Leo, she realized uncomfortably. She didn't want to betray Flint's trust, but Leo needed to know that he couldn't scale her apartment windows anymore. She just hoped he wouldn't nail her with questions in this instance. With his help, she had an idea of where to get Mrs. Flint settled for employment, though. Hadn't Leo mentioned he had a pretend job at his mother's clinic in one of his letters? Perhaps Mrs. Hurst would be amenable to having someone to discretely do the actual work that Leo's pretend position covered. It was something like filing paperwork, she recalled, which meant it shouldn't be difficult even for someone without any work experience to attempt.

It would be a delicate act, she knew—keeping Mrs. Flint's identity from Leo and Mrs. Hurst while at the same time keeping the fact that she was Harriett Potter from the Flints. It would be worth it, though, if for once she could use her talent for dissembling in the service of a good cause.

She drained the rest of her drink, waited a bit longer just for good measure, then headed for the floo. She was as quiet as possible coming through the grate. Her parents' near-constant exhaustion would work in her favor, as they tended to sleep more heavily after a long day, and all their days had been long since Addy came along, but that didn't mean she could stomp around like a troll during mating season.

She did take a piece of toast from the kitchen on her way to the stairs, just so she had a flimsy excuse in case one of her parents happened to be wandering the halls. She needn't have worried, though. All was quiet as she crept up the stairs, avoiding the creaky ones on autopilot, and slipped into her room at last. Her clothes went back into their drawers, despite smelling like a bar. It was better than leaving them in her hamper to be questioned if by chance her mother decided to add Harry's laundry to her own this week.

She cast an alarm charm to wake her at six, and fell asleep to a whirlwind of plans and ideas that mapped their way across the inside of her mind with impatient fractals of thought and instinct. She wrapped a blanket across her shoulders and retreated into meditation to help her doze despite the cacophony of intentions all vying for attention between her ears. There would be time enough to plan again tomorrow, and the day after, and the one after that, as well. Sleep she had to take when she could.

She woke early the next morning, dressed unobtrusively in slightly worn robes and a scarf to pull up over her face once she reached the Leaky Cauldron. The last thing she wanted was to run into someone who knew 'Harry' while she was supposed to be 'Rigel.'

Her mother was already feeding Addy in the kitchen when she ambled in. Harry smiled a good morning as she slipped past her to grab a cup from the cabinet, aiming for the pitcher of juice on the counter once she'd decided it was probably orange.

"Harry, you're up," Lily said, pleasantly surprised, "Not feeling too poorly?"

"Sleep was just what I needed," Harry said, emphasizing her alertness with a healthy gulp of juice.

"Glad to hear it," Lily smiled. She let one hand trail over Addy's fine red curls absently. "Can I fix you anything? I haven't had a chance to start on breakfast properly yet."

"That's okay, I know you've got work in a bit—I'll grab something in Diagon on my way to the apothecary—they should have my order in this morning," Harry said, affecting a look of anticipation.

"If you're sure you're up for it," Lily said, looking only a little bit concerned. Her mother knew Harry's practicality well enough to respect her judgment in most things.

"It's not too far," Harry assured her, "And I think a brisk morning walk might be just the thing."

"Wear your winter boots," Lily told her, reaching out to pat her cheek gently, "It's still a bit wet out."

"I will," Harry promised, rinsing her glass in the sink and smiling once more before leaving the kitchen to hunt down her shoes.

She was through the floo to the Leaky Cauldron with plenty of time before their designated meeting, but a quick glance around the pub revealed that Flint and his mother were already there, bent quietly over the innkeeper's English breakfast in one of the more tucked-away booths.

She kept her eye out for people she recognized as she crossed the dining area, but wasn't too worried. It was early yet for anyone to be coming to the alleys to do business, and the folk she knew who lived in the alleys didn't usually venture this far out.

Mrs. Flint didn't look much like her son, save for the suspicious look in her eyes as Harry approached and sat down across from them. "Hello, Mrs. Flint," she said, lowering her scarf a bit so her words would be audible, "I'm Rigel, Fl—Marcus' friend."

She older woman merely looked away, focusing on her sausages and curling her thin form inwards ever-so-slightly.

"You're early," Flint grunted, seeming more his usual self this morning, as opposed to the stressed, somewhat scattered young man he'd been the night before.

She shrugged noncommittally. They sat in silence for a few minutes as the Flints made quick work of the rest of their meal, then Flint—Marcus—threw down a few coins and they all got to their feet.

"The apartment isn't far from here," Rigel said, "But I think it would be best to floo there for now. I can show you around the neighborhood afterwards, if you like, but walking through Diagon alley might not be wise."

Mrs. Flint pulled her grey shawl tighter around her head. Flint nodded once in acquiescence, and Harry led them over to one of the Leaky's floo grates. "The address is number eight, Dogwood Lane," she told them.

"You go first," Flint said lowly, "I'll send my mum after, then follow."

Rigel collected a handful of courtesy floo powder from the jar and brought the green flames to life. "Number eight Dogwood Lane," she said clearly.

She emerged in a familiar living room and stepped clear of the grate, sneezing softly as she disturbed a thin layer of dust. As she waited, she looked around the room with a critical eye. It wasn't exactly Magical Mansions material, but there was nothing a few cleaning charms wouldn't fix. Cleaning charms that Mrs. Flint couldn't do, she realized with a lurch of discomfort. Quickly, she pulled out her wand and cast several brusque vanishing spells at the dirt she could see from where she stood.

A few seconds later, Mrs. Flint came stumbling out of the floo, looking slightly ill. It occurred to Rigel belatedly that many people didn't prefer to use floo travel right after eating. She gestured to one of the chairs that Leo had procured for her, asking if Mrs. Flint wanted to sit down, but the lady only hugged herself quietly and kept an eye on the floo.

When Flint emerged, scowling a bit as he wiped soot from his sleeves, she felt rather relived. The seventh year looked around, moving to the window to peer past the curtains with a critical gaze. She supposed he was judging the quality of the neighborhood by the state of the neighbors' window boxes.

"It isn't regularly lived in," Rigel said, attempting to explain the somewhat sterile state of the apartment without outright admitting she—or Harry—had never used it.

"Smells like old people," Flint sniffed, turning away from the street view to inspect the rest of the room.

"Harry rents it from an elderly woman who lives across the street," she said, shrugging a bit, "It'll probably go away once you starting cooking meals here and such."

"Does she keep up on the utilities?" Flint asked sharply.

"Yes, it's paid through June at the moment, amenities included," Rigel reassured them. She thought about what else they would need to know. "There are several children on this street, so you may hear them playing from time to time. Your downstairs neighbor is a bit nosy, I think, so if she or anyone else comes to call either ignore them or tell them…you're Harry's aunt. That's what I'll tell Harry to tell the owner. I doubt anyone will bother you, though, especially if you use the floo to move in and out—that's what Harry generally does."

"Will Miss Potter be in and out of here at all hours?" Flint asked, sounding displeased.

"No, of course not," Rigel said, "She might check in from time to time, make sure nothing is wrong, but she'll owl before she drops by. Just call her Harry, though—people around here don't hold much with nobility, and not many know she's Harriett Potter."

Flint nodded with what seemed a bit like approval. "How far from Diagon are we?"

"Far enough that no one who shops there would find their way here," she said. "I'll draw a map before we leave, but I wouldn't advise walking all the way there until you know your way around a bit more. Best to floo to the Leaky Cauldron if you really need something. There're plenty of small stores around here, though, where you'd be less likely to meet anyone who'd recognize you."

"Not that many would," Flint said, a bit darkly, "Mum hasn't been out in society much."

She nodded in understanding. A sudden thought made her wince, though. "Are you closely related to a man named Aled Flint, at all?"

They both frowned in thought, and Rigel could suddenly see a stronger resemblance between the mother and son pair.

"Very distantly, maybe," Flint said, "We don't really associate with the lesser branches of the house. Why? He live in these parts?"

"Not close by, but yes, he runs an smithy here in the lower alleys. If he hasn't met your mother, though, there's no reason for him to recognize her." She wasn't sure if she should be speaking to Mrs. Flint or to her son, but as Marcus was the only one answering her, she settled her attention on him. "I'm going to see about getting her a job, if she's interested. It won't be difficult work, if I can make it happen, and the place I'm thinking of has a floo, so she could get there and back without wandering the streets, if she is reluctant to."

She really wasn't sure if being hidden away most of her life would make Mrs. Flint more or less eager to walk about in the alleys, but if what Leo had been intimating was true, it may be safer for her indoors anyway. At least if she could get her a position at the clinic, she would have somewhere to go and people to talk to during the day. She knew from experience how liberating having one's own source of income could be, as well.

"This may just work, Rigel," Flint said, letting out a slow breath.

She smiled. "Let's look at the rest of the rooms, then. You can help me tidy them up a bit."

Flint muttered something about not being a house elf, but nevertheless pulled out his wand and helped her Evanesco the worst of the built-up grime. His mother seemed to relax marginally as they made their way through the house, taking everything in with wide, sullen eyes. She would have to thank Leo again for furnishing the place, as it would have been significantly more troublesome to try and acquire amenities at such short notice.

When they reached the bedroom, Flint un-shrunk a trunk from his pocket and set it at the foot of the bed gently. Rigel hoped that the place would feel more like home once Mrs. Flint had unpacked. Maybe the woman would even be happy there.

She turned over the key to the front door once they were satisfied with the accommodations. She offered to show them the way to a small grocery store just up the street, but Mrs. Flint, her voice rusty with disuse, pleaded exhaustion, so they let her rest instead while she and Flint made the trek by themselves.

"It's an okay place, Rigel," Flint said after a few minutes of walking. His eyes took in the quaint streets and well kept, if a bit run down, stoops.

"Yeah," she said, "It's not a bad place to make a life."

He jerked his head as though cracking a stiff joint in his neck. "Hard to believe this is it. I always knew someday I'd get her out of there, but I thought…it'd be different, I guess. Less sudden."

"Does she need medical attention?" Rigel asked quietly.

Flint tossed his head irritably. "No. Not this time."

They lapsed into silence once more, Rigel only speaking up to point out useful shops and streets as they neared the grocer's. It was only twenty minutes' work to collect the basics of a rudimentary pantry. They were back at the apartment and unloading bags of food almost before she knew it.

"I should be getting back to the house," Flint said once his mother was as settled as they could make her.

"I'm going to see about that position I was thinking of," Rigel said, walking him to the floo, "Once that's settled…"

"Our debt is fulfilled," Flint said, eyeing her cautiously, "You…came through. Thank you for that. I may be a hard assed prick most of the time, but my mother…she deserves this."

"Everyone deserves a chance like this," Rigel agreed, "If you or she ever needs anything, unrelated to whatever debts or vows lay between us, just ask, okay?"

Flint grunted in a way that told her he would not under any circumstances ask for help that he wasn't already guaranteed by a magical oath. She supposed she'd just have to keep an eye on him, as well as his mother, for good measure.

"What name should I give people when they ask who Harry's aunt is?" she asked suddenly.

He was quiet for a moment, then said, "Merriam. She had a cat named Merriam once."

Rigel nodded. "Merriam it is. Flint…" she wasn't sure how to say this, so she just blurted it out. "Are you sure going back to your father's house is a good idea?"

Flint sneered at her, and she could see a spark of his usual derision in his eyes when he said, "Enough with the sap routine, Rigel. The deal is you worry about my mother. Leave my father to me."

Rigel held his gaze speculatively for a moment, but there was no fear or hesitation in his set expression, so she let the matter go. He would be back at Hogwarts in little under two weeks anyway. If he thought he'd be fine, who was she to tell him she knew his life better?

She bid the surly seventeen-year-old farewell, then returned to the bedroom where Mrs. Flint was sitting on top of the bedcovers, looking a bit lost.

"Marcus told me you might like the name Merriam," she said kindly.

The woman raised her eyes to Rigel's and blinked in a way that she supposed was agreeable. Rigel crossed the room to sit next to her on the bed, and took her hand in her own the way she would Lily's on the rare occasions her mother wasn't feeling well.

"I'm going to see about getting you a position at a nearby Healer's clinic," she said, searching the woman's face for any sign of an opinion on the matter, "The lady who runs it is very nice, and won't ask many questions. Would you like to work? You don't have to—your son has arranged everything, so if you'd rather just stay here for a little while before jumping into a new life, that's all right, too."

She waited for the lady to speak, patiently holding her slightly unfocused gaze until her lips pried themselves apart and she mumbled, "'m a squib."

Rigel tried not to soften visibly at those words, said so defeated, as a blind person might remind someone who'd asked them about the sunset. "That's all right; there's actually a proportionately large population of squibs in the lower alleys. And the work I'm looking into won't be magical in nature, strictly speaking—just paperwork, really."

Mrs. Flint looked down at her hands, one clasped in Rigel's, the other twisted unsurely in her lap, and shrugged.

Rigel patted her arm soothingly and rose. "You think about it, and rest up a bit more. I'll see if the position's available, and get you all the details to make your decision. I'll come by either later today or tomorrow to let you know and check on you, how's that?"

For a long moment, she thought the woman wouldn't say anything, but after a time a very soft "thank you" fell from her mouth.

"It's no trouble at all," Rigel said, hopeful that Mrs. Flint and she would become something like friends over time.

She bid goodbye and slipped out of the apartment, intent on making her way to Mrs. Hurst's clinic while she was out and about anyway. Halfway there she stopped dead in the middle of the street and cursed herself for being an idiot. She had put her green contacts in her pocket that morning specifically in case she ended up going into Rogue territory and then almost forgotten to put them in. She re-directed herself toward the nearest public restroom. As a rule she avoided such places, as the stink alone could peel the skin from one's nostrils, but it would have a mirror, and with a few sanitizing spells she would be able to insert the contacts without risk of infection.

When she ducked into the street toilet, she sighed at the state of the sink—someone had obviously been sick in it the night before, and the mirror that hung above it was cracked and warped in several places. She held her breath while she cleansed her hands quickly and bent over the foul mess to situate the contacts in her eyes. Magical contacts never failed to impress her, the way they settled automatically on top of her irises and then blurred, blending into her natural eye as though they were a part of her all along. She dug a pair of false spectacles out of her pockets as well for the finishing touch.

Her identity as Harry thus secured, she hurried out of the restroom and made a beeline back along her original trajectory toward the clinic.

Janice was manning the front desk when Harry stepped in, shutting the door quickly to keep out the cold air. The older nurse smiled in a matronly way and said, "What can I do for you, young man?"

Harry didn't miss the way the healer's eyes ran over her from top to toe, assessing even as the expression on her face remained polite. She could guess that the conversation would have started differently if she'd looked to be in any way injured.

"Is Healer Hurst in today?" she asked, approaching the desk.

"Of course," Janice smiled, "You're Leo's young friend, aren't you?"

"Yes, ma'am. I'm Harry," she said, smiling in an embarrassed way that made her look like an awkward, but overall harmless, youth.

Janice nodded, "It's nice to know your name, Harry. I'm Healer Janice. Healer Hurst is in her office at the moment—would you like to go on back? She doesn't have any appointments until lunch."

"Thank you," she said, skirting around the minimalist counter that separated the waiting room from the offices and examination rooms in the back. "I'll try not to trouble her for long."

"Healer Hurst is immune to trouble, rearing that boy of hers," Janice chuckled.

Harry took a brief moment to wish that she was immune to trouble as she smiled in return. She made her way back to the head healer's office, sidling up to the open doorway with what she hoped was an endearingly appealing expression on her face.

"Harry!" Mrs. Hurst looked up and smiled widely at the sight of her. "Come in, dear, how are you? I've not seen you since the summer."

She rounded the little desk to accept a hug from the healer, taking a moment to appreciate the woman's particular brand of warmth and kindness before moving away to take the seat across from the desk with a self-deprecating smile. "I've been well, Mrs. Hurst. And yourself?"

"You know me, keeping busy—mostly thanks to my ungrateful whelp of a son, who seems to spend his entire week coming up with ways to run me ragged," Mrs. Hurst huffed in a tone that belied the fond smile on her face.

"I heard he'd taken up employment here," Harry said, fake-casual.

"That's a word for it." The healer shook her head. "Another one's mischief."

"It's nice of you to accommodate him like that," Harry offered.

Mrs. Hurst softened. "He's a good lad. The work he does in these alleys is sorely needed, no matter what outsiders think of the Court of Rogues. If I can make juggling his different lives a little easier, well, that's a mother's prerogative. I opened this clinic to help people, after all, and if helping Leo helps them too, then all the better."

Harry hesitated a moment, but supposed this was a good a time as any. "Mrs. Hurst, I wonder if you might be amenable to helping one more person." Mrs. Hurst's eyes swept her in a practiced fashion, and Harry hastened to clarify. "Not me. I have an aunt who is looking for work. Her husband recently passed away, so she's staying with me, now, and I'm worried she might feel at odds during the day while I'm away at school."

Mrs. Hurst leveled an expectant look at her and waited for the flush of realization to spread over Harry's cheeks. "My magic gets irritated by lies," she gently reminded Harry, who had indeed forgotten that little fact when she launched into her tale. How could the woman be so good at detecting perfectly plausible untruths? She wondered if the healer had some soothsayer blood in her family. "Should I take it simply that this woman you speak of, regardless of any supposed relation to yourself, is indeed in some kind of trouble?"

Harry's face settled into apologetic earnestness. "She is. I can't tell you the particulars, but I've recently given her lodging in my apartment, and I think employment will help her get back on her feet. I heard that Leo was pretending to have a job here, so I thought maybe this woman could quietly do the work Leo was pretending to do. You wouldn't have to do it anymore, to cover for Leo. You don't even have to take her on as an official employee—I'll pay her wages, even. She just…needs a place to go, with nice people who will talk to her and notice if she seems to be having trouble with anything. I'd really appreciate it, Mrs. Hurst. She's not a criminal, or anything—just very quiet, and a bit timid, and—"

"Stop, Harry, for the Mother's sake," Mrs. Hurst cut in on a laugh, "You don't have to keep convincing me—if this lady needs help, then we'll help her. It's that simple, child."

"You'll let her work here?" Harry smiled in acute relief, then paused. "She's…she can't do magic. It's just filing papers and such, right?"

The healer smiled kindly. "That's no problem. We have a man who delivers all our supplies who's non-magic, as well. She won't find any prejudice here."

"I knew that," Harry said, filled with gratitude for this wonderful lady, "Thank you so much, Mrs. Hurst. I'll ask her tonight or tomorrow how she feels about the idea. When should I tell her you'd like her to come in?"

"Bring her by anytime for a full physical," Mrs. Hurst said, pulling out a notebook to jot a few things down, "We always keep a healthy staff, for the patients' sake, so she'll need to be cleared of contagions and the like before she officially starts. Her hours can be flexible, to start with—just coming in whenever she feels up to it is fine. We haven't any desperate need, after all. Once she is trained and feels confident enough we can see if she fancies a more regular schedule."

"That sounds perfect," Harry smiled, "Her name is Merriam. As far as I know she's been a housewitch most of her life, but she was homeschooled at one point, and she has experience with children. I…don't know much else about her, but if anyone asks she's my aunt."

"Where does she live?" Mrs. Hurst asked, looking up from her quill.

"Dogwood lane, number eight," Harry said, "I rent it through Mrs. Whitlock, who lives with the Bottings."

"Nice family," Mrs. Hurst said absently, scribbling down the address, "Little Clara lost a tooth just last week and made me promise I'd send it to the tooth recycling factory so that a little baby somewhere could get his first tooth in because, I quote, 'without teeth babies can't eat real food, and baby food is yucky.'"

Harry laughed softly. She'd only really met the child once over a year ago, but she remembered her precociousness quite well.

"Let's see…I think that's everything," Mrs. Hurst said, tapping her quill thoughtfully. "Except…" she brought a frank look to bear, "Is anyone looking for her? We can hide her from Aurors if need be, but we'll need to know so we can be prepared."

Harry shook her head slowly. "I don't think there will be a search of that magnitude. She's…not in that kind of trouble. She's a good person—just needs a place to make a new home. It might be best to keep her away from prying eyes for a little while, but I doubt anyone who may be looking for her will look here—that's why I brought her to the alleys. I think she'll be safe."

"Noble, was she?" Mrs. Hurst said dryly. She sighed and held up a hand when Harry grimaced. "No, don't tell me. I can guess most of it anyway, and the rest will be confirmed when I check her over. A healer always knows." Harry thought Mrs. Hurst overestimated other healers, or at the least greatly underestimated her own perceptiveness. Other people simply did not come to correct conclusions when left to their own devices—she should know, as she took advantage of that very human flaw with great frequency.

"Thanks again for doing this, Mrs. Hurst," Harry said after a moment, "Please let me know if there's anything I can do to help, or if you have any trouble."

"You're a good lass, Harry," the healer said, standing and coming around the desk and lifting her into another long hug. "Be careful walking home—the alleys are a bit different in the cold months. And don't be a stranger."

"I won't," Harry promised, giving the woman one last smile before heading for the door. "Say hello to Leo for me."

"You'll no doubt see him before I do," Mrs. Hurst chuckled, "He's got ears on you in these alleys, that's for certain."

Harry admitted that was true, though privately she suspected that Leo in fact had people in Diagon that kept an eye out for her. She almost always came to the alleys through the Leaky, after all. She doubted he'd get word she was in the area today, at least until she got back to Diagon on her way out.

She bundled up tight before journeying back into the winter air, though she didn't bother to pull her scarf over her face, as it didn't really matter if people recognized her as Harry at that point.

She hurried along through the winding alleys, admiring the many festive decorations hung from windows and doorways along her route. They had nothing on the fever of trappings going on at Sirius' house, of course, but then Sirius always did have too much time on his hands.

She passed Kyprioth Court and turned onto Knockturn Alley, briefly debating stopping in to see Krait. She'd have to drop by the next day with his next order of potions anyway, so there wasn't really any need, unless she simply felt like bothering the grumpy salesman. In the end she decided not to, and turned her eyes elsewhere along the narrow alley. As she neared the mouth of the alley where it met Diagon, her gaze caught on a little sign hung outside of Borgin and Burkes that read 'New Books Just In.'

Curious, she wandered closer, peering through the grimy window to see if there was a display of some kind. Most of the stuff in Borgin and Burkes was cursed junk, as far as Harry had heard said, but every now and then the antique shop came across something particularly valuable or intriguing in someone's estate sale. It was for this reason that it was frequented by a variety of patrons, including some of the upper crust, who came to look or even sell, if not always to buy. Maybe she would have a look—more knowledge was always an advantage.

She caught sight of a flash of red hair through the window, and couldn't believe the odds. She and Bill Weasley were really starting to see too much of one another—not that he'd seen her, yet. She pulled her scarf up around the lower half of her face and casually opened the door, sending a bell clanging feebly as she edged into the small shop and headed directly for the bookshelves, keeping her face turned away from the two men talking at the counter.

"All books are buy one get one," Borgin's voice, as oily as his hair, called from across the shop. Harry made a vaguely interested grunt, after which Borgin seemed content to ignore her.

She examined the titles in a perfunctory way, much more interested in seeing what Bill Weasley was doing in Borgin and Burkes. Was he breaking a curse on something? Or looking for a last-minute Yule present, perhaps? She knew she shouldn't really spy on people for no reason, but there was something about Bill that piqued her interest. He played in a lot of different sandboxes, and she thought it would pay off to keep an eye on him, since he was undoubtedly keeping an eye on her, as well.

"Borgin," Bill sighed, sounding a bit frustrated, "I need to know."

"I've already told your goblins I ain't heard anything about it!" Borgin snapped, "Told the Aurors, too, when they raided my bleedin' shop and caught half the alley on fire."

"The Aurors barely understand what they're looking for," Bill said, a bit derisively. She could hear the cajoling note enter his voice as he added, "Gringotts is willing to pay a substantial sum for any information leading to the reclaiming of their property."

Borgin sighed disgustedly. "You think I'm hanging onto it or something? Keeping the information for myself? I got no use for the sodding thing—got enough cursed gems in this shop already, an' can't sell 'em quick enough. Ruddy rubies give me the heebie-jeebies."

"It's not a ruby," Bill said quietly, "Much bigger. Not a true gem, but a stone of magical origin. And no, I don't think you're keeping it for yourself, but you might be protecting the information on behalf of another."

"Like who?" Borgin grumbled.

Harry had to agree—Borgin would sell his own mother up the river for a fistful of coin.

"Maybe someone powerful," Bill said, "Someone who could buy your silence with gold—or fear."

"If you want to know if Lord Riddle's paid me to keep quiet about the stone, just ask me," Borgin sneered. Bill must have made some silent entreaty, because the older man snorted loudly. "No, Will, I ain't been made silent on the matter—I just haven't got a clue about it, same as everyone else 'round here. You lot are looking in the wrong place, as I told you the last three times you came asking."

Bill sighed, and a bit of the tension in the room relaxed. "You know I have to ask, Borgin. My job."

"I know, Will," Borgin said dismissively, "Them goblins is stubborn little things."

"In this case, it's to everyone's betterment," Bill said, "The more I hear about this thing, the more dangerous it seems."

"I reckon they don't call it the 'Dominion Jewel' on account of its passivity," Borgin chortled.

"Indeed," Bill said shortly. There was a shifting of boots against the hard floor.

"Yer not going already?" Borgin sounded put out. "Need you to take a look at this necklace, Will."

"Today?" Bill sounded a bit harried.

"Before tomorrow afternoon," Borgin said, "I've got a bloke looking to buy it for a relative, but he wants to know what sort of nasties are on it first."

"I don't think I'll have time to break any curse I find before tomorrow," Bill said tiredly.

"Don't need you to break 'em." Borgin wheezed a laugh. "He wants his inheritance! I'll charge him extra for any curses you find, Will'em."

Harry bit down on a horrified choke and sincerely hoped Borgin was kidding. On the other hand, the man sold poisons, so…maybe not. She must have stiffened or gave some other sign of awkwardness, as Borgin suddenly snapped, "Buy something or get out, Bint, this ain't a library."

She waved a hand over her shoulder to placate him, plucking a book at random from the shelf in front of her and holding it up as proof that she was a serious customer. He grumbled a bit too quietly for her to hear, but subsided. She made a show of bending down to peruse the lower shelves just in case, but it seemed his attention had left her.

"Just a quick glance," Borgin encouraged, "Won't take but a mo'."

"I'll come by after work tonight," Bill said, "But it'll be double the usual price for the inconvenience."

Borgin made a token complaint, but overall sounded rather satisfied with the compromise. Bill left shortly after, and Harry made her way over to the counter with the book she'd grabbed, feeling too guilty to put it back now that she had used the man's shop to eavesdrop on his business acquaintance.

When she handed it over, Borgin glanced at the cover with raised eyebrows, looking up at her with slight disbelief. She looked down and read 'Mermaid Hunting for Fun and Profit.'

Stifling a wince, she looked innocently up at him, "How much?"

"It's buy one get one," he said, looking at her like she was slow.

"Right," she muttered, annoyed at herself. She marched back to the shelves and picked up the first potion-related book she found, depositing it on the counter with a sweet smile.

"Wilderness Survival Potions: Brews for the Barely Prepared," he read, lip curling a bit in derision.

"You're selling it," she muttered, pulling out her coin purse.

He charged her an outrageous three galleons, but she forked them over without complaint. It was her idea to go in there, after all. She ducked out of the shop and turned toward Diagon Alley before smacking straight into someone who'd been loitering awkwardly close to the shop's doorway.

"Sorry," she said automatically, glancing up. "Oh. Hi." It was Bill Weasley, and he was looking more than a little annoyed. "Fancy seeing you here," she tried, summoning up a friendly smile.

"Were you spying on me?" Bill asked, crossing his arms and staring down at her.

Harry tilted her head. "Spying? No, just browsing. Why, were you doing something suspicious?"

"Does your father know where you are right now?" Bill asked, scowling.

"Does your father know where you are right now?" She returned, raising an eyebrow. Bill eyed her unhappily for a moment. He opened his mouth but she cut him off. "There's really only one thing to do, Will. I'll pretend I don't know who you are and you pretend you don't know who I am and we'll remain the best of friends."

Bill frowned harder. "I have a right to be here. You—you're just a kid. A girl kid."

"I thought you knew," Harry lied.

Bill stared at her. "Everyone at the Rogue thinks you're a boy, Harry."

"Leo doesn't," Harry said, "And Rispah knows, too." That was a recent development, but he didn't need to know that. "It's safer for me to be a boy, anyway—you don't want to put me in danger, do you, Will?" She blinked big green eyes up at him, a mixture of apprehension and sorrow swimming in their depths. It was a potent combination, according to Marek.

"Stop it," he said weakly, "You're not getting me to cover for you. The lower alleys are no place for an heiress like you."

"Were you worried about me before you knew I was Harry Potter?" she asked, trying a different approach.

"I thought you were just another orphan lad with no where else to go," Bill snapped, "Not some rich girl playing at slum life for kicks."

Harry reared back, feeling as though she'd been slapped. "I'm not…slumming," she said slowly, incredulity in every syllable. "The King of Thieves is my friend. I go to the Phoenix to see him and those of his people I've become close to, and I don't have to justify how I spend my time to you of all people."

"What's that supposed to mean?" Bill scoffed.

"Your family doesn't know about your alter ego 'Will,' do they?" Harry accused, "You should know better than anyone that the lower alleys offer opportunities that are hard to find other places. You've no room to call me out for taking advantage when you're doing the same thing, selling your skills on the side for a little extra coin."

"My extra coin goes to keeping my parents in their home," Bill said sharply.

"And mine means a lot to me, too," Harry shot back, putting a hand to her hip in unconscious imitation of her mother in a snit. "You're not the only one who gets to have responsibilities, William."

Bill rolled his eyes. "You're thirteen."

"And I'm a full-time brewer at the potion shop on this very street," she said, lifting her chin, "Where else do you think they let halfblood little girls ply their trade? I'll give you a hint—nowhere."

Bill looked taken aback for a moment. "That's…you shouldn't be working anyway, at your age."

"How is that your decision?" she asked, lifting a brow.

"It's your parents' decision," he said, looking triumphant.

"My parents encourage me to be independent," Harry said drolly.

"I don't think this is what they had in mind."

"Luckily, you don't have to think about it, because you're not in charge of me."

"It's not safe, Harry," he snapped, running a hand through his brilliantly-colored hair in agitation.

"The world's not safe." Harry wrinkled her nose. "But I've got more people watching my back here than anywhere else. Leo is my friend."

"Not everyone in these alleys answers to Leo," Bill sighed.

"Well, I've got you watching my back too, apparently," Harry snorted.

Bill made a face at her. "Just…be careful."

"I will," she said, letting her face settle into more serious lines. "You be careful, too. This business with the artifact you're tracking down—it's heavy. Sounds like there are some major players involved, and it would be a shame if you got in over your pay grade."

"You were spying on me," he grunted, annoyed.

"Just looking out for you," she replied, widening her eyes in fake concern. "The alleys are a dangerous place, Will. A nice boy like you could get into trouble."

"Get out of my sight before I drag you back to Diagon," Bill said, eyes narrowed.

"I'm headed that way anyway," she said primly, stepping around him with a carefully timed sniff.

"And if your dad finds out what you've been up to, I knew nothing about it," he added as she walked away.

Harry shot a mock salute over her shoulder and ignored the groan of defeat that echoed up the alley after her. All in all, that had gone better than she might have anticipated. Checking her watch, she noted she'd be home just in time for lunch. Perhaps afterwards she could quiz Archie some more on the personalities and background information of people he might meet on New Year's Eve. They still had a lot of work to do before the gala. And then they could do a bit of research into the so-called 'Dominion Jewel.' It had an ominous ring to it that made her want to know everything she could on the off chance she crossed path with it again.

Chapter 11

Draco looked into the mirror and recognized intrinsically that which looked back at him. A young lord on the cusp of ascendance, his clothes and jewels only the accompaniments of his station. The true reflection of his position lay bare in his eyes—Malfoy grey, the color of sober grace, and in the set of his shoulders—poised with the duty of his birthright, but far from bent beneath its weight. He looked and felt older than his thirteen years.

The last addition was the silver dagger his godfather had gifted him that summer. As coming of age presents went, it was spectacular in symbolism and, because it was Uncle Severus, usefulness. A plethora of enchantments made it as deadly as it was beautiful, and Draco knew his godfather had only allowed its incredible splendor so that he may carry it ceremoniously in places true weapons were discouraged, as he would tonight. It did look fine with his silver-trimmed robes, Draco was pleased to note.

A cleared throat turned his attention to his dressing room doorway, where his father loitered with a mixture of pride and regret bare on his usually impassive face.

"Severus has excellent taste, for all that he rarely employs it on his own behalf," his father remarked, eyeing the dagger that hung weightlessly at Draco's waist with approval.

"The taste was incidental, I suspect," Draco said, a grin tugging at his mouth as he met his father's gaze through the mirror. "It's charmed to open locks—and to only strike true in the hand of one of my own blood."

"Keep it away from Bellatrix," Lucius drawled. Draco chuckled, nodding his agreement. His father examined him carefully for a long moment. "You have grown up so quickly, my son."

"It does not seem quick to me," Draco said, turning his gaze back to the mirror, this time seeing the flaws—the slight ganglyness that spoke of heights not yet reached, the chin that was not quite as firm as what his father's granite profile boasted.

"It will accelerate before you realize," Lucius said, "When you look back on tonight you will remember it as a milestone."

"It's just another party at the Parkinsons' estate," Draco said, raising an eyebrow in skepticism, "We've been to dozens."

"Not a gala," Lucius said, shaking his head slowly.

"I've been to other galas," Draco pointed out.

"This one will be different," his father said, eyes serious in a way that made Draco instinctually pay closer attention. "The sphere is widening this year. The Parkinsons are very well connected. There will be a great many Ministry officials in attendance with their families. More Neutral and even Light leaning families there, as well."

"Really?" Draco processed this silently. Tilting the field away from a concentration of Dark families was not necessarily a bad thing, politically speaking.

"You will pay special attention to Miss Parkinson tonight," Lucius said, "Flaunt our close connection."

"I will, Father," Draco said, frowning a little, "Though…I do not wish to send the wrong message. Pansy is beginning courting negotiations this winter—"

"You could do much worse than Rose Parkinson's daughter," Lucius cut across him sharply.

"Yes, Father," Draco said, automatically obedient.

His father eyed him through the mirror thoughtfully. "Perhaps you had a different prospect in mind?" Draco blinked in slow confusion. "Your friendship with Heir Black is quite close, Draco," Lucius prompted drolly.

Draco's nose wrinkled instinctively before he could still it. "Rigel is a friend, Father." There was a confusion in his breast that voiced some uncertainty about the exact nature of his relationship with Rigel Black, but it was easy to ignore. "Like you and Severus," he offered when his father looked unconvinced.

Lucius laughed shortly. "Severus and I were not always such good friends, Draco."

"I thought you were schoolmates," Draco said, eyes narrowing. He was sure his father and godfather had told him they met at Hogwarts.

"He was several years younger than I," Lucius said dismissively, moving from the doorway at last and approaching the large window on Draco's left. It looked out over his mother's garden, which the house elves decorated beautifully with silver lights in the winter months.

"How did you become close, then?" Draco asked, now curious as to why he'd never heard the story. "Through the SOW party?"

Lucius' smirk was incredibly wry. "In fact, when Severus first petitioned to join the Party I suspected him a spy." Draco's mouth fell open, prompting a dark chuckle from his father. "Oh, yes. He was a nobody in school—kept to himself and distained Society in all its forms. I don't blame him—Society is no place for a halfblood whelp without family to recommend him, which is exactly what Severus was. Then he took his Mastery at seventeen—breaking half a dozen records in the process—and suddenly all his reticence and taciturn disgust disappeared. He made the right friends, said the right things, and he was talented—so talented that he didn't need to say or do the right things, don't you see? The Party would have accepted him anyway, on merit alone."

"You suspected him of playing his way in?" Draco whistled. "I hope you didn't say that to his face."

"Of course I did," Lucius smirked, "I was young and indelicate—this was before I married your mother. Snape was easily provoked. A slur to his heritage brought his acerbic nature to the fore with little trouble; he was suspiciously resentful when it came to blood rights, for one who pledged himself to a Party created on the basis of their existence. I accused him of treachery and duplicitousness and demanded a duel to satisfy the honor of the Party."

Draco could not believe his ears. "You…what?"

"Don't look so surprised." His father sighed with acute chagrin. "I lost, of course. Severus annihilated me on the dueling field. I retracted my accusations at once and shortly thereafter the two of us became friends. I even sponsored his ascendance in the Party after that. I never forgot, though." Lucius had a far away look in his eyes all of a sudden. It made trepidation blossom in Draco's gut. "And I still have my suspicions. Severus is a little too close to Dumbledore, for all that he is employed at Hogwarts. Your godfather does not enjoy teaching."

"You don't say," Draco snorted. That much was certainly obvious.

"Whatever his excuses about contributing to the next generation—however arduous a task it may be, as he says—it has always felt off to me," Lucius said. He clenched his hand into a slow fist. "Severus is valuable to the Party, and he has become a good friend to our family, but he has secrets, Draco."

"Why are you telling me this now?" Draco asked after a moment of silence. "I know you've cautioned me about speaking freely on certain subjects with Uncle Severus before, but you've never said anything so explicit about questioning his…his loyalties."

"I tell you this to illustrate my relationship with Severus, which you claim is just like your relationship with Rigel," Lucius said, voice pointed. Draco swallowed. Before he could formulate a response, not sure if he ought to defend Rigel or Snape or neither, his father went on. "I understand your friendship with Heir Black, Draco. Talent calls to Malfoys—I raised you to respect it, to seek it out. Rigel is also family, which rightly elevates him even more in your esteem. You can be his friend, but I must tell you to be careful. Like we are careful with Severus. For all his seeming good-naturedness and harmless intellectual façade, Rigel Black has secrets, too. I am sure of it."

Draco knew as much already, had known as much almost from the start. But Lucius and Severus had been friends well over a decade, even with what was apparently a sea of doubt between them. He and Rigel would be just the same. He, the powerful, charismatic Lord Malfoy, and Rigel the anti-social but endearing academic who everyone esteems but only Draco really understands. Pansy would be there, too. It would be perfect. Or as close to perfect as real life got. Certainty wasn't the gold standard for everything—much less the Malfoy standard, which meant considerably more.

Draco moved a stray hair back into its place, then turned from the mirror at last. "Ready, Father? We best not keep Mother waiting."

"If your mother is finished with her coiffure, I'll go to the gala in stockings," Lucius said, nonetheless following him from the room. As they approached the floo room to await the lady of the house, his father placed a hand on his shoulder that was heavy with meaning. "You will be careful, Son. Use your gift. Discover whatever you can, whenever you can. Keep the knowledge close. It is impossible to predict what—or who—may become critical to your future."

"I will, Father," Draco said, attempting to assure himself as much as anything. He would try to be careful. He had a feeling that carefulness was a ship that had sailed without his realizing it, however. Unlike Lucius and Severus, who approached friendship with wariness and restraint, Draco was already neck-deep in it. He couldn't imagine his future in any capacity without Rigel in it. His father may as well advise him to be suspicious of himself, so awkward and unwieldy the imperative felt.

Still, tonight was as good a time as any to approach his friendship anew. He would pay closer attention, and try harder to see things as they were, rather than as he would have them be. Somehow he doubted Rigel would even notice his increased scrutiny. Draco heaved a mental sigh. It was probably better that his friend was so oblivious. Draco wanted to take his father's advice seriously, but he didn't want Rigel to think him actually doubtful—Rigel had enough trouble understanding their friendship as it was. The last thing he needed to do was add complications to what was already a difficult concept for Rigel to grasp.

Sometimes he wished he could have simple friends—ones with simple needs and easy-to-suss-out goals, ones who didn't hide behind personas of gilded lies and who never over-analyzed anything Draco did or said. His wishing never lasted very long, though. That sort of friendship was for boring people, with small minds and even smaller lives. Draco was made for more interesting things, even if sometimes the interesting things were the most troublesome.

Harry gave up looking for some semblance of herself in the mirror after a few unsuccessful minutes and simply settled for staring at the strangely glittering creature within. Her mother had made good on her promise to help her in dressing for the gala that night, but Harry hadn't imagined that her assistance would characterized by such…alteration. Lily had, with her cautious permission, grown her hair out several inches, until it was long enough to twirl around the ends of her mother's wand like the ribbons of a party balloon. The effect was very feminine, she had to admit, but the way the curls stuck together in formation even when she shook her head was a bit eerie.

"Stop moving," Lily laughed, "They haven't set completely yet."

"They look very set," Harry said, voice dubious.

"That's because you're used to wearing it messy." Lily rolled her eyes. "James is just the same—every time I style his hair he claims I've cemented it. Just because it isn't tousled with flyaways…" she trailed off with a distracted mutter as her wand made another pass over the curls at Harry's nape.

Addy gurgled somewhat unhappily from her blanket across the room, summoning Lily to her side like an ancient Sheba. Harry took the moment to lower her glasses at the mirror, examining her eyes suspiciously. Her mother had done…something to her eyelashes, darkening and thickening them in a way that gave her gaze an unnatural intensity. Lily assured her it was subtle, but Harry thought it entirely alien, even with the frames of her glasses to divert attention. Her eyebrows had been thinned, giving her a wide-eyed look that she wasn't sure she approved of, and she was pretty sure her mother had altered the color of her lips slightly when she wasn't looking. She had no idea how she would undo all of it before she went back to Hogwarts, but with luck at least some of the spells would be temporary.

Her mother was playing a guessing game of some sort with her little sister while she examined her face. Addy was making variously insistent noises while Lily tried to figure out what exactly the infant wanted. Harry wasn't sure Addy was actually communicating at all, as in her observation infants tended toward nonsensical noise making for mere practice's sake, but her parents had lately begun asserting the opinion that Addy was interacting intelligently with the world around her. She supposed they had more experience than she did on the matter.

"Your ball?" Lily said, holding up said toy with an exaggeratedly questioning expression on her face, "Or your blanket?"

Whatever Addy gurgled must have made sense to Lily, who smiled indulgently, "Your blanket? Okay, here's your blanket." The ceremony with which she handed over the snitch-patterned cloth would have done royalty proud.

"She's just so smart," Lily said, pride in her smile as she returned to the vanity. "Before you know it she'll be talking away. I'm going to teach her French, I think, once she's able to articulate most of the sounds."

"Shouldn't we teach her English first?" Harry said, smiling.

"Bilingualism starts young," Lily said, smoothing her hands over Harry's curls with a satisfied air, "I learned French in primary school, you know."

"I didn't," Harry said, surprised.

Lily nodded, smiling a bit wryly. "I suppose I don't speak it much anymore, but I was quite good at a young age. I even applied to Beauxbatons when I got my letter outlining my schooling options. I didn't get in, of course—it's listed as a school that accepts muggleborns, but I'm afraid that's mostly for posturing purposes. They only really accept those from old French families, and of those they prefer the ones with old money, besides."

"So you went to America," Harry said, wondering how she'd never known Lily hadn't gotten into the school of her choice either, all those years ago.

"So I went to America," Lily agreed. She smiled softly. "It was for the best, in the end. I'd never have gotten my grounding in experimental Charms at Beauxbatons. They're very traditionalist when it comes to spell casting. I think Addy might do well there, though… at least, with the Potter family name, they can't refuse her application."

Harry wasn't sure what to say to that. She wondered if it still stung, being refused admittance to the elite French school. At least Harry had grown up knowing intellectually that she wouldn't be accepted to Hogwarts—for Lily the knowledge of her magical abilities and the disappointment of her blood status must have come all at once.

"If we'd thought far enough ahead with you, James and I would have taught you another language, too," Lily said sadly, "We didn't mean to limit your choice of school to America or Australia—we just got so caught up in the moment, growing with you day by day, and by the time we realized your future bore serious consideration, it was too late to give you a background in another tongue. Not enough to be schooled in it, anyway."

"It's all right," Harry said, trying to cheer her mother up again before they fell into a conversation of regrets. "When you teach Addy, maybe I can learn, too. It'll be fun, learning together. And when she gets old enough we can take a family trip to Paris."

"That sounds lovely," Lily said, beaming. "What did I do to deserve such an understanding daughter?"

"You gave me a father whose behavior instills a good deal of patience and understanding," Harry said.

"Speaking of which," Lily laughed, "Run into the study and tell your father it's time for him to begin dressing. He and Sirius always wait until the last minute."

Harry slipped out of the room, her steps almost mincing in the unfamiliar slippers she had donned to match her delicate dress robes.

The light was on in the study, but the door was closed, which immediately struck Harry as odd. Closed doors weren't exactly a thing in their house, unless someone was sleeping. Wondering if her father and uncle were plotting something interesting for their joke line, she crept closer on silk-clad feet.

"—still can't believe we're attending Satan's circus again," James was saying, "And the rest of them got roped into it as well somehow."

"Not Remus," Sirius said, sounding as though he was leaning close to the door.

"Well we can't all be werewolves," James sighed. "Even if it does get one out of a surprising number of fussy parties. What happened to the Split, anyway?"

"It's weakening," Sirius said, his voice nonchalant, "We knew it wasn't forever. Twelve years is a long time to have held Society so apart. We can't stay separate indefinitely—won't solve anything."

"How Neutral of you." James sounded annoyed. "Don't see any Dark purebloods going to Dumbledore's soiree though, do you?"

"Maybe this year they will," Sirius shot back. Harry could tell from the absurdist bite to his words that he was joking. "The gala is practically a Ministry event anyway, this year. Lord Parkinson's intellectual crowd will all peek in as well, no doubt. Lily and the kids will be fine."

"I know." James heaved a long breath. "I'm just dreading it. Security is going to be a nightmare. The Minister invited half his cabinet, and the other half will probably gate crash. We can't search the guests as they enter without offending everyone's family honor and all that rot, and ceremonial weapons are permitted anyway—not to mention the damage you can do with a wand, if you don't mind being found out as the perpetrator. I've got a team at the estate now, getting familiar with the layout, but with this many people expected I doubt it will make any difference how many Aurors are there."

"It's going to be fine," Sirius insisted, "I'm sure you've planned for every eventuality."

"If I'd had time in the last two months to tie my own shoes I'm sure I would have, too," James said, audibly exasperated. "We've been run ragged with all this jewel searching nonsense."

There was a short pause, into which Sirius made a kind of 'hmm' sound. "How is that going, anyway?"

"Not well. The goblins are breathing down our necks and not saying anything helpful at the same time. We know this thing has something to do with upsetting magical creatures' natural temperament, but there's no solid information on what kind of a danger it poses to society at large. Hogwarts was the first real lead we had, with that mess on Halloween sending the office into a tailspin. We can't exactly raid the place without real evidence on where or who to search. The ward inspection was the best idea we had, and sodding Malfoy came up with that one!"

"How is the cow party mixed up in this anyway?" Sirius asked.

"We don't know," James groaned, "They seem as eager to butt into the investigation as the goblins. If only we knew what this thing was supposed to do, we might have a better idea for motive. I've asked Remus to keep an eye out at the school. I need to go through your library though, if you don't mind. We need hard facts on this thing before we have another mass dragon escape or the selkies go rouge or…whatever. All we know so far is it's dangerous, and whoever has it isn't being careful."

Harry fought against the impulse to step forward, open the door, and go to her father, tell him who she thought had the Dominion Jewel—tell him that it was called that, even. Only the knowledge that she couldn't explain how she'd come by such information kept her feet rooted to the carpet. Maybe she could send in an anonymous tip to the DMLE. Then again, random information wasn't exactly the sort of evidence James needed to perform a legal search and seizure. She could investigate, though. Remus would be keeping his eyes open, apparently, but he didn't know where to look. Harry allowed herself a determined smile. She would add her eyes to Pettigrew's movements. When she had proof to present, she could go to her father. Or, she amended mentally, Archie could go to James.

She knocked on the door before opening it to stick her head in. "Mom says it's time to get dressed, Dad. You too, uncle Sirius."

James blinked at her rather stupidly. "Fawn? Is that you?"

"Course it's me," Harry rolled her eyes, fighting a flush. She didn't look that different.

"You look sparkling, kid," Sirius said, winking, "Lily up to her old magic, eh?"

"I was held as wandpoint for over an hour," Harry deadpanned, "Now it's your turn."

James winced. "She always puts glue in my hair."

The two men wandered off in search of combs and Harry headed to the floo room to wait. Archie was already there when she strode in and debated the merits of sitting and wrinkling the back of her robes or standing awkwardly for the next fifteen minutes or so.

"Don't do it—Aunt Lily will throw a fit," Archie warned her, apparently reading her mind.

"She probably won't," Harry said, biting her lip indecisively.

"She spent ages picking those out," Archie reminded her. Harry glanced down at the loose flowing folds of lavender and sighed. Standing it was.

She leaned one shoulder against the fireplace, surveying her cousin briefly. "Where are your gloves?"

Grimacing, Archie pulled a pair of black dress gloves out of his pockets. "They feel weird. Like I can't use my hands."

"You have to wear them," Harry said, stroking lightly over her own silk-covered fingers.

"I know," Archie moaned, "But how am I supposed to eat?"

"You don't need to eat," Harry said, "I rarely partake at parties."

"Right," Archie sighed despondently, "I'm pretending to be a robot."

"Put your gloves on, robot," Harry chuckled. Archie reluctantly pulled them over his fingers, hiding the green rings that mirrored the ones on her own finger. She'd procured a cheap ring of fake jade for Archie, to match the suppressor she wore, and even without the gloves she didn't think anyone would notice the difference. Rigel was known to prefer wearing gloves, though, so Archie would wear gloves tonight as well.

"Is this going to work?" Archie asked, swallowing with obvious trepidation.

"Just keep your head down," Harry said calmly, "No matter what you do, no one can prove you aren't Rigel Black. My friends will chalk up irregularities to being in Sirius' presence most of the time, so relax when you're with him. When you aren't, just keep your mouth shut unless directly addressed. Better to seem preoccupied than to risk contradicting something they think is true about you. If you get into trouble, just feign amusement. It might be an inside joke."

"The fate of my life hangs on your inside jokes," Archie sighed.

"It hangs on your ability to fake a laugh," Harry corrected him.

Archie laughed loudly, clutching his belly and relaxing all his features into mirth.

"What's so funny?"

James, Sirius, and Lily filed into the floo room, her little sister propped on Sirius' shoulder. All four were dressed to the nines, even Addy, who looked surprisingly alert in her cobalt dress, which made the red hair on her head pop luridly.

"It's an inside joke," Harry said, sending Archie into another round of laughter, this time genuine.

"That's the spirit," Sirius said, rubbing his hands together, "Now. The Parkinsons are an all right lot, so all we need to worry about are the other dark wizards—"

"Sirius," James shook his head exasperatedly.

"What?" Sirius held a wounded hand to his heart. "I'm saying this for Harry's sake, Prongs. Unlike the rest of us, she hasn't dealt with these kind of snobby, tight-eyed people before. Harry, just remember that you can't be formally charged on capital offenses until you're seventeen, so—"

"Please don't encourage my daughter to murder anyone," Lily pleaded.

"Especially anyone she hasn't met yet!" Archie said, grinning. "She might get along really well with the party nobs."

"She'd better not," James grimaced.

"Yeah, no schmoozing with the politicians, Harry," Sirius said.

"I'll just stand in a corner, make no noise, and pretend not to exist," Harry said.

"I don't know, corners can be dangerous places to stand at parties," James mused, "Perhaps you should just stay home."

"She can't," Archie said, pouting, "Professor Snape wants to meet her."

"What?" Sirius frowned, "She's only going to see Snape?"

"He wants to talk to you, too," Archie said innocently.

"Let's not go," Sirius said, eye twitching. Harry marveled at how well he reversed roles, depending on who he was performing for. Hadn't he just played devil's advocate to James' bemoaning about attending the gala? She wondered if that was what a lifetime of practice at dissembling afforded one.

"It's too late, we're already dressed," Lily said, smiling indulgently. "We're going to be endlessly polite and friendly, show everyone how happy and healthy our family is, and have a lovely time. Does everyone have their emergency portkeys?"

"And did everyone put extension charms on their pockets?" Sirius added earnestly. "Remus is partial to chocolate biscuits, so every time you pass a refreshment table be sure to surreptitiously sneak one."

"On the bright side, they probably won't invite us back," Harry said.

"Or we'll be a huge hit," Sirius protested.

"Someone is going to get hit," James muttered.

"Let's just go," Lily sighed, taking Addy from Sirius in preparation for the floo trip.

Sirius volunteered to go first, spinning away in green smoke and ash with a look that was a little too eager to be believable. Archie followed, with Harry close behind. They stepped out of the way for her parents to come through, and once they were all assembled, an extremely well-mannered house elf directed them from the ornate floo room to the adjacent hallway.

It was a corridor of glittering mirrors and gilded portraiture, and as they walked along it eyes followed them from every angle, either their own or someone else's. They could see other groups forming a cue up ahead, waiting to be announced at the entrance to the ballroom.

Harry glanced up to see an enormous archway entwined with golden fairy lights over the main doors. It was like walking through the gates of a grand estate, only inside the house. She had always known that her family, even with their more-than-comfortably-sized houses, understated their income in terms of material possessions. Most of their gold lay in their vaults, uncounted except by goblins, and for the most part ignored. Coming to houses like this had opened her eyes to the true extravagance that was pureblood wealth. It was impossible to ignore the incredible details etched into the frames of each mirror and painting they passed, nor the sumptuous oriental rug that ran the entire length of the corridor beneath their feet.

As they passed beneath the archway, Harry almost couldn't believe the scope of the room before her. She had been to the Rosiers' ballroom the previous year, but the ceilings that had seemed impossibly large then were now dwarfed in her memory by the sight before her. The ballroom itself was shaped something like an arch, much higher in the middle over the dance floor than around the edges. Even the low ends of the room were two stories in themselves, however, with three staircases spaced evenly on the left and right sides of the room that led up to spacious indoor balconies. She could already see dozens of people gazing down over the low banisters, observing the room from what was probably a spectacular viewpoint. On the far end of the room from the main entrance, she could just glimpse a long table that likely held refreshments for the dancers, many of whom already moved gracefully in the center of the classically tiled floor.

She couldn't see where the music was coming from at first, until she realized it emanated from a giant chandelier hanging in the epicenter of the ballroom. The ornament dripped with pearls and what she suspected were real diamonds, rather than crystals. It struck her how clever is was to center the music above the dance floor. The dancers would be able to hear it equally well whichever side they were on, yet the music would be fainter from the edges of the room, where people were more inclined to strike up conversation.

They reached the front of the receiving line, and Sirius hung back with Archie to allow the Potters to go first. Usually James wouldn't be in the receiving line, as he was there in official capacity in addition to being a guest, but as his family was there, and particularly as his children were to be presented for the first time, he was bound by the duties of his House to make introductions.

"Lord James Potter, Lady Lillian Potter, and daughters Harriett and Adriana Potter," the announcer called out, cueing them to step forward to where the Parkinsons waited, expressions politely expectant. She could see Pansy on her mother's left, dressed in forest green robes with filigreed gold at her waist and hem.

James approached first, with Lily at his elbow. Harry stood a half-step back on her mother's side, just far enough away that Addy's grasping fingers couldn't pull at her hair from where she perched.

"Lord Potter," Mr. Parkinson intoned, "We are grateful for all of your help in organizing the security details for this evening."

"Let us hope they prove superfluous," James said, inclining his head shortly.

"And Lillian, it had been much too long," Mrs. Parkinson said, stepping forward to embrace Lily briefly, mindful of Addy sitting in Lily's right arm.

"So long you've forgotten to call me Lily," her mother said, a soft smile adorning her face. "How are you, Rose? I daresay you've outdone yourself this year."

"There, you see, Cassius?" Mrs. Parkinson smiled widely, "I told you the fairy lights weren't too much. I shall tell anyone who says otherwise that the Lillian Potter has given the party her aesthetic approval—that will still their tongues."

"First we ought to still our own, at least until the introductions are complete, my dear," Mr. Parkinson said, a slight hint of amusement in his tone.

"Of course," Mrs. Parkinson laughed lightly, "It was so good to see you again that I forgot myself. Lord Potter, Lady Potter, let me present to you my daughter, Pandora—"

"Honestly, Mother," Pansy sighed.

"—who prefers to be called Pansy," Mrs. Parkinson finished with an indulgent glance in her daughter's direction.

"It is a pleasure to meet you, Pansy," Lily said with a sly smile of her own. "You might get on well with our own daughters, Harriett, who insists that she was named Harry, and Adriana, who we call Addy for brevity's sake."

"I'm sure I will," Pansy said, turning curious eyes in Harry's direction.

Harry's instincts summoned up a deferential bow before she could stop herself. Halfway through she realized she was wearing skirts, but had no graceful option except to complete the dip as naturally as she was able and offer a smile to the Parkinsons that she hoped took the edge off of any perceived slight.

"How charming," Mrs. Parkinson said, positively beaming at her. "It is so wonderful to finally meet you, Harry. And you as well, of course, Addy." She wiggled her gloved fingers shyly at Addy, who blinked big blue eyes in her direction and gurgled a bit.

"Thank you for having us at your estate this evening, Lord Parkinson, Lady Parkinson," Harry said, keeping her voice soft even though without the voice-altering charm she didn't sound too much like Rigel these days. "It's lovely to meet you, Pansy," she added, offering her friend a distant smile.

"You are most welcome, all of you," Mr. Parkinson said. With a sweep of his hands he gestured to the ballroom at large. "Please, enjoy your night."

They moved off to one side to allow Sirius and Archie space to greet their hosts.

"I didn't know you knew the Parkinsons, Mum," Harry remarked as they waited.

"Long ago," Lily said, "Before the Split, Dark and Light aligned families nearly always attended the same functions. Some charity, some political, others just for fun. There used to be a grand Yule Ball at the Ministry each year, but they stopped throwing it when prominent members from either side of the Split refused to attend as long as families from the other side were attending. I did not know Rose Parkinson so well as all that, however. She is an eminently friendly soul, and pretends to a greater affection than we carried in truth between us."

"It is part of her charm," James put in, "And the only thing that makes her husband's company bearable."

Lily discretely elbowed James in the side. "Be nice. He is our host, and he was perfectly polite."

"Exactly," James snorted, "Perfectly polite. And not one iota more."

"It's not as if they owe us anything," Lily said quietly, "Politeness is more than enough, for tonight."

"More than we expected, at any rate," James allowed. He ran a hand through his hair automatically, only to wince when he intercepted his wife's annoyed glare.

"Hold Addy while I fix this," Lily said, shifting the infant to her hands and holding her in Harry's direction.

Harry tried to shake her head, but Lily was depositing the baby in her arms before she could voice a protest. To her surprise, Addy seemed perfectly content to finger Harry's short curls while sucking on her own fist. Of course, she realized a moment later. She was projecting her aura now, so Addy wasn't unnerved by her presence. Taking full advantage, she pressed Addy close to kiss her cheek in a rarely allowed show of affection. Addy smiled, a bubble of spit dripping cheerfully from her open lips.

Lily casually plucked her husband's handkerchief from his breast pocket and wiped the drool away before taking Addy back into her arms. Before she could return James' handkerchief to his pocket, they were approached by a portly man in a bowler hat who said, "Potter! At last! That fellow you assigned me won't stop hovering."

"Minister." James greeted him with a professional smile. "It is his job to hover."

"Well tell him to do it from further away." The Minister, who Harry now recognized as the confidently smiling man in the Prophet, flapped his hands agitatedly. "How am I to charm new contributors for my next campaign with that stony mug looming over my shoulder?"

"I'll tell Dawlish to loom from ten feet, how's that?" James said, a smile tucked away into the corner of his mouth.

"Not satisfactory," the Minister said, frowning, "I need your pretty face, Potter. Come guard me." James gave Lily an apologetic glance, which the Minister caught with a jolt of exaggerated surprise. "Oh! Your lovely wife must come, too. My wife is dying to see her, anyway." The Minister peered at Harry with curiosity. "This your daughter, Potter? My little sunshine would be glad to entertain her for a while."

Remembering Draco's disparaging comments about the Minister's daughter the year before, Harry said quickly, "I'll wait here for Archie and Sirius."

"Black?" the Minister smiled widely, "Good, good. Tell him I want to talk to him before he leaves tonight—now that the Black House is Neutral again, we have a few things to discuss."

Harry thought that sounded rather ominous, and was suddenly glad to be inconsequential as she waved sarcastically to her parents, who were herded quite expertly into the crowd.

Archie and Sirius joined her not a minute later. "Did they lose you already?" Sirius asked with a laugh.

"They were captured by the Minister and pressed into his service," Harry said, "I barely escaped with my life. He's after you next, Uncle Sirius."

"Thanks for the warning," Sirius said, "Now I know who to avoid."

"Not talking about me, I hope."

Regulus Black emerged from the crowd just behind his brother, who gave a half-hearted wince as he turned to greet him. He was dressed impeccably, if severely, in all black, his dark hair pushed back neatly in contrast to Sirius' wild mane.

"Reggie," Sirius said bracingly, "How are you?"

"Just tickled to see you, brother," Regulus said. His voice could have been mistaken for the scraping of a knife across stale bread.

"It's wonderful to see you, too, Uncle," Archie put in before Sirius could give a retort, "What have you been up to?"

"The usual," Regulus said, sounding bored, "Protecting people from their own stupidity."

"I told you when you specialized in ward construction that you would spend all your time arguing with architects," Sirius said archly.

"At least I spend my time doing something," Regulus said, one eyebrow lifting, "When was the last time you added to our family's fortunes instead of merely depleting them, Brother?"

"I have a team of incredibly talented investors who do that for me," Sirius said, waving his hand dismissively.

"And how do they feel about you going Neutral?" Regulus asked, a sly smirk adorning one cheek, "Are they just ecstatic? Does it warm their accounting books to know that all those galleons you've been funneling into the Light Party's donation fund are safe in the vault where they belong?"

"My employees don't give a rat's arse what I do with my money," Sirius said, scowling.

"Hmm, and what about Dumbledore?" Regulus pressed, his smirk widening further. "How is the old puppet-master getting along without your oh-so-regular contributions?"

Harry's eyes widened as she realized for the first time that Sirius claiming Neutral status might have greater repercussions than he had intimated to them.

"Lord Dumbledore will be fine for a few years," Sirius said stiffly.

"So you admit you swung Neutral only in name, in a distasteful attempt to squirm your way back into the world your son has already begun to embrace, like a child swimming after its parent into deepening water." Regulus had lost his smirk, and now looked merely disdainful. "Is Lord Potter donating double, to compensate for your clinging need to smother your Heir? Or perhaps you're still funneling galleons in your friend's name."

Sirius stiffened and even Archie looked shocked that his Uncle would state such an accusation out loud.

"You impugn my honor, Brother?" Sirius actually sneered, a look that brought him closer to the old paintings of Black Family Heads than Harry had ever known he could come. "You only insult yourself, as I am the Lord of the House you serve."

"As long as you acknowledge that I am the only one of us currently serving the House of Black," Regulus said smoothly, and oily smile his answer to Sirius' affront. "Well, me and your son, that is."

He gave Archie an ironic nod, which Archie did not return, instead meeting his uncle's gaze evenly, insulted pride on his father's behalf obvious in his eyes.

Regulus shrugged minutely at Archie's silence, and turned his attention to Harry instead. "Who's this, then?"

"I'm Harry," she said, smiling ever so politely, "Your…second cousin once removed, Mr. Black."

"Potter's Heiress," Regulus said, grimacing slightly, "Careful of the company you keep, Rigel."

With that, he walked off, leaving Sirius to fume for about thirty seconds before pulling himself together visibly.

"Well. Why don't you two run along and meet Archie's friends?" Sirius suggested. "I'm going to get a drink before I find some way to royally embarrass little Reggie until he remembers to avoid me."

She really couldn't tell if her uncle was kidding. They dutifully bid him goodbye, though, and began searching for her classmates.

"Stop searching so obviously," Archie said lowly after a moment, "I should be the one to recognize them, not you."

She didn't think anyone would be watching them so closely, but she did as he asked, scanning the room more subtly as Archie looked obviously about them.

"Maybe they aren't here yet," Archie said, frowning.

"The Malfoys at least have to be here," Harry told him, "They're close with the Parkinsons, and were probably one of the first families to arrive."

"I see blonde hair that way," Archie said, gesturing to the far side of the dance floor.

"I think that's Draco's parents," Harry said, "You don't want to talk to them yet—Mr. Malfoy can sense fear."

"I'm not afraid of him," Archie protested.

"You should be," Harry snorted. She caught sight of Millicent suddenly through a gap in the crowd. "This way."

She pretended to follow Archie, all the while mumbling directions, until he recognized the group of young purebloods she was leading him toward. She dearly hoped his memorizing pictures from backlogged society pages at the public library would get him through the introductions without hiccup.

Draco, Theo, Millicent, and Blaise all stood together near a pillar under one of the balconies. They looked over when Theo called "Rigel!" with a grin stretching his thin features.

"Hey Theo, good to see you," Archie said, smiling easily. He checked himself after a moment, reigning in his smile to a more reserved expression. "Draco, Millicent, Blaise. How's the party?"

"Excellent," Millicent said, "The food is being made continuously. It tastes like you plucked it from the chef's hands yourself."

"And the music is instrumental, thank Merlin," Blaise said with an appreciatory smirk, "Not that vocal extravagance last year."

"I liked the merfolk band," Theo protested.

"You would," Blaise snorted, "Sirens sing sweeter, and they can do it above water."

"And half the guests would suspect they were being hypnotized," Theo argued.

"Only the paranoid ones like you," Archie put in with a grin.

Well done, she mentally applauded him. All that time studying her friends' defining characteristics had paid off.

"At least I haven't left my cousin just standing there without an introduction," Theo sniffed. He relaxed into a more friendly expression a moment later. "Do you remember me, Miss Potter? We met in Quality Quidditch once."

"I remember you mistook me for me cousin, Mr. Nott," Harry said, smiling.

"You had shorter hair then," Theo said, coughing embarrassedly.

"It's Harriett, right?" Millicent said, leaning forward to catch Harry's eyes curiously.

"Just Harry is fine," she said, blinking uneasily from behind her glasses. Would Millicent think it odd that her eyes were less brilliant than rumored? "You're…Millicent, is that right?" She glanced at Archie as though double-checking.

Archie nodded, "Harry, this is Millicent Bulstrode, Theo you already know, Draco Malfoy, and Blaise Zabini." He nodded to each of them in turn.

Harry dipped a small curtsey, feeling entirely out of place doing so. "It's nice to finally meet you all. Rigel has told me so much about you."

"Not too much, I hope," Blaise said, eyeing her in what looked like indulgent amusement. "We hardly know a thing about you."

"We know she's interested in potions," Theo said, seemingly taking it upon himself, as the only one who'd met her before, to smooth her way into the conversation.

"More even than me, if you can believe it," Archie put in, grinning slightly.

"We really can't," Draco said drolly.

There was an awkward pause, in which Harry affected polite aloofness to hide the feeling that she was intruding on something. She had known intellectually that meeting her friends as Harry would be different from meeting the Weasleys, whose easy acceptance was a reflection on their open-heartedness, not on the way friendships worked in general. She wondered if she had adequately prepared herself emotionally, however, as her Slytherin friends visibly hesitated on how to proceed.

"Did you all hear about that dragon escape?" Archie said, painfully drawing the subject into neutral territory. "It was all over the news before Yule, but they haven't printed much since then. Have they caught them all yet?"

"Only three," Blaise said, "The press is keeping a lid on it, so it looks less like incompetence at this point."

"Even though that's what it is," Draco said, sneering, "Those dragon-lovers on the reserves can hardly control the beasts in their fear to hurt them."

"Dragons are kind of hard to control in the wild," Archie said fairly, "It's difficult to make them go anywhere, when they can run in so many directions; all they can do is keep them away from human settlements until they run out of energy and fall asleep."

"They aren't doing a very good job, though, are they?" Millicent said, shaking her head exasperatedly, "My father told me one of them went hunting in a menagerie in Spain a few days ago. Caused an international incident, since apparently it ate a few members of an endangered species they were trying to repopulate there."

"They shouldn't be breeding magical creatures at a menagerie anyway," Blaise said scathingly, "Wizards never get it right. The creatures end up with mutations that then end up in the genetic pool and weaken the species substantially."

"Like the unicorns they tried to breed in America," Draco said, mouth twisted in distaste, "The whole herd ended up slaughtered by a pack of rouge werewolves, because they couldn't run as fast as true unicorns ought to be able to."

"And the muggles running the American Ministry acted like it wasn't their fault!" Theo exclaimed, "Like they weren't messing with sacred magic their half-formed cores couldn't possibly underst—oh." He looked suddenly at Harry like he'd been jolted with low-grade lightning. "Uh, no offense. It's true, though…" he trailed off with an awkward mutter.

"No offense taken," she said faintly, her face perfectly blank even as her heart pounded uncomfortably hard in her stomach. He hadn't said the word 'mudblood' to describe the American officials—no one in polite company used the word so freely—but by calling them 'muggles' it was a strongly implied sentiment. Everyone knew the Americans didn't hold with pureblood elitism, and often overemployed muggleborns and halfbloods in their international departments as a big thumb to the nose at other countries.

Archie looked incredibly uncertain, likely feeling a strange sort of guilt that her own friends were treating her so carelessly. She should have told him to expect it—should have expected it more herself, really. She recalled how stilted and pointed all of them had been with one another, when they first arrived at Hogwarts, and they were all on somewhat even footing at the time. Now, with her the strange halfblood they'd just met, coming into their circle with only Rigel's recommendation to say they ought to like her, well, she could understand the defensive, even somewhat possessive look in their eyes as they assessed her. She was Rigel's other friend, the one he'd known since birth and possibly valued more than them. She understood the unspoken comparison that was going on, even as she felt it abominably unfair that she should have to compete for her friends' affection with herself.

She could feel Draco's gaze on her, and wondered what he was sensing from her emotions. Hurt? Understanding? Or Betrayal? Whatever it was, she doubted it made a whole lot of sense to him.

The conversation moved on in fits and starts, and Harry realized none of them were going to relax as long as she stood there, among them yet apart. The forced casualness became too much after a few minutes, and Harry quietly and politely excused herself, faking a friendly parting smile with what she thought was remarkable skill. Archie looked like he might protest, likely afraid of what he might say or do without her there. Harry had faith in him, though, and let him see the encouragement in her eyes as she turned away.

She felt oddly touched, that her friends could be so protective of 'Rigel,' but she also felt acutely shunned, knowing that at least part of their unfriendliness was because of her blood-status. It was always glossed over when they spoke of Harry to Rigel, but she ought to have predicted that something easily ignored in conversation would be more jarring when confronted for the first time in the flesh.

She supposed to them a lower blood status was something like a disease. Like spattergroit, maybe. It was one thing to describe the symptoms in compassionate terms in a textbook; facing the grotesque reality of the disease in the form of the actually afflicted would always be more difficult. It was an instinctive disgust, to them, and Harry supposed she would feel the same if confronted with something she had been raise to think disgusting—like a dead body, or a torture curse.

She took that knowledge into herself, making it clinical and holding it tightly until it didn't hurt anymore.

Not sure what to do with herself, she eventually settled on climbing to one of the balconies and taking in the party from above. If nothing else, it would be a glittering, beautiful memory that might distract her from the last fifteen minutes or so.

She chose the least occupied balcony, not wanting to fight for viewing space with other, much taller guests. The stairs curved elegantly as she ascended, giving her a moving perspective of the entire crowd as she climbed, from the line of people still entering under the main archway to the old biddies circling the hors-d'oeuvre table like particularly discerning vultures.

The gently swirling couples on the dance floor were somewhat mesmerizing from above, and Harry allowed herself to get lost in watching them for a moment. A taller body settled in next to her at the balcony, and after a moment, spoke.

"Rather graceful, aren't they?" she was surprised to recognize Rosier's voice and turned her head up toward him, but he wasn't looking at her. He was staring down at the dance floor in deep ennui. "Almost beautiful, when you can't see their faces."

She didn't know what to say to that, not sure Rosier even knew who he was talking to.

"That's my friend down there, with his future wife," the older boy said, almost to himself. "Looks happy, doesn't he?"

"Which one?" she asked, though she knew full well, able to see Rookwood and Selwyn's twirling figures from where she stood.

He glanced over at her for a moment, as though surprised she had answered, then did a double take. "Ri—no. You're…" His eyes flicked across her face, to her hair, her mouth, then settling on her glasses and the eyes behind them.

"I'm Harry," she offered, "Rigel's cousin."

"Aldon," Rosier said, smiling faintly, "Nice to meet you."

"You say that like you mean it," Harry said before she could stop herself.

"I do." Rosier blinked curiously down at her. "People being unfriendly?"

"No," she said quickly, shaking her head, "No, of course not. You just—ah, seem especially sincere."

"Well that's one I haven't heard before," Rosier laughed.

Harry blinked at him innocently, "Why's that? Do you lie a lot?"

"No more than most," he said, shrugging.

"Most people you know? Or no more than most people in general do?" she pressed.

"I suppose I can only speak for those I've met," he said slowly.

"Maybe you should keep better company," Harry said idly.

"You volunteering?"

She turned away to hide her smile, looking back over the pulsing crowd. "I was here first, but I guess I can't make you leave."

"You wound me, fair lady," Rosier said, sighing dramatically.

"Don't bother," Harry huffed, "Rigel's told me all about you."

"What does Rigel say about me?" Rosier asked, leaning toward her with undisguised interest.

"He says you like to confuse people," she told him.

Rosier looked perplexed at that, leaning back against the balcony banister with a thoughtful expression. "Rigel is intimidated by those who might see him too clearly. He confuses himself."

Harry looked back at the ballroom below them, wondering at that. She didn't know he thought so much about her—Rigel, that is.

"So what are you doing up here, cousin of Rigel's?" he asked, resuming a front-facing position next to her so he could gaze down in boredom at the masses.

"I don't really fit in down there," she said, surprising herself with her own honesty. Maybe she just needed to say it. Maybe if she said it out loud it would release some of the pressure in her chest. She looked sideways to judge his reaction, hoping for something other than pity or contempt. Understanding, maybe? He looked pained, at least. "It's all right," she said, not sure if she was reassuring him or herself, "I didn't really expect to. It just sort of hit me for a moment. It's quieter up here."

"Quieter in your head, you mean," Rosier said, "I understand."

For a little while that was enough. Even if he was only being nice to her because she reminded him of Rigel, or because he rejected everything his family stood for, including their hatred of people like her. She still appreciated it. They stood in silence, just soaking in the atmosphere passively.

"Want to count how many people we can see pretending not to be drunk?" Rosier suggested after a time.

"You're on," she said, scanning the crowd immediately, "There. That woman in the blue fur shawl just spilled her drink down her front, and now she's trying to wipe it up without looking like she's adjusting herself."

"The one giggling?" Rosier laughed lowly, "She's definitely tipsy. How about that man, in the brown top hat? He keeps teetering."

Harry shook her head. "He's wearing risers in his shoes to make himself seem taller. See how his tailored pants don't quite reach down to where they should? He's tried to disguise it by wearing boots, but you can tell because those are the boots he wears outside, and the pant leg is showing part of the boot that usually stays covered—see? The material is lighter where is doesn't normally get exposed to the elements."

Rosier stared at her. "How could you possibly see that? Do those glasses magnify things?"

Harry smiled secretively. They did indeed, though she didn't usually advertise that fact. "It would be pretty inefficient to wear glasses that only corrected my sight."

"You cheat!" he said, smiling widely.

"It's only cheating if I use this pair for Quidditch," she said.

"Well I feel cheated," Rosier protested.

"I'll let you have the next one," she said kindly.

"I only met you ten minutes ago and you're already patronizing me," he said incredulously.

"I was patronizing you the whole time," she told him sadly.

"All right, so that's how it is," he muttered, turning back to the dance floor with a scowl. "There. Lady in the orange shoes. Just started doing the steps to the Italian version of that dance while they're clearly playing the French music."

"I thought this song was Austrian," Harry frowned.

Rosier laughed, though not too unkindly, "Way off, Miss Potter."

"Just Harry," she said, feeling a bit like a broken record that night. "Oh, there's one—the man in those weirdly-cut satin robes, over by the far staircase."

"In the shadows there?" Rosier squinted. "He doesn't seem drunk."

"That because he just took a sobering potion," Harry laughed.

"You saw him?" he asked, smirking.

She shook her head. "See how he winces every time the lady next to him raises her voice to talk to that old man on her other side? And how he averts his eyes from the lights? That man has a serious hangover, and unless he got drunk at eight o clock this morning, it's because he just took a sobriety potion and is waiting for it to fully kick in. The cheaper ones take the buzz away first, then cure the headache once the willow bark fully breaks down in the system."

"You are uncommonly observant," Rosier sighed, "I am never going to win this."

"Is there anything you're good at?" she asked, laughing lightly. Her smile fell when he was quiet a moment too long.

"Probably," he said, not looking at her and letting out a short laugh she could tell was forced.

She felt like that was her cue to say something, but she wasn't really any good at comforting people. They lapsed into silence once more, not entirely uncomfortable, but not the easy calm that it had been, either.

"I should go back," she said eventually, "Check on my family."

"I'll walk you down," he said, the pureblood gentleman once again.

They descended the staircase slowly, neither particularly eager to rejoin the scene. As they reached the bottom, he grasped her hand suddenly.

"Would you like to dance?" his eyes stared down at her, imploring, but all Harry could think was how strange that would be, dancing with Aldon Rosier.

"Not on your life," she said, summoning the smile Rispah had taught her for use when turning people down to soften the bluntness of her speech.

"You and Rigel are quite a pair," Rosier said, smiling with the tiniest bit of self-deprecation as he released her.

She resisted the urge to roll her eyes. "If you say so, Rosier."

"It's Aldon," he said quietly, staring at her with a frown.

Belatedly she realized he hadn't introduced himself with a last name, which meant it was odd of her to use it. "Of course," she said, smiling sheepishly, "Rigel calls you that—sorry."

"It's all right," he said, gold eyes relaxing from their sharp inspection. He looked a little disappointed for some reason.

She glanced around the room indecisively. Should she rejoin her parents? Try to find Archie? A sudden glimpse of curtain-like black hair from across the room decided her—Professor Snape was here. "I have to go do something," she said, looking up at Rosier with a half-grimace. "It was nice to meet you. Thanks for…you know, distracting me."

Rosier bowed shallowly with a smirking grin. "Anytime at all, Miss Potter."

"Harry," she said, shooting him an annoyed look before she made a beeline through the crowd. Now was as good a time as any to have Archie 'introduce' her to Master Snape. She just had to find her cousin first.

He watched the Potter Heiress disappear into the sea of people around them and wondered that Fate should plague him with another Rigel Black—albeit a softer, more relaxed version that didn't seem to know it was strange to be so unflinchingly honest to someone you just met.

A tap on his shoulder turned his attention to Edmund, who had apparently danced through the soles of his shoes and finally abandoned the dance floor—though not his dancing partner, who even Aldon had to admit looked ravishing that night. Really, he could understand Edmund's fascination with the girl at times like these.

"Still sulking?" Alice asked, her kohl-lined eyes slightly narrowed in mocking appraisal.

Then she went and opened her mouth and Aldon remembered why he thought his friend could do better than that soulless harpy.

"Was that her?" Edmund asked, his eyes following the wake of the Potter Heiress with thinly disguised curiosity. "Rigel's cousin? I've heard people saying the Potters were here."

"It was," Aldon said, affecting a light-hearted expression for his friend's sake—no need to infect the happy with melancholy thoughts. "She's a bold one. Very much like Rigel." Only not nearly so defensive, he added to himself.

"They are engaged," Edmund rumbled, "Pansy informed me just before break."

He wasn't sure what he felt, but it was something between disgruntlement and longing. "They won't marry," he said, nothing but certainty infecting his tone.

"Sure that's not just wistful thinking?" Alice said. He could easily detect the pity and censure that colored her tone.

Aldon gave her his coldest smile. "It would be like marrying oneself, so alike are they. Such a waste. It won't bear fruit."

"You like her," Edmund said, smiling slightly.

"I don't dislike her," Aldon corrected. Honestly, he'd met the chit an hour ago.

"High praise," Alice rolled her eyes.

"She'll be an interesting one to watch, at least," Aldon allowed, generously ignoring Selwyn's attitude problems.

"Don't you have enough to interest you, Aldon?" Edmund looked disapproving, but that was not a novel look for him, at least where Aldon was concerned. Lifelong friendship did not exactly equate to a lifetime of support and encouragement in every pursuit—on either of their sides.

"Never enough," Aldon sighed. Nothing was ever enough to relieve the boredom. Some things pushed the cold feelings back for a while, but nothing he'd found so far could banish them completely.

She could tell Archie was nervous as she subtly steered him in Snape's direction. He had been having a relatively good time with her friends, it seemed, though it didn't surprise her, as one of Archie's strengths was his ability to meld seamlessly into any situation he found himself in. She couldn't think of a single person he'd ever met that he didn't get on with.

"Just make the introduction and then make yourself scarce," she told him quietly as they wove through the crowd. "The last thing you want is to get caught up in a potions conversation—you're good, but not good enough to pass Snape's scrutiny."

"I know," Archie said, laughing a bit hysterically, "Why do you think I'm so concerned?"

"He won't be looking too closely at you," Harry assured him, "He'll take you for granted at this point. Keep it simple, and you'll be fine."

"Simple," Archie said, nodding. "I can do simple."

"There he is," Harry said, indicating a group up ahead that included the Malfoys and Regulus Black in addition to Snape himself.

Archie cleared his throat uncomfortably, but squared his shoulders and approached the little circle with something like aplomb. As he neared, the Malfoys stepped slightly back in an inclusionary way, and Harry couldn't help but be moved on Archie's behalf. The Malfoys really were too good to her—Rigel—whoever.

"Lord Malfoy, Lady Malfoy, Uncle Regulus." Archie's bow was perfectly deferential. "Please excuse me, but I would like to borrow Professor Snape for a moment."

Snape glanced from Archie to Harry without expression. "Excuse me, gentlemen, lady, I must attend to this."

The other three all intimated various degrees of gracious agreement, and Snape led her and Archie to the room's periphery, his face as unreadable as stone.

Archie, probably eager to get the interaction over with, turned to Snape with an open expression. "Sir, this is my cousin, Harriett Potter. Harry, Master Snape would like to speak with you regarding the potions knowledge that is passed between us." Neither Harry nor Snape spoke, instead opting to size one another up in silence. Archie waited a beat, then said, rather abruptly, "About that other thing, Professor Snape…" When Snape's eyes flicked toward him questioningly, Archie hastened, "The apprenticeship, I mean."

"What about it?" Snape asked, eyes assessing, "Have you reconsidered?"

"Not at all," Archie said, voice sure. "I had some advice for when you approached my father, though, if you don't mind it."

"I welcome it," Snape drawled, managing to only sound a tad bit sarcastic and long-suffering.

"Try to time it so that you make the offer in front of my uncle Regulus," Archie said, eyes careful. "If you make it seem as though it's a matter concerning me as the Black Heir, not just as my father's son, he will feel obligated to consider it seriously. With my uncle there watching, I believe my father will be more likely to evaluate the offer from the perspective of the Family, rather than just in terms of what he thinks would be best for me."

Snape looked as surprised as Harry felt. She had no idea Archie was so empathetic when it came to Sirius' impulses. She always underestimated the close bond that existed between the two.

"An astute suggestion, Mr. Black." Snape inclined his head slowly. "I will take it under advisement."

With a final glace between the two of them, Archie began slowly edging away. "I'll just leave you to it, then."

Harry bowed deeply to her professor, saying quietly, "I cannot thank you enough for your lassitude in this matter. Rigel's second-hand instruction has been inestimably valuable to my own education, and it is thanks to you that I am afforded it, Master Snape."

She lifted her head when he did not immediately respond, meeting fathomless black eyes with no small amount of trepidation. If he wanted to, Snape could easily refuse to 'share' any more of his knowledge with Harriett Potter, thus rendering their explanation for her impeccable potions education rather holey.

It was a strange feeling, to be completely at another's mercy in such a way. She couldn't say she enjoyed it, but she comforted herself with the knowledge that even if he completely refused her any future knowledge, she would still be studying under him in Rigel's guise. It would make their eventual reversal less believable perhaps, but it wouldn't do irreversible damage to their deception. It was with equanimity, then, that she met Snape's gaze, ready for whatever he thought to throw her way.

It was not often that Severus had to consciously force himself to look at something. He had not led a sheltered existence, and had come across and catalogued innumerable disgusting and chill-inducing specimens of nature. He flinched from neither man nor beast, but at that moment it was difficult to prevent his eyes turning away from the sight before them.

The girl had been sent to torture him, perhaps in payment for some offense he'd laid against the gods. Every feature was a barb, digging into his soul with careless momentum. Her hair, arranged in exactly the style Lily had favored as a girl. Her eyes, a watered-down bastardization of the green they imitated. More than their color, though, it was the expression they carried that had him grinding his teeth. The girl looked at him like he were a magistrate, and she awaited a stay of execution order. Didn't she know how foolish it was to give power over oneself to a complete stranger? She gazed up at him calmly, even with the fervent hope burning in her eyes. Was she an idiot, to place so much unnecessary faith in a name she'd read in some backlogged Guild periodical?

He supposed there was a simple way to find out.

He couldn't recall what inane speech she'd made as he considered the merits of walking away, but it didn't matter. He would not be swayed by words of supplication or gratitude, no matter how neatly thought out. He cared only for talent, and he need only discover whether she truly possessed any, or whether she was, as he half-suspected, merely riding her more talented cousin's coattails.

"I read the notes you sent me," he informed her, aware that the silkiness in his tone had been known to send grown men into tremors. "You have a very forthright style of explanation, which will serve you well in academic endeavors. It is much like Rigel's."

The flat insinuation ought to have taken the anticipatory flush right out of her cheeks—instead she merely raised an eyebrow as though he'd said something somewhat interesting, but ultimately trite.

"Rigel and I are both academics—we learned our styles from the same essays and issues growing up." She did not appear to give his unstated accusation any weight. "Did you find the notes interesting? Do you think the brewing technique I outlined might be worth implementing on a larger scale?"

He did, in fact, find the possibilities raised by such a process intriguing, but that was not the substance of the discussion he wanted to have. "It seemed altogether impossible for most mid-level brewers to imitate," he said, sneering slightly in a habitual reflex that was directed more at himself than at the girl. It had taken enormous amounts of concentration and willpower for him to replicate even the most rudimentary of the shaped imbuing recipes outlined in the notes she'd sent him. That with the instructions before him and the knowledge that what he was attempting was theoretically possible. The idea that this slip of a girl had created such a technique on accident was an insult to the abilities of Potions Masters everywhere.

"Most people don't bother learning wandless magic." The child shrugged—shrugged, as though such a skill ought to be taken for granted. "Once you can perform the requisite magic, the brewing itself is simple."

"Forgive me," he said lowly, eyes flashing in what his students would recognize as a warning, "But how is it that you are able to perform the requisite magic, Miss Potter?"

She looked wary for a moment, then noticeably relaxed, as though she'd considered it, but ultimately dismissed his words as a threat. "I've always had good magical control, Master Snape."

"This technique requires excellent magical control," he said sharply, looking for any sign of a lie in her attentive expression. "And a not inconsiderable amount of raw magic to power that control. Frankly, I doubt you have the reserves necessary to make this a worthwhile technique."

Her eyes widened slightly in what he assumed was belated understanding, but she didn't appear either guilty or conniving as she answered, merely…sheepish. "It's true I don't have an incredibly powerful core or anything." She actually smiled up at him as though apologizing for the natural state of her magic. "But I've enough for one relatively-powerful Shaped Imbued potion before my core runs dangerously low. It does make the research slow-going, but it's not as though I can do magic over the holidays anyway—I may as well use it all in my experiments."

Severus stared down at her, not sure if she was deliberately misinterpreting his words or just immune to insinuation. He had only glanced at her aura at the Guild's workshop, mostly out of curiosity's sake, but he had noted her low reserves. Did she think she could bluff her way around a basic lack of power? She couldn't know that he was able to easily discern her core's magic level through her aura, but she ought to know that eventually she would need to prove in person that she could use the technique she was claiming to have invented.

She continued to stand there patiently, not fidgeting or showing any signs of unease even while he took an uncomfortably long time in answering each of her statements. Feeling no remorse for any discomfort she was suppressing, Severus took a moment to adjust his magical sight. He would check her aura again, just to be sure of his assessment.

Her Occlumency shields came into focus first, and he frowned as he took in their general shape and feel—they were very similar to the way Rigel's had been constructed, the last time he'd bothered to peruse them, making him suspect that his student had been teaching his cousin more than just potions. Severus turned his attention to the next level of his magical sight, the aura.

What he found didn't make immediate sense. Her magic reserves appeared perfectly adequate—slightly above average, in fact. He didn't understand how he could have misread the projection that summer; her aura was rudimentary in its simplicity. Nothing complicated about this one, he thought, the snideness calming his mind and allowing him to reach for the obvious explanation. Clearly she'd exercised her magic heavily before the open house that day. If she had brewed one final Shaped Imbued potion before the presentations, the aura he had read reflected her state of exhaustion, not her true average.

In retrospect, he ought to have found the low levels of magic he'd observed a little odd. Whatever else could be said about her parents, their magic was strong.

"Tell me about your schooling," he said eventually, opting to drop the subject of her magical ability completely—he would take it as true that she could have come up with her technique.

"I attend the American Institute of Magic," she said, looking a little perplexed.

"You are not in the Potions tract," he prompted, remembering Rigel's convoluted explanation of this fact.

The girl nodded slowly. "The Healing tract at AIM is better than the Potions tract. The knowledge I would have learned in Master Tallum's classes I can pick up more efficiently in self-study. The Healing classes there are superb, however, imparting knowledge that cannot be learned from books. By joining the Healing tract, I optimize my learning."

"Which will you choose, in the end?" he asked.

"Potions," she said. The statement was neither earnest in an attempt to convince him nor casually thoughtless. It was a simple relation of fact.

"Why learn to Heal at all, then?"

She gave him an odd look. "Rigel has already explained this, hasn't he?"

"He did a poor job of it," Severus told her, smirking slightly. Rigel was at times both long-winded and incredibly circulatory in conversation, when he truly cared about the subject matter.

Looking slightly exasperated, she sighed. "I'm learning Healing because Rigel could not attend AIM himself. The same reason he is studying under your expertise, Master Snape. We both have near-equal interest in both subjects. So we each chose the one we could get the best instruction for at our respective schools, and we trade tutelage whenever we have the chance."

"It seems rather incredible that the two of you would be such devoted scholars from so young an age," he said, making his disbelief plain. "However did you come up with such a scheme?"

"Needs must," she said, shrugging slightly. He could tell she was becoming uncomfortable as his questions became more personal.

"And so you want my permission to continue learning through Rigel all that I teach him," Severus said, mercifully moving back to a neutral conversational point.

"I would very much appreciate it," she said, accentuating her statement with a short nod. "You don't know me, but I'm just as dedicated as Rigel is, in regards to potions. I've spent my whole life studying the field, but not everything can be learned from books. The Guild's internship showed me just how much more I could learn from a Master, and to be frank, you're the best, Sir. I won't squander your teachings. I won't use them for unscrupulous gain or take credit for the knowledge in any way. I just want to be a good Potions Master."

"Mistress," he corrected absently. Her face twisted in something like distaste for a moment before it smoothed into a nod of agreement. He filed that reaction away, thinking the chit may be wiser in the ways of the field she wished so fervently to enter than he'd assumed.

"As you are aware, I am attempting to take Rigel on as my apprentice this year," Severus told her, allowing a forbidding expression to cross his face. "You are asking me to essentially put my name behind two apprentices, to take responsibility for your potions career as well as your cousin's."

"You'll hardly notice me," the girl said quickly. "I'll be like the invisible apprentice who never bothers you. Rigel will do all the work of teaching me."

"And I will bear all the accountability," Severus countered. "If you blow yourself up attempting a potion you are not prepared to attempt, questions will be asked. Am I to say that I carelessly allowed upper-level knowledge to be imparted without supervision or controls of any kind?"

"You could deny all knowledge," she said, blinking up at him. "No one has to know I blew myself up trying to brew a potion whose recipe I got from you through Rigel. I'll tell my parents I want to experiment with free brewing—"

"You will not," Severus snapped, unable to believe the nerve underlying her words.

"I won't," she hastily assured him, "I'll just mention it in passing, and then if I get blown up they can tell the Department of Magical Accidents how they should have seen it coming, and it will be terribly sad but no one will question you about it."

He stared at her for a moment, not entirely sure there was an appropriate response to that bit of nonsense.

She sighed at his lack of response. "I'm sorry, Sir. Sometimes my hypotheticals run away with me. Suffice to say I'm not planning on blowing myself up. The labs at AIM and the one I use at home all have excellent safety provisions built in. Explosion wards and everything. I promise not to die in a potion-related mishap."

"Your share Rigel's inability to be sincerely reassuring." He scowled at her.

"Rigel gets it from me," she said, smiling in an odd way that he immediately disregarded as irrelevant.

He was no closer to deciding what to do about the girl than he had been at the beginning of the conversation, though it was now apparent he didn't have a good reason to dismiss her out of hand. A part of him was amiable to humoring the continued leeching, if only because it would please Rigel so well for some reason. He also had to admire the girl's spirit, from an intellectual standpoint. She certainly seemed to have the dedication and drive that he looked for in students. She might have done very well at Hogwarts, had she been born a couple decades sooner. He took a moment to disparage those who voted to ban half bloods for depriving him of perfectly good academic stock.

"It would mean immense amounts of individual study," he told her, hating the hopeful, happy look that lit up her face at his words. "I'm not agreeing—yet. I will consider this matter further. You should be prepared to work incredibly hard, however."

"I prefer self-study anyway," she said, looking as though she was only restraining a triumphant smile through sheer willpower. "Sir, you won't regret this—"

"I have not agreed," he hissed disgruntledly.

"Of course," she said, smoothing her expression expertly. "Take all the time you need."

The implication that he required more time to consider because he was a slow-thinker did not sit well with him either, and he thought spitefully that he would make her wait for a decision much longer, for that.

"This is dependent upon Rigel's father agreeing to the apprenticeship as well," he reminded her, determined to wipe the happiness from her soul.

"Sirius will agree," she said confidently. After a pause, she leveled a sharp look at him. "As long as you don't antagonize him needlessly."

"Excuse me?" he growled.

"Just try to be nice," she said cajolingly, as though she were dropping him off at the schoolyard and encouraging him to make friends. "Talk about Rigel and nothing else. Emphasize the good things that Rigel will get from the arrangement. And downplay the advantages you'll get politically in the Guild from having a talented apprentice."

He could not begin to fathom how she knew so much about Guild politics. What were they teaching their interns these days? Just as he was on the cusp of a cutting retort, their conversation was interrupted by an obnoxiously familiar voice.

"Snape! Who dragged you out of a lab?"

They both turned to see Malcolm Hurst, Aldermaster of said Guild, melting out of the crowd like a specter sent by the Fates to haunt him. Why, in the name of all decency, had he thought he could attend this circus without getting cornered by one of the ringmasters?

"Malcolm," he said, intentionally freezing any hint of welcome from his tone. "Don't you have someone else to impress?"

"I've been impressing people all night," Hurst said, smiling like the press goober he so often aped. "I need a break talking to someone who doesn't put stock in pandering and charm."

"Lucky me," he drawled.

"And who's—Harry!" To his surprise, the Aldermaster recognized the girl immediately on site, stepping forward to embrace her like a long-lost daughter. "I didn't know you'd be here. How is your third year going? That old fusspot Tallum treating you well, I hope?"

"My schooling is going well, Master Hurst," she said, smiling politely and even fondly up at the other man. "How is your wife? And Leo?"

"My other half couldn't be here tonight—work in the clinic has been piling up these last weeks," the man said regretfully. Severus vaguely recalled his wife had started a St. Mungo's funded clinic in one of the less savory alleys beyond Knockturn. He had no idea where the Potter chit would have met the woman, however—she wasn't known for skulking about the Guild like some other Masters' wives he could mention. "And Leo I haven't seen in days—he's moved out, now, so you'd know better than I how he's doing, I daresay."

So the girl had an in with the Aldermaster's son? That certainly explained how she got her internship. Judging by her embarrassed glance in his direction, she knew exactly what he was thinking. Not immune to insinuation after all, then.

"Perhaps if I tell him I saw you here, he'll be more inclined to accompany me next year," Hurst was saying thoughtfully.

"This doesn't seem his scene," the girl said, smiling slightly at some humor he was not a party to.

"Nor yours, I would have said," Hurst said, not unkindly.

The girl bowed her head agreeably enough. Unselfconsciously anti-social, then. Severus told himself firmly that he was not going to award the girl points just for that. It surprised him how like Rigel she was, though. One Marauder offspring turning out atypical from his expectations could be passed off as a fluke—two, however, bore contemplation. Was it Lily's influence? Or the werewolf's?

The girl spoke up before he could let his mind wader too far down that unpleasantly paved road. It was not his place to speculate on the lives of others, especially those not under his Slytherin banner.

"I ought to go check on my parents, see if they need help with Addy," she said, inclining her head once more in a polite farewell. "It was wonderful to finally meet you, Master Snape. Have a pleasant evening, Master Hurst."

As she left, Hurst turned eyes on him that were both curious and serious. "So you've officially met our most interesting new brewer—how did you find her? She reminds me of you, sometimes."

"I beg your pardon?" Snape sneered. It was an ice age too soon for any whelp of James Potter to be compared to him.

"Hardworking, passionate about the field, innovative, proud," Hurst ticked the traits off on his fingers with a small smirk. "She's much more polite than you, though, and more forgiving, too. I once witnessed one of her fellow interns deliberately sabotage her potion, and she didn't so much as send an accusatory glare at him—just fixed the mistake and presented the final product like nothing had happened."

"She is exceedingly foolish," Severus said, "She will never reach the position in the Guild she yearns for."

"Why's that?" Hurst asked mildly. "Because she's a woman?"

"Because she is weak," he said, mouth drawn in a harsh line. "She places her hopes in others, instead of relying only on herself. She lacks the competitiveness to move other, more ruthless brewers out of her path. She will defer to everyone around her until she ends up playing second fiddle at some large-scale, small-impact brewing company. Her name will never see the major journals, and she will fade, bitter and resentful, into obscurity."

"That's a bit harsh, Severus," Hurst said, voice soft but admonishing. "Harry Potter is an extraordinary young lady, and I believe her talent will take her places where ruthless competitiveness is unnecessary."

"Going to see to that?" he asked snidely.

"I see to all new talent in need of encouragement," Hurst said stiffly, not missing the accusation of favoritism. "Harry doesn't need my help—but yes, she will always have it. And not because of her friendship with my son and wife."

"So you say," Severus drawled, not believing a word of it.

Hurst bristled subtly, and snapped, "I did not know they were friends until after I'd evaluated her brewing skills. Her potions speak for themselves—I thought her much older, and more experienced, in fact, when I went looking for their maker, and no one was more surprised than I to find that the brewer I'd been tracking down was Heiress Potter, but there she was. Not everything requires such cynicism, Severus. Sometimes the young do surprise us. Surely you know that, working at Hogwarts for so many years. There must have been students that you just knew, immediately, were something special."

His mind lit immediately on Rigel Black, and he could not deny that such outliers apparently existed. He just thought it unlikely that they could exist so close together, in the same family, even. Statistically, it struck him as impossible.

"Where did you come across her work?" he questioned suddenly, realizing the implications of what Hurst had just said.

"I…came across it accidentally," Hurst said, looking uncomfortable.

Intrigued at the usually open man's reticence, Severus pressed. "You make it sound as though she were distributing—surely they haven't given the girl a license already? The Ministry is not quite that foolish, I daresay."

"She works through licensed distributers," Hurst said quickly, obviously not wanting Snape to think anything untoward of the girl.

He simply couldn't believe what he was hearing. "Plural? At her age? Who?"

Hurst grimaced, "It really isn't common knowledge. I shouldn't have said anything, I just didn't want you to be to dismissive of the young lady—she really is quite talented."

"Who?" Severus repeated, intimidation tactics coming automatically to the fore.

"One of them is Horace Burke," Hurst said, looking reluctant, "And that's all I can say, really. I'd appreciate if you kept this knowledge to yourself, however—she sells her potions anonymously, and I don't believe her parents are fully appraised of her activities…"

Snape's eyes narrowed. He used Burke himself for certain ingredient acquisition—his quality was always assured. If he distributed even one of the girl's potions, it meant she had access to some very well written recipes. Whatever was she selling potions at thirteen for? And without the knowledge of the elder Potters? Somehow he doubted she was strapped for funds. Did she simply enjoy the practice? She could donate them to St. Mungo's were that the case. Severus himself had done that while studying for his Masters examination—many potions students did, as there was never any need to waste good potions.

It struck him again how similar she and Rigel were turning out to be, at least in terms of how they dealt with the world around them. Rigel, too, avoided the supervisionary involvement of adults wherever possible. If he had not warded the time-turner in his desk drawer himself before the winter holidays, he might suspect Rigel of playing a very dangerous game with him. As it was, he was slowly coming to accept that against all odds there were two incredibly talented and ridiculously secretive young potions brewers in England. Salazar help them all when those two became old enough to apply for Guild membership. He had a bad feeling that the field as he knew it was going to be shortly turned on its head.

"I will keep this information to myself," Severus agreed after a long moment. He would certainly be talking to Horace Burke, however. Clearly he needed more information on this Potter girl, if he was to make her his de facto proxy apprentice through Rigel. He ignored the part of himself that pointed out his diction indicated he had already made his decision on the matter. He was certainly not invested in her circumstances already. He would decide if and when the girl was deemed a suitable vessel for his expertise, and no amount of mysterious backstory was going to intrigue him into capitulating sooner.

Harry walked away from the Potions Masters feeling cautiously pleased. She thought it had gone well—even if her nerves had gotten the better of her at the end and caused her to act as though under a mild babbling charm. All she could do now was wait.

She circled the room in search of her family members, thinking vaguely that her mother might like her to carry Addy for a while. Babies got heavy, she gathered, if you held them long enough.

She passed the Parkinsons, where it looked like the receiving line was finally dying down—how late was fashionably late, anyway? Surely whoever had just arrived was pushing propriety. After sparing the party a curious glance, she saw to her surprise that it was Marcus Flint and an older gentleman who was, presumably, Lord Flint. She fought the impulse to freeze or duck guiltily, reminding herself that Harriett Potter did not know either man.

As she passed close enough to overhear the conversation, she caught Flint Sr. saying, "Home sick, unfortunately, otherwise she would have loved to be here, isn't that right, Marcus?"

Marcus' response was an annoyed grunt, followed by, "I feel a bit sick myself." He broke away from the group abruptly and made a surly beeline for the bar. Harry just managed to turn her face casually away as he passed her.

She moved on, weaving here and there around increasingly drunk partygoers. Apparently the Parkinsons were not at all stingy with their refreshments.

A few minutes later, she found her friends once more; they had drifted somewhat from the spot under one of the balconies that they'd occupied earlier. Archie was with them, but so were Adrian Pucey, Lucian Bole, and Caelum Lestrange—and he and Archie didn't appear to be having a polite conversation.

"—which is why I can't fathom the level of sheer nerve you managed to summon in trespassing for the second year running where no one wants a—"

"Do shut up, Lestrange, no one is listening," Harry cut in, smoothly stepping up beside Archie so that she was physically between him and Lestrange. Archie could hold his own in petty bickering, she knew from experience, but he should haven't to put up with the pretty boy's nonsensical venom when there were perfectly good ways of stemming it.

"You." The icy-eyed boy sneered elegantly down at her. "What has it come to, that they allow the rabble to roam in hallowed halls?"

"I missed you too, Caelum." she smiled sweetly at him. "How's your final year shaping up?"

"Don't talk to me like we're friends," the black-haired boy hissed, trying and failing at not looking alarmed.

"But we are," she blinked innocently up at him, widening her eyes in a show of hurt confusion. "You told me your favorite color and everything."

"I did not," he snapped.

"Then how do I know it's dark blue?" she asked reasonably.

"It isn't," he growled, clearly annoyed. His expression only grew darker when several of the others chuckled lowly. Lestrange visibly collected himself, apparently realizing how foolish she had made him sound. "Still up to your usual nonsense, Potter. How plebian."

She bowed mockingly, not bothering to hide her satisfied smile.

"How do you two…ah, know one another?" Bole was apparently the only one brave enough to ask.

Lestrange turned to the other boy with a smirking expression. "We happened to intern at roughly the same time at the Potions Guild this summer. I got in on merit, of course, while she…well, I suppose she filled the novelty quota."

Harry moued thoughtfully. "He's right. It probably was novel for the Guild to have an intern with real talent for a change."

"Talent is about dedication," Lestrange spat, "Any two year old can throw random things in a cauldron and call it a new discovery. If you had any sense of what being a true potions maker was about, you'd build on the tradition before you, not blow it to smithereens with your wild half-blood ideas."

"Maybe you're right," Harry sighed sadly, "I guess only purebloods can have good ideas." She turned to Archie ostentatiously and said, "Rigel, would you mind telling Master Snape that Caelum Lestrange—that's C-A-E-L-U-M—thinks that he ought to keep his half blood ideas to himself, for the good of potions brewers everywhere?"

"I'd be happy to pass along the message," Archie said, smiling slightly, "Do you have a card I could include with the note, Lestrange?"

The older boy looked close to frothing with rage, but instead he merely shot her a glare that promised retribution, turned, and strode off with a disgusted huff.

"He's getting better at taking his lumps," Harry observed into the silence that followed.

Archie nodded in agreement. "Not one call for his mother that whole time."

Theo, Millicent, and Pucey all snorted with laughter, and the others visibly relaxed. "I don't know how you two manage to just smile through his vitriol," Bole said, shaking his head. "Don't you know how powerful his parents are in the Party?"

"Our parents aren't in the Party," Archie reminded him delicately. "So we don't give two knuts what Lestrange thinks."

"And he's mostly bluster, anyway," Harry said fairly, "He's not so bad if you get to know him—just likes to push people's buttons, that's all."

"He just insulted you in about a dozen different ways," Draco spoke up, eyeing her oddly again.

"He didn't really mean it," Harry said, shrugging.

"Sure sounded like he did," Millicent muttered, looking at Harry with something like reconsideration.

"You can't always tell what a person means by the words they say," Harry said. In fact, she'd been far more uncomfortable with her friends' insincere politeness earlier than she was with Lestrange's honest disparagement. At least his insults could be met head on.

"Very well put," came a voice just behind her. She turned to see Pansy, finally free of the receiving line, smiling widely at her. "You're wise, Miss Potter. We could use more women of wisdom in the world."

Harry blinked, taken aback at the rich compliment, and hesitated before saying, "You are too kind, Miss Parkinson."

"Just Pansy," the blonde reminded her gently. After waiting for Harry to nod, she tilted her head, sending shoulder-length blonde hair swaying. "Would you honor me with this dance, Miss Potter?"

Harry could admit that was the last thing she expected her friend to say. "I—don't dance very well. Sorry."

Pansy laughed lightly, "That's what Rigel said to me once, but I saw him dance a set with Millie earlier, so you'll forgive me if I don't entirely believe you, Harry."

She shot a look at Archie, who shrugged sheepishly. She turned back to Pansy to come up with another polite refusal, but Pansy cut across her.

"You wouldn't refuse your host a dance, surely?" her blue eyes gazed assessingly into hers, and Harry found she could not find a good excuse after all. At her hesitation, Pansy went for the kill. "Rigel once refused me a dance, and I was rather heart-broken. If you turn me away, too, I shall develop a complex."

Harry allowed exasperation to narrow her eyes, but nevertheless knew she was outmatched. "It would be my pleasure," she said, managing not to grit her teeth noticeably.

She couldn't even blame anyone but herself, she thought with irony, as it had been her as Rigel who ducked out of dancing with Pansy and thus set the proud girl on the idea. Knowing that didn't make her feel any less awkward, however, as she accompanied Pansy to the dance floor.

Pansy was certain Harriett Potter did not realize the service she was doing her, dancing the most popular set with the halfblood friend of a friend. Already people were turning to look—sidelong and very surreptitiously, but Pansy could easily pick them out.

They took their positions among the other couples on the floor, and Pansy had to stifle a surprised chuckle when the green-eyed girl took up the dominant position seemingly without conscious thought, despite the fact that, as they were both girls, blood status ought to have been the next deciding factor in the roles they danced. They grasped hands lightly, as the starting position demanded, and Pansy leaned forward to say quietly, "You know that technically I should be leading, don't you?"

Harriett flushed, her eyes widening with slight dismay. "Forgive my impertinence," she said, grimacing a bit. "I am more familiar with this form. I meant no disrespect."

"I know," Pansy told her, smiling reassuringly, "I don't mind, in fact. You are Rigel's cousin, and that makes us equals in my mind. I merely wanted you to know, in case you decide to dance with someone else tonight."

The other girl's eyes widened again, this time in surprise and, she thought, something like gratitude. Pansy wondered if the others had been less than polite to her—she would have words with Draco, if that were the case. Rigel was depending on them to make Harriett feel welcome. If they did marry, and Pansy was not sure at all that Rigel would put forth the effort in finding himself a better match if he already had a girl suited to his hobbies and habits at home, they would be seeing a lot more of her. That, coupled with the fact that if it came to a choice between his friends and his family, Pansy was not at all sure Rigel would choose them, meant that they had to make a good impression.

They began to move through the dance steps, mirroring one another in each choreographed spin and gesture. Harriett wasn't bad, per say, but she was obviously uncomfortable with the entire activity. It was all Pansy could do not to smile with amusement as a particularly grandiose hand flourish made Harriett's nose wrinkle with distaste.

It really was a shame the girl was half-blooded, she thought. It showed great courage to come to an unfamiliar place and stand up to sneers and titters when there was nothing to be gained from it, in the end. The other girl also seemed to be clever and polite. Harriett might have made a prodigious match, had she been born pure. Pansy might have considered her for herself, in fact, if things had been different. She certainly had Rigel's talent for dissembling, if the interaction Pansy had overheard with Lestrange was any indication. Pansy admitted to herself that it was one of the things she liked most in her dark-haired friend, and to find it in someone she didn't already think of platonically was a rare pleasure.

With a mental sigh, Pansy turned her thoughts away from such matters. No matter the current pending legislation, her parents would never allow her to marry someone less than pure. They didn't have a strong prejudice against half bloods themselves, but the fact that others did made it a foolish move socially and politically. Still, she thought, one could never fully predict the whims of society. Things might change in that regard.

Why, only two centuries before it would have been completely unheard of for two women to dance together, and look at them now. Society was a fickle thing. It was all well and good to stifle and contain their offspring into strictly heterosexual matches, but once their population became dangerously depleted, the old biddies certainly changed their tune. In a strange way, they actually had blood mania to thank for the openness of Wizarding relationships in modern times, she mused. When purebloods became desperate for more children to fill out their ranks, in competition as they were with all the new muggleborns who came pouring into the Wizarding world each generation, it was suddenly less important to uphold conventional standards of sexuality and more important to encourage any couple, regardless of makeup, to marry and have babies with whatever magical assistance was necessary.

As she twirled and spun on autopilot, Pansy thought cynically that it didn't hurt that having the option of a homosexual relationship doubled the candidates with which one could be matched without resorting to incest. Pureblood insanity had taken a dramatic drop off when people warmed to the idea that marrying your sister wasn't necessary when you had a fourth cousin twice removed who could bear children with the right combination of potions. And how like the upper echelons of Society to veil this pragmatic change behind a pretense of cultural openness and an encouragement of love and free will.

The dance was coming to a close, so Pansy pulled her wandering attention back to her partner, who looked a little too relieved to be perfectly polite when the music wound down at last.

"That was lovely," Pansy said, placing her arm on Harriett's as they exited the dance floor.

"Yes," Harriett said, smiling in a way that Pansy could tell was fake, but only because she'd seen a similar smile on Rigel's face so often. "Thank you very much for the dance, Pansy."

"Anytime," Pansy said, smiling at the uneasy look that produced on the other girl's face. "I must return to my parents. Will you escort me there?"

Harriett adjusted her glasses uncomfortably, but inclined her head nevertheless. "I should check on mine as well; perhaps I will spot them on the way."

As they maneuvered through the crowd, Pansy couldn't help but think that Harriett had never escorted anyone anywhere before. The green-eyed girl had noticeable trouble navigating the crush on both of their behalf, and several times had to stop and recover Pansy from where she'd been cut off between groups of people. With her incredibly apologetic grimaces each time it happened, Harriett came off entirely endearing, though Pansy had to wonder why someone obviously unaccustomed to leading would have practiced the lead position in dancing so singularly. Perhaps she had learned from Rigel. She would have to ask her friend when she saw him again. However innocuous Harriett Potter tried to come across, there was something curious about her that tugged at Pansy's mind even as she told herself to let it go.

It was with acute relief that she spotted Pansy's parents at last through the sea of people. To her surprise, her own parents were there with them, in a group that looked as though it was made up of all the most important people in the room. The Minister stood at James' side, along with several prominent Wizengamot members, including Marchbanks and Ogden, who Harry never seemed to see apart. On the other side of the circle stood Lord Riddle, the Lestranges, the Malfoys, and, of course, the Parkinsons.

Harry left Pansy with her parents, and circled the group until she reached Lily's far side, where Addy was propped on one slender hip.

"Harry, we wondered where you and Archie had gotten to," her mother said, smiling brightly down at her. "Are you enjoying yourself?"

"It's a lovely party," she said, smiling slightly, "Would you like me to hold Addy for a while?"

"Please," Lily sighed gratefully. "Your father is on duty, so he can't exactly relieve me."

Addy was handed down into Harry's unsure grasp. Her little sister blinked up at her assessingly and she awkwardly adjusted her until the babe felt somewhat comfortable in her arms. Eventually Addy seemed to decide Harry was not an immediate threat, and began dozing against her shoulder unselfconsciously. Harry comforted herself that if Addy managed to drool all down her robes, at least most of the people present would be too intoxicated to notice. Half the conversations around her seemed punctuated by giggles with unusual frequency.

Lily was having a lively conversation with Tiberius Ogden about the latest project she was working on for her experimental contracting company. Madam Marchbanks appeared to be tittering along to a story Rose Parkinson was relating with sparkling humor in her eyes. The Minister was in quiet conversation with what Harry thought was one of his cabinet members, James looking on stoically. Riddle was engaged in discussion with the Lestranges, Mr. Malfoy, and Mr. Parkinson, but Harry noticed the Lord's eyes were fixed on a point across the room. Harry turned subtly under the pretense of readjusting the sleepy Addy in order to follow his line of sight.

She could just make out the dark clad form of Professor Snape, in close conversation with both brothers Black across the hall. They were all three strikingly tall, which made them stand out from the crowd even at a distance. Riddle was not the only one eyeing the three, she noticed, and no wonder when it was common knowledge that Snape and Sirius despised one another.

Harry could not prevent the silent prayer that graced her lips, just in case anyone was listening, that the conversation happening across the room would go smoothly. It would be revolutionary for Snape to take her on as an apprentice—a thirteen-year-old was almost unheard of. The things she would learn…

She tore her eyes away, aware that there was nothing she could do at that point. She cast about for a distraction, and her eyes lit immediately upon her mother, almost magnetically drawn. Blinking, she took in Lily with fresh eyes, suddenly realizing that she had never been to a formal event with her mother before, and had never seen her like…this. She was captivating—not just her beauty, which Harry had always taken for granted, but her sheer presence. She was certain Lily had never had such an aura of charm and grace about her before—what had happened to her tired, over-worked mother who lounged about the house after dinner in her pajamas?

At some point in her musings, she noticed Archie approach their circle on the other side, with Draco leading him to a place near Mr. Malfoy. Their eyes met and they exchanged brief smiles, but there was little opportunity for a proper greeting across the many different conversations around them.

Harry turned back to watching her mother with a frown. Perhaps it was the dress robes, she thought, but immediately dismissed the idea—she had seen her mother dressed up before. Lily's modest robes in no way outshone the plunging, glittering ensembles of the society matrons around them, besides. It was something in the way she held herself, the way she responded to others. Harry stepped closer, to better observe this new phenomenon.

"You young people always want to change things," Ogden was complaining tiredly. "No respect for the way things have been done for generations."

"It is not a lack of respect that drives us forward in search of progress," Lily said, her voice light yet sure. "Just the opposite—we build on the monuments of the past in reverence and appreciation."

"It is not called appreciation when one alters a masterpiece—rather, it is desecration," the elder Lestrange, Rodolphus, cut in brusquely.

Lily was perfectly unruffled, somehow managing to look humbly intrigued by Lord Lestrange's comment even while saying, "I do not think tradition is like a painting—not a stale, stagnant creation to be hung on the wall unchanged for centuries. Rather, it is a living thing, contributed to by all who inherit it even as it is preserved."

"You cannot preserve something and change it," Bellatrix said, her lip curling.

"But surely such a standard is self-defeating," Lily said, a kind concern in her expression now. "Imagine your own manors and estates, handed down through the generations from fathers and mothers to sons and daughters—they cannot remain completely unchanged, can they? You must update them to adhere to modern standards of comfort, perhaps add on a wing here or a garden there, attend to various repairs and improvements constantly, even as you preserve them in their entirety for the next generation. The result is the beautiful ballroom we stand in. More than a relic of the past, it is an heirloom that we live within. Is tradition not just so?"

Harry was amazed to see the lords and ladies around her carefully considering Lily's words. Somehow she had delivered them as an offering, not a challenge. Somehow her mother had put a group of proud, disdainful purebloods at ease by combining a sense of admiration for them with a soft confidence that was all her own, and wasn't abrasive in the least.

"Still, it does not do to renovate a historical home beyond recognition, wouldn't you agree?" Narcissa said from across the circle. "At that point one may as well build a new manor entirely."

"Is there no merit in building new homes?" Lily asked softly, eyes earnest without demanding anything. "Not everyone has an ancestral manor, after all. And what happens when your family grows too large for its walls? All great manors were new once, were they not?"

"Interesting argument," Lord Riddle spoke up. All eyes turned to him in deference. "In that analogy, all the great witches and wizards of our past would be the architects of the future we now inhabit. By implication, you're saying that the present legacy they left is now…inadequate?"

Lily stood strong beneath the disapproving gazes that swung her way. "The measure of time itself is decay—it isn't a question of inadequacy, merely of inevitability. When a volcano first erupts, it is brilliant and powerful. It creates an island with rich soil that blossoms into a flourishing paradise naturally. Years pass, however, and the ocean of time beats away at the island's shores, diminishing it. This degeneration does not call into question the might of the first volcano. It merely calls for a new volcano, a fresh source of power that could bring new life to something in the midst of decline."

"A new volcano might also destroy the island completely," Lord Malfoy said smoothly, one eyebrow raised, "Depending on where and how it erupts."

"That is true," Lily allowed, "Change should always be approached slowly, with great care. Just because something requires care, however, does not mean that it isn't worth doing. The traditions of our past are not pedestals. They are stepping stones. Some of the greatest and most respected of our heroes were the daring innovators of their time. The Egyptian pharaohs, the Chinese mystics, Merlin, the Founders, and so on. To resist change is to shy away from the possibility of greatness. There are risks, of course, but also great opportunity."

"How very true," Riddle said, his voice, while not loud, carrying easily through the noise around them. "Stepping stones, indeed. Still, to move in the wrong direction would be as disastrous as standing still. Better to follow those stones along the path the wise men before us have laid out. To press forward is admirable—but only insofar as one sights along the proper trajectory. We are not wiser than the Founders, surely?"

Lily bowed her head graciously, conceding the point, though she did add, "How difficult it is to know where the path may lead before one walks it."

Riddle smiled, and the conversation was ended. Until Harry picked up the faintest of hisses, words whispered mockingly on an invisible breeze to roost in her ears. "Some of us see more clearly than others."

She saw Riddle's eyes flick toward Archie, and Harry looked to him, too, but Archie remained completely oblivious, not having heard the comment, as he didn't actually speak Parseltongue, and certain pitches of the language were lower than the average human register. Harry tried not to wince as Riddle's eyes narrowed and a frown briefly creased his brow. She would have to relay the comment to Archie later, and see if he could slip mention of it into conversation if he ever had occasion to speak to Riddle alone.

Lily took Addy back, looking incredibly graceful despite cradling a baby in one arm. Harry had to take a moment to truly admire her mother's carriage that evening. She had lost not an iota of her own self-worth, yet she had made everyone around her feel entirely valued and important despite arguing blatantly against their way of life. Harry had no idea how to go about replicating such a thing, but she could certainly admire it from afar. It struck her that her mother could play a crowd as well as Sirius did—only she did it without being self-deprecating or hyperbolic.

Her father, too, was changed by her aura. James looked like a Lord with Lily at his elbow, seeming stoic instead of stiff, and reserved rather than proud.

A movement across the circle distracted her; Riddle was stepping back from the group with quiet apologies to the Parkinsons. Mr. Malfoy stepped back with him, sending a glance across the hall in a very familiar direction. Sure enough, when Harry casually glanced around she saw Snape walking away from the Black brothers with a triumphant smirk on his face. She lost her focus for a moment, caught up in the implications of that. Did Sirius agree? Was she—Rigel—really going to be Master Snape's apprentice this year? She had to fight to keep from beaming in happiness—had she ever imagined that their ruse might come so far?

Her thoughts realigned themselves to the present moment when she caught Snape sending a discrete nod to Mr. Malfoy, who followed Mr. Riddle out of the room in short order. They were going to discuss the situation with the artifact, she realized, and Pettigrew too, probably. She wished she could go after them—her curiosity was burning her up inside; she couldn't be so reckless, however. Eavesdropping so obviously as to excuse herself in front of all these powerful people was just asking for trouble.

Not five minutes after Riddle's subtle exit, as though her thoughts of trouble had summoned the thing itself, a sound that no one was prepared for smothered the flames of conversation like a sudden vacuum. A hoarse cry of shock and pain, followed sharply by the sound of a body hitting the tiled floor.

Mr. Ogden had collapsed, crumbling to the ground in a spray of blood that caught several hideously expensive ball gowns even as their wearers stumbled back in horror.

Madam Marchbanks let out a cry like a wounded animal and lashed her foot toward her fallen companion in a move that made no sense until Harry saw it connect with some sort of golden thing on the old man's back, flinging it away. There was more frantic retreating as those closest sought to avoid coming into contact with whatever it was.

Her father surged forward, between the golden thing, which was writhing and skittering across the ground now, and the Minister. When it was close enough, he brought a booted foot crunching down onto the biggest part of the contraption, and it twitched like a crushed bug before going still.

Marchbanks meanwhile had knelt beside Ogden with tears running down her face, pressing gloved hands to the wounds on his back and whispering frantic pleas under her breath.

"We need a Healer!" someone shouted. Everyone started looking around as though they would see the traditional Healer robes somewhere in this crowd of glitterati.

"Where is Master Healer Cunnington?" James asked, moving to kneel by the injured man's side as well. Harry recognized the name of the Chief of Healing at Mt. Mungo's and felt acute relief that such a well-practiced Healer was in the vicinity. Mr. Ogden would be in good hands.

"He left early," Mr. Parkinson said, tense anxiety in his voice.

"Intoxicated," someone else muttered scornfully.

"Is anyone trained in mediwizardry?" Rose Parkinson called to the room abroad, half of which was just now noticing that something was wrong.

"Snape," someone called uncertainly.

"Not here," Mr. Parkinson said, his eyes flicking to the archway where Snape had left not minutes earlier with Riddle and Mr. Malfoy. He looked clearly torn between going in search of the man and staying to mediate the tragedy unfolding.

"I will go and search for him," Bellatrix said, stepping carefully around the fallen man before heading for the entryway.

"There's no time," someone from the crowd snapped, "Look at the blood."

There was indeed a pool of red rapidly spreading from Ogden's prone form.

"There must be someone here trained in Healing!" Mrs. Malfoy exclaimed, one gloved hand raised to her mouth in utter dismay.

Harry turned her eyes toward Archie even as James looked up from the floor and said, "My daughter is." All eyes turned, somewhat incredulously, in her direction, and she froze uncertainly. "Harry, can you…?"

There was nothing for it, she supposed distantly as her father's pleading eyes met hers. She stepped forward on shaking legs, digging deep in her pocket for her wand as she knelt down to see the damage. She should ask for Archie to do it—but how would she convince them that he was more qualified? Her eyes sought his for a panicked moment, but Archie only gazed steadily back at her, eye bright with trust and confidence. With a deep, steadying breath, she moved Madam Marchbanks' hands aside and ripped Ogden's robes with one hand while quietly casting the spell that would slow localized blood flow with the other. Once she could see the wound, she let out a deep sigh of relief—there were stab marks on his lower back, but none appeared to have brushed his spine. To be sure, she sent her consciousness into Healer mode, probing the extent of the damage swiftly.

The spine was fine, but one of the strikes had come in at an angle and torn right through the right renal artery that led to that kidney, severely damaging the inferior vena cava as well, which explained why there was so much blood. Ogden would die quickly in cardiovascular collapse if she didn't fix that immediately.

"Mr. Parkinson, do you keep a supply of Blood Replenisher Potions in the house?" she asked, her voice somewhat monotone as most of her attention was diverted to making sure the Ureter wasn't damaged—she didn't need bodily waste spilling out into the abdominal cavity.

"Accio Blood Replenisher," was Mr. Parkinson's response.

"Archie, can you give it to him?" Harry said, not glancing away from Ogden to see if anyone found her request odd. She needed his help, so the ruse was just going to have to adjust if necessary.

A few moments later, Archie was beside her on the ground. "I'm going to spell it into his stomach," he told her quietly, taking out his own wand.

"After that, check his lungs," Harry said, "His breathing is too shallow, for someone unconscious."

She turned her attention to knitting the major blood vessels back together carefully, aware of how important the kidneys were to a number of bodily functions. It was imperative that their homeostasis not be upset. Once she could feel the Blood Replenisher begin to work, she turned her attention to siphoning away the blood that had leaked internally around the kidney and spine.

"His left twelfth rib deflected one of the thrusts," Archie said at her ear, "It's fractured."

"It can wait," Harry said, "What about his breathing?"

With a subtle nod of approval, Archie said, "No wound accounts for it. Check his blood for toxins."

Harry frowned. "Poison…" she grimaced at what her magic was telling her. "Some kind of paralytic. No wonder the muscles around the entrance wounds have all seized up."

"Poison!" Marchbanks' exclamation caught the attention of those around them who were watching with morbid concern. "Is he going to die?"

"Not if we counteract it," Harry said, trying to both reassure the woman and concentrate on what needed to be done.

Out of the corner of her eye she saw Mrs. Parkinson and Mrs. Malfoy step up to draw Marchbanks slightly away, comforting her with soft murmurs. She appreciated their initiative in giving them the space they needed to fix this.

"I can keep his lungs working for a while, but if it's already in the blood stream, we have to stop it before it can damage the heart too severely—otherwise we're looking at long-term recovery in St. Mungo's," Archie said quietly.

"Do you recognize it?" Harry asked, eyes tight with stress. "It looks like saxitoxin to me, but that doesn't make any sense."

"Like in shellfish?" Archie wrinkled his nose, "It would have to be extremely concentrated to have so fast an effect. Though if it got into the inferior vena cava when it was nicked, I guess it wouldn't have to be that powerful."

"Let's assume we're right, and flush it out," Harry decided. There were only a few poisons that needed special means of removal, and saxitoxin wasn't one of them. Provided they were careful, they should be able to detox Ogden with minimal difficulty.

It took a good ten minutes, even with two of them sweeping Ogden's system. Archie took care of flushing the delicate heart and lungs while Harry focused on the liver and kidneys—thankfully, not much of it had gotten to the extremities and the digestive tract was largely unaffected. They did have to painstakingly comb through the soft tissues of the brain to make sure absolutely none of it was left behind in the cerebral cortex.

As his breathing evened out and color returned to his cheeks, Ogden began to visibly retreat from death's door. She could vaguely hear people around them murmuring optimistically as she and Archie paused to wipe the sweat from their brows.

"I'll take the fractured rib," she said after a moment, "Will you finish up the flesh wounds?" Archie was very good at cosmetic Healing, or so he claimed.

Archie nodded, sparing a glance up at Marchbanks and the two ladies who held her hands. "He's going to be fine, Madam. Won't even have a scar—though he will have to take a regimen of muscle-strengtheners for his heart. He'll probably end up feeling better than before by the end of it."

Marchbanks broke down in relieved tears, even as Archie turned his wand back to the task before them. She had no trouble with the bone—it was hardly broken at all, and Harry was very familiar with fixing broken bones, even if she mostly practiced on animals. A glow of satisfaction lit her face as she rocked back on her heels finally and watched Archie close the last few inches of open skin on Ogden's lower back. After checking the elder's vital signs and sensing no sign of further bodily distress, they both stood.

"He's fine, now," Harry said, gesturing Marchbanks forward. "You can wake him."

With a breathless laugh of pure happiness, the elder knelt and hurriedly repaired and cleaned Ogden's robes to their previous glorious state. She then pressed her wand to his side and whispered, "Enervate."

Ogden coughed, groaned, and pushed himself up from the tile with a confused grimace. "What—what happened?" he said, bracing himself on his hands and knees before climbing to his feet slowly, supported by Madam Marchbanks the entire way.

"You were attacked, Tiberius," Marchbanks said, arranging his hair with gentle, trembling fingers. "There was so much blood…"

"Attacked by who?" Ogden said, looking around the room with enraged suspicion.

"This." James stepped closer from where he had stood out of the way while Harry and Archie worked. He held up a mangled, golden device that on closer inspection seemed to have been made up of intricately interlocked gears. It might have resembled some kind of insect, before it was crushed, she thought. Many of its limbs tapered into sharp, lethal-looking points that dripped with red blood, marking them as the instruments of Ogden's wounds.

"What on earth…?" Ogden cringed away from the metal thing. "How did that even get in here?"

"I've been examining it," James said, holding it by one bladed leg to demonstrate its mechanisms. "This part here retracts—it appears that it could have masqueraded as a regular object smaller than the palm of a hand, which then transformed upon activation."

"So someone smuggled this weapon into my home," Mr. Parkinson looked rigidly livid. "Can it be traced?"

"It's covered in Elder Ogden's blood, now, so the only thing it would lead us to is him," James said, shaking his head.

Harry was looking at the mangled golden thing with something like nagging horror, knowing that it reminded her of something, but not sure what. Where had she seen an insect like that before…? With a jolt of memory, she paled. She opened her mouth, then shut it abruptly—that hadn't happened to Harry. It had happened to Rigel.

"Rigel," she said pointedly. Archie looked over at her with a questioning eyebrow. "Doesn't that seem familiar? Remember in your first year, when you were attacked…?"

Archie gave her a blank look and blinked. "Um, sort of…it was that Jordan fellow, wasn't it?"

Draco was suddenly there at Archie's elbow, "Lee Jordan? You're talking about that spider thing he tried to use on you? It had a paralytic agent too, didn't it?"

Archie nodded unsurely, clearly trying to recall what she'd told him of the incident. "Yes. It had a neuro component too, though, to induce memory loss. It was primarily organic, too, while this thing seems to be mostly mechanical."

"Not to mention all of Jordan Sr.'s breeding experiments were destroyed after the Ministry was apprised of his illegal activities." Blaise Zabini had come up behind them to join their little powwow.

"That would explain how unsophisticated this one is compared to the one that attacked Rigel, though," Harry pointed out. "The poison on its blades was raw saxitoxin, not synthesized or anything like the neurotoxic venom bred into the insect that Rigel destroyed."

"How crude," Blaise wrinkled his nose in academic displeasure.

Meanwhile, James was interrogating Mr. Ogden about who may have motive to arrange for such a thing.

"No one at this gala has any grievance against me," Ogden said stoutly.

"It might have been stowed away on an unsuspecting wizard's person," James said, frowning, "By the looks of it, the insect might have been disguised as a piece of jewelry, a boot buckle, anything really. Anyone you might suspect could be a lead."

"Tiberius," Marchbanks said suddenly, "Where is your pocket watch?"

"My…" Ogden paled and swayed, "No. He wouldn't." Nevertheless he began to search his pockets frantically, looking more disturbed by the second.

"It was a gift from his nephew," Marchbanks told James quietly.

"One Leonard Jordan the first," Blaise muttered, dramatic irony thick in his voice.

"He wouldn't," Ogden insisted, his ancient visage drawn with pain. "He's capable of such an invention, I don't deny, but he wouldn't use it like this."

"He was asking about his inheritance," Marchbanks said, one hand on Ogden's arm, "He wasn't pleased that you were considering marriage to me so late in life."

"He's fallen on hard times," Ogden insisted, face red with suppressed emotion. "He hasn't got a truly violet bone in his—in his—" He clutched at his chest, wheezing a bit.

Harry and Archie started forward automatically, with Archie just barely remembering to hang back and let her do the diagnostic charm. "Your heart is still weak, Elder Ogden," she said respectfully, "You'll need to avoid putting stress on it for at least a week. Nothing that raises your blood pressure, if you can help it."

"Who are you?" Ogden asked, one wizened brow raised somewhat incredulously at her presumption.

"She's—" Marchbanks broke off as she realized they hadn't been properly introduced. "Auror Potter's daughter. She saved your life, Tiberius, along with young Mr. Black."

"Saved—" Ogden seemed to come to the sudden realization that he didn't know where his wounds had gone. "I thought a Healer…"

"There wasn't time to find one," Marchbanks said, voice tight, "You were bleeding out, Tiberius."

"From that little thing?" Ogden looked shocked, "Its blades are barely the width of my finger!"

"One of them nicked your inferior vena cava," Harry told him, "It was unlucky—if not for that there might have been time to move you to St. Mungo's for treatment."

"And if not for the poison," Archie piped up helpfully.

"Poison?" Tiberius looked incredibly shaken.

"It almost stopped your lungs, Tibby," Marchbanks said, clutching his arm a little tighter.

"You say your nephew gave this to you as a pocket watch?" James clarified.

"I…suppose so," Ogden said, looking defeated. "I received it as a Yule present from the whole Jordan family. My great niece even wrapped it in pink ribbon. I just can't believe that they would… and over money?"

"They might not all be involved," James said, gruffly reassuring, "After all, if it looked like a watch to you, any one of them could have fooled the others. They may even have bought it in a shop thinking it innocuous. We'll know more when we question them." With a nod of his head, he motioned two Aurors, who had been hanging back in lieu of clear action to take, to step forward. "We'll need your nephew's last known address."

"You may want to question his great-nephew, Lee Jordan, especially closely, Auror Potter," Draco spoke loud enough for James to hear, drawing the attention of Ogden and the others, as well.

"Why is that, Heir Malfoy?" James asked, his professional mask fully donned.

"Lee Jordan orchestrated a similar attack in our first year on a fellow student," Draco said, "The insect was different in construct, but the use of poison is similar. And the attack on Mr. Ogden at my family's garden party two years ago also involved poison."

James frowned. "Dawlish, see to it that someone digs up the incident report on that attack, as well. Heir Malfoy is probably correct in relating them. We will look into Lee Jordan's means and motive carefully," he added, nodding gratefully in Draco's direction.

As Aurors were organized and scrambled, Mr. and Mrs. Parkinson began retaking control of the party. Harry was surprised they were going to continue as though nothing had happened, but she supposed it was the biggest event of the season, and no one had actually died.

Ogden came over to where Harry and Archie stood, something like shock and disbelief still manning his expression. "I must thank the two of you for your timely assistance," he said gravely. Marchbanks, still clutching his elbow, nodded in agreement. "It alarms me to think how fortunate I was to be within saving distance of two young people so learned in the Healing arts. It is a rare skill, in these times, and the night could all too easily have ended very differently."

Harry privately reflected that it wasn't so much a rare skill as it was a skill primarily taught to muggleborns and halfbloods, who attended schools like AIM. Hogwarts did not emphasize Healing abilities, and hadn't for some time, offering only a few scant students a year the opportunity to begin learning the art before they graduated. Even with Madam Pomfrey's tutelage, Harry would not have been able to save Ogden's life just using what she'd learned at Hogwarts alone; she had learned the nuances of poison treatment from Archie's notes, after all, not to mention all that she'd absorbed about the kidneys from one of the assignments he'd sent her.

She wondered suddenly if Dumbledore deemphasized subjects that foreign schools like AIM emphasized on purpose, like Alchemy, to give those children of lesser blood a competitive edge in the workforce despite numerous Ministry sanctions discouraging employers from hiring those schooled abroad. Certainly Lily would have had a much harder time finding a job at her contract company if there had been a plethora of purebloods equally trained in experimental charms.

No, she concluded with a mental shake of her head, that would be too manipulative on too large a scale, even for a professional politician like Riddle, much less a respected public figure like Dumbledore. Out loud she merely said, "No thanks necessary, Elder Ogden—we learned first aid for a reason."

"That was quite a bit more than first aid." Lily came over, smiling proudly, one arm around Addy and the other coming to embrace Harry briefly. "I had no idea your studies were so progressed."

"Treating blunt trauma is the first thing they teach at AIM," Archie said, smiling a bit, "The later years are all reserved for diagnosing and treating more complicated things, like wounds inflicted by curses or other forms of foreign magic, virulent diseases, and injuries to more delicate parts of the body like the brain, eyes, reproductive organs…" he trailed off at the somewhat odd look Draco was giving him. "What? I read Harry's syllabi."

"I know, I just didn't realize you were so excited about Healing," Draco muttered. He looked a bit put off. Harry supposed that wasn't an emotion he was used to feeling from Rigel, to be fair.

"Whatever the reason, I am grateful," Ogden said, smiling indulgently, "To you both. Mr. Black, I am already indebted to you, as you may recall. I am chagrined to have to offer you once more my life in debt to your timely assistance."

Archie bowed deeply, a flush rising on his skin that Harry would tease him about later. "It is the duty of one wizard to another, Elder Ogden. There is nothing but respect between us."

"I hope you are not as humble as your friend, Miss Potter," Ogden chortled, turning tired eyes her direction. "I really must thank someone for my continued health."

"She is much worse," Archie told him conspiratorially, "But she wears it better."

Elbowing Archie discretely in the side, Harry bowed her head under Ogden's curious gaze. "No thanks are necessary, Elder," she said politely. "Your wellbeing is gratification enough. Do see a professional healer, though, at your earliest convenience." Such was common sense, but she had a nervous sense of complete liability that she hadn't anticipated. Did real Healers feel this way?

"I will see to it myself," Marchbanks cut in, giving Harry a soft smile. "Thank you, Miss Potter. We had heard from our friend, Master Thompson, that you had a rare talent. How fortunate that it extends across such disparate disciplines."

The elders took their leave, heading slowly toward the entryway. She noticed they passed Riddle on his way back in, and stopped to talk for a short moment. Whatever they said drew Riddle's focus directly to Archie, who didn't seem to notice as he spoke animatedly with Draco and Blaise about what had just happened.

Riddle paused until Malfoy and Snape, who had come hurrying into the room shortly after him with Bellatrix at their side, caught up. They exchanged words briefly, and then all three began making their way across the ballroom.

Harry felt the distinct urge to run, but her mother had a proud hand on her shoulder and Addy had at least three locks of her hair clutched in a grubby fist and Archie was turning to her with a concerned look—

"What?" she said, blinking, "Sorry, I wasn't listening."

Archie laughed, though she noted it was a bit strained. "Draco was just asking about your wand, Harry."

"My—" she tilted her head in an effort to disguise the freezing dread that came upon her. "What about it, Mr. Malfoy?"

Draco had a hard look on his face, but it was tempered by confusion, not outright accusation. "It looked like Rigel's."

Lily, who of course overheard that comment, frowned, "That's odd. They aren't of similar woods, are they? What was yours again, Harry? Ash?"

"Elm," Harry said blandly, not meeting Archie's increasingly doom-filled gaze.

Lily looked confused for a moment, "I thought Archie had Elm."

"He has Holly," Harry said, fighting valiantly to keep her expression bored.

"I must have misremembered," Lily said, smiling, "It seems like so long ago, now."

"Children grow up so quickly," Mrs. Malfoy said, gazing at Draco somewhat despondently.

Draco flushed slightly in embarrassment, but was unfortunately not distracted from his confusion for long. "I've seen you use your wand a thousand times, Rigel, and I'm sure it looked odd just now."

Archie had apparently decided to just get the mystery over with, and began digging in his pocket with an expression that clearly said he was humoring Draco. Harry wished she could tell Archie that now was the worse possible time to do this, with Professor Snape coming their way along with Malfoy Sr. and Riddle himself, but instead she had to affect a mildly curious look along with everyone else looking on—namely Mrs. Malfoy, Mrs. Parkinson, Lily, Draco, and Pansy. The only reprieve was that James and Mr. Parkinson were occupied discussing the filing of a report on the assassination attempt, and any of the other partygoers who might have been interested in the drama involving Mr. Ogden had left when he did.

"Here, what's so odd about—oh." Archie looked down at the wand in his hand as though in stunned surprise. "Harry—this is yours." He laughed lowly, shaking his head as though unable to believe it. "We've switched again."

"Again?" Harry, too let her eyebrows rise in surprised amusement. She dug into her own pocket to produce the holly wand. Sighing with exasperation, she held it out to her cousin with a roll of her eyes. "I specifically reminded you this morning to take the right one once we were done flying. You always just grab whichever is closer."

"Well you didn't notice, either," Archie said, smiling teasingly.

"Only because I don't use it over the break anyway," Harry said, taking the elm wand and putting it into her pocket casually.

"You used it just now," Draco said, still looking a bit incredulous. "Are you telling me you use each others' wands without even noticing?"

Harry and Archie exchanged a look. "I suppose," Harry said, shrugging, "Is that odd?"

She knew very well that it was, but it wasn't as though they could prove she and Archie were lying. What other explanation could they think of for their switched wands, besides?

"You two always did share everything," Lily said, shaking her head fondly. Turning to the other adults, Lily smiled, "They used to wear one another's clothes when they were young. We'd dress them in the mornings, but by noon they'd traded half their garments for seemingly no reason whatsoever."

"Aunt Lily," Archie protested, his ears pinking.

Undeterred, Lily smirked faintly, "Why, the number of times I had to go through Sirius' laundry to find all of Harry's dresses—"

The other mothers tittered in delighted laughter while Draco turned incredibly amused eyes on his friend, successfully distracted. "You did what, Rigel?"

"Harry made me," Archie muttered, unable to look anyone in the eye.

With eyes on her, Harry shrugged in a deliberately nonchalant way. "His clothes were more comfortable. And he looks better in lace, anyway."

With low chuckles, the conversation moved on, at last, to other things. Riddle and Mr. Malfoy began conversing in low tones with Mr. Parkinson, no doubt divining what exactly had occurred in their absence. Her eyes caught those of Professor Snape, however, who was looking between she and Archie with a considering expression. It wasn't quite suspicious, but it seemed dangerously thoughtful to Harry, who knew very well that Snape knew how much trouble Rigel had using most wands that were not his own. Would he believe that Harry's wand was an exception to that?

Lily shifted Addy higher on her hip, and the movement caused her suppresser bracelet to catch the light dazzlingly. Snape's eyes shifted from Archie to Lily, and his gaze sharpened in realization and disappointment after considering the bracelet for a moment. Seeing his look, Lily followed his eye line to her suppresser and flushed almost guiltily. She sent the Potions Master a look that pleaded for understanding, but Snape turned pointedly away, lip curled in utter disgust.

Harry turned her eyes away and tried to pretend she didn't see the exchange. Somehow, the gala was not turning out like she'd thought it would. She remembered being bored at the previous one, but not consistently uncomfortable. Was that the difference between being a pureblood and a halfblood? A boy and a girl?

Mrs. Parkinson left with Mrs. Malfoy to begin the lengthy process of making the rounds to various groups of important partygoers and assuring them that all was well. Harry supposed somewhat cynically that most of them had been too proud to gawp like tourists as Ogden bled out on the floor, but weren't too proud to solicit the juicy gossip from a reliable source afterwards.

"I'm going to get food," Archie said at her elbow. At her raised eyebrow, he grinned sheepishly, "I uh…worked up an appetite Healing." Deciding that that was believable enough not to make him seem out of character, she waved him off. Draco followed her cousin, though he did send her a single, penetrating look as he left. Pansy was assisting her mother in talking to as many people as possible before speculation ran rampant. The male adults were in heavy discussion, James and the Minister included, which left Harry with Lily and Addy, the latter of whom was looking very cranky.

Lily shushed her quietly, grimacing as she shifted the baby once more on her hip.

"Want me to hold her again?" Harry asked.

Lily smiled, "Are you sure? You always seem so convinced she isn't going to let you."

Harry smiled back. "Tonight is lucky, I think."

"Very lucky," Lily said, suddenly serious. "Harry, that was an amazing thing you did. When you first insisted on joining the Healing tract instead of the Potions tract just so you and Archie could live some sort of vicarious half-life through one another, well, it made my heart ache. I think now, though, that maybe you were meant to. You saved a man's life today, little Fawn. And from what I understand, Archie saved his life a year and a half ago with some very specialized potions knowledge that I can only assume came from you. I think Fate had a hand in that. You two are going to do great things."

"It really wasn't that big a deal," Harry said, "If there had been someone else within hearing that knew how to Heal, they would have done the same."

"Well this time it was you, and you did wonderfully. And to thank you, I'm awarding you babysitting duties for the duration of one hour," Lily said cheekily, transferring Addy to Harry's shoulder with a sigh of relief. "I'd put a weightless charm on her, but I'm half-afraid I'll forget I'm holding her and let go."

"I'll watch her," Harry said, smirking, "Go dance with Dad." From what she could see, James seemed to be winding up his discussion with Malfoy, Parkinson, Riddle, and the Minister.

"What a marvelous idea," her mother mused, eyes twinkling, "It has been too long since James drooled at my feet, hasn't it?"

Grimacing, Harry made a face that only Addy could see. "Whatever you say, Mum. I'm going to take Addy someplace quieter so she can rest."

"Find us before midnight," Lily said absently, already eyeing her father like she was a cat and he a particularly lively ice mouse. "Sirius will want to toast together."

Murmuring a promise to do so, Harry resituated Addy more comfortably and wandered off, in search of a corner that was quiet enough to calm Addy down without being dark enough to risk coming across something unsavory. Eventually, she decided a balcony was her best bet and chose one at random.

She took the stairs carefully, very aware of how fragile the thing in her arms was, and how little she knew about infant anatomy, in case of an accident. Mentally adding that to her list of things to learn once she got her time-turner back, she ascended the final step and looked up, then faltered.

Rosier was up there with Rookwood and Selwyn, and all three were looking entirely curious. She hesitated, but realized it would be churlish to retreat at this point. Instead, she inclined her head politely in Rosier's general direction and hoped he would just leave her alone. She was tired, and quite ready to give up the evening as a bad job. Well, apart from her talking to Professor Snape as herself. That part she was pleased with.

He didn't, of course, leave her alone, instead waving his friends over to meet her. She supposed she couldn't be too annoyed—from Rosier's perspective, he was probably taking social pity on Rigel's pathetically friendless cousin. From that angle, he was actually being very nice.

"Miss Potter," he said, "This is Edmund Rookwood and his fiancé Alesana Selwyn."

"Congratulations," she said, eyes flicking to the lovely dark-stoned ring on Selwyn's finger. "It's lovely to meet you both. Rigel had mentioned you many times."

"Thank you," Rookwood rumbled, giving Selwyn a proud, smoldering look. Turning his eyes back to Harry, he added, "We can say the same of you, Miss Potter."

She blinked. She didn't really talk about herself that often when she was Rigel…did she?

Selwyn smirked slightly, her beautiful eyes rimmed flawlessly in kohl. "Why so surprised? You must know how he esteems you."

"I'm all he's ever known," Harry said, a bit wryly.

"Not any longer, though" Rosier said, smile like a razor.

Impervious to his attempt to goad her, Harry smiled back, just as sharply. "That's true. It's nice to see him make friends. He's so prone to trouble, as I'm sure you've noticed. Perhaps, once you've known him as long as I have, you'll be better at keeping him out of it."

Rosier looked positively offended, which made it worth throwing herself under the bus. She could not quite suppress the amusement she felt at getting under his skin for a change. As Rigel she worried about offended him—they were friends, after all. As Harry, though, she could say whatever she wished.

Rookwood chuckled appreciatively. "Careful with this one, Aldon. She is under no obligation to put up with you."

"I noticed," Rosier said, looking as though he was holding back a pout. "She refused to dance with me, you know, then went and danced a set with Pansy. It hurt my feelings."

Harry suppressed a snort. "When have you ever denied Miss Parkinson something? The girl is impossible to refuse—Merlin knows I tried." When Rosier insisted on holding onto his hurt expression, she sighed. "Miss Parkinson invited me personally tonight. How could I refuse her invitation in light of that?"

The golden-eyed boy hummed. "I suppose that's true. Very well, I forgive you. Provided you dance with me at the next gala."

"I won't be at the next gala," Harry said, disbelief coloring her expression. "I told you, I'm only here because I was specifically invited, and Rigel wanted to introduce me to Professor Snape."

"Snape?" Selwyn's eyebrow lifted. "Why?"

"I'm his biggest fan," Harry deadpanned.

"Regardless." Rosier waved a hand, looking mildly disturbed. "If need be I will personally invite you to the next gala."

"Your family hosted the last one," Harry said, "You can't host it again next year."

Rosier's eyes sharpened just a tad. "Rigel really tells you everything, does he?"

"Yes." Harry intensified her gaze until she knew it could give a grown man shivers and held Rosier's eyes. "Everything."

The upperclassman dropped his gaze with a grimace, distinctly uncomfortable of a sudden.

Selwyn laughed. "I like you, Miss Potter. Most halfbloods would think twice before antagonizing the son of Lord Rosier."

Not sure if she should be flattered or offended, Harry demurred. "Do you know many halfbloods, Miss Selwyn?"

"Very good," Selwyn said, eyes flashing. "If you do return next year, keep that gumption. It will serve you well."

Harry was about to ask what she meant by that when Addy began to fuss. Harry began juggling her awkwardly, really not sure what she should do to make her stop. When she began crying louder, Harry winced and cast an imploring look at the other three. "How do I—ah—stop this?"

"Haven't you any experience with her?" Rosier asked, "She is your sister."

"Not really," Harry said, attempting to switch Addy around—maybe she wanted to see something? "She sort of dislikes me." At her less than graceful handling, Addy let out a shrill shout of annoyance that caused several nearby people to look over in annoyance.

"Let me," Selwyn said sharply, scooping Addy out of Harry's hands with natural ease. The dark-haired girl held the baby closer to her chest, instead of further away to spare her ears. She rocked very gently back and forth, her free hand stroking Addy's soft hair. Harry started to profusely thank the girl, only to pause upon registering the acute look of longing on the other girl's face. Selwyn looked more fond of Addy in that moment than even Harry was, and she considered herself quite attached to the small wailing creature.

"You're very good with her," Harry said, injecting the proper amount of gratitude into her tone.

"I had a little sister, once," Selwyn said softly, her attention far away. "She was sickly, but she had a cry that could shatter crystal. I used to hold her for hours at night, when my mother needed to rest."

Harry, noting the past tense with a pang, kept silent as Rookwood curled an arm around the older girl. Noticing their sympathetic expressions, Selwyn's face closed abruptly. "We lost her to the Fade. The doctors warned us, of course. Everyone knows the risks. It was a foolish ambition."

Harry found she couldn't tear her eyes from Addy in that moment. She knew about the difficulties pureblooded families had in producing more than one child—everyone did, just as Selwyn said. The cause wasn't completely understood, but healers thought it had something to do with the nature of magic taking root. Pureblooded mothers could often carry one child to term, but after that it became exponentially more difficult. Second children were often squibs, but more often they were born weak and struggled to live despite nothing being physically wrong with them.

When such a child died, they called it fading, and textbooks described the slow, inevitable drain of strength and life that afflicted the infant. No book could describe the horror of standing by while a child died, however. Looking at her little sister, Harry was struck by how much she took for granted in her life. How many of the women at this gala had lost infants? How many were too afraid to try, paralyzed by the probability of tragedy. Were there others, even among her own friends, who might have had younger siblings?

"Take good care of her," Selwyn said, shifting to hand the now-quiet Addy back to Harry.

"I will," Harry promised. She was unable to keep herself from wondering, as Selwyn walked away, if her little sister was the reason she could see thestrals. Harry hoped not.

Rookwood and Rosier bid her a quick farewell, hurrying after their friend.

There was a very large clock of white gold hanging over the refreshment table, and with the hands only minutes from striking midnight, Harry supposed she ought to find her family once more. After everything that had happened tonight, she couldn't say she wasn't looking forward to going home. She just wanted to lock herself in her lab for days, or at least until her mind stopped feeling like a sieve, leaking thoughts and emotions into the rest of her body like a flash flood.

Maybe the new year would be better. Simpler. She could go back to being Rigel, soon, and concentrate on her upcoming apprenticeship. Ignoring the little voice telling her that pretending to be someone else wasn't supposed to be easier than being yourself, Harry cast one last glance over the glittering assembly, then turned away.

The sounds of several hundred indisposed notables filled the room, but he could not join in their frivolity. He had too many things to consider, in light of all he had learned that night. Plans to make. Vengeance to take. His position required he make nice with the fabulously wealthy and powerful as the year was made new, but is was all he could do to survey the hall without losing his dinner. Jewels dribbled from ears and down necklines like rivulets of particularly pristine drool, marking their wearers as members of that indescribably extravagant class of wastrels. How distastefully predictable they seemed to him.

His perusal of the scene was interrupted as the young Lord Black and his family caught his attention. Sufficiently distracted from his distain, his lips curled at the thought of Dumbledore's faction now short all that precious funding. Not to mention the Wizengamot votes. And it was all thanks to the man's heir, the enigmatic Rigel Black.

How very innocuous the boy looked, smiling in anticipation just as a dozen other young wizards were as the clock counted down the seconds in a loud ventriloquism spell. He looked different than last he saw him, but he supposed that was the fluidity of youth. There was something suspicious about the boy, nonetheless. Already an anomaly, tonight the young Heir Black demonstrated knowledge of Healing that was inexplicable in light of what he knew of his schooling. Lucius had certainly not mentioned any Healing classes. He would have to interrogate Severus more closely on the matter, but even if the boy was incredibly gifted, he could not have learned so much in four months of third-year Healing classes. From Cassius' report, Black had demonstrated at least as much capability as his cousin, who had the benefit of two and a half years of intensive study in the art, at the best Healing program in the Western Hemisphere, no less.

It patently did not square. Then add to that the spectacle of a witch and wizard accidentally using one another's wand. Unheard of. A witch would sooner accidentally take another's child from the playground. It shouldn't even be possible to use another's wand with such a degree of skill, at least without consistent practice and the wand's full allegiance. Might they have been swapping wands for so long that it became moot? Could a wand have dual allegiances? He didn't know, and that displeased him. Perhaps a visit to Ollivanders was in order.

The girl, too, was suspicious. More, in fact, from what little he'd seen to judge. Severus had spent nearly fifteen minutes in deep conversation with the chit, which was red flag enough, but her aura was off, too. At his first, perfunctory glance, it was nothing special. When he'd reentered the ballroom after her Healing, however, it hadn't fluctuated one bit. She ought to have been nearly drained, if her magic levels were accurately reflected, but they didn't have a dent in them. Her cousin, however, had ravenously attached himself to the food table shortly thereafter.

Had Rigel Black been supplying the majority of the magic without anyone noticing? Why would the girl pretend to be doing the work? To secure a life debt? It would be difficult to conceal such a ruse under the noses of some of the sharpest witches and wizards he knew, however. On the other hand, why would she conceal the true levels of her magic? There weren't many wizards with the skill to even read auras, much less falsify their own. To think that a little girl had picked up the ability by chance was absurd. But what need could she possibly have?

He had briefly considered plucking the information from her mind, but a quick scan had revealed Occlumency shields at least as substantial as her cousin's: likely able to detect his attempt, at any rate. He would have to come by the understanding honestly, it seemed. There was at least a dram of satisfaction to by found by such inefficient measures. Now was not the time, however.

With a deft mental compartmentalization, he turned his attention to more important matters. He had things other than thirteen-year-olds to consider at the moment. His mind's eye turned to Hogwarts, and the rat who thought he could escape there with his prize. That could be his only priority. No one fooled Tom Riddle and lived to gloat about it.

Chapter 12

Hermione was staring at him again. She'd been distractedly examining him at odd moments all week, which was very unusual for the studious witch. Normally nothing could pull her attention from the blackboard in class. Archie glanced over at his friend with a raised eyebrow, his quill taking over where his hand left off without pause. Hermione spared the dicto-quill a disapproving look before turning back to gaze at him again, her own eyebrow raised right back.

Resigning himself to being confused until the curly-haired girl got around to explaining herself, Archie sent Hermione an exaggerated eye-smile that had her turning back to her notes with a silent huff. He had to let a real smile out at that. Hermione was too cute when she got annoyed—which was often, and rather refreshing, he thought. Harry almost never got annoyed at him—even when he was being purposely annoying! Drawing his thoughts away from his cousin's unnaturally thick skin, he tried to concentrate on what their Medical Procedures professor was saying. Something about consent. And how was a person in dire need of medical care supposed to consent, anyway? He peeked at Hermione's notes to see if she'd written down anything about that, and saw 'emergency—implied?' scrawled in the margin. That's what he loved about Hermione—they were always on the same page.

"You're on the wrong page," Hermione hissed, jabbing his arm with her pointed quill. Archie checked the pair of students to his left and realized that they had, in fact, moved on to a new chapter when he wasn't paying attention. He offered a winning grin as he quickly flipped to the page everyone else was reading from. "Honestly," his partner said, sounding quite exasperated, "You said you would be in charge of the book this semester. If you can't keep up—"

"Can I help it if you're so distracting?" Archie muttered playfully. "How can I pay the lesson any attention when I've given it all to you, 'Mione?"

"Don't blame me for your lack of focus," Hermione whispered sharply. She pulled the book they were sharing closer to her side of the desk with a narrow-eyed glare that just dared him to object. Archie merely smiled and leaned closer to read over her shoulder. Objection was the furthest thing from his mind.

Fifteen minutes before the lesson was scheduled to end, Professor Bernhart told them to pack up their materials. Hermione looked as confused as he felt, so Archie felt confident that this hadn't been in the lesson plan.

"As you all should know, this is the last year of general Healing classes before you will be expected to begin considering a specialty," Bernhart said, brushing a lock of curly hair back from her rectangular frames. "Beginning in fourth year, your schedules will be considerably more flexible. You'll be responsible for choosing classes that best reflect the area of Healing you'd like to someday practice. There is room for overlap, of course, and many students prefer to keep their options open until sixth or seventh year, but it is important to begin as you mean to go on. With this in mind, today we'll be testing your individual levels of magical output to give you some idea of where your talents might be put to best use."

"What does that mean?" Sally Parks looked very worried behind her long, straight bangs.

Professor Bernhart looked slightly uncomfortable, and said delicately, "Some fields of Healing make higher demands on a witch or wizard's core than others. At this point most of your cores should be fully matured. The level of magic you have access to will likely not fluctuate much in the coming years. If the more magic-intensive Healing procedures are beyond your capabilities, it would be better to know now, so that you can choose your specialties sensibly."

Several of their classmates seemed apprehensive at this information. Archie could understand why—they'd all worked very hard to get to this point, and to be told that your future career depended on something you couldn't control was disheartening.

"Don't look so alarmed," Bernhart said, smiling kindly, "Very few fields have such a restriction on them—just Critical Care, Infectious Diseases, and Neonatal-Perinatal, really."

Sally, who Archie suspected was leaning toward Toxicology, looked relieved, but Hermione and Archie shared a silent look. Hermione was fascinated with Wizarding childbirth and he had never considered any specialty besides advanced-stage disease treatment and prevention. To have this potential obstacle come out of nowhere was a little off-putting.

Hermione raised her hand with a determined expression and Professor Bernhart, to her credit, only looked slightly apprehensive as she called on her. "Why were we not told of such a requirement at the outset of our choosing this tract?"

"There was little point in bringing it up before you could be tested, Miss Granger," Bernhart explained gently. "A witch or wizard's core can't be properly measured until their thirteenth year. Making you worry over something you could not influence would only be detrimental to your studies. It isn't quite the crisis I'm sure you're imagining. There are many interesting and important fields of study that do not require above average levels of magic for success. Don't worry, and think of this as a learning exercise. Your levels of magic are not a reflection of your talent or ability. They are something you should understand about yourself, however, so that you may grow to your full potential."

Hermione did not look at all satisfied with that answer, and Archie knew she would spend the next week researching the various factors that influenced a wizard's power levels. There wasn't time for any more questions, however, as Bernhart was already pulling out a device that Archie recognized by its cylindrical shape as a magometer.

"When it is your turn, you will step out into the hall with me," Bernhart was explaining. "Simply channel your magic as you would when performing a basic bone mending, except instead of stopping when the bone is knit, you will continue to feed magic into the device at a constant rate until you run out. You are excused from your practical work this afternoon, as your cores may take a night to replenish what the device siphons off." Seeing the unnerved expressions on some of the faces around the room, Professor Bernhart added, "It won't hurt. Who would like to go first?"

Unsurprisingly, Hermione's hand shot up with eager anticipation. Bernhart smiled encouragingly, and led Hermione out to the hallway for a little privacy. Archie leaned back in his chair, mulling over this new development. He supposed he didn't have much to worry about—the Blacks were known for generally high levels of magic, on average. Hermione though—well, muggleborns were hard to predict. A lot of them had below-average level cores, but sometimes they had nearly double that of a regular core. Aunt Lily, for instance, apparently had much more magic than he had previously imagined, if what Harry said was true.

Hermione came back into the room a few minutes later with a pleased glow across her cheeks, and Archie realized he needn't have worried.

"It turned light blue," Hermione whispered softly, aware that their curious (and rather competitive) classmates were not-so-subtly trying to listen in. "She said that's plenty of magic for Neonatal Care, especially as I'm so efficient with my spells."

"That's great, Hermione," Archie said, proud and gratified on her behalf. His brilliant and hardworking friend deserved to study whatever she wanted.

When it was his turn, he ambled out into the hallway, mildly curious at what his own diagnosis would be. Since hearing Harry describe the device, he'd wondered what it would feel like. He grasped the end of the long tube firmly, taking a moment to stir his magic to activity.

"If you need any help in channeling your magic, just let me know, Mr. Potter," Bernhart said. She had a clipboard in one hand that Archie could see, with his perfect peripheral vision that everyone assumed he didn't have because of the fake glasses he wore, bore a list of names with several blanks after each.

He gave his professor a relaxed smile, then began funneling his magic into the device as though it was a person he was trying to Heal. He could feel the runes in the device helping him direct his raw magic, which would probably have gone all over the place otherwise, and noted with interest that the crystal sphere on the end was blooming with color already. He watched it absently as it turned from red to orange and began to bleed yellow, then got distracted by a sudden lurch in the pit of his stomach.

Something was tugging at his magic, and it wasn't the device. He felt a familiar tingling in his face and realized with mild horror that the magic holding his metamorphing in place was beginning to unravel. He firmed the transformation immediately, as the last thing he needed was for his teacher to witness a sudden inexplicable shift in his features. As he pulled magic back into maintaining his guise, however, he felt the magic that was being channeled to the device slow significantly, shortly coming to a stuttering halt.

Archie let out small pants of breath as Bernhart took the device from his numb fingers. He was monstrously exhausted all of a sudden. At the forced smile on his professor's face, his gut clenched further and his eyes darted to the end of the magometer. It was a sickly yellow-green.

"Perfectly respectable, Mr. Potter," the older woman said evenly, marking down the shade on her clipboard. "And what specialties are you considering?"

"I want to do Infectious Diseases, Professor," he said, voice subdued.

"You…may want to reconsider," she said gently. "There are a lot of other—"

"I don't want to do anything else," he said firmly.

Bernhart's lips pressed together in a suppressed sigh. "The Infectious Disease path is one of the most difficult, Mr. Potter. I'm sure you have the drive, and you aren't lacking in intelligence, but at some point the practical work will be too much for your reserves. Many of the more advanced treatment procedures simply require a great deal of magic to pull off. I'm sorry, but it won't be possible to employ you in such a field."

Archie made a show of shrugging nonchalantly. "I don't need to be involved in treating them myself, Professor. I'm more interested in the research side of things, to be honest. I want to made headway in curing difficult or poorly understood diseases, but I don't care if I'm the one doing the physical curing. It's enough for me to focus my studies on them, and work in the theoretical aspects of the field."

"Even so," Bernhart protested, "The coursework required to achieve such a specialty is itself magically demanding. It would be difficult to pass with distinction—"

"But not impossible," Archie said, giving the professor his best believe-in-me smile. "I can do it, Professor. If it becomes too much I promise to reconsider switching specialties, but you can give me a chance, can't you?"

Bernhart looked torn, but allowed, "It is your decision. I can only attempt to guide you toward a responsible choice."

"Put me down for Infectious Diseases, please," Archie insisted. "I'll make it work."

She sighed, but did as he asked. He strolled back into the classroom with an air of supreme unconcern, but Hermione's frown told him she wasn't fooled at all.

"That took a long time," she said softly, "Is everything all right?"

"Perfect," Archie told her, "I'm Infectious Diseases, like I wanted."

"That's wonderful," Hermione said, excitement leaking into her voice, "What color did you get, if you don't mind me asking?"

"Green," he said, telling himself it wasn't technically a lie. No need to worry his friend. Especially since it wasn't a true concern, in any case. He hadn't realized staying constantly morphed tied up such a large portion of his magical core. It took enormous concentration, of course, especially to keep it up in his sleep, a feat he still felt great pride in having achieved, but he'd never considered the magic involved. Still, he wouldn't need access to all his magic until the upper years of study. By then, maybe Harry could come up with a way to make their Polyjuiced forms even more similar, so that his metamorphic abilities didn't have as much work to do.

Since their practicals had been canceled for the day, he and Hermione took a stroll out to their favorite tree to get some reading done before dinner. After the unexpected excitement of magic testing earlier, Archie had almost forgotten Hermione's unexplained staring problem, but when he caught her giving him measuring looks from over her textbook he tilted his head in friendly invitation to speak.

"How was your winter break?" she asked, very casually.

Archie was pretty sure she'd asked him that several times since they'd been back, but he played along. "Really great. How was yours?"

"Fine," she hummed. After a moment she added, "It's strange going back to the muggle world after so much time here, though. What's it like, living with other wizards? Do you do anything exciting for Christmas—I mean, Yule?"

"Nothing spectacular," Archie said, "Just gift exchange and lots of food, really. Some folk go to services for the old gods at Midwinter, but my family isn't particularly spiritual."

"What about New Year?" Hermione asked, blinking curiously. "I've heard wizards mark the modern calendar year as well with parties and the like. There's a really popular one in England, now that I think about it, isn't there?"

"Ah, yes," Archie said, trying not to frown. "There's a big gala on New Year's Eve that the SOW Party throws. It's sort of a fundraiser, but also sort of a social event for, um, high society types."

"You mean purebloods," Hermione said bluntly, "Yes I've heard. Have you ever been?"

"I…did go this year," Archie said, wondering why on earth Hermione was so interested in the event. Had she heard something? There wasn't anyone at AIM who would have been at a pureblood society event besides him, he didn't think. American and British Wizarding communities didn't really mix, and all the Englanders at AIM were muggleborns or halfbloods. He supposed someone might have family who'd been there, but why would they talk to Hermione about it?

"That's unusual, isn't it?" Hermione commented, "It's my understanding that the guest list is very exclusive, at least when it comes to those of mixed heritage like us."

"My cousin wanted to introduce me to some people," Archie said vaguely, "And my dad was working security for the Minister that night, so my family went along. It was unusual, yes. I probably won't attend again."

"Why not?" Hermione asked, "Don't you get along with those Sow Party types?"

"I just won't have cause to," Archie said, a bit uncomfortable. Looking to change the subject, he added, "It's pronounced like 'sew' by the way, not 'sow.'"

"What?" Hermione looked taken aback, and Archie congratulated himself for successfully distracting her. "No, I'm sure I heard someone call them the Cow Party, and it rhymes, doesn't it?"

"Actually, no," Archie explained, "That's a reference to what the Party used to be called. It started out as the C.O.W. party, then it got changed later to the S.O.W. party."

"What does C.O.W. stand for?" Hermione wrinkled her nose, "And why would anyone think up such an awful acronym?"

Archie laughed. "I don't think anyone called it the C.O.W. Party back then. It was the Cure Our World campaign. It—well, it was actually extremely bigoted. 'Cure' was meant mostly as 'Cleanse,' I think, and the entire platform was the thinning out of mixed or muggle blood from Wizarding Society."

Hermione's mouth fell open in outrage. "But that's barbaric! It's the same sort of rhetoric that excuses ethnic genocide! How could there possibly be a political platform in this day and age that supports such obvious—" she broke off into a short growl of disbelief. "Cure our world indeed—just who do they think they are?"

"They're mostly prejudiced gits who are too blinded by their own enmity to notice that the world has moved on without their bigotry," Archie said, shrugging a bit, "It's made up of families from a political oligarchy that goes back centuries, really, but their party was losing influence steadily after the fall of Grindelwald, until about forty years ago when Riddle took over and revitalized it completely. He's the one who changed the name to Save Our World, and it was his people who started calling it the SOW Party. Their motto is something to do with sowing the seeds of the future or whatever—that's why it's pronounced like 'sew' not 'sow.' It's mainly Light-sided wizards who remember what the true root of the Party is that call it the Cow Party—it's an insult, and a reminder, see?"

Hermione's eyes widened, "That's why their seal has a bag on it—it's a bag of seed!"

Archie grinned slightly, "Thought it was a bag of money, didn't you? That's what a lot of people think, cause it's made up primarily of old moneyed families."

"I knew the Sow Party had strong stances against muggle influences on society, but I didn't know it was the basis of their entire platform," Hermione said, looking incredibly upset.

"They have a lot of other agendas, too," Archie said, "At least, they do now. Riddle champions all sorts of causes through the Party, like the releasing of restrictions on Dark Magic and Artifacts, the reintroduction of certain standards of schooling, the establishment of various societies and charities devoted to the preservation of traditional Wizarding culture…all sorts of stuff, really. Blood supremacy is just one of the most volatile and controversial issues they push for. And the oldest."

"They have so much influence, though," Hermione groaned. "How can roughly half of an entire population be so—so—wrong?"

"It's not half," Archie reassured her, now regretting bringing up the subject. "I mean, purebloods do make up a quite a chunk of the population, but a lot of purebloods are in Dumbledore's Party, too. There're loads of people who don't care either way, too. It's just that those few who have a lot of influence in society tend to be in one party or the other. There aren't a lot of really powerful Neutrals anymore."

"They aren't all purebloods, though," Hermione said suddenly, "Other people associate with them, don't they? You went to one of their events, even. Why would anyone who wasn't pureblood support their agenda?"

"The SOW Party has power," Archie said, "Influence. They've rigged the employment system with laws and incentives so that the only way for a halfblood or muggleborn of talent to get a position in the Ministry or in the numerous private companies secretly funded by the Party is to play by their rules. Also, like I said, they support other things. Most Dark inclined witches and wizards support the Party, even if they aren't pureblooded, because it's the only organization fighting the stigma against Dark Magic."

"Why would anyone want to support Dark Magic?" Hermione snapped, clearly indignant.

"It's not all Unforgivable Curses," Archie said slowly, "It used to have a better reputation, actually. The Light aligned wizards have spent a lot of time in the last fifty years working to undermine the SOW Party by attacking the kinds of witches and wizards who support it. Traditionally Dark families also tend to be more politically conservative and more blood-obsessed. So by working for restrictions against Dark Magic and setting a tone of intolerance about it, Dumbledore's Party can indirectly discredit other things Dark wizards stand for, and resist efforts by the SOW Party to pass blood supremacist legislation as well."

"So instead of debating the real issues, both sides just attack the parts of the opposition's platform that are easiest," Hermione summed up, disgust on her face, "But that's ludicrous. Then you've got people who don't even care about blood supporting prejudiced policies for the sake of some other end and causes of real merit being overlooked on both sides because of which side endorses them—it's so terribly inefficient and irresponsible!"

"It's politics," Archie said, not sure what there was to be so worked up about. Then again, he grew up knowing how things were in the Wizarding world. "It's always been complicated. Everything is about alliances and money and power and the exchanges they facilitate. There are ways to get around the system, though, if you're clever."

"It's idiotic," Hermione insisted. "Someone has to do something." She began muttering to herself wildly as she abandoned her textbook completely in favor of scribbling out long lines of neatly printed letters in one of her notebooks.

Archie settled back to watch her fume and plot. He wasn't sure if there was anything a thirteen-year-old could do, exactly, but if there was, Hermione would be the one to figure it out. She was alarmingly brilliant when she set her mind to a problem. All the more reason to keep her mind on things other than him, in fact. If nothing else, solving the Wizarding world's woes would keep Hermione too busy to consider his many idiosyncrasies.

Transitioning back to her role as Rigel after the break came almost too easily to Harry. Even after being on the other side and meeting all her friends as herself for a brief moment, Rigel's semi-persona was comfortable and almost relaxing. Here at Hogwarts she didn't have to worry about what Archie was doing or saying or what her parents or Sirius would think or what others would think they were thinking or…anything. She could just let go of all that drama for a while and get back into the familiar rhythm of classes, studying, and, of course, potions making.

Her friends hadn't brought up anything about the gala since she'd been back, which she took as a good sign that their ruse had been pulled off rather deftly—that is, until she walked in on them talking about it without her.

It was the first Saturday after break, and she was the last to wake. She'd been absolutely exhausted by the time she collapsed into bed the night before, having turned back a full day and a half cumulatively since the last time she'd slept. On weekends, when Defense Club meetings meant there was no need to wake up early to exercise, she could take as much sleep as she wanted, getting the most out of her sleep-cycle adjusting potion, even if it did make her look like a bit of a layabout to her roommates.

She washed her teeth and face and grabbed her bag, thinking to beg a meal from Binny before turning back once again to see Snape about an assignment she was meant to be handing in that week.

Spotting her friends across the common room, she wove her way over with the intent to see what was on the agenda later in the day. As she approached, however, she heard Millicent saying, "You noticed too? I thought maybe he was nervous."

"Rigel doesn't get nervous," Theo, whose chair was facing away from Rigel as she walked up, scoffed lightly, "More likely he was acting for the sake of his fam—"

A swift elbow from Blaise, who had noted Rigel's presence, shut Theo's mouth rather quickly, but it was too late at that point to pretend politely she hadn't heard. She loitered at the edge of the couch as serenely as she was able, smiling good naturedly to make sure Theo knew she wasn't offended—she knew he didn't think long about most of the things he said. It was part of his charm.

"You guys are talking about the gala, right?" she said.

"We just thought you seemed a bit uncomfortable that night," Pansy, ever the diplomat, said. "Was everything all right?"

"Of course." Rigel shrugged. "I suppose I must have been distracted. I worried about Harry most of the night—she's not very social, and I know how many people were looking forward to meeting her."

"Miss Potter was just lovely," Pansy said, "There was no reason to be concerned. How could we not like anyone you held in such esteem?"

"That's kind of you to say, Pansy," Rigel said, amused. "Harry did mention to me how solicitous you were that evening. It meant a lot that you all included her."

She hid a smile at the slightly guilty looks on several of her friends' faces. Serves them right, she thought slyly. As Harry she didn't care much how people who were essentially strangers looked at her, but as Rigel she wanted better of her friends.

"We were, ah, going to work on that Transfiguration essay this morning," Theo said after a long moment. "Did you want to join us?"

Rigel shook her head. She couldn't tell them that she'd finished the essay on Tuesday when it hadn't been assigned until Wednesday, but she had other business in any case. "I have to go see Snape."

"It's Saturday." Draco frowned. "And you just saw him last night."

She mentally winced, realizing that was an idiotic thing to let slip out. She was in fact about to turn back to the previous night, but it was entirely surreal to hear Draco tell her she'd already done something she hadn't, in fact, done yet. "I forgot to ask him something," she said, resigning herself to making up an excuse to stop by that morning when she was next present in it, just in case one of her friends checked.

As she left the common room, she wondered if she was overdoing it on the time-turner, now that she had it back. This would make her third—no, fourth—Friday evening. She had also spent Friday evening brewing in her lab, researching obscure cauldron treating techniques in a secluded corner of the Library, and working on one of Flint's essays in the Come and Go Room. At this rate, she would be through most of the things she was interested in learning by the end of the year. Then again, those things would likely lead to new things to learn, and she didn't know how long she would be allowed access to such a valuable resource. It would be criminal to waste it.

She slipped into an alcove and turned back sixteen hours to the previous evening. With a quick check to make sure she did, in fact, have the assignment for Snape finished and in her bag, she made her way through the dungeons toward Snape's office. With a quick nod and greeting to Draco, who was going in the opposite direction, she knocked on the door and waited to be admitted.

There was no immediate answer, which she found odd, as they nearly always met at the same time on Friday evenings to discuss the week's assignments. Perhaps he was tied up elsewhere. She debated leaving the assignment under his door, but decided she could wait at least a little while for him to show up. It wasn't as though she didn't have the time, she thought with a secret grin. The grin left her face when she realized she had forgotten to get breakfast before turning back to meet Snape. Her stomach rumbled and she patted it sympathetically. She had the suspicion that time-turning took a toll on the user's energy reserves, as she was much hungrier than usual of late.

It was ten minutes later that her Head of House came striding down the corridor with wide sweeps of his robes. She put her Herbology textbook back in her bag and stood aside patiently while he unlocked his office door. She settled into the chair he conjured for her and took out her assignment from her bag. He'd given her a recipe for an unknown potion and asked that she fill in the blank ingredients and directions based on what she imagined the recipe was intended to do. She'd come up with two possible versions that she thought were, if not equally viable, at least interesting interpretations, and was eager to see what he made of them.

Snape dropped a bag from his pocket onto his desk and scowled at it for a moment before sitting down as well. As his robes met the chair, they sent up a fine cloud of black dust that glinted oddly in the torchlight.

Rigel's eyes fixated on the metallic particles floating between them for a long moment, a memory stirring. "What is that from, Professor?" She didn't think she'd seen it anywhere at Hogwarts. It definitely looked familiar, though.

"This?" the Potions Master spelled it away with an annoyed sneer. "From the Metallurgists' Guild, of course. Their foyer is coated in it."

"The one on Craftsman Alley?" she asked, frowning. She'd never been there, but it wasn't too far from the Potions Guild.

"Mm," Snape hummed, sounding displeased. "I acquired a number of suspiciously cheap moonstones from a dubious associate and required use of the Guild's expertise to ensure the stones were genuine."

"Does the Metallurgist Guild often work with the Potions Guild?" she asked distractedly as she tried to recall where she'd seen the dust. Somewhere in the alleys…it hit her. She'd knocked into a man on her way to the Guild one morning, a man whose robes were covered in the black dust, and whose little brown sack she'd helped to recover… she had to stop herself from groaning out loud. It had been Pettigrew. She hadn't recognized him as her parents' old friend at the time, but looking back it could have been no one else. He'd probably had the jewel on him that very day—in the sack she'd so blithely handed back to him, even!

"The metallurgists will check the properties of any materials you bring them, for a relatively low fee," Snape was saying. "Though I might have saved myself the trip—the odds of Fletcher having anything but synthetic moonstone were miniscule in any case…"

He seemed to be speaking mostly to himself, now, which was good, because Rigel wasn't hearing most of it. If Pettigrew had been to the Metallurgist Guild with the artifact, they may have tested its properties—they may know something about the jewel, or remember Pettigrew and be able to recognize its description if someone were to ask. But how would anyone know to ask unless she did something about it?

"In any case, your assignment, Mr. Black?"

Rigel snapped back into the present, relegating the jewel to the back of her mind for the moment. "Here," she said, handing it across the desk. She sat silently as he perused her work, and felt a little glow of pleasure as his lips twitched just the slightest bit in pleased approval.

"Very creative," he said, drawling his voice a bit, "Though your adding the jasmine blossoms in the second variation is a bit of a stretch—its only purpose would be to eliminate the effects of the garlic, which would make putting garlic in the potion to begin with rather fatuous."

"But not beyond the capacity for idiocy that some recipe designers possess," Rigel said innocently, fighting to keep a smirk off her face.

"Hmm, quite," Snape said, his eyes flicking up from the parchment to assess her politely interested expression. "Still, it was a bit impudent to turn Heinrich's Vampire Repellant into a breath-freshening potion, don't you think?"

"Is that what the original recipe was?" Rigel's eyes widened dramatically. "I had no idea."

Snape looked very close to rolling his eyes. "Clearly you require more difficult coursework in the future."

"I wouldn't want to strain your question-fabricating abilities," Rigel said, affecting a concerned look. "I'm sure it's been a while since you had to come up with new assignments. Er, how long have you been teaching again, Sir?"

"Impudent brat," Snape snorted. "For that, you can write a four foot essay on the effects of modern muggle agricultural technology on the potency and availability of magical ingredients worldwide."

Rigel couldn't stop the smile that escaped her. That sounded interesting. "Thank you, Sir."

Snape sneered, but nonetheless wrote out the assigned topic for her with a generally satisfied air. "Now," he said, leaning back once more, "Your extracurricular classes are going well, I presume? No difficulty completing the winter assignments without your time-turner?"

"Yes, Sir, everything is going smoothly," Rigel said, tamping down on any guilt she might feel at overusing the device until nothing but responsibleness and gratitude shone on her face.

"Good," he said, "Your next Ministry-required evaluation will be mid-February."

"All right," she said, not particularly worried. The last few had been straightforward—well, as straightforward as the Department of Mysteries got, apparently.

"As to your apprenticeship—"

"He said yes?" Rigel beamed, having been waiting for this moment since she stepped off the train.

Snape gave her an odd look, and Rigel realized he would have expected Sirius to have told her already. He probably did tell Archie, but Archie likely assumed she would assume correctly.

"He did," Snape said, valiantly suppressing a sneer at the barest mention of Sirius in passing. He really was getting better at ignoring his sustained hostility in her presence, she thought, quietly grateful. "As such, you ought to have some idea of what your commitment will entail. These past three years we have covered a wide assortment of potions, moving much quicker through those of common or important use than I had originally anticipated when first I agreed to tutor you."

She allowed herself a small sigh of pride that she was certain did not escape his amused notice.

"We will continue filling in what few gaps remain as the year progresses, moving on to exceptionally difficult and dangerous potions in your weekly lessons," Snape went on, "However, I anticipate that your grounding in the material aspects of the field will be as thorough as I can reasonably make it within the next few months." At her surprised expression, Snape allowed a wry smirk to cross his mouth. "You underestimate how far you have come, Rigel. I have never taught a student so dedicated to mastering the field."

She felt her cheeks grow warm against her will. She thought there ought to be a word for the feeling that welled up when everything you'd ever wanted was handed over without ceremony.

Snape cleared his throat uncomfortably. "There is more to mastery than an in-depth knowledge of ingredients and recipes, however. That is why, beginning next year, I will be teaching you free brewing." Rigel felt her breath actually catch in her lungs. Was he serious? "It is a dangerous technique, and many Potions Masters go their entire careers without so much as dabbling in it, but you are not most brewers, Mr. Black. I believe you could become quite adept at the art, given enough practice."

Her smile probably looked ridiculous, but she couldn't help it. Free brewing was the ultimate mode of experimentation in the potions community. Successful free brewing had resulted in some of the most revolutionary discoveries of the last few centuries.

"I would like that very much, Sir," she managed to get out after a moment of internal celebration.

"There is a condition," Snape said quietly, in a tone that caused the smile to slide right off her face. "Free brewing is not a technique that everyone is capable of performing safely. It requires a good deal of magic, and exceptional control over that magic, to hold an unstable potion together until it can be neutralized manually. Without that magic and control, the first misstep might cost a brewer his hands—or his eyes."

Rigel grimaced, but it was not at the gruesome image—rather, it was at the direction she could now see this conversation progressing. "You want me to stop using the suppressor." All enthusiasm was gone from her voice, now.

"Not immediately or all at once," Snape said, attempting to be diplomatic. "Eventually, however, yes. You must learn to harness all of your magic, Mr. Black."

She refrained from saying that such a statement was merely his own opinion, and instead said evenly, "Is this a condition of the apprenticeship itself, or only of learning free brewing?"

Snape scowled. "I have accepted you as my apprentice, Mr. Black, regardless of your own stubbornness, but remember that I have just explained the increasingly shallow body of knowledge I have to impart. I could spend the next four years coming up with exponentially more obscure and unlikely recipes and ingredient combinations, but that would not service your potions education in any useful way. Alternatively, we could attempt to fill the remainder of your school years researching various projects, but would it truly be enough to satisfy you? You sought this apprenticeship because you wanted to benefit from my instruction, did you not? Free brewing is something only a small handful of people on this half of the world can teach you. I am offering this knowledge to you, and, if you are very adept and can convince me of the prudence of such a thing, to your cousin Harriett Potter, as well. All you have to do is gain control of your own magic—something which will benefit you in all areas of your studies. Do you truly believe that is an unreasonable condition?"

She felt as though she'd swallowed something that had been advertised as sweet and had instead turned out extremely sour. A rather childish part of her was saying, he can't do that, in the back of her mind, but he could, and he was, she was forced to acknowledge. She couldn't argue with his reasoning, either, really. She had heard many times how dangerous free brewing was, and magic was the ultimate stabilizer, everyone knew that. It made perfect sense that wizards of greater magic would be better able to brew unstable potions without getting blown up. Even so, she couldn't help but think this was just Snape's excuse for making her give up the suppressor he disapproved of without a fight. She had to give him points for Slytherin cleverness, at least.

At her long, silent hesitation, Snape frowned, and asked, uncharacteristically earnest, "Why are you so against this? An honest attempt at controlling your magic does not seem so much to ask, in exchange for what you want more than anything—do not deny it." She wasn't going to. It was everything she'd ever wanted. "You are a Slytherin, Rigel. Why do you even consider jeopardizing your primary ambition simply so that you may remain mediocre?"

She chaffed at the last comment, but recognized that Snape was making an honest, if somewhat snarky, effort to comprehend her reticence. "I'm not sure you can understand," she said slowly. "Most of the Slytherin students have ambitions of power or wealth; they want to be important, to be known and have influence in some way or another. I—my ambition is somewhat antithetic to that. I don't want to be important. I want to do important work, but I don't want to be noticed myself."

Snape looked unconvinced. "You cannot tell me you don't crave recognition—I have seen it. There is no shame in such a desire, Rigel. You should be proud of your talents."

Rigel felt her forehead crease with frustration, not sure there was anyway to explain what she wanted in a way he would understand. "I just want to learn potions. When I came here, yes, I wanted your recognition, because it validated my reasons for pursuing this field. When you told me I was good at potions—I don't think you can understand what it meant to me. No one ever told me I should study potions. It was a hobby my family humored, and financially supported, which I'm very grateful for, but it wasn't—I needed someone who knew potions to tell me I had a real chance at making it in the field. You made me believe that even though I'm a—" she broke off before her mouth could run completely away with her. She had almost said halfblood girl. "Even though I'm young, that I have the potential to do something great with my abilities. I do think that now. And it's enough. I don't care if other people know how talented I am. If I make Mastery, I won't care if anyone ever hears the name Rigel Black again. I just want the knowledge, and to further the field, and invent potions that change people's lives, and—" She swallowed hard. "I just want to be left alone to brew, Sir."

Snape had the oddest, most unfathomable expression she'd ever seen as he looked at her. After a lengthy pause, however, he merely said, "What does this have to do with your magic? Learning control will only help your potion brewing. You can still be an anonymous academic if you wish."

"I can't though, don't you see?" Rigel frowned deeply, wondering if he was being deliberately obtuse. "I'd be happy living my life mostly unnoticed, apart from my work, but having powerful magic is not something people in our society just ignore. Those with unusual gifts are picked out of the crowd, elevated to a position of high expectations. People start calling them 'Lord' and push them into throwing their magic around, if not literally, then socially and politically. Everyone wants to be acquainted with them, except no one actually wants to be their friend. I don't want that life. I just want to be left alone."

"You do not know that such a fate is inevitable," Snape argued, "There are plenty of powerful wizards who live in relative peace."

"No, there aren't," Rigel said flatly. "Don't say Dumbledore and Riddle, either, because neither of them are left in peace. People watch them constantly. They have to make friends with other powerful people because if they don't make friends they'll make enemies simply by being perceived as too aloof or secretive. People are too curious to leave power alone. They already look at me differently because I speak Parseltongue and because of the weird thing my magic can do with other people's cores. If it got out that I had magic so powerful I could barely control it, everyone would want to know what I was going to do with it. No one with power manages to stay unnoticed for very long, unless they hide it, which is what I am trying to do."

"You are ignoring it, not hiding it," Snape scowled.

"But it's for the better, can't you see that?" Rigel leaned forward to brace her hands on the desk in front of her. "Most of the people with high levels of magic in history end up becoming Dark Lords or getting killed by someone jealous of their power or creating dangerous magical artifacts that ravage the earth or—or—something else incredibly egomaniacal and stupid. No one should have that kind of power. It's dangerous to the whole world. If I develop my magic, that's one step closer to using it—if I even can use it without hurting people. More than likely I'll lose control and something terrible will happen."

"Who do you insist that you are a danger?" Snape said, visibly frustrated. "Have you ever actually hurt anyone with your magic?"

Rigel shook her head slowly. "No…but I have this gut feeling I can't shake. It's telling me my magic is dangerous."

"A feeling is not sufficient reason for ignoring your potential," Snape snapped. "What's dangerous is not learning to control your magic. If pent up long enough it will hurt someone."

"Not if it's suppressed all the time," Rigel said stubbornly, "It's only if I take off the suppressor that it will have the chance to lash out. My aunt keeps hers suppressed all the time, and—"

"Do not bring Lily into this," Snape snarled, bringing a hand down on the top of his desk angrily. With a deep breath, he reined his temper, and added, "This is about you. No one else."

"I don't want to take a chance with other people's safety."

Snape rubbed his temple in irritation, "And I need you to acknowledge that I have more knowledge on the subject of magical abilities than what panicked conjectures you've come up with on your own. You are not the first student with unruly magic I have taught, nor will you be the last. There are ways to control it, ways that do not involve putting a lid on it. Just because you cannot feel your magic at the moment doesn't mean the fire isn't there. If you leave things as they are too long, it will boil over. You must learn to tame your magic, not simply cage it."

"Some animals can't be tamed," Rigel muttered. "My magic is not a lion. It's a lethifold."

"You are being dramatic," Snape told her, sneering. "And what's more, you know that I am correct in insisting on this. It is not for negotiation. Promise me that you will work on it."

Rigel mulled the demand over silently, trying to come up with another argument she could give him. What rankled was that she had other arguments, but they all pertained to keeping she and Archie's ruse running as smoothly as possible. If she began developing her magic, surely people would notice, and people noticing Rigel meant higher expectations for Archie. He didn't have as much magic as she did—it would be impossible for him to pretend he did, unless he kept his aura shielded his entire life and ducked all attempts at making him use his power somehow. It was just too dangerous for them if Rigel Black had uncommonly powerful magic. She couldn't tell Snape that to flaunt her magic was to risk a stint in Azkaban, however, and without that argument he would see no reason why attempting to harness her full power could cause problems.

The most she could do, she realized, was stall for time. "I will work on it," she said, begrudgingly and with no small amount of bitterness. That was vague enough to put him off for a while, surely. Perhaps in the meantime she could find out exactly how much magic a free brewer needed, anyway. There's no way it was as much as she had. Then she'd just have to adjust the suppressor until she had enough to be successful without letting all of it out to overwhelm her and cause trouble.

"If I think that you are not making sufficient progress, I will take things into my own hands, Mr. Black," Snape said, sinister warning in every syllable. "If you break your word I will have no compunction doing whatever is necessary to facilitate this."

Rigel pressed her lips together in slight resentment, but nodded once, capitulating, if a bit gracelessly. It felt like she'd been backed into a corner, and told that it was for her own good, to boot.

As she left the office, she willed herself to relax. She was Snape's apprentice. She should be happy, not angry. She was going to learn things many potions brewers would give their golden cauldrons to be privy to. And really, what could Snape do if she didn't put all her energy into controlling her magic? He could forcibly remove her suppressor, perhaps, but he couldn't make her use her magic. She would just outwait him, and show him that she was talented enough to learn free brewing without lord-level magic.

That evening she slipped up to the Owlrey, a note printed by dicto-quill on nondescript parchment clutched between gloved fingers. She reassured herself that there was no way to trace who the letter had come from, even if the best people at the Ministry tried tracking it. They would only see that it came from Hogwarts, and they already suspected the jewel had something to do with someone at the castle, so there was no reason for anyone to think of her, specifically, when they read it. Even so, she could not help feeling very vulnerable as she read through the words one last time.

To: Aurors in pursuit of goblin artifact,

Man with large jewel of suspicious origin was seen in the Metallurgist Guild on Craftsman Alley, July. Questioning the material specialists there may yield the answers you seek.

-A concerned citizen

She picked the most common-looking owl she could find and whispered the destination "Ministry of Magic, Department of Magical Law Enforcement" in its ear. It winged away silently into the night, and she sighed with more than a little relief. She had done something to help the Aurors without implicating herself in the slightest. Feeling pleased with herself, she stole back down the tower steps and made her way toward the Come and Go Room. By now, her earlier self should be done using it, and she wanted to get a short workout in before crashing there for the night.

It was a few weeks into the new semester that Rigel finally made the acquaintance of the other Alchemy student Dumbledore had told her about.

She was somewhat surreptitiously slinking through the Library late that evening, skirting slightly close to curfew but not quite breaking the rules yet. She technically shouldn't be out without her invisibility cloak on, as she was currently also in Gryffindor Tower finishing up a study session with Percy, but she wanted to check out a couple of books, and that meant being visible to Madam Pince going both in and out of the Library.

There was no one there to see her anyway, so near to closing time. Madam Pince locked up a half hour before curfew set in every night, and it was too early in the term for there to be frantic OWL and NEWT students begging for five more minutes.

She was quite surprised, then, to round the corner of the dusty, seldom-used isle on Alchemy texts and see someone else standing there, nose deep in a thick, faded tome. He looked up at her approach and frowned in a way that reminded her of Percy Weasley.

"This section is restricted," he said, eyeing her tie in an obvious way. "You have to have a pass."

"I have one," she said, judging the boy to be around sixteen or seventeen, despite his rather petite size.

"From who?" he asked, looking incredulous.

"Professor Dumbledore," she said, frowning back at him. Did he not believe her? She didn't know why he cared, but maybe he was a prefect she didn't recognize.

The boy snapped his book closed emphatically and scoffed. "The Headmaster gave you a pass to the Alchemy section? You don't look old enough to even be an OWL student."

"I'm in third year," she said, trying to be polite. "I'm very interested in learning Alchemy, though, and Dumbledore was kind enough to give me a pass and a few recommendations when I asked."

"You can't learn Alchemy from a book," he said, a patronizing expression on his face.

"What are you doing here, then?" she asked, a bit annoyed at his condescension.

"I am looking up conversion tables for the magic coefficients of rare materials," he sniffed, "Not that you know what that means."

Realizing at last that he must be the sixth year student Dumbledore had told her about, she took a deep breath and reminded herself not to be antagonistic toward someone who could help her out, if she convinced him of her good intentions.

"You must be Mr. Albright, then," she said, smiling in a friendly way that seemed to catch him off guard. "Dumbledore said you were in his Alchemy class."

"Really." Albright's eyes narrowed, but he dutifully held a hand out nonetheless. "Yes, I am the Heir of the House of Albright. And you are?"

"Rigel Black," she said, shaking his hand for only a moment before he snatched it back with a slight sneer. Ignoring that, she offered, "He said you were working on a project this semester. Can you tell me about it?"

"I think not," he said, wiping his hand on the side of his Ravenclaw robes.

"I understand," Rigel said, forcing a smile, "I suppose you want to keep it a secret until it's finished."

"No, I just don't want to discuss it with a burgeoning Dark wizard. Rowena knows what you'd do with the information," Albright said, looking perfectly serious despite the outlandish nature of his remark.

"I'm not a Dark wizard," she said, eyebrows rising.

"Not yet, maybe," Albright said, unconvinced.

Deciding to try a different tract, she said, "I won't ask about your project, then. How did you become interested in Alchemy? Have you been studying it since third year, or did you start earlier?"

The affronted look on his face was almost humorous. "Don't you know who I am?"

"You're Mr. Albright," Rigel said, containing a sigh, "You haven't told me your first name yet."

"I am Eric Alright, son of Ulrich Albright, Aldermaster of the Alchemist Guild, Premier Executive of Illuminux Inc.," Albright said, no small amount of exasperation in his voice. "You want to study Alchemy and you don't know that my family is Alchemy? Nicolas Flamel is my many-times-great uncle, for Merlin's sake."

"Oh," Rigel said, trying to look impressed, "I didn't know."

"How could you know anything about Alchemy?" Albright said, shaking his head in disgust, "It's a Light art. Ordered. Precise. Balanced. Requiring measured sacrifice. Not something Dark wizards can understand."

"What makes you so sure I'm Dark?" Rigel asked, a bit exasperated. While true that Alchemy was a highly exact field of magic, you certainly didn't have to have Light magic to use it. No more than you had to have Dark magic to use Divination, though that field of magic was highly unpredictable and very forceful in nature.

"You're a Black," Albright shrugged, as though the answer were obvious, "Your Darkness is bred into you by centuries of selective magical copulation, just as my Light magic was carefully cultivated by my own ancestors over a multitude of generations."

"It…hasn't been proven that magical natures are determined by genetics, actually," Rigel told him. "A lot of people have different natures than their parents or grandparents."

"That's what Dark wizards say to deflect suspicion from their dark deeds," Albright said, sneering. When she opened her mouth to protest, he cut her off, "I don't have all night to spend arguing with you, Black. Just try not to leave fingerprints all over the books—or better yet, give up this passing fancy with Alchemy now. You'll never get anywhere in the field with your family history, anyway."

He stepped around her pointedly, giving as wide a berth as he could in the narrow isle. "Thanks for the advice," she said, the sarcasm helping to soothe her annoyance somewhat. She got the books as quickly as she was able, and just barely managed to get them to the front desk before Pince could order her out.

She hurried to get back to the common room before curfew set in. She had down in her notebook that she had turned back a few minutes after her earlier self had left the Gryffindor common room, so she should be all right to reenter the common room as she was.

Draco came across her in the dungeons, and joined her on the way to the common room entrance. His hair was wet from showering after Quidditch practice, which had been running later and later as Flint's 'win or else' philosophy began to gather momentum as the Quidditch Cup approached.

"You looked exhausted," Rigel said, eyeing the way he winced every other step. Too much time on a broom could severely cramp the leg muscles.

"It'll be worth it, if we win," Draco said, smiling tiredly. "Where've you been?"

"Gryffindor common room," she said, anticipating his annoyed huff with a grin.

"What do you see in those blood traitors, Rigel?"

"Oh, the usual," she said lightly, "Friendship, companionable silences, long walks by the Forbidden Forest—"

"Stop, before I hurl what little dinner is still left in my stomach all over your ugly boots," Draco groaned.

"They aren't ugly," Rigel sighed, "They're—"

"Practical," Draco mimicked. "So you've said."

They walked the cold corridors in silence for a little while, Draco pretending not to shiver and Rigel pretending not to notice. Rigel's mind kept going back to Albright, and how peculiar his opinions had been, and she wondered if his family was indeed as notable as he seemed to believe, or if he was simply full of himself.

"Draco," she said, "Have you heard of a family called Albright? I think they're—"

"Albright?" Draco's head snapped around so quickly that several drops of water flew off his hair and onto her face. She wiped them away with amusement as her friend demanded, "What about them?"

"You know of them, then?" Rigel said, a bit surprised, "I've never heard them mentioned in society before."

"Not Dark Society," Draco rolled his eyes at her, "They're Light supremacists, Rigel. The whole family is a bunch of high-strung narcissists who spend all their political capital opposing everything my family does regardless of principle or reason."

"I thought they were mainly Alchemists," Rigel said, taken aback by Draco's passionate dislike.

"That's their income source," Draco said, waving a hand dismissively, "They've had a stranglehold on the Alchemist Guild for centuries, and use it to channel money back and forth between the research labs there and the Albrights' private corporation, which is basically an elaborate front for them funneling Guild money into their various political campaigns."

"That…sounds involved," Rigel said, "How do you know so much about it?"

"Ulrich Albright hates my father, and I assure you the feeling is entirely mutual," Draco said, his face pinched and angry. "Albright is always getting in the way of the SOW Party's agendas. Father thinks Illuminux is being used to manipulate the market on magical materials, too. They're always buying up huge stockpiles of ores or crops, claiming they need it for their 'Alchemical research,' but really they're just monopolizing the commodities so they can allocate them strategically and force the prices up. You remember that shortage of fairy eggs two years ago?"

Rigel blinked. "Of course. The price tripled for almost six months. I had to start substituting doxy eggs instead for some of my potions."

"Everyone did," Draco said, crossing his arms indignantly, "And guess who just happened to buy up an enormous pile of doxy eggs right before the fairy egg shortage? Illuminux. They planned the whole thing. Or at least took advantage of insider knowledge somehow. Just like they did with the ginseng crop during the Sleeping Sickness."

Rigel's lips parted in surprise. "That was them? How did they know? And why weren't they selling any of it, if they wanted to make money?"

"To spite my father, of course. I almost died, Rigel," Draco reminded her.

"There's no way they could have known you were allergic to the substitution," Rigel said, frowning. "You father didn't even tell the school nurse what your allergies were."

"They probably got access to my records at St. Mungo's," Draco said.

"Those are heavily warded, I'm pretty sure," Rigel pointed out.

"Well I don't know how they do it, exactly, but it's a pretty sinister coincidence, don't you think?" Draco scowled.

"I suppose, but surely they wouldn't take a political rivalry so far as to try and indirectly kill you," Rigel reasoned.

"They certainly would." Draco looked at her in an incredulous manner. "The Albrights are the sworn enemies of the Malfoys."

He said it with such deadly seriousness, even as his hair dripped a puddle onto the flagstones, that Rigel couldn't help but poke fun. "I thought that was the Weasleys."

Draco scoffed. "The Weasleys are an embarrassment. And blood traitors anyway. The Albrights are evil."

"They probably think the Malfoys are evil, too. Maybe you're both just misunderstood," Rigel suggested, starting to walk back toward the common room again.

Draco spluttered as he scrambled to catch up. "We are not misunderstood. The Malfoys are evil."

She shot him a sideways look that said clearly, are you sure you want to go with that?

"I mean, we have tended in the past to be a bit unscrupulous. And drawn to Dark Lords." He paused for a moment in thought. "I mean, in the past some members of my family have done what might be considered regrettable things in the pursuit of power. But it's family tradition."

Rigel snorted, "That is a rotten tradition."

Draco's face was positively indignant. "It is not. Tradition is what holds our way of life together. It's what—"

"I've heard the Party speeches," Rigel cut in, summoning a grin to show she wasn't actually annoyed. "You have to admit that not all traditions are good, though."

"Like what?" Draco said, lifting his chin defiantly.

"Like…" she cast her mind around for something that wouldn't offend her friend. "The Blacks have a tradition of beheading our house elves and mounting their heads on the hallway walls."

"What?" Draco spluttered, "My mother never told me that."

"Well, it's true," Rigel said, smirking, "At least for the main household. It's stupid though, because they smell even under the preservation charms and they clash with every décor style that isn't utterly macabre. That is an example of the power of tradition, though. Some Black ancestor decided to behead his house elf and keep it around, so every Lord and Lady Black after that did the same thing without thinking how distasteful and pointless and gruesome it actually was."

Draco was silent for a moment, looking slightly grossed out. "I'm sure it had…great significance at one point," he settled for saying, not even managing to keep the dubious look off his face.

And Rigel was sure it was just another example of blind adherence to inherited patterns of behavior and thought, but she was much too fond of her friendship with Draco to ever say something to bluntly dismissive out loud. There were some opinions he was simply ill equipped to hear.

The first Quidditch match of the new term was on the last Saturday in January, between Slytherin and Ravenclaw. Spirits were particularly high on the Ravenclaw side, as the ravens were currently leading in points for the House Cup, and a victory on the Quidditch pitch would put them almost irrevocably ahead. Usually when Slytherin played a match, the two houses not participating would choose to root for whoever the other team was, but in this case the lions and badgers didn't want Ravenclaw to pull so far ahead in the House Cup either, so the support for the two teams was rather mixed.

Rigel was in the staff box, having been invited along with Pansy to once again spend the match with the Malfoys. She was beginning to think they simply enjoyed having people to talk down to wherever they went. Or else they were hoping for a progress report on their son.

"How is the new term coming along?" Narcissa asked after greeting them with her patented poised smile.

"Very well," Pansy said. "Draco is doing particularly well in Transfigurations and his Dueling Club is a complete success. We've had nearly a dozen new members since he opened it to the school."

Rigel hid a smile at her friend's prompt report. Apparently she was not the only one who suspected the true reason for the Malfoys' ongoing invitation.

"How wonderful," Narcissa said, smiling proudly. "It is so nice to see Draco taking up the mantle of leadership at such a young age."

"He has a natural charisma," Rigel chimed in. "Even the older students from other Houses listen respectfully when he runs drills." She didn't add that some of them probably only listened to him because his father was a school governor. There were plenty of people in the club who did genuinely respect Draco's way of doing things.

"He is only a third year," Mr. Malfoy pointed out with an air of polite disbelief. "Your interpretations are perhaps influenced by your friendship with our son."

"Results speak for themselves," Pansy said serenely. "He's already had several requests for individual training sessions. Not that he'd agree to allow his time to be monopolized like that, of course."

"The individual training sessions are for us, after all," Rigel added.

The adults laughed politely, looking satisfied that their son was at least doing well enough that his friends had nothing unhappy to say.

"And how are your studies progressing, Miss Parkinson?" Mr. Malfoy asked after glancing down at the pitch for a moment to check the progress of the warm-ups. "Which classes are you taking this year?"

"My extracurriculars are Divination, Arithmancy, and Care of Magical Creatures," Pansy recited, looking as though she'd told him so before at some point and wondered why he was asking again.

"Ah yes, I recall now," Mr. Malfoy said, smiling in a way that Rigel didn't believe for a second was casual. "And you, Mr. Black? What electives did you select again?"

Rigel fought to keep her eyes from narrowing, sure that she had heard more than casual interest in his tone. "Arithmancy, Runes, and Magical Theory," she said.

"Not Healing?" Malfoy frowned in a politely curious way that didn't fit his face at all. "But you are so skilled in the art, Mr. Black."

Rigel affected a look of earnest gratitude. "Madam Pomfrey is kind enough to tutor me unofficially whenever we both have free time. My cousin Harriett lends me her Healing textbooks over the holidays, too, and has been a great help in furthering my understanding of the subject."

"Why not simply take the class, if you have such an interest in it?" Narcissa asked, looking genuinely perplexed.

Rigel shrugged a tiny bit. "I had to choose the three subjects I thought would be most difficult to learn on my own. I can learn Healing through my cousin and Madam Pomfrey's generosity, so there was no reason to take up a slot on my schedule that could be filled by a subject I have no other way to study."

"Is it wise to attempt to focus on so many different subjects at once, instead of choosing to master a few that interest you greatly?" Mr. Malfoy asked, one eyebrow raised.

"They all interest me greatly," she said, as guilelessly as possible.

"It is so rare to meet such a devoted academic these days," Narcissa cut in, smiling in a way Rigel knew was meant to soften her husband's rather pointed inquiries. "Perhaps some of it will rub off on our Heir."

"Draco doesn't take direction from his peers," Pansy said, drawing the attention away from Rigel once more. "It's quite the other way around."

The game began soon after, and Rigel's attention was distracted from wondering why Mr. Malfoy was suddenly so interested in her schoolwork. Perhaps he was simply curious as to how a Hogwarts student learned so much about a subject that was not emphasized in the curriculum. It had seemed like more than that, but Rigel admitted to herself that she was probably being paranoid. She had been feeling increasingly as though she were missing something important, lately, and it was apparently starting to give her suspicious tendencies.

Snape had appeared sometime just before the tip off, and now stood at the elder Malfoy's elbow as the game commenced.

"The team looks in fine form," Malfoy remarked a few minutes into the match. "The Chasers are remarkably efficient."

"As I understand it, Captain Flint has been particularly driven this last month," Snape drawled.

"I think the words you're looking for are 'increasingly manic,' Professor," Pansy offered, shaking her hair back until it hung against her upper back instead of her face.

"Well, he may actually graduate at this rate," Snape smirked. "Presumably he sees this year as his last campaign, so to speak."

It certainly did look like the chaos of war as players on both sides attempted to claim an early lead by any means necessary. Rigel had to wince as both Slytherin beaters attempted to shoot bludgers at the Ravenclaw keeper simultaneously. It was obvious that the keeper was used to intercepting balls rather than dodging them, as his first instinct to fly toward the incoming bludger was only checked at the last moment in a desperate and panicky roll to the side.

She could see Draco circling high, his sharp features flushed with adrenaline and the cold slap of the wind. After a few minutes she realized she was missing all the action, just keeping her eyes on her friend, and attempted to catch back up with the rest of the game. Before she could so much as determine who had the quaffle, however, a stabbing pain eclipsed her lower abdomen and sent her gasping to her knees.

"Rigel?"

She heard Pansy's concerned cry vaguely over the noise of the stadium, but it was hard to concentrate over the nauseating sensations of snakes crawling through her belly. She felt like she'd just swallowed a galleon of Polyjuice Potion, only several times worse.

"Mr. Black," it was Snape's voice now, and his hand on her head. She blinked up at him, but he was going in and out of focus like a poorly timed picture. Her brain put two and two together just as Snape's eyes began to narrow, and she ripped herself away, turning toward the stairs with an exaggerated groan.

"I'm going to be sick," she gasped out, and that was enough to make the few adults between her and the steps step back automatically.

She dashed between them and ran with all of the speed she could muster down stair after stair until she reached a landing with no one on it. Pulling the cloak she had been grasping for in her bag over her head she fumbled with her time turner and gave it a random spin, too panicked to care how many revolutions it took as it whisked her away from the present moment and back to the only safety afforded to her just then.

She saw Snape rounding the landing just above her as she faded, invisible, from the scene, and made a note to reappear somewhere believable when she sorted things out.

When she opened her eyes from where she'd closed them against the dizzying sensation of time travel, it was to a silent stairwell, probably hours or possibly a full day before the match was set to occur. Rigel kept the cloak firmly over herself as she hurried down the rest of the stairs and away from the pitch. She still felt violently ill, but she could also now feel the beginnings of a transformation that, if she had been thinking at all, she should have been able to predict.

She headed for her lab, despite having no idea what time it was and therefore no clue whether there was another version of herself in there at present. She didn't remember the door randomly bursting open at any point in the last week while she was working in there, so logically, if the time stream was consistent, she hadn't interrupted herself—or wouldn't. Whichever.

After cloistering herself in her lab and locking the door with as powerful a spell as she could think up, she pulled her cloak off and breathed deep in both relief and in an effort to calm herself down enough to think clearly. When her body came back into view, it was obvious what had happened. The Modified Polyjuice she had taken that summer had worn off completely. Scowling at the inconvenience, she nevertheless had to admit that it was entirely her own fault. She knew the modified potion would only have an effective life of about a year. What did she think was going to happen when she crammed so much extra time into her days and weeks?

Still, she paused, had she really lived a year in roughly four and a half months? That was a little much. She briefly considered cutting back on the time turner for a while, then realized that if she was going to get out of this mess, the time turner was her only chance.

She needed to brew a new Modified Polyjuice using hairs from the same samples that she'd used the last time she took it. Otherwise, her appearance would change. Luckily, or rather due to her incredibly obsessive tendencies when it came to potions ingredients, that much would be no problem. She took out her potions kit from her bag, and opened the expanded drawer that contained all the human samples she collected. She had plenty of her own hair, having been collecting it at regular intervals for years. Finding one from the end of summer was a cinch. She needed Archie's too, though.

Skipping over those vials labels with names of other people she knew, and grimly hoping her friends never found out about her strange but oddly comforting habit of keeping bits of their hair in her potions bag, she found the row of vials with Archie's name on them and skimmed the labels. She had more recent samples from the winter break (mostly because she was curious what would happened if you Polyjuiced with hair of a metamorph who was transformed when the sample was taken), but she needed the one dated August… there!

She only had three hairs left from that sample, but one was all she needed. This is why Theo is right and paranoia pays, she thought idly as she set the vial aside.

Now the real problem: completing a new Modified Polyjuice Potion, which took an entire month to brew properly, in the next… she cast a quick tempus charm and grimaced. Six hours. Before she could despair, she sat down on a stool and pulled out a piece of parchment and a quill, muttering determinedly.

"Okay. I can do this. What do I have? Most of the ingredients…" she made a quick inventory, grimacing as she realized she'd have to somehow get ahold of an amber stone. One preferably a bit bigger than the pea-sized ones she'd been using. She didn't want to be doing this all over again if she happened to somehow squeeze another year into her remaining four months.

Amber wasn't stocked in their student storeroom, she knew, and while it was possible that Snape may have some in his private store, it was not possible that Snape would not ask her what exactly she needed it for. She could owl order it, but she didn't know how long that would take, and it was the very first ingredient she needed to put in the cauldron.

There was also the problem of logistics, she realized. Her time turner could only go back a week at a time, and Polyjuice needed to brew continuously for a full moon cycle. She would have to fold four weeks into one while somehow not running into herself or anyone else along the way.

"Oh, no," she groaned out loud, realizing that reliving the same week four times would be impossible. "I've already done Tuesday three times." That would put her at seven selves in one time, which was very, very dangerous according to everything the Ministry and Snape had told her. "Okay." she talked herself through it. "All right. I'll redo this week three times, then go back to Wednesday on the fourth go-round and live through Monday, then go back again to Saturday morning once the potion is finished. Yes. But where….?"

At various points in the last week she had already been present in the Room of Requirement and her lab, ruling both of them out as places she could leave the Polyjuice because she didn't remember there being unexplained Polyjuice in either place when she was last there. She would need somewhere to sleep, too, or rather four different places to sleep throughout the week that somehow didn't include her dorm or the Come and Go Room, since she had already slept in both places almost every night over the last week.

"What a mess," she sighed. She could try camping out in the forest, but the odds of her not being eaten eventually by Acromantula while she slept were probably fairly low. With a reluctant grimace, she realized her safest option was going to be leaving Hogwarts altogether. Once out of the school, she could purchase the amber stone at any apothecary and simply hole up in a series of cheap hotels.

It felt wrong to contemplate leaving the school in the middle of the semester, but, she reasoned with herself, it wasn't as though she wouldn't also be at school that week. It would only seem to her as though she'd taken a month off of classes. No one else would even know.

It was probably going to involve breaking a dozen rules, but hadn't she already? "Better than being sent to Azkaban for using a Ministry controlled potion to impersonate a pureblood," she muttered halfheartedly. That was the likely consequence if she couldn't get her appearance back under control before Snape tracked her down after the Quidditch match. She had seen in his eyes the beginnings of suspicion—and why not, when he likely knew exactly what the symptoms of Polyjuice wearing off were? There was no way she could buy the standard potion on the black market and use that until she had enough legitimate time to brew her own, long lasting version—Snape would likely be watching her more carefully than ever as soon as she rejoined the time stream. She wouldn't put it past him to arrange for her to be in his presence over an hour continuously that very day just to be sure she wasn't taking the potion.

How much easier things would be if she and Archie had been twins instead of cousins. She loved her mother dearly, but it was difficult sometimes not to imagine how simple life might have been if she could have just gone to Hogwarts a normal girl.

Curious, almost against her will, she took out her wand and conjured a basic mirror. The person who looked out of it at her was like a vision from another life. Dressed in Slytherin robes, she smiled tentatively, almost unable to believe her eyes. She certainly didn't look like Archie anymore.

With a tilt of her head, she took in her reflection raptly, realizing that this was the first time in over a year and a half that she had seen her true face. Longer than that, she amended, if you counted the months of folded time, too. Her hair was the same, short and black, but nearly everything else was…off. She squinted and realized belatedly that her eyesight was even worse than she remembered it being. Perhaps she'd just gotten used to perfect sight. With a sigh, she realized she didn't have a pair of glasses here at Hogwarts—why would she? She resigned herself to a long month of nearsightedness.

Stepping closer to bring her features into sharper focus, she noted to her surprise that she looked a bit like Lily, in her face shape, at least. It was rounder than the pointed purebred look she'd been sporting for so long. Her cheeks were softer and her lower lip slightly fuller. Her eyes were uncanny, after seeing them in grey and dull green contacts for so long. They almost glowed, but that might be the intensity with which she was inspecting herself. She didn't know if the girl in the mirror could be called pretty—she just looked odd to her.

She'd never considered vanity one of her defining traits, but she couldn't deny a certain amount of fascination as she experimentally turned from side to side. She was definitely maturing, she noticed with mixed feelings. Her waist was sloping in and her chest slightly out. She'd also lost at least an inch in height, she thought with annoyance. It figured that Archie would be taller than her. At least she still had her musculature. Relative health was one of the things about the body that even Polyjuice would still reflect.

After one last look, she banished the mirror, satisfied that at least no one would recognize her as Rigel Black while she was away from school. She would have to lose the school robes, though. "This is going to be more elaborate than I thought," she complained to herself, mentally drawing up a list of things she would have to do. First was collecting a couple changes of clothes and her savings from her dorm room. As it was very early Saturday morning, she would have to wait until her previous self woke up and left for the Quidditch match. That gave her a few hours to prepare the rest of it.

She began gathering cauldron, scales, stirring rods, knives, and anything else she might need to complete the Polyjuice. She used the cauldron as a carrying container, as her book bag was not quite extendable enough to shove an entire pewter size two inside comfortably. She made a list of what books she wanted to grab from her dorm to read while she was waiting for the potion to brew, then tried to decide if there was a way she could get food from the kitchens without any of the elves asking who she was and why she looked sort of like Rigel. Binny, at least, would probably notice something off. Food would wait, then.

Where should she go first? "Not Hogsmeade," she said aloud. She was obviously school age, even if she didn't look like Rigel Black. It would be too easy for someone to alert the school. They'd probably even think they were doing what was best for a young girl wandering about on her own. A moment later she realized that her youth, at least, she could fix.

An Aging Potion only took a couple of hours to whip up, after all. She would have to renew the dose every few hours, but with no one watching her every move, that was easy enough. She rolled up her sleeves and got started, determined that her plan was going to work. It had to work.

Slipping out of the castle with her supplies had been almost unnervingly simple. The Marauder's Map led her straight into Hogsmeade through the one-eyed witch's hump, and from there it was an easy matter to Floo to Diagon Alley. Fifteen minutes later she had a key to room number six at the Leaky Cauldron and rent secured through the week.

The first thing she did was purchase a hideously garish scarf to wrap around her head. The material was so eye-catching that she doubted anyone who glanced her way on Diagon would be able to remember anything else about her. Thus garbed, she strolled in her newly lengthened dress robes right into Tate's shop and purchased the largest amber stone he had. Tate didn't blink an eye at her, to her amused relief. She was back in her room at the Leaky with her prize and enough food for a few days long before the Aging Potion wore off.

It was a quiet week. The barkeep, Tom, seemed incredibly disinclined to pester his guests, and if anyone noticed the admittedly noxious smell coming from her room, they didn't care enough to say anything.

When Saturday came back around, she found herself a bit at a loss. Where would she stay next? She snagged a copy of the Daily Prophet and flipped through it to see if anyone was running advertisements for a room for let. The only mention was for an apartment complex off of Craftsman Alley, which seemed geared toward attracting the international clientele that came to visit the English Guilds for business reasons.

"I can work with that." She smirked slightly, crossing to the large satchel she had been using as a makeshift suitcase for the last week and pulling out the blonde wig that she had never gotten around to getting rid of, even after Snape ensured she had full use of the Library. "I knew this would come in handy."

A few minutes later, or a week earlier, depending on how one thought about it, Eloise Barnes from Paris, France stepped out of the Leaky with her things in tow. Her Polyjuice Potion was tucked away beneath her invisibility coat, kept simmering with an overpowered Warming Charm that she hoped would do until she could get it over a fire once more.

The address given in the paper led her further down Craftsman Alley than she'd been before. She passed several different Guild Houses on her way, one of which she took special note of, as it had "Alchemists of England" in big letters across the gate, which appeared to be made of gold. She wondered if that was a reference to the fabled Philosopher's Stone, which supposedly turned lesser metals it touched into gold, or just an incredibly obvious show of the Guild's wealth. Either way, she wondered how she hadn't noticed it before.

Turning down a side street, she found the complex of small apartments without trouble. The woman at the front desk looked up with a friendly smile as she walked in, though her nose twitched unmistakably as she drew closer, no doubt able to smell the Polyjuice from across the room, even if she didn't know what she was smelling.

"I'd like to rent a room for ze week," she said, putting on her best heavy French accent. "I'll need it until Saturday."

"Would you like one with a window?" the woman asked, very subtly turning her nose into her own collar in the guise of looking down at some papers.

"Oui, ah, yes," she said, smiling tiredly. "Merci."

"No trouble," the woman said, "Just the one bed all right?"

She nodded, trying not to look like she was in a hurry. She could feel the cauldron at her side cooling off slightly, and attempted not to glance down at it in worry, knowing she must already look pretty odd with her arm propped out from her side for seemingly no reason.

"Would you like to pay now, or when you leave?" the lady asked, her expression turning serious for a moment. "I must tell you that if you wish to postpone payment we'll need to fill out a few forms, and I'll have to register your wand, as well. Just in case." She smiled brightly, as though by sheer friendliness she could erase the insinuation that she might try and shirk payment.

"I'll pay now," she told her, pulling out a small sack of galleons with her free hand and handing it over.

"Oh, you've already exchanged for galleons, good," the woman said brightly.

Right. Obviously a French traveler would have French Wizarding money. Ah, well. It probably wasn't unusual enough to merit comment.

"You'll be in room twelve, my dear, just up the stairs and to the left, all the way at the end," the lady said. "All right?"

"C'est bien," she murmured, taking the key with a grateful smile and hurrying away up the stairs.

After putting down a flame retardant mat and setting up her cauldron over a fire once more, she sighed and began unpacking the meager necessities she'd accumulated over the past week. The room was very comfortable looking, if a little outdated. Overly floral wallpaper was the least of her problems, she supposed. She checked on the potion once more before taking out her Ancient Runes book and flipping through to where she'd left off. At least one good thing would come from this spectacular misadventure—she'd be way ahead on her schoolwork.

Near the end of the second week, she began looking once more for a place to stay. There were some high-end hotels off an alley near the Gringotts end of Diagon, but in addition to being hideously expensive, they had somewhat stringent standards for their guests. She would not be able to avoid registering at least her wand, if not her name and Gringotts vault number, if she attempted to stay in one of those rooms for a week.

In her guise as Eloise, she stepped into a second-hand robes shop and begged the owner for a quick moment of her time.

"What is it, dearie?" the old woman asked, peering at her distraught face with wizened eyes.

"I 'ave come to England to look for my brother, madam," she said, her French accent actually pretty good after a week of practice. "I 'ave checked all ze 'otels I could find, but none of zem 'ave seen him. I thought, perhaps someone who lives 'ere would know of somewhere else I could look."

"Oh, dear," the old woman said, a frown scrunching up her wrinkly forehead. "Well, are you sure he's come here? He could be in any number of Wizarding settlements in England, you know."

She nodded tearfully, her long hair falling into her face. "Oui. I know 'e is in ze alleys. 'is note was very clear." She wrung her hands in distress. "I do not know what 'e was thinking. Zer is no way for him to afford living on 'is own."

"Well, if he hasn't much coin you won't find him at the big hotels," the old woman said, taking her hands between her own kindly. "Have you checked the Leaky Cauldron?"

She sniffed. "Oui. And ze apartments for rent by ze Guilds."

The woman thought for a moment. "Well," she said slowly, "I suppose if your brother was truly in desperate straits he may have tried the Lamia Lodge…"

"Where is zat?" she asked, not having head of it before.

The old woman hesitated visibly. "It isn't in a very nice part of the alleys, dearie. And it's…well, I suppose it wouldn't hurt for you to ask there, at least." Her face took on an anxious expression. "You will go now, won't you? While it's still light out? It's no place for a lass like you to be wandering after dark."

"Of course," she promised, grinning internally. It sounded like the perfect place to lie low. "Is et near?"

The shop keep wrote down detailed directions, and with a last, slightly concerned look, bowed her from the shop with wishes of luck in finding her brother.

She perused the directions on her way back to her temporary apartment. The Lamia Lodge seemed to be situated off of Knockturn Alley, somewhere on one of the side alleys between Krait's place and Kyprioth Court. The old woman was right to be wary of sending her there. It was certainly not a place a young woman wanted to walk alone at night.

On Saturday morning, she packed up her things once more and said a friendly farewell to the proprietress as she left the building. She stepped into a public loo to lose her blonde wig and, cauldron awkwardly held under one arm, turn back a full week for the third time. After making sure no one else was present (and why would they be, when she'd turned back to the early dawn hours of Monday morning?), she tucked her invisibility cloak away and traded it for a long, nondescript black cloak with a deep hood. Once on, it concealed most of her features and disguised the awkward way she held the cauldron close to her side in its heavy folds.

As the sun rose slowly over the sleepy streets, she made her way down Knockturn Alley. The nocturnal denizens had largely deserted the alleys by now, and it was not yet day enough to tempt even the most accommodating shops to open their doors, so it was to the sound of her own quiet footsteps that she navigated her way through narrow streets. She found herself before an imposing building with narrow windows that had all been boarded or blackened and a door of deepest grey that seemed to have been gouged in several places near the doorknob.

"Charming," she muttered, steeling herself. "At least no one will recognize me here."

The numbers hanging crookedly above the antiquated knocker, a match to the ones the old woman had written down, were the only assurance that this was the correct place. Steeling herself, she grasped the knob and opened the door with a confidence she did not feel.

It swung inwards with an awful squeak that she felt had to be contrived for some sort of effect. There was simply no way those gleaming hinges actually contained that much rust. A narrow, carpeted hallway led to a slightly larger room with a desk pushed somewhat lazily into one corner. Slumped at the desk, facing away from the entrance, was a thin, wane man with long, lank hair and robes that looked like they'd lost a fight with a nest of moths sometime in the distant past.

"Excuse me," she said, raising her voice slightly in case he was as asleep as he looked.

"No need to shout." His voice sounded like a spider had spun cobwebs in his throat. She half expected dust to come spewing from his lips, but barely a particle of air stirred as he rose fluidly from his slumped position and turned to face her. He was quite a bit taller than she was, but she told herself that height was a ridiculous thing to be intimidated by.

"Do you have any vacancies?" she asked, a bit quieter this time.

"Vacancies?" he repeated, sounding distantly amused at something. "Whatever for?"

"I'd like to rent a room," she said, tucking her chin to keep her face in shadow as he bent down as though he might peer at her from across the room. "This is a hotel, is it not?"

His laugh was raspy and took an unnaturally long time to fade out. "This is the Lamia Lodge, child."

"I know," she said, "And I'm not a child, Sir."

He was looming over her before she'd noticed him move. His hand moved faster than her eyes could track, whisking the hood from her head even as she drew breath to protest. His eyes, which she noted belatedly were too black to be normal, took in her face briefly. "You smell younger than you look, under the stench of whatever you are holding," he said, interest trickling into his tone.

"Well you smell older than you look," she snapped, annoyed. "Do you have a room or—what is so funny?"

He was laughing again, slightly louder this time, and as his lips pulled back she caught a flash of fang that made the blood drain from her face. He was a vampire.

"You should see the look on your face," he said, his eyes flashing red in what was probably an attempt to scare her. She told herself firmly that it wasn't going to work, though there was a voice in the back of her head that asked just what she had gotten herself into. "Did you honestly come to a vampire hotel without expecting to see any vampires, child?"

"I didn't know it was a coven-run hotel," she admitted. "I just need a place to stay for a week and heard this place was cheap."

"Oh, it is." he smirked, showing fang again. She wasn't sure if it was meant to be threatening or not. "I'm curious, though; did you imagine it was called the Lamia Lodge because of the food?" He laughed again, apparently highly amused at his own joke.

"I thought it was named after the beetle," she muttered, realizing in retrospect that Lamia was also the name of an ancient Libyan vampire who had a habit of eating her own young.

Vampires were apparently very easily amused, as hollow sounding chuckles filled the space between them once more. She was about to suggest she look for lodging elsewhere when another voice spoke up from across the room where a narrow stairwell descended into the floor.

"What is all this racket, Gavril?" the newcomer asked. She was a vampiress with long red hair braided back from her face, and her voice was low and sleepy. "Some of us are trying to rest."

She hadn't thought they'd done anything loud, but she supposed a vampire's hearing must be as good as she'd read.

"This one wants a room," the first vampire, Gavril, said slyly.

"So give her one." The vampiress shrugged gracefully. "If she isn't a Carpathian, what matter?"

"She's human," Gavril said, looking almost proud of this fact.

"Truly?" the other vampire wrinkled her nose, "She smells like the dead."

"I can just go," she offered, feeling very uncomfortable.

"Nonsense, you must stay," Gavril said quickly. "Why, we happen to have a lovely room overlooking the inner courtyard. Won't you consider it?"

"How much?" she asked, more than a little wary.

"We can discuss that later." Gavril smiled widely.

"I'd rather discuss it now." She frowned, stepping back unconsciously.

"Stop being such a beast," the vampiress swatted her companion with an annoyed glance. "The room is yours for a galleon a week," she added. "I assure you no one here will bother you. This idiot just hasn't fed in a while."

That did not make her feel any better, but on the other hand…one galleon for the whole week was an incredible deal. Even if there were bloodstains on the walls, she'd be a fool to pass it up.

"I'll take it," she said quickly. She would just have to make sure to only leave her room during the daytime. If there were other guests, they'd probably be too busy sleeping to be curious about her comings and goings.

"This way," the female said, brushing past Gavril with a pointed look. "Go downstairs and find something to eat. I'll watch the door while you're away."

She beckoned with one hand and led Harry through a door that was the same color as the walls, making it nearly invisible until they'd drawn near. On the other side was a staircase going up, which took them to a curved hallway lit with antique candelabra. The vampiress stopped before a door that looked much like all the other doors and unlocked it with a large brass key.

"I hope you enjoy your stay," the vampiress said softly, sending involuntary chills up her spine as she crossed the threshold. With a mumbled word of thanks, she closed the door behind her and slumped to the ground. That was the last time she took directions from strangers, even if they did look like someone's sweet old grandmother.

To her surprise and relief, her week at the vampire hotel passed quickly and uneventfully. Even so, she wasn't keen on finding yet another shady place to sleep when Saturday, once again, rolled around. She was picking up food at a market off Kyprioth Court, her hood drawn up around her face as a precaution, when she overheard a witch mentioning the Court of Rogues to her friend.

It made her wonder what Leo was up to, and if he'd kept away from her flat on Dogwood Lane like she'd asked. Hopefully Mrs. Flint had been able to get settled without too much trouble. A moment later she froze, nearly dropping the apple in her hand as a sudden thought struck her. She had a flat. She hadn't considered using it, as Mrs. Flint lived there now, but…maybe she should.

Wasn't the premise of their backup plan that Harry was living on Dogwood Lane while Archie was at AIM in her place? If she popped in while Mrs. Flint was staying there, well, that was a pretty solid alibi, should the worst happen. She had warned Mrs. Flint that it was her cousin Harry's house, and that she might stop by now and again, hadn't she? Surely the woman wouldn't begrudge her kipping on the couch for a week. All she had to do was avoid going outside much, as it would be hard to explain to any of her alley friends why she suddenly looked so very girlish.

Immensely pleased with her plan, she hurried back to the Lamia Lodge and gathered her things once more. The potion was looking exactly as it should, and in seven more days, she would finally be done with the whole ridiculous charade. By the time the last dose of Aging Potion had worn off, it was almost dusk, and she was impatient to get going. She cast one last look around the darkly furnished room to make sure she hadn't forgotten anything and locked the door behind her, cauldron under one arm, wrapped safely in her cloak.

Downstairs, Gavril sat on one corner of the desk, his mate, the vampiress who'd first welcomed her to the hotel, pressed close to his side. She had over the past week met the two of them several times, as they seemed to be the only ones about during daylight hours. At night, however, the sounds of dozens of other voices filled the courtyard outside her balcony.

"Madam, Sir." She bowed her head politely. "Here is your key."

"Leaving so soon, human?" Irina, the female, smiled wryly.

"Thank you for your hospitality," Harry said, smiling tightly. She handed over the agreed upon galleon, and bid them a polite farewell.

"Do recommend us to your friends," Gavril called after her, his voice, while not loud, carrying eerily down the hallway after her.

"You're hilarious," she muttered, knowing he could hear her. "Really, you should consider a career on the wireless." His distinctive laughter chased her out the door.

"Never again," she promised herself, once she was far enough down Kyprioth Court that she felt safe relaxing. She pulled her cloak tighter around herself and picked up her pace a bit. She wanted to get to Dogwood Lane before the sun set completely.

She was halfway there before she stopped, groaned aloud at her own stupidity, and made a beeline for the nearest public toilet. She pulled the invisibility cloak over her head and awkwardly got out her time turner one-handed. With a long-suffering sigh, she turned the hourglass over and over, keeping a mental count until she reaching the number that would take her to Wednesday morning. That done, she strolled back out into burgeoning sunlight and twittering birds. Sometimes she wondered how her circadian rhythm was ever going to recover from owning a time turner.

The street was just as she remembered it, quaint and quiet, and she let herself into the foyer shared by numbers seven and eight with her own spare key. The stairs leading up to her apartment were clean, and a cute little rug that she didn't remember being there before sat by the door. She knocked quietly, and, after a moment, realized she should remove her hood if she didn't want to scare the woman witless.

She heard soft footfalls, and then the door was opened just the tiniest crack, an eye peeking out at her suspiciously. "Who's there?"

"Hello," she said, smiling softly, "My name is Harriett. My cousin Rigel told you about me, I think. Is it all right if I come in, Ma'am?"

There was a long pause, but the door did slowly retreat inwards as Mrs. Flint shuffled back away from it. Harry slipped inside and set her cauldron down out of the way before turning to hold out her hand. "It's a pleasure to finally meet you. I'm sorry to drop by so unexpectedly, but I was wondering if I could impose on your hospitality for a few days?"

Mrs. Flint took her hand slowly, her eyes flicking from her face to her satchel to the cauldron she'd set on the floor, and back. Harry stared back, and noted with approval that the woman seemed much healthier than she'd last seen her. Her form was a little more fleshed out, and her hair and attire spoke of a woman taking good care of herself.

"It's…your apartment," the woman said after a moment. Her voice, while soft, was nowhere near the disused, halting sound it had been.

"It's yours now," Harry told her. "If you aren't comfortable with it, I'll leave at once and find somewhere else, I promise. I just thought I'd see if you wouldn't mind company for a week."

Mrs. Flint looked around the room, as though there would be something to tell her what to do, and Harry waited patiently while she made up her mind. "I don't mind," she said after a long pause. "I'll…" she glanced back toward the bedroom, but Harry cut in.

"I'll sleep on the couch, if that's all right. I won't be in your hair at all, ma'am," she said.

The older woman nodded slowly, then looked questioningly toward the cauldron she'd brought.

"It's nothing dangerous," Harry said, moving to set it up by the window. "If we open the shutters a bit, it probably won't smell up the house much." When it was settled, she turned back to Mrs. Flint. "Thank you so much for letting me stay. I'll get my own food, so you don't have to worry about cooking for me or anything."

"I like to cook," she said suddenly. "I cook for the ladies at the clinic, sometimes. They like my food a lot."

"That's really kind of you," Harry said, "Do you like working there, then?"

"Very much," Mrs. Flint said, nodding earnestly. "It was your doing, wasn't it? Healer Hurst told me you arranged it all. Thank you. I've never—they're so good to me, there."

"I'm glad," Harry said, smiling widely. "Mrs. Hurst is a lovely woman." After a moment she added, sheepishly, "Could you, er, maybe not tell her I'm here, though? I'm supposed to be in school."

"In America," Mrs. Flint said, nodding slowly, "I remember. Why are you… sorry, sorry, never mind. It doesn't matter."

"It's okay," Harry said. She didn't want the woman to think she begrudged her questions. "My friend is covering for me, so they won't miss me at school. I just had a couple of errands to run here. And I had this potion to finish." She gestured to the cauldron, hoping that vague explanation would do.

"Healer Hurst says you brew for Mr. Krait," Mrs. Flint said, almost tentatively. "Is it for him?"

"It's for my other distributor, actually," she said, in case Mrs. Flint ever thought to ask Krait about it. She was surprised the woman had met or heard of Krait already, as his storeroom was fairly far from the inner alleys, but she supposed it was a relatively close-knit community, and those prominently positioned in the Rogue were fairly well-known. "I have to keep an eye on it all week, so I can't really attend class again until it's finished. I should be out of your hair by Tuesday morning, though."

"Stay as long as you need," the woman murmured politely. With a glance at the clock near the fireplace, she said, "I ought to get going."

"Of course," Harry said, retrieving a book from her satchel and attempting to look unassuming. "I'll stay here and study. Can't be too far behind when I show back up at school."

Mrs. Flint's smile was relatively weak, but it still brought an answering smile to Harry's face. Once the older woman left, she relaxed onto the couch and settled in to while yet another day away waiting. She had never missed Transfigurations lectures so much as she had the last few weeks. She loved to read, but apparently she needed to rethink the assumption that she could spend the rest of her life alone with her studies. It was supremely boring, after the first couple of weeks.

By the time Monday evening rolled around, she and Mrs. Flint were, if not friends, at least very comfortable around one another. The Polyjuice Potion had finished maturing without mishap, and the only awkward moment had been when Mrs. Flint flooed home to see Harry in the middle of drawing runes on the living room floor. When Harry explained that the ritual was harmless (without explaining exactly what she was blending two random hair samples for), Mrs. Flint had seemed inclined to leave her to it, though Harry did see the older woman peeking curiously out from the kitchen several times after it had begun.

Mrs. Flint had even fed her dinner afterwards, when her core, or at least what part of it she had access to, was nearly completely depleted. After a quick nap to restore her energy to basic human levels of functioning, Harry packed her supplies away for the final time, bottling the dose of Modified Polyjuice she would take and carefully disposing of the rest. It would be useless if not taken in the first week, so saving it for later was impossible.

She bid Mrs. Flint a fond farewell and Flooed to the Leaky Cauldron before Flooing on to Hogsmeade, just in case. The village was quiet, and Harry decided she'd have to turn back to a busier time of day if she wanted to sneak into Honeydukes' cellar without being noticed.

She chose Friday evening, so that she would have plenty of time to prepare for re-entering the time stream, and turned to approximately six o'clock, when plenty of people would be running pre-weekend errands after work.

By the time she made her way back into Hogwarts under her invisibility cloak, dinner was over, and she was pretty sure the two other versions of herself were in the Library and in the Room of Requirement, respectively. As she reentered her lab, she had the strangest feeling of surrealism. She felt like she'd been gone a year, but technically she hadn't even gone anywhere yet.

She went to put all her brewing utensils in the places she remembered them being before she left, then laughed when she realized they already were in the places they'd been, and stowed her duplicate materials in an out of the way cupboard to be collected when their originals disappeared into the time stream with her previous self the next day. She sat wearily on her familiar stool, thinking over what she had just accomplished. Archie, if she ever told him, would have a hard time believing it. She took out the little vial of Modified Polyjuice and had to laugh at how much work had gone into making such a tiny thing. She uncorked it and brought it to her lips, then hesitated.

She stood, grasped her wand in her other hand, and conjured a mirror before she could second-guess herself. She stared at her reflection a long time, taking in her green, green eyes and vulnerable mouth and stubborn chin. It didn't look like her at all, really. She looked down at the vial in her hand and tossed it back impatiently, grimacing at the awful taste that swam down her throat and pooled like grease in her belly. Her appearance began to waver, then stretch and bubble in a sickening dance. She closed her eyes against the feeling, then opened them when her body had settled into a shape.

The person in the mirror blinked back at her, familiar, yet not, after a month in a different skin. "This is who you are," she reminded herself, watching the lips move along with the words. "I am Rigel Black. I am Rigel Black. I am Rigel Black."

By the fourth or fifth time she repeated the phrase, it started to sound true, and after pacing the length of her lab for another ten minutes, she felt as though she'd never left. It was just another night brewing in her lab. The next morning she would return all the books she had taken to her dorm room, though it would be a close race to return the books after her first self had left for the game but before her other self came to collect them… She fished in her bag for a Headache Relief Potion and reminded herself firmly that it would all be over soon.

Snape found her kneeling in the stall of a stadium bathroom the next morning, face green from the combination of mustard and salt water that she'd choked down just a minute earlier. As he burst in the door, she heaved spectacularly into the toilet once again, unable to even smirk at her excellent timing as the biscuits she'd begged from the kitchen just a few hours earlier came roiling back up.

"Mr. Black." Her Head of House knelt beside her and hesitated only a moment before pulling her head back away from the bowl and peering intently into her clammy, pale features. She knew he was looking for any sign that she had been taking Polyjuice, but all she could do to convince him was play dumb.

"I think," she panted harshly, "I may have…messed up…my sleep cycle potion." After fighting a gag rather convincingly, she muttered, "I knew those skullcap flowers looked off. Should've—" She heaved again. "Just ordered more."

"Do you require assistance in reaching the Hospital Wing?" Snape asked, standing back up and looking down at her with veiled suspicion.

"I'll just take a Stomach Calming Potion," Rigel said, shaking her head tiredly. "As soon as I can get it down." She made a show of standing, bracing her hands on her knees for a long moment and then crossing to the sink to wash her face and mouth. She dry heaved a couple of times into the sink, then fumbled in her book bag for the potion that would settle her gut. After a long swig and a sharp shudder, she brushed her hands through her hair calmly and nodded to Snape gratefully. "Thank you for your concern, Professor. We should return to the game now."

Snape's eyes were still dissecting her, but he nevertheless led the way. Waiting outside for them was Pansy, who looked equally relieved that Rigel was alive and that she didn't have to enter a male restroom just to be sure.

"What on earth happened, Rigel?" she asked, folding him into a gentle hug. "You looked like you'd been stabbed—your face positively contorted with pain and I was half afraid you'd pass out and fall to your death down those stairs, you were moving so fast, and—"

"I'm fine," Rigel said, smiling reassuringly at her rambling friend. "Just got sick to my stomach all of a sudden; I think I ate some bad fish this morning."

"You had porridge this morning," Pansy said, clearly dubious.

"Must've had fish in it," Rigel said, snorting slightly.

Pansy gave her an exasperated look, but after examining her closely and seeing that she was, at least, in one apologetic piece, she sighed. "Well try not to panic half the stands next time you get a stomach ache, Rigel."

"I didn't mean to be so dramatic," Rigel said, ruffling her hair sheepishly. "You have to admit it would have been worse if I puked on Mr. Malfoy's shoes, though."

Pansy gave a disgusted noise, and flounced toward the stairs. "I'll thank you not to ever suggest such a thing again in my presence. Honestly. Boys."

"Girls," Rigel sighed, looking over at Snape ruefully. If she was expecting a commiseration of some kind, she was to be disappointed. Snape swept past her with a sneer, no doubt supremely annoyed at having gotten worked up for no reason.

As she followed them back up to the staff box, she had to take a moment to bask in the sheer relief and pride she felt at having somehow pulled off such a farce. She vowed then and there that she was going to back off the time-turner as much as possible, only using it when she truly needed to. She had come to the conclusion over the past week—month—whichever—that it might be more trouble than it was worth.

Unfortunately for her integrity, her solemn decision to respect the sanctity of the laws of time did not last longer than the first week in February, when she realized that there was a very important thing that she should be doing with her time turner, but wasn't.

It had taken that long for her to come to the conclusion that either the Auror department was very inefficient in investigating anonymous tips or the metallurgists at the Guild hadn't remembered Pettigrew's visit after all. No one from the DMLE even came to question the Creatures professor, and eventually she realized more proof was needed.

It was a simple thing to watch the Map and get a feel for his schedule. Pettigrew spent most of his time in his room when he wasn't teaching, but he also took frequent late-night trips to the Library, it turned out, and while she hadn't yet seen him do anything besides paging furiously through book after book, it comforted her to know that if he did do something majorly suspicious, she would be the first to know.

That was why, when she caught sight of his dot sliding out of the castle one evening just before dinner, she felt no compunction stealing away from her friends for a moment to turn back an hour, giving herself plenty of time to sneak outside under her cloak and wait.

He hurried across the lawn with a heavy cloak swamping his short frame, muttering to himself all the way. She tried to creep closer, to hear what he was saying, but when she rustled a leaf too near he swung around with a wild, hunted look on his face, brandishing his wand unsurely.

"Who's there?" he called, his breath coming sharply as his eyes darted here and there. He looked like a man under siege. Or perhaps one going mad. Seeing nothing, he backed away a few halting steps before taking off at a faster pace toward the Forbidden Forest.

She hung back, not wanting to give herself away, but regretted that decision when she lost sight of him around a large tree. She hurried forward as quietly as she could, but couldn't see him anywhere when she rounded the tree herself. She frowned and listened, but couldn't hear anything but the smallest of rustling in any direction. Where had he gone? She took out the Map to see which direction his dot had taken, but only just caught sight of it falling off the edge of the Map before it disappeared entirely.

Annoyed at herself, but mostly at him for traipsing suspiciously through the forest like he was hoping to be caught out at being up to something, Rigel retraced her steps and hurried back toward the castle. There was no telling how long he would be in there, and she could watch for his dot coming back toward the grounds just as easily from the warmth of Hogwarts as she could from the freezing forest.

She would figure out what he was doing with the Jewel, no matter how long it took. Time was in her favor, after all.

It took a couple of weeks to get back into the rhythm of classes after her unconventional hiatus, but all the extra studying she'd done while mindlessly waiting for the Polyjuice to finish had an unexpected consequence.

"How did you finish so quickly?" Pansy asked lowly, looking exasperated as Rigel looked up from the book on exotic poisons she'd been perusing as the rest of the class finished their Arithmancy quizzes. "It took me ages to figure out which formula to use when calculating exponential loss of magic in semi-permanent artifacts of a non-sentient nature."

"It's a combination of two formulas. They were explained in the appendix of our Arithmancy text," Rigel told her. She knew, because she'd read the whole thing twice while trying not to listen to what she thought had been some kind of vampire revel going on in the courtyard beneath her balcony one night.

"Two?" Pansy sighed, "Well, I've botched that one, then."

"It was extra credit," Rigel said, smiling a bit at Pansy's perfectionism. "I think your marks will recover from this blow."

"Not my dignity, though," Pansy said, "I always fancied myself good at numbers, you know. My maths tutor said he'd never seen a child so fast at mental computations. These word problems are so convoluted, though. It's not at all what I expected when Father told me it was like Divination done with numbers."

Rigel had to agree with that assessment. While in the higher levels, perhaps, Arithmancy could be used to actually divine the outcome of complex events, at the level they were on it was simply a tool for calculating magic empirically in various situations. Some of it was the basis if Alchemy, figuring out how much of A was needed to get effect B, except A was always magic and never other materials. Arithmancy could also be used to calculate how many runes were needed in a ritual, how long the wards on your house would last after you cast them, and even, she'd learned, to solve for the amount of raw magic one needed to keep a potion from destabilizing.

It had surprised her to learn that when Potions Masters were designing new potions from scratch, they almost always had to rely on Arithmancy to tell them mathematically how much magic would be required at various stages to make it viable. It was also a sure way to double check a recipe prior to brewing it to make sure it wouldn't explode midway through. She wished she'd known that, as she would have looked into learning Arithmancy much earlier, even if she did personally find it much easier to feel how the potion was doing through an imbuing link. As it was, she was making good headway in the subject, but would probably never be as efficient at the actual calculations as someone like Pansy, who had a true appreciation for numbers.

Pansy might do very well as a real Arithmancer, in fact, someone who could assign numbers to real-life circumstances with a degree of accuracy. It took years of practice and a good head for relativities, according to their professor, but it was an extremely sought after skill, if only because so many wizards had difficulty with logic to begin with.

Professor Vector finished collecting the last of the quizzes and waved her wand to fill the chalkboard with notes. "Today we'll be starting on Personal Arithmancy." There were scattered murmurs of interest. "As the name implies, this is the study of self-arithmancy, which means you'll need to first collect a series of data points about yourself. Can anyone give me an example of the sort of information you need before you can begin assigning numbers to your own magic?"

"How much magic you have to work with," someone said reasonably, "The size of your core, I mean."

"Yes, your reserves must be taken into account for high-level projects and rituals, but what else?" Vector asked.

"Your magical affinity?" Another student guessed. "Some runes have to be aligned with a Light/Dark balance, so a person's magic might interact with them if it had a strong inclination, right?"

"That's correct," Vector nodded, "It's important to know where you lie on the affinity scale. Anyone else?"

"The rate at which you can cast," Pansy said, a thoughtful look on her face. "Speed of magic is important in determining short-term outcomes."

"Yes, excellent," Vector said. "What about non-magic-related data?"

"Age," someone suggested, unsure.

"Generally, yes, although you only need to know the broad category you fall into; in the case of you all, it is the 13-25 range," Vector said. "Anything else?"

"Sex," one of the boys laughed. "Girls' magic is different from boys' magic."

"Yes and no," Vector said, raising an eyebrow. "Certain spells or rituals can react to a person's biology, so it is important to keep it in mind. A pregnant witch or wizard's magic is also very different from one of their sex not carrying a child. Relative things like health and infirmary can have effects, too. What else?"

There was silence as people tried to think what else could affect magic.

Rigel frowned, thinking there was an obvious one no one had mentioned. Vector caught sight of her perplexed expression and nodded her direction. "Yes, Mr. Black? Did you think of one?"

"Blood status," she said, attempting to speak without inflection. Several people laughed, but were stifled with a swift look from their professor.

"Interesting," Vector said, her eyes boring into Rigel's face. "Some people would say there is no difference in the magic of purebloods or halfbloods or muggleborns, other than an accident of birth. Many of your classmates were thinking something similar, but did not have to courage to say so, as the rhetoric behind one's blood status is increasingly political in our time. Ten points to Slytherin for speaking your mind, Mr. Black, but I wonder if you can tell me what you think the difference is. Blood? Power?"

"No," Rigel said clearly. "Those things are immaterial." She ignored the low gasps and murmurs that broke out around her, telling herself firmly that if Archie were sitting here in the same chair as she was he would say the same thing, and not be afraid. "There are plenty of powerful muggleborns and pureblooded squibs." The murmuring was louder now, and some of it was disgruntled, so she spoke louder. "There's no clear evidence one way or another that your ancestry makes you a better or worse wizard."

"But you just said it should be taken into account," Vector pressed, smiling slightly.

"The same way Light and Dark affinities should be taken into account," Rigel said, nodding. "There is a difference, but it isn't a matter of power or worth. It's just different. Purebloods have had magic in their genetic make up for so many centuries that it's been refined, made to follow genetic patterns that run through bloodlines, and sometimes manifest into Gifts or Magical Abilities that are common to a particular Family. Muggleborns never have refined abilities, because their magic is closer to the natural source of magic—it's new, you could say. It's raw in a way that magic that's been running through generations of magical families just isn't. It's mercurial and more unpredictable, but also more Neutral and more versatile. Since the magic behaves slightly differently in its raw form, there's no way it couldn't make a difference in upper-level casting and rituals, right?"

Vector clapped slowly, a smile wider than they'd ever seen her wear on her face. "You are the first third year in many years to be so versed in the theory of Wizarding Genealogy, Mr. Black. Too often I see students whose personal beliefs cloud their understanding of the facts." She held up a hand against any protest. "I do not intend to discuss politics in this class. What you do with facts has no bearing on my lessons. I will, however, give you the facts and allow you to interpret them as you will. Mr. Black is correct. There is a quantitative difference in magic between purebloods and muggleborns, though halfbloods are much more difficult to accurately numerate." She looked briefly annoyed at that. "Qualitative, we shall not speak of, nor am I interested in reading your family's stance on the issue of blood status in your next essay." She pinned them with a very stern expression. "Facts. Only."

After a long silence in which Vector made sure every student understood how strict her policy on the subject of opinion-driven research was, she moved back to the front of the room and gestured to the blackboard. "Now, we will begin collecting your data. Due to the kind of problems you'll be expected to solve on this year's end of term exam, we will be focusing on your rate of casting, rate of recovery, and relative depth of reserves…"

The class went on, and Rigel settled down to take notes, ignoring the many, varied looks that were sent her way throughout the period. Perhaps, she reflected after catching even Pansy looking at her oddly from the corner of her eye, she ought not to have expressed her ideas on magical genetics quite so bluntly. Or forcefully.

As they copied down their homework assignment—given the relative rate of casting and recovery of you and your evil wizard opponent, predict your probability of successfully escaping—and packed up their things, Anthony Goldstein, a Ravenclaw boy, walked over to their desk.

"I've never heard of that theory you were talking about," he said abruptly. Rigel was going to shrug and apologize if her words had offended him, but he added, "Can you tell me what book you found it in? I'd like to read about it for myself."

She blinked, but rattled off the books that contained the best information on the subject automatically. Goldstein scribbled the titles and authors down on a spare bit of parchment and smiled at her tightly. "Thanks. See you around, Black."

"I heard muggleborns were descendent from squibs, and that's where their magic comes from," Pansy said quietly as they walked back toward the common room. "I…Father says that muggles are there as a repairing mechanism for magic that's gotten too convoluted in Wizarding bloodlines. He says it gets rejected in the form of squibs and then after a while it repairs itself and becomes muggleborns, thus recycling magic back into the system."

Rigel thought that sounded like the sort of thing that gave purebloods a reason to call muggles and muggleborns trash or defective or lesser, but instead of saying so, she shrugged. "It's not clear yet how magic works or doesn't work in the instances of muggleborns and squibs. There are a lot of theories. All I know it that they've measured the differences in magic between muggleborns and purebloods empirically and shown that while there aren't significant, consistent differences in average power levels, muggleborn magic is closer to the unbound, formless magic found in nature and magical creatures than the magic of wizards who've had tons of wizard ancestors is."

"I'd like to read those books too, I think," Pansy said, face blank.

"They're in my trunk," she offered stoically. "You can have them whenever you want."

It wasn't really her intention to push her friends into considering new ideas. She'd always been content to let them think what they want, seeing as it wasn't their fault what they were brought up to believe, and it certainly wasn't her place to rock the system—she'd lost that privilege when she decided to use it to her advantage. And yet, somehow, she was having an increasingly difficult time keeping her opinions to herself. Maybe because she'd seen the effect her friends' mindsets had on other people as Harriett. Maybe because they were growing up, and it was natural to begin asserting personal beliefs more strongly. Whatever the reason, she would have to step lightly. The last thing she wanted to do was alienate her friends. She cared about the truth, but she cared about her friendships more. At least…she thought she did.

The first weekend of February, she received a note with her breakfast from Remus, asking if she would be amenable to tea in his office that afternoon to catch up. She sent her uncle a cheerful thumbs-up from across the Great Hall, which made him chuckle visibly into his goblet at the Head Table.

"What was that about?" Draco asked from the seat next to her.

"Remus wants to have tea with me this afternoon," she said honestly.

"That's a first, isn't it?" Millicent said, eyeing her curiously from across the table. "I thought you said at the beginning of the year that you and Professor Lupin were close."

"He's been maintaining a professional distance," Rigel explained. "He knows he'll see me all summer at home. It's important for his integrity that it doesn't look like he favors me."

"Seems a bit concerned with appearances," Draco said, eyebrow rising, "After all, everyone knows you're a talented student. No one would think you hadn't earned your Defense marks."

"He has to be concerned with appearances," Rigel said, feeling a little defensive on his behalf. "People are always watching him, waiting for him to make a mistake or show any sign of unsuitability."

"You know, sometimes I forget he's a werewolf," Theo said conversationally, "I mean, he's a bit boring actually—not his classes, of course, but just as a person. I'm honestly more scared of Professor Trelawney."

"She is rather terrifying," Pansy said, smiling in amusement. "Do you know she's predicted three deaths this week alone?"

"Not yours, I hope," Draco teased.

"She wouldn't dare," Pansy sniffed. "Though she did tell me I was going to fall ill around the end of term."

"Not much of a prediction," Millicent snorted, "Everyone falls ill at the end of term—finals put stress on the immune system."

"Pomfrey is already having Snape brew Calming Draughts for the OWL and NEWT students," Rigel said conspiratorially. "It's driving him spare."

"Is that why he took twenty points from that Hufflepuff student for, and I quote, 'breathing so loudly you give credence to an alternate explanation of your House's dubious nomenclature'?" Blaise asked.

They burst into undignified laughter at the way Blaise perfectly captured their Head of House's ungodly derision.

"Someone should be writing these down," Millicent said, wiping her eyes, "We can give it to him as a book when we graduate."

"I'm not sure that will make him remember us fondly," Theo grinned.

"Not to mention if he started using the same material it wouldn't be as effective," Pansy pointed out. "Half the fear he induces is of the mindboggling, how-on-earth-did-he-come-up-with-that-so-quickly variety."

"He was probably teased a lot as a child," Blaise said suddenly, causing them all to fall into an uncomfortable silence. The dark-skinned boy cleared his throat. "I mean, generally speaking that would have necessitated quick comebacks."

Thinking about Snape as a kid brought a grimace to Rigel's face. He'd attended Hogwarts in a time when halfbloods were still admitted, but everyone could see the direction the policy was beginning to take. How must it have felt, to be one of the last halfbloods around Hogwarts? Did he feel lucky, to have barely squeaked ahead of the political wave? Or resentful, that his was a dying circumstance and everyone knew it. It was probably why he worked so hard as both an educator and a researcher, she mused. To prove his place in society wasn't unwarranted.

The mood mostly ruined, they finished their breakfast in a subdued manner, and split up shortly after to pursue their own activities. Rigel went to her lab, thinking she could brew up a few batches of Calming Draughts before her meeting with Remus and give Professor Snape a break from the monotony. She honestly didn't know how he found time to be a professor and the Hogwarts potions supplier while conducting his own research as well. It wasn't as though he had a time-turner.

Wondering vaguely why they didn't give all researchers time-turners, to speed up production of groundbreaking discoveries and cures if nothing else, she got out the supplies she needed automatically, lost in a world of thought.

By the time she'd finished her last batch, she was slightly overdue for her tea with Remus, but that was fixed with a quick half-turn back of the hourglass, which hardly even counted, as the overlap was really negligible…she told herself.

Before leaving the lab, she pulled out what she was calling 'eau de Archie' in her head and sprayed it liberally under her arms and around her collar. That done, it was an easy thing to make her way to Remus' office and muss her hair up just before entering, throwing the door open with a dramatic flourish and close it swiftly behind her for good measure.

"Hey," she panted lightly, "Remus. How…are you?"

"I'm well, Ar—Rigel," Remus said, smiling a bit, "May I ask what your haste is about? You aren't late yet, you know."

"Archie's fine when it's just us, Uncle Remus," Rigel said easily. "And I may have, ah, turned the hangings in our dorm room Hufflepuff yellow. My roommates are on the warpath." That should explain the overwhelmingly sweaty scent she was sporting, at least.

"Your father would tell you to use the Map to avoid them, instead of running every which way," Remus said, chucking. "As I recall that's how Sirius avoided the people he broke up with until their ire cooled down."

"And what would you say, Moony?" she grinned lopsidedly, affecting Archie's boyish charm.

"Well, as your educator I would have to advise against such childish diversions," Remus said gravely. A smile snuck into his voice as he added, "But as your Uncle I'd tell you to try pranking people you don't share a dorm with. Unless you enjoy being hexed in your sleep."

"So you don't think I should dip Draco's essay in peanut butter tomorrow?" she asked, voice innocent.

"That depends," he pretended to think, "Is it his Defense essay?"

They laughed, and Rigel began bouncing her foot a little as the silence settled. The key to playing Archie successfully around people who knew him was to never be still. Archie was movement, restless impatience and energy and excitement over anything remotely not-boring. To be still would remind Remus of Harry.

"How are your other classes going?" Remus asked, sipping on his tea with a relaxed expression. "You're in Magical Theory, aren't you? I took that myself at your age. How are you finding it?"

"Fascinating," she said, smiling happily, "I'm taking it with Hannah Abbott, who want to be an experimental charms researcher in a private company like what Aunt Lily does, and Anthony Goldstein, who doesn't actually like the class I don't think, only he wants to be a cursebreaker, and Magical Theory is a prerequisite for the NEWT cursebreaking class. Did you know Ron Weasley has an older brother who's a cursebreaker? He works for Gringotts."

That was another thing about Archie—he noticed people, more than objects or ideas, and could ramble at length about anyone he'd had the slightest contact with. It was what made him so good at relating to complete strangers socially, as evidenced by his spectacular performance at the gala.

"I've heard that's a very exciting career," Remus agreed. After a moment, he paused, "Archie, you are good friends with the Weasley children, aren't you? Sirius mentioned you'd gone to their house a couple of times over break."

"Yes," she nodded easily, "They're really nice, except Ginny who pretends she's not nice because it makes her seem tough, and I think her brothers picked on her a lot when she was young. Ron is in the Dueling Club with me, and Percy helps me with my Transfiguration homework sometimes, and the twins…well, lets just say I sleep with one eye open at night."

Remus chuckled obligingly, but asked, "How do your other friends feel about your friendship with the Weasleys?"

"Um, they get sort of annoyed, actually," Rigel said, not seeing the harm in being honest. "Draco especially doesn't approve of them, though he's been a little better now that Ron is listening to him in Dueling practice."

"That's good," Remus said, looking relieved. "I wouldn't want you caught in the middle of anything. You're a good young man, Archie. You should build friendships wherever you see fit."

"Remus," she said suddenly, frowning a bit, "Why do people like Draco dislike the Weasleys so much? It almost seems like they look down on them as much as they look down on muggleborns, which doesn't make sense. I mean, they're both purebloods, no matter what their stance on politics." Remus looked troubled, and Rigel hurried to add. "It's not that I don't understand the political issues at stake. It just seems to me that you could disagree with someone without actually hating them, you know?"

Remus took a long drink of tea, seeming lost in thought, then said, somewhat delicately, "There are many families across the Light/Dark political divide who do respectfully disagree. The Weasleys, however, are considered—by the most extreme supporters of blood purity mind you, not the general populace—to be blood traitors."

"That just means they support muggleborn and halfblood rights equal to pureblood rights, doesn't it?" Rigel said, a bit confused. She hated not understanding a problem completely. "Everyone who supports Dumbledore's faction is anti-blood-supremacy."

"But they aren't all looked upon as the Weasleys are, are they?" Remus said knowingly, watching the wheels turn in her head.

"What…what's the difference I'm missing?" she asked, troubled that she hadn't picked up on that nuance before.

"What do you know about the term 'blood traitor,' exactly?" Remus asked, slipping into professor mode.

"Well, it's an insult," she said slowly, "A sort of synonym for 'muggle-lover,' I guess."

"Precisely," Remus said, "In fact, the root of the term is a reference to the literal meaning of the insult 'muggle-lover.' Both terms are used loosely as insults for people who support or even sympathize with muggles and muggleborns, but originally it was very explicit. A muggle-lover—a blood traitor in its truest sense—refers to a witch or wizard who has relations with muggles or muggleborn witches and wizards."

Rigel wrinkled her nose. "That doesn't make sense, though. The Weasleys are pureblood."

"There are some," Remus said carefully, "Who believe it is a mere technicality." He looked incredibly awkward, but soldiered on in his explanation. "Some purebloods believe that the Weasley family…bred with muggles or muggleborns on purpose, in an effort to revitalize their bloodline. The accusation, indelicate though it may be, is that blood traitors like the Weasleys are thought to make an effort to circumvent the fertility issues that true pureblooded families contend with by periodically—no more than once every few generations, mind you—marrying and producing children with those of less than pure blood. They are then accused of intermarrying aggressively with other purebloods once more until their own line is considered technically pure—that is, the current head of family has four magic-wielding grandparents. Their pureblooded pedigree is thus considered somewhat of a sham, if you will—a veneer that protects the family socially while not bearing up under idealistic scrutiny. Thus the term 'blood traitor' refers to someone who betrays his own blood while not relinquishing the claim to that blood status completely."

Rigel was trying not to look shocked, but she had honestly never heard anything of the sort. "If people think—if they believe that families like the Weasleys can actually achieve increased odds of fertility simply by infusing a little genetic variation into the bloodline, then—then why don't they try it? So many purebloods lose children to unknown causes. If the Weasleys have found a way around that, I don't see why everyone isn't using it."

Remus grimaced. "Archie, you were raised in a moderate, open minded household. I'm not sure you can ever understand how deeply preconceived notions about the world can run. Imagine if someone told you tomorrow that your thoughts on, oh, academic integrity were all wrong, and that if you wanted to get good marks on your final exams the only way to do so would be to cheat. You would think them ridiculous, and insist that you could get good marks by studying hard and doing what you've always done, and you'd think that anyone who cheated to pass the test was an immoral fool who didn't deserve a good mark—isn't that right?"

"Well, yes," she said slowly. "I suppose so."

"To people who believe very strongly in the superiority of blood status, telling them that mingling with muggles might save them is not only blasphemy—it's incompatible with every truly-held faculty within them." Remus sighed. "What seems obvious to us is little more than ridiculous posturing by unworthy specimens of magic to them. They would sooner change almost anything else they think or endorse than change their stance on blood purity."

"But the children," Rigel murmured, unable to really understand. "If someone told me I had to cheat on a test to keep Addy alive, I'd do it without question. I wouldn't care about my integrity at that point."

Remus reached across the small tea table to pat her arm gently. "It isn't so simple, I'm afraid," he said softly. "No one walks up to pureblooded mothers and says 'here are your choices: mate with a muggle or watch your child die.' Of course it isn't so simple. Instead they have people on every side telling them not to worry, or that it's worth the chance that everything turns out all right. And the Healers don't fully understand it. And the media doesn't make any sense at all. And everyone they know and love and trust is telling them this is the only way, the way it's always been, the way it has to be… do you see how difficult it would be to think anything else?"

"I suppose," Rigel said slowly, "That the real miracle is that families like the Weasleys ever thought to try something new in the first place."

"That's a good way to look at it," Remus said, smiling wanly. "I'm afraid any change that upsets what people view as the natural order of things is going to come slowly, and with much confusion."

"Yeah," she said shakily, wondering how she ever thought a few well-chosen words in her friends' ears would change anything.

"You don't need to worry about all that," Remus said abruptly, "Come, I didn't bring you here to despair about the world. Let's talk about something else."

"All right," she said, trying to get back into Archie's character somehow. "How is the New Wolfsbane working? Are you doing well?"

"Very well," Remus smiled, "Thanks to you and Professor Snape, I hardly feel the call of the moon most months. It does make me a little disoriented after I wake, but that is a small price to pay. I heal faster from the transformations, and my appetite in greatly increased in the days leading up to the full moon. And you can tell all that to Harry, who I know put you up to that question."

His smile was fond, and Rigel couldn't help but smile back sheepishly. "She worries about you, is all."

"I am very lucky to know so many generous, caring young—"

He broke off as the door to his office was flung open suddenly.

"Remus, my old friend, I have to tell you something—" Peter Pettigrew stopped, looked at Rigel and mouthed a soundless 'oh.' He looked back and forth between them, something in his face seeming shaken and torn.

"What is it, Peter?" Remus said, beginning to rise.

Pettigrew shook his head quickly. "I don't know. Never mind." He bolted out of the office as though he had hounds on his heels.

"What on Earth?" Remus slowly sank back down into his chair, perplexed.

"Maybe he found something interesting in the Library," Rigel said suddenly, seeing her chance.

"The Library?" Remus frowned in confusion. "Why would you think that?"

"I see him in there a lot," she said, trying to hint innocently. "He's always in there, it seems, paging through old books. I wonder if he's studying for something, or just looking for information on something in particular."

Remus cleared his throat and averted his eyes. "How odd. He never was the studious type."

She hoped dearly that he was pretending ignorance for her sake and that he did, in fact, suspect something about his old friend. All she could do, she realized, was plant seeds. She would have to trust the adults to take matters into their own hands, once presented with enough information.

Rigel thought ruefully that when she was an adult, she would be much more proactive about things than the generation before her seemed to be.

Before she knew it, Valentine's Day had come to pass. In Rigel's defense, it was struggle enough to remember which day of the week she was present in and how many other times she'd done it already, so keeping track of the actual calendar days had sort of fallen by the wayside. She supposed it was her own fault, then, that she was taken almost completely by surprise.

She had attributed her friends' unnaturally good spirits to the upcoming weekend until they walked into the Great Hall and saw a huge crowd over by the message boards, all gabbing excitedly about something or other.

"It's a Hogsmeade weekend coming up, right?" she guessed, trying to seem engaged in the present.

Draco snorted. "It's the fourteenth, Rigel."

"The…" She grimaced. "Oh." Of course it was.

"Perhaps there's an activity of some sort planned," Pansy said, eyeing the mass of milling students with interest.

"Let's go see," Draco said, glancing at Pansy with fond patience. "It would be a shame to have to get the story secondhand."

Thus decided, they crossed the Great Hall to see what the fuss was about. When the first young girl turned and spotted Rigel, immediately dissolving into a fit of giggles, she thought maybe she'd surprised the girl by standing too close behind her. After the third person to turn around, catch sight of her face, and nudge the person next to them, however, she was starting to feel dread pooling in her stomach.

Draco, perhaps feeling her sudden change in emotional state or else noticing the odd behavior of the students around them as well, said, "What?" very loudly.

Laughter spread through the mob and several students obligingly parted before their trio to let them have a look at the message board. There was a lurid pink flyer taking up most of the five-by-five foot space, and smack in the middle of it was a Wizarding photo of her. The Rigel in the photo wasn't looking anywhere near the camera, wherever it had been, but was rather gazing off at something out of frame, frowning as though gently intrigued. It was, frankly, ridiculous.

"Rigel Black's Labor of Love," Draco read, grimacing even as the words left his mouth. "Got a letter you're scared to loose? Is your amour better off anonymous? Rigel Black has got your back! One day only, put your passion to parchment and let Romantic Rigel do the rest." He turned to Rigel with a pained expression. "What is this, Rigel?"

"I don't know," she said, her voice rising a bit as she took in the rest of the poster. "It obviously wasn't me!"

"Hmm, it says 'sign your smoldering secret Valentines with the name Rigel Black, and I'll deliver them free of charge,'" Pansy noted, amusement in every syllable. "'On my honor, every tender triviality, adoring affection, and devious detail will be delivered—with your identity incognito.' It even has a copy of your schedule today so people can give you their love notes at any time—how sweet is that?"

"How quickly can I eviscerate the Weasley twins?" Rigel muttered darkly. They had taken the Rigel-signed note thing too far this time.

She turned and made for the Gryffindor table, ready to nip this prank in the bud with extreme prejudice. Before she'd gone two steps, however, a tentative hand grasped her sleeve and waylaid her.

"Are you…Rigel Black?"

Rigel looked down into the beet-red face of a Gryffindor first year. "I am," she said, fighting a grimace. "Who are you?"

Instead of responding, the eleven-year-old girl pressed a small paper heart into her hand with an embarrassed grin. "The name is on the inside. Thanks, Black."

Before Rigel could protest that she was certainly not a Valentine's Day owl, the first-year was gone, and Rigel was staring down at a piece of red-colored parchment with a bewildered expression. "How is this my life?"

By the time she made it to the Weasley twins, she had four cards in her hand and she was fairly certain another stuffed in her pocket when she wasn't looking. They took one look at her irked expression and burst out laughing. "Why the long face, Rigel? Didn't you get any valentines?" Fred asked, sending George and several of the other Gryffindors who'd overheard into appreciative chuckles.

"Why?" It was all she had to say. "Why do you do this to me?"

"One day you'll thank us," George insisted. "You're going to be a symbol, Rigel. A symbol of love, truth, beauty, and—"

"Grouchiness," Fred said, poking her cheek, where she could feel a tick developing.

"I will get you for this," she promised. "Both of you. Maybe not even at the same time."

"I don't think anyone's ever threatened to prank us separately, George," Fred said, looking interested.

"Could be fun," George agreed, grinning.

Rigel sighed, and turned back to the Slytherin table, not sure why she even bothered. When she went to take her seat, however, she found a pile of cards stacked on top of her plate. A round of snickers met her disheartened sigh.

"Didn't know you were such a romantic at heart, Rigel," Pucey spoke up from a few seats down the table.

Rigel took a deep breath, picked up the armful of Valentines on her plate and dumped them unceremoniously into Pucey's lap. "For that, you can deliver these, Adrian."

Pucey spluttered. "No way. Do you know what it will do to my reputation if I go handing out little pink hearts?"

"All I know is that you owe me several favors, Adrian," she said, raising an eyebrow challengingly. "I think the least you can do is help me out today, don't you?"

"He's got a point, Adrian," Derrick said, smirking. He pulled out an elaborately embossed red card from his breast pocket. "Deliver this to Lucian for me, won't you? Don't tell him who it's from."

Pucey scowled and snatched the card roughly before tossing it across the table into Bole's lap. The fact that Bole was sitting right next to Derrick didn't appear to amuse Pucey. "Rigel, come on, have a heart…" he trailed off with a resigned groan.

"Oh Rigel has hearts," Theo piped up, arriving at the table with a large grin. "There's a whole stack of them by the common room entrance, in fact, all addressed to him."

"Already?" Pansy hid a smile behind her hand. "My, word certainly spreads quickly."

If Rigel thought her friends were going to have their fun and then let the joke go gracefully, she was quite mistaken. All day, in addition to having to smile politely while students from all grade levels handed her cards, letters, and even, in one case, an elaborate origami flower, she also had to endure her so-called friends' poorly-stifled guffaws and smirks.

Most of the people whose names were on the valentines she found piled on her desks or passed along by her friends were students Rigel didn't even know. She had to rely on good-natured classmates from other Houses to get many of them delivered, but she was almost proud to say that by the end of the day she'd sent every last wretchedly tacky heart on its way.

She made it back to the common room just before curfew, having successfully delivered the last batch to a very helpful Cho Chang at the base of Ravenclaw tower. Adrian Pucey intercepted her on the way to her dorm room, saying, "I hope you know that we are assuredly even after this, Rigel. I have never been the butt of so many jokes."

"That you know of," Rigel said, summoning up a grin. "Thanks, though. I wouldn't have managed them all on my own."

"Yes, well." Pucey cleared his throat. "Here." He produced two modest-looking valentines that had her groaning in protest.

"No more," she pleaded. "I can't look at another one. Can't you deliver them?"

Pucey smirked lopsidedly, "I am."

"What?" She blinked dumbly at the proffered cards.

"These are addressed to you," Pucey said. "They're signed from you, too, but I'm assuming you aren't that much of a masochist."

She took them with an incredulous laugh. "Thanks…I guess."

"Yeah, whatever, Black," Pucey sniffed. "Next time do your own dirty work."

Rolling her eyes, she made a beeline for the third-year hallway. All she wanted to do was sleep. Theo and Blaise were already in their sleeping attire when she walked in, with only Draco still sitting up in his school clothes, penning something on his personalized letterhead.

"Writing thank you notes for all the valentines you got today, Draco?" she asked, chuckling a bit. She'd delivered one herself that had been handed off by Daphne Greengrass of all people. It had actually fountained confetti upon Draco opening it.

"I only received the one, as you very well know, and there's no way I'm writing a thank you note to a second year," Draco scowled.

"You know who it's from?" Rigel lifted an eyebrow. "I thought the ones coming through me were supposed to be anonymous."

"It's that Greengrass chit," Draco rolled his eyes, "The younger one. She was only stalking me all day to see my reaction to getting it. I could feel her depressing brand of fearful yearning from across the castle."

"Astoria, right?" Theo put in from where he was sprawled across his bed. "At least she's nicer than her sister."

"It would be difficult to be more harridan-like than Daphne," Blaise said mildly, not even looking up from the book he was perusing.

"I suppose a thank you note would only embarrass her," Rigel shrugged. "Still, you could at least nod politely the next time you saw her. I think she looks up to you after you calmed her down in the carriage that time."

"And encourage her?" Draco wrinkled his nose. "I think not. I've enough problems without adding lovesick shadow to the list. If I ignore her, maybe she'll get the hint and go away."

Rigel sighed, but knew that it wasn't really any of her business. It might even work, at that. She sat down on her own bed and kicked off her shoes before opening her own valentines curiously. Maybe the twins had sent her one each. It seemed like the sort of cherry-on-top thing they'd do.

After close examination, however, they didn't seem to be gag valentines at all; rather, each contained a message that appeared to have been intended genuinely. The first, a white card with red ribbon tying it closed, read simply: Be Mine? The second, smaller in size but filled with red ink, said: I've always admired your honest compassion, and thought I may as well say it now. You make me think better of Slytherins, and better of young men in general. Thanks for being inspiring, in your own quiet way. Happy Valentine's Day. It was signed Your secret admirer/ Rigel Black.

Her lips quirked at the thought that she had a secret admirer. How unlikely.

"What're those?" Draco asked suddenly, coming off his bed to have a look. "You've got valentines, Rigel?"

She shrugged in an unconcerned way. "Guess so."

"Oh, stop, I can feel your gooey insides just melting," Draco drawled. "Let's see them, then."

She held them on her other side, out of his reach. "Read your own."

Blaise, the traitor, snatched them from her hand from his side of the bed before she realized he'd left his covers. "I haven't got any to read," he said, smirking. Opening the first, he cleared his throat before saying, in a dulcet tones, "Be. Mine. How incredibly deep."

He went to open the other one, but Theo had made a grab for it before he got the chance. "Ah-ah-ah, I know you've had a valentine from Hannah, because it had adorable animated crups running along the border. I get to read this one." He recited the note grandly, interspersed with laughs from the other two, and when he was finished, he handed the card back to Rigel with great aplomb. "Looks like we have a little mystery, boys. Who could our Rigel's secret admirer be?"

"Admirers," Blaise corrected, handing the card he'd taken back as well.

"I bet I can figure it out within the week," Draco said, smirking.

"You have an unfair advantage." Blaise rolled his eyes.

"Which you still have no proof of," Draco sniffed, not having officially told anyone other than Rigel and Pansy about his gift.

"But which is nevertheless entirely obvious," Blaise said dryly.

"I'd really rather not know," Rigel said hastily. "It's more fun as a mystery…right?"

"No," Draco said flatly.

"Nope," Theo grinned.

"It is always better to know something than not," Blaise said, nodding firmly.

"Well, good luck then," Rigel sighed. "Just leave me out of it."

"Careful with your ice cold attitude, Rigel," Theo laughed. "You're going to break hearts at this rate."

"Like you're one to talk," Draco said, getting back to his letter. "I saw that tear-stained love letter from the Patil girl."

"We parted amiably," Theo said, sounding exasperated. "And we only dated once. It's not like there was some grand romance that fell to ruins. She's being dramatic."

"It's probably the first time she's dated anyone," Blaise said reasonable. "She'll gain perspective once she matures a bit."

"That doesn't help me now," Theo grumbled. "She wants me to take her to Hogsmeade on Saturday, but I've already asked Geoffrey Hooper."

"What are you doing for Hogsmeade, Rigel?" Draco asked, cutting across Theo's whining.

Rigel looked over. "I haven't any plans. I don't really need anything, except maybe some more lacewing flies, I guess. Actually, I should probably get a few other things as well." She frowned, wondering why she hadn't thought to replenish the ingredients she'd gone through with the Polyjuice while she was staying in the alleys.

"I meant for fun, not errands," Draco said. "Who are you going with? Pansy has a date, you know."

"Oh." Rigel wondered why she hadn't known that. Maybe she'd been asked that day, while Rigel was running about delivering cards. "Well, I guess I'll go with whoever doesn't have a date, then."

"I'm not going," Blaise said, grimacing apologetically. "I have to spend the summer at my family's Italian estate, and Millie offered to start catching me up on European politics."

"Just us then," Draco said, his tone a little too casual. "What should we do?"

"Whatever you like," she said, not too concerned. It wasn't as though they hadn't been to Hogsmeade before.

She turned over to get more comfortable and missed the look of calculation on her blonde friend's face. Had she seen it, she might have been a little more on her guard. As it was, Hogsmeade was the furthest thing from her mind. Though it wasn't far off in the liner sense, she had several more days of time-turned classes and studying to get through before looking to the weekend.

Draco was of the firm opinion that no proper wizard should ever rouse himself from bed before the sun had bothered to grace the sky with at least a grasping finger's breadth of pink luminescence. At least, he had been of that opinion, before morning exercise with a certain dark haired roommate of his had somehow become a normal part of his cultured existence. The recent frequency of early rises hadn't made them any less utterly and uninspiringly odious, but sometimes it was necessary to make sacrifices for larger ends.

That was why, even though it was so obnoxiously early that dawn hardly described the situation, Draco roused himself with difficulty from the cocooning warmth of his blankets. His roommates, lucky sods, slept soundly as Draco crept to the foot of his bed and slipped one hand into his trunk. Feeling around for the little pouch that he'd specifically left on the top of all the other items the night before, he grinned in the darkness in a way that he told himself was not at all deranged. He'd always heard stories from his father about hatching plans and seeing them come to fruition, but he hadn't really had the chance to make his own plans. There had never been any reason to. Until now.

Rigel Black was up to something, and as his friend, it was Draco's responsibility to figure out what. That, and the curiosity was eating away at his soul. After getting a handle on his rather unexpected Empathic Gift, he'd become accustomed to knowing things. It was immediately obvious to Draco when Rigel began sneaking around at the beginning of the year, but every effort he'd made to keep an eye on his friend had been frustrated by the fact that Rigel was always doing something perfectly reasonable. Draco was practically drowning in feelings of guilt and excitement every time Rigel made an awkward excuse and ducked into a bathroom or around the corner or…wherever he would disappear to for inexplicably short amounts of time. He was never unaccounted for longer than a few minutes, which was the really strange part. Draco just knew he was up to something, but what could possibly be both interesting enough to hide and accomplished in five minutes?

His running (if admittedly unlikely) theory was that Rigel had a relationship he was keeping secret, which had him sneaking off for kisses in broom cupboards all over the castle…or something. Nothing else that he'd come up with made any sort of sense, unless Rigel had had an embarrassing case of irritable bowel syndrome all year.

Today, he would find out one way or another. His plan was foolproof. In his hand was a tiny little tracking device purchased for a modest seven sickles from a certain joke shop he'd visited over the break. While advertised for use on professors—and how ridiculous a notion was that, putting a tracker on Snape's robe hem?—Draco thought it would be perfect for keeping tabs on his most suspicious friend. He stepped quietly over to where Rigel's shoes were sitting on the floor beside his bed and carefully attached the tiny tracking bug onto the underside of Rigel's right sole. With anyone else, this would be a bit of a gamble, but Rigel wore the same pair of shoes every day. It would be his undoing, Draco thought with a somewhat maniacal smirk.

As he slipped back into bed to 'go back to sleep' until the others woke up, he had to admit it was pretty exciting, sneaking around like one of Grindelwald's spies. He could see why Rigel would find it appealing, but that didn't mean he would just let the other boy get away with it.

He was creeping through a dark forest, his wand at the ready—wait, that wasn't his wand, it was a sugar quill. Taking a bite thoughtfully, Draco spotted a majestic unicorn coming into the clearing. "Hail, Unicorn!" he said, saluting with his sugar quill smartly. "Hail, Draco!" the unicorn whinnied, bowing its horn low to the ground. "Where did you learn to bow, Unicorn?" he asked, confused. "The same place I learned to curtsey," the unicorn said, now wearing a skirt. That made sense, he thought, setting off to a different part of the forest. He was looking for something…something important…there! A flashing light up ahead made him break into an excited jog. The light led him to a clearing full of sunlight. There were birds singing and the most delicious smell in the air. It was…it was…he opened his eyes and fell forward into a meadow of strawberries. Only they weren't strawberries, they were strawberry tarts and they were calling out his name. Draco…Draco…

"Draco, get up." Someone was shaking him. He opened his eyes into Rigel's exasperated grey orbs. "Weren't you the one so eager to get to Hogsmeade today?"

Draco yawned, rubbing his eyes and hair simultaneously. "I hate mornings."

"It's almost nine, Draco," Rigel said, openly amused at his expense.

"I didn't sleep well," he said, trying to regain a semblance of his usual poise. Rigel's secret had better be worth his beauty sleep.

"That's a first," Rigel snorted. "Usually you're out cold the moment your head hits the pillow. Bad dreams?"

"Malfoys don't have bad dreams," Draco informed him. "Even the figments of our imagination know their place."

"Yes, yes, all hail Draco, King of Dreams," Rigel said, heading for the door. "When you rejoin reality, I'll be at breakfast."

"Hail Draco, yes," he murmured sleepily, reclining back into his pillow once more. A few minutes later he sprung up with a gasp and cursed quietly. "Focus, Draco," he told himself firmly, pushing the covers back and hurrying to make himself presentable. He could not afford to be off his game today—not if he was going to catch Rigel by surprise.

He arrived at the Slytherin table in time to hear Rigel inquiring politely about Pansy's date.

"It's obligatory," their friend sighed. Draco wasn't fooled by her nonchalance, however. He could read a subtle excitement underlying the slightly disengaged calculation that he'd come to understand was Pansy's norm.

"Don't dissemble," Draco teased her. "We know you love sussing out new people."

"Especially when they don't see it coming," Rigel said, moving over a bit to make room for Draco to sit.

"Only fools take the world at face value," Pansy sniffed, fluttering her lashes. "Can I help it that so many young men these days are fools?"

"Not us, though, right?" Theo grinned lasciviously from across the table.

"No comment," Pansy said sweetly.

They finished their meal and broke off in different directions for the day. Rigel and he took a carriage to Hogsmeade alone, and Draco tried to remember the last time he'd done something with just Rigel and none of their other friends.

"How've you been?" he asked, somewhat lamely, just to get the ball rolling. If he could persuade Rigel to tell him what he'd been up to now, it would save him a lot of trouble. Then again, Draco thought with a slight frown, he'd already gone to the trouble of coming up with such a brilliant plan. It would almost be disappointing if Rigel revealed his secret right off.

"Just fine," Rigel said, smiling a bit and radiating amusement to Draco's senses. "Snape is letting me brew Felix Felicis next week."

"That's very advanced," Draco said, suitably impressed.

Rigel smiled wider, visibly pleased. "It would take six months to complete, and of course the Ministry doesn't encourage casual brewing of the substance in any case, but we'll at least be able to get a good start on the base before the end of the school year."

"Sounds…involved," Draco offered.

"It's going to be fascinating," Rigel agreed. "So where do you want to go today?"

"Wherever you like," Draco said. His plan was actually to let Rigel get comfortable, while simultaneously monopolizing his time all morning. Then, if his usual pattern was anything to go by, Rigel would inexplicably feel the need to sneak away at some point. Draco would graciously pretend to believe whatever excuse Rigel made, then he would follow Rigel using the teacher tracker and see what he was really up to. It was perfect.

Rigel was quiet for a few minutes, staring out of the window, radiating pensiveness. "Would it be all right…if we went to see the Shrieking Shack?" Rigel asked, glancing hesitantly at him, as though fairly certain Draco wouldn't want to.

Normally, he wouldn't go anywhere near the supposedly haunted place, but his plan called for Rigel to be completely oblivious to any attempts at manipulating him, which meant Draco would appease his curiosity, in this instance. "Sounds good, I haven't seen it yet, either," Draco said, smiling magnanimously.

"Thanks." Rigel smiled, but the subtle expression was nothing compared to the quiet gratitude that floated Draco's way, filling up his senses as though the air in the carriage had been perfumed with the emotion.

Draco breathed it in deeply, despite knowing it wasn't an actual smell.

They departed the carriages and made their way slowly through the village, content to stretch their legs and take in the bustle and energy of the student-flooded town. They passed the main shopping streets and before long had reached the outskirts of the village. The noise of rowdy students had long since faded away, and by the time they reached the fence that set the shack back from the road, Draco might have thought them in another place entirely, so eerily silent was the atmosphere.

Rigel rested both arms on the fence and leaned forward until his chin was propped atop them, gazing at the dilapidated, boarded-up house with what Draco recognized after a moment was sadness, mingled with pity. Not knowing why Rigel would feel pity for a house, even a beat up old neglected one, Draco said, "I've heard that a family of banshees live there until some villagers found out about them, then set the shack on fire to try and run them out. The banshees died in the flames, though, and every now and then you can hear the awful shrieking as their ghosts relive the anguish."

Rigel, instead of appearing appropriately impressed with Draco's gruesome tale, merely snorted. "That's not true."

"You sound sure," Draco said, smiling as he felt Rigel's amusement and knew he'd been the cause of it.

"I am," Rigel said. "This shack was built in the same year as the Whomping Willow." A flicker of unease crossed the air between them, and as Rigel rushed on Draco wondered if he'd said something he hadn't meant to. He didn't see what that violent tree had to do with the shack in Hogsmeade, but he tucked the information away in any case. That was what Malfoys did after all—they remembered things that seemed important even if they didn't understand why they were important. Someone else might understand, one day. "Anyway, the shack was actually built a couple of decades ago at Dumbledore's behest. It looks much older, but that's part of the intended façade."

Draco lifted a brow. "How would you know that?"

Rigel hesitated visibly, but seemed to decide there was no harm in telling Draco whatever was making him look so morose. "My uncle, Remus, didn't become a werewolf later in life—he was bitten as a child, and never imagined he would get the chance to attend Hogwarts like a regular kid. Dumbledore took a chance on him, though, and arranged for this place to be built so that Remus would have somewhere to go during the full moon. You can't tell from here, but the entire structure is heavily warded, and with a few rumors spread among the locals to keep people away, it was the perfect place to keep a werewolf hidden, but safe."

Draco could not quite stop the shocked look that crossed his face. "Dumbledore brought a werewolf to Hogwarts…on purpose? Before the Wolfsbane potion was even invented?"

"It was a calculated risk," Rigel shrugged. "Dumbledore believes the best of people, and in this case, he was right. Remus never took his education for granted. He worked incredibly hard, studied everything he could, and graduated near the very top of his class."

"It's impressive, considering how ill he must have been several days out of every month," Draco allowed.

"It didn't do any good in the end, though," Rigel said, frowning. "For all his brilliance and kindness and work ethic, Remus has never been able to keep a steady job. He refused to hide his condition, refused to lie about what he was, once he graduated. He wanted to be appreciated on his own terms. And the world let him down. Every time, he was told no, you aren't good enough, no, we can't take the risk."

"You can't blame people for—"

"Can't I?" Rigel sighed. "He's more risk to his family and friends, the people who stand by him when the moon waxes, than he is to an employer who would likely never see him after five o'clock anyway. We saw the good in him. Dumbledore saw it when he was only eleven. I've never understood…why couldn't other people? Why is it so hard to look past someone else's circumstances?"

Draco didn't have an answer to that. At least, not one he thought Rigel would understand. Rigel wasn't afraid of anything. Of course he didn't comprehend how fear could motivate people to prioritize themselves over others, even unnecessarily so. It was basic instinct, not something rational that you could change about the world. People would always shun the monsters and embrace the ordinary.

"I'd heard about this place, but I've never been here," Rigel said, looking at the shack once more. "Seeing it…I wonder how it would have felt. Remus was our age—younger, the first time he was brought here. A dark, lonely house that creaked in the wind. Waiting for the sun to go down and a monster to claw its way out from his own soul. Then waking up, alone and in pain, and wondering what he'd done the night before and waiting for someone to come collect him. Wondering if they would this time, or if they'd finally decide to just leave the monster be. Sometimes, when I encounter difficulties, I think of Remus, and I wonder if I would have had the strength that he did. Most werewolves bitten young don't live to adulthood, you know."

"I didn't," Draco said, feeling distinctly uncomfortable. If he'd ever thought long about werewolves in the past, it had been in terms of whether he was ever likely to meet one on a full moon. He certainly hadn't thought about what life was like from a werewolf's point of view; he hadn't ever thought about how a werewolf became that way, except in the academic sense. It made him realize that he could become a werewolf, easily, if he were unlucky enough to be caught and bitten. That thought bred an automatic fear that he had difficulty channeling into objective caution; his instinct was to avoid thinking about werewolves at all.

"The curse is hardest on the mind, and children are weak-willed and weak-minded, generally speaking," Rigel said flatly. "In most cases the child either gives into the wolf and goes completely feral or dies in the violence of the struggle to remain human. Whenever I find life difficult or aggravating I remind myself that I have suffered nothing, compared to some."

Draco made a noncommittal noise, really out of his depth in the conversation now. He didn't spend inordinate amounts of time thanking Fate for the lot he'd been handed. Somehow, he was deserving of it—or, that's what had been implied. He was a Malfoy, after all. It wasn't accident, but providence that he should be so favored. Rigel's depressing self-deprecation couldn't go unremarked, however.

"You're a good person, Rigel," Draco told him, utterly serious. "You work hard, get all you can out of every moment, and do your best at everything you take on. I don't think you can ask more of yourself than that. It's not a bad thing that you haven't suffered—it's a good thing, and you should be glad of the life you live. If you don't appreciate it, then…then it is wasted, right?"

Rigel mused for a long moment, then turned to Draco with a soft smile. "Yeah. You're right—I should appreciate what I have more, instead of worrying if I'm somehow less because I've avoided hardships that others may experience."

Draco thought it odd that Rigel had said 'avoided' instead of something like 'not been subjected to,' but he ignored that in favor of putting a solicitous hand on Rigel's shoulder. "The past was shitty, Rigel. For a lot of people. The future will be better." It ought to be, anyway, with everyone alive having already inherited the world of those who came before them. Draco had always thought that the present was naturally better than the past. It was inevitable, in many ways. They wouldn't even have to try that hard—it was like strolling along a garden path; each step came organically, easily, a continuation of the step that came before. Nothing strenuous or difficult about it, in the grand scheme of things. He didn't get why people got so worked up about changing the world, come to that. Change was always happening, with or without people's help. It was halting change that was the real challenge. His father was always lamenting the pervasive, inconsiderate march of 'progress.'

"I suppose you're right," Rigel said at length. "I'm being overly somber, aren't I? My apologies, Draco. This wasn't what I intended by coming here. It's just I've heard so many stories…being here sort of brought them to life, you know?"

"Sure," Draco said easily. "There's a portrait in my father's private office of my great great great grandmother, and when I was seven she told me that she strangled a Ministry official with her bare hands in the blue salon. I've never been able to walk past that room without shuddering."

Rigel let out a mildly horrified laugh, and the tension was broken at last. "Why did she strangle him?"

"Her," Draco said, grimacing a bit. "Apparently my ancestor suspected the witch of conspiring to bear a Malfoy bastard. The claim was never substantiated of course—mostly because the witch never got a word out."

Rigel was suddenly very disturbed, so Draco hurriedly changed the subject. "Let's get back to the village. We can get a butterbeer and you can tell me how you've managed to show so much improvement in Dueling this semester—did you spend the whole winter break practicing, or what?"

They spent the rest of the morning walking and talking and generally just wasting time. Draco hadn't been so amused in a long while—his friend's dry wit and semi-caustic opinions almost made him forget that the day had a plan. Almost.

They had lunch in the Three Broomsticks, and afterwards Draco began to subtly press Rigel into admitting that he had somewhere to be. "I wouldn't mind splitting up for a while, I mean, if you needed to get some errands run."

"I don't really have anything besides going to the apothecary on my list," Rigel said, looking entirely nonchalant. Draco didn't believe it for a moment—he hadn't gone this long without sneaking off for a moment all week. Whatever his secret was, he knew it needed some kind of…maintenance or something. Any moment now, Rigel would make his excuses.

"Right, the apothecary," Draco said, working to keep a knowing smile of his face. "I suppose you wouldn't mind if I tagged along."

"Of course not," Rigel said, eyebrows rising. "I suppose it might be sort of boring for you, though. If you have something else you want to do, I'd understand."

A-ha! Rigel's face was calm but Draco had felt a subtle thrill go through his friend as he spoke. He was hoping Draco wouldn't want to accompany him, for whatever reason. Well, he wouldn't make it hard on his friend, he thought with a smirk.

"I'll just run to the sweet shop then, shall I?" Draco said casually.

"All right," Rigel said. "Will you pick me up a licorice wand?"

Draco mentally cursed. His friend was crafty, making sure Draco really would have to go to Honeydukes if he wanted to make his story believable. No matter. Rigel would be in the same position, having to really go to the apothecary to throw Draco off his scent, which meant Draco had time to run and get a couple of sweets before getting down to the serious business of ferreting out Rigel's secret.

They parted ways, and Draco hurried through the packed streets until he spotted a group of students coming out of Honeydukes with bags full to bursting. "Hey, do you guys have any licorice wands?" he asked quickly.

One of them, a sandy-haired boy with lots of freckles, clutched his bag possessively. Bingo.

"What did you pay for it?" Draco asked. "I'll give you double."

His eyes went wide, and he glanced between Draco and his friends, torn. "I waited in line forever, though…."

"Triple," Draco snapped. "For the licorice wand and one other sweet."

The boy sighed forlornly. "Okay. It's a deal."

They exchanged goods quickly, and Draco ducked into a relatively deserted side street to pull out the 'map' that had come in the package with the teacher tracker. It was a mostly blank piece of paper with a black dot in the center and a series of rings set up like ripples around it. Each successive ring had a different value of distance noted next to it, and at the top right there was a crude compass designating North. When he said the activation phrase, the tracker in Rigel's shoe would show up as a red dot on the map, which would move around in relation to the center dot—a bit like a radar system that only showed one thing.

More excited than he would care to admit, Draco whispered the activation phrase and waited with baited breath for the dot to appear. It winked into existence slowly, a little unsurely, not far from where Draco was standing—which made sense, since he wouldn't have had time to go very far yet. What didn't make sense was the way another dot blinked into existence a heartbeat later, much further away from the center dot and the other red dot. Then, a moment after that, yet another dot appeared, closer to the second but separate enough to be distinct. He frowned down at the map, confused.

He began walking experimentally, and all three dots moved relative to his position, just as they should. Why was it defective? Did the map pick up all teacher trackers in the vicinity? That was annoying. And actually, there should be many more dots if that were the case. There were about twenty on the shelves of Zonko's alone. Maybe it only showed trackers that had been activated. That was still a rather obnoxious design flaw.

At least he could be reasonably sure that the dot closest to him was Rigel. He began tracking that one, not noticing until he was nearly on top of it that the map had led him straight back to the apothecary. Maybe he was going to run his 'errand' first, and then sneak off? Draco settled into the alley across from the apothecary to wait.

Fifteen minutes later, he was bored, and twenty-five minutes later he was annoyed out of his mind. What was Rigel doing that was taking so long? Wasn't he in a hurry to get to wherever he had been sneaking off to? Draco was sure he would see Rigel meeting up with a mysteriously cloaked stranger who was extorting him for money or else an older, more experienced paramour who was too embarrassed by Rigel's age to be seen in public with him…

He looked down at the map again, but the dot he thought was Rigel was stubbornly in the same exact spot. He began to get uneasy. What if the map didn't work at all? What if Rigel had left his shoes behind? No, that was ridiculous. Rigel loved those shoes. And yet…what was he doing? No one could possibly spend so long picking out potions ingredients. Not even Rigel. And what about that thrill of eager anticipation Draco had felt? He just had to be up to something.

Draco's toes were starting to get cold, and he was sick of standing in the same alley without anything exciting happening. How did professional spies do it? They had to have more sophisticated methods of keeping track of people. He bet no real spy ever had to wait outside in the bitter elements for over an hour while their mark tried out all the cauldrons in the store or whatever Rigel was doing.

Finally getting fed up, he crumpled the map in his pocket and stormed into the store. He found Rigel standing in front of a shelf of newt parts, a stupid smile on his face as he looked back and forth between a jar in his left hand and a packet in his right.

"Rigel," Draco said, exasperated, "Have you been here the whole time?"

Rigel blinked at him in mild confusion. "It's only been…" He glanced at the clock behind the register. "Twenty minutes, Draco. Did you have somewhere to be?"

It was all Draco could do not to strangle his infuriatingly oblivious friend. Twenty minutes? As if. He felt like he'd been standing out there for hours. "It's fine," he grit out, suppressing an eye twitch with difficulty.

"I'm almost done," Rigel said, voice apologetic now. "Here, what do you think—should I get the single-wrapped newts or the bulk-packaged one? The bulk ones are better quantity per Knut, of course, but they sometimes slip some shoddy quality newts in with the good ones…"

"What difference does quality make in newts?" Draco asked.

"The eyes, mostly," Rigel said, "Sometimes if the newt died under stress the eyes are strained or damaged."

"If you get bad eyes on a few can you still use the rest of the newt?" Draco said.

"Yes…" Rigel said slowly, "I suppose I could just buy a small container of eyes, in addition to the bulk-packaged newts. That's probably still cheaper than buying a bunch of individually packaged newts. Thanks Draco." Rigel smiled like he'd just solved Merlin's Paradox. Draco did not immediately forgive the boy for wasting his time.

As Rigel paid for his ingredients and the two of them started back toward the castle, Draco heaved a mental sigh of disappointment. It looked like his friend was more wily than he'd thought. He was a Slytherin, for all that sometimes he seemed more like a Ravenclaw. He supposed it was only right that it be hard to catch him out. Still, Draco had all semester. He would leave the tracker in Rigel's shoe, even if it did seem to be a bit glitchy. Eventually, he would figure out what had his friend so secretive.

That is, more secretive than usual.

Rigel had no idea what was making Draco act so oddly while they were in Hogsmeade, but she was ready for an hour or so of quiet when she got back to the castle. She left the common room, which was pretty rowdy that Saturday, in favor of heading to the Library, where quiet was guaranteed thanks to Madam Pince's stringently consistent enforcement habits.

She had been planning to read some more of Dumbledore's handwritten 'textbook' that afternoon, but when she caught sight of Ginny scribbling away at a corner table she was reminded of a question she'd been meaning to ask the girl. Rigel made her way over and waited patiently while Ginny finished the paragraph she was working on.

"To what do I owe this honor?" the redhead said, propping her chin on one hand in a parody of interest.

"Do you have a minute?" Rigel asked. "I wanted to get your thoughts on something I'm working on."

"I suppose," Ginny said, clearing her parchment and quill off to the side. "It's not like this Charms essay was going to win any awards."

"I'm sure it's very good," Rigel said politely.

"I'm sure you're full of crap, like usual." Ginny smiled sweetly.

Ignoring her confrontational conversational style, Rigel sat across from the girl. "How is your Occlumency coming along, if I may ask?"

Immediately, she was on guard. "Why?"

"I've been working on mine, and I'm having creative difficulties," Rigel admitted. "I wondered if I could pick your brain for new ideas."

Ginny shrugged, relaxing a little. "As long as you aren't doing so literally, sure. What's up?"

"Well," Rigel said slowly, aware that this was a delicate topic for the second-year. "When that construct had you imprisoned in your mind—"

"Careful, Rigel," Ginny said sharply.

"Pretend it was the other way around," Rigel said quickly. "Imagine you were trying to imprison something—him, or anything similar, really—in your mind."

"Why?" Ginny frowned, looking uncomfortable.

"Just for the sake of the exercise," Rigel said, shrugging off the question for the moment. "How would you do it? I mean, you have experience being on the other end of it, so I thought you would have good ideas on what you would do. What kinds of safeguards you would put into place, that kind of thing."

"Rigel. What. Are. You. Doing?" Ginny leaned forward and lowered her voice. "If you're trying to build your own construct I will personally poke your idiot eyes out."

"I'm not," Rigel promised. "It's—remember I talked to you last year about building a guardian for my mind? Something semi-autonomous that would take the place of active Occlumency in a pinch?"

"I remember telling you it was a terrible idea," Ginny hissed. "Have you learned nothing?"

"I have," Rigel said, mildly offended. "I've put lots of restrictions on it, based on what I've learned. And that's why I'm asking you—to see what you learned, and if it's different than what I thought of."

Ginny looked sour, but said, "What have you done so far?"

"Well," Rigel said, a bit excited to be talking about her personal project with someone else, "I've already got a form for it—kind of a hollow shell that I'm planning on making autonomous—"

"How?" Ginny broke in, frowning fiercely.

"I'll get to that," Rigel said, "It's theoretical. Anyway, I gave the construct a form like a human, so that it could move around the mindscape, and fool an intruder into thinking it was me if necessary. I knew there were areas that I didn't want it to have access to, though, in case it could be influenced by an intruder and, I don't know, turned against me or something. So I altered the defenses around other areas of my mind, specifically those containing my magic, my consciousness, and my memories. I figured there wasn't much damage it could do to me, that way, but it would still be able to fight off anything that came into my mind from the outside."

Ginny nodded slowly. "That's good. But you can't only think of yourself. The mists aren't only an entrance—they can be an exit, too. That's how real Legilimens get in and out of other people's heads. If you're going to create something even potentially dangerous, you better make sure it can't leave your head and get into someone else's."

Rigel blinked, taken aback by that idea. "I didn't think of that at all. I don't know Legilimency…do you really think something I created would have any way of figuring it out if I don't have the knowledge myself?"

"You said you were making it semi-autonomous," Ginny said, eyebrows lifted challengingly. "Doesn't that mean a basic level of sentience?"

"You're right," Rigel frowned. "I'll have to build a perimeter of some kind to keep it in. That will take some time, but maybe I can work it into a first line of defense to keep others out, too. That would be fairly efficient."

"What about the parts of your mind that control physical movement?" Ginny asked. "It might be able to control your body even if your consciousness was out of its reach."

Rigel considered that. "The physical ties to the body are all over the mindscape. I couldn't block off its access to all of them without severely limiting its usefulness. I don't think it would be able to take over my body if my consciousness was free, though—I have the stronger tie to my physical self than an outside presence, after all."

"It isn't an outside presence," Ginny said pointedly. "It'll be an extension of you, right?"

"Exactly," Rigel said, "A part of me. I think it's unlikely to try and do anything that might destroy itself."

"Don't make the mistake of thinking you can trust all the parts of yourself," Ginny said darkly. "You're a teenager. Inevitably there will be parts of you that are dumb, self-absorbed, and contemplate world domination."

Rigel winced. She wanted to say 'not every teenaged Slytherin boy is like Tom Riddle,' but she wasn't sure Ginny would believe her. That, and her concerns weren't exactly unfounded. Just because she personally didn't have any interest in power or subjugation didn't mean a semi-sentient creation might not develop its own interests.

"I'll just have to make sure it's not an independent entity," she said, thinking hard. "Tie it to my will, so that even if it can think for itself, it can't do anything contrary to what I want. How to design something like that, though…"

"Tie it to your commands, not just your will," Ginny suggested, also deep in thought. "Sometimes your desires can be conflicting, and that might give it leeway somehow. Make it so that it can only act within the perimeter of specific jobs or orders you give it. It can still respond creatively, but only along a prescribed track of goal-oriented behavior. And make it logically consistent, so that it can't respond to the command 'protect my mind' in any way except ones that will ultimately protect your mind. Make sense?"

"Yes," Rigel said, tapping her fingers on the table idly. "I'll have to design a whole chain of commands, to keep it appropriately bound. It will take time, but I can probably borrow from other sources. Typical formats for magical oaths, maybe. And records of command sequences others have used. Semi-sentient objects aren't that uncommon, after all."

"Except most people don't make them in their own heads." Ginny rolled her eyes. "I still think this is a bad idea, but I'm not your moth—" She froze for half an instant after saying that, half-poised to apologize for the slip, but apparently decided to just keep going instead. "Well. You should ask Percy for help, if you're determined to be stupid. He's been studying all kinds of Wizarding law this year, looking into future career options. Barristers have to come up with airtight contracts all the time, right? He should be able to help with the wording, once you get what you want figured out."

"Good idea," Rigel said, making a mental note to do just that. She really wanted this project to work. She had so many theories about how mental magic operated, and so many things she wanted to try, if she could get this up and running. For instance, could she treat the construct like a second consciousness, of sorts? Give it selective information and then ask it to solve a particular problem? That would be fascinating. She'd be able to simulate an objective opinion inside her own head. And what if she could store data in the construct, like a back-up brain in case one of her memories was Obliviated? The possibilities were endless, really.

"How are you going to give it sentience, anyway?" Ginny asked, reluctantly curious. "It takes years sometimes to design sentience spells complex enough to seem life-like."

Rigel smiled, "I have an interesting theory, actually. You know how when magical folk give birth a tiny part of the mother's core breaks off and grows into the child's core? I think maybe I could take a piece of my raw magic and put it into the construct. Magic has a certain amount of its own willpower, so that, combined with complex command chains, might be enough to give it its own sort of impetus."

"Wild magic may have its own will sometimes, but the magic in you has only your will," Ginny said, frowning slightly. "I think that would only give you a vessel that you could command with your will…which now that I think of it would actually be pretty useful. You might get good enough at controlling it that you wouldn't have to be meditating to direct it, which means it could be doing some activity that normally you would have to be present in your mind to accomplish. There aren't many tasks like that, but you could direct it to build something, maybe…" Ginny shrugged, looking bored again. "Let me know if you get anywhere with it. I've got to get back to my essay."

Rigel thanked her for all her help and left her to it. She had a lot to think about, but she was feeling optimistic. The experimenter in her couldn't wait to see if her theories panned out. She reminded herself that she couldn't let her enthusiasm outpace her caution, but couldn't bring herself to be too worried. Talking to Ginny had only cemented the idea that, with the proper precautions, getting her construct up and running was a project worth her energy.

After Madam Pomfrey had heard what happened at the New Year's Eve gala, her Healing classes had taken on an intensity that had previously been absent. The older woman had muttered something uncomplimentary about young people who thought they were fully qualified at something just because they'd read a few books on the subject and determined that if Rigel was going to be Healing real people so much sooner than the nurse had anticipated, then at least no one would be able to say she hadn't taught him well.

As such, her lessons had been running longer than usual, with Pomfrey packing as much information into each session as the madam possibly could. The nurse had also taken to insisting that Rigel practice on human subjects when it was possible, as in the case of diagnostic spells and charms.

Unfortunately, that was also where they ran into a bit of a snag.

"You cannot understand what the reading should look like if you haven't seen it on a healthy person," Madam Pomfrey said, exasperated. "This Charm in much more in-depth than the ones we've been working with, and that means the information it gives is both more complicated and harder to interpret correctly."

"I've already cast it on you," Rigel said, a stubborn tilt to her chin.

"And now you must cast it on yourself," Pomfrey said, hands on her hips. "A male reading differs on a number of levels from a female's. There will be differences due to our different ages and medical histories, too, and it's important that you be able to pinpoint where in the output they occur."

"I don't want to," Rigel said, trying to be as firm as possible.

"Why on earth not?" Pomfrey finally demanded. She frowned at Rigel's silence, adding, in a softer tone, "What on earth is wrong, child?"

"I just don't want to," Rigel said, shrugging uncomfortably. "Don't I have a right to refuse? Doesn't any patient?" she added, attempting to look at least a little less suspicious.

"Yes, of course," Pomfrey sighed, "But why?"

"It's personal," Rigel said, unblinking. "What would I do, then, if a patient refused to be diagnosed?"

"That is an interesting question," Pomfrey said, allowing herself to be distracted with a modicum of grace. "It depends on what, exactly, the patient has refused—the diagnostic spell itself, or treatment in general."

"People can refuse treatment?" Rigel said, surprised. "I mean, for optional operations, sure, but for life-saving procedures?"

"They can." She did not look at all approving of such a thing. "Any patient has the right to refuse any or all aspects of Healing, even if it would save their life. The only exception is when the patient is with child. In some cases, the parent would not have the option to refuse Healing that would benefit the child, as long as it created no risk to the carrier."

"What about children themselves?" Rigel asked.

"Children cannot refuse care until they are eleven—old enough to have a wand, old enough to self-determine matters of their own health, or so says the law," Madam Pomfrey explained. The disgruntlement was clear in her tone as she said, "As a Mediwizard you must bow to the wishes of your patients, even if it is not the course of action you would endorse."

Rigel laughed quietly. "You don't bow much to the whims of your patients, if I may say so, Madam."

Pomfrey sniffed. "My patients sometimes don't speak loudly enough for me to hear. And many of them don't know that they have the right to refuse, poor dears."

"Were you a Slytherin?" Rigel asked, amused.

"I'll never tell," she said primly. "Now come. You can do the charm again on me, if you insist, and I will attempt to explain where the differences would be. Some areas of information you must ignore, as they are not applicable to male anatomy…"

The lesson went on as though nothing unusual had occurred, but Rigel could feel the older woman's eyes on her through the rest of her instruction. Madam Pomfrey might have let the matter go, but she would not, Rigel suspected, forget it. She would have to be especially careful around the matron, from now on.

It was early March before her insistent stalking of Peter Pettigrew bore fruit. She was finishing up an essay for Flint in the Room of Requirement, with the intention to spend the night there, as a pervious version of herself was already sleeping in her dorm room. She'd taken the habit of checking the Marauder's Map every so often just to check up on the professor, and this time caught sight of him heading for the Library.

It was a couple of hours past closing, but that was not unusual for Pettigrew. He spent inordinate amounts of time reading in the Restricted Section—if you could call paging feverishly through tables of contents reading, at least. Rigel ought to know, as it wouldn't be the first time she'd followed him there to try and get a look at what books he was looking through. So far, she didn't know anything except that Pettigrew didn't appear to have any idea what he was looking for. That, or he was completely pants at research of any kind.

She put aside the essay and fished out her invisibility cloak, pulling it on with a tired yawn and promising herself she'd sleep a full ten hours that night. The halls were silent as she made her way toward the Library, avoiding ghosts and patrolling prefects deftly. The door to the Library was unlocked, as Pettigrew was there before her, so all she had to do was sneak in quietly and close it soundlessly behind her. The trick would be getting out before Pettigrew re-locked it. The other night she was almost certain he'd felt the displacement of air as she slipped out just behind him.

Pettigrew carried a fairly bright lamp to read by, so it wasn't particularly difficult to see where he was. By the books on magical compulsions again, she thought. She was coming to know the layout of the Restricted Section rather well, from all the hopping around Pettigrew did while she observed him. He was sweating slightly in the light of the lamp as he shakily turned page after page, muttering anxiously to himself as he was wont to.

After a short time, he sighed despairingly with a murmured, "No, no, no. This isn't it at all." He re-shelved the book and selected another from the same section, seemingly at random. Did he honestly expect that to work? That he'd somehow just come across the answer by luck or through sheer probability if he searched through enough books?

The short man looked so hopelessly lost that she almost felt sorry for him. A sound from the hallway outside the Library echoed through the dark stacks just then, and Pettigrew froze completely like a frightened animal, clearly spooked. He hastily grabbed an armful of books at random and began scurrying toward the door. Rigel followed silently, wondering how this man had gotten up the gumption to put himself in opposition to such powerful people when he was afraid of his own shadow. He seemed pathetically inept to her.

She shook her head in silent self-admonishment. She should know better than to judge by a person's appearance. For all she knew, his bumbling fool routine was an act. Pettigrew's foot caught in the hem of his robe and he sprawled noisily, books tumbling to the floor. In his scramble to pick them up, his knee became tangled in his shoulder bag, and the moment he attempted to stand, the seam split and papers fluttered into the air around his dismayed expression of stupor.

It could be a very good act, she supposed dubiously as the man fumbled and muttered as he attempted to collect all the books and papers that had spilled. Halfway through, he realized he ought to repair his bag first, and had to put everything down and start again. Rigel shifted her focus impatiently, feeling slightly rude while watching him crawl around so piteously.

Her gaze caught onto a piece of parchment covered in scribbled notes, which had floated, unnoticed by Pettigrew, a fair distance further than the other papers. Holding her breath, she crept forward slowly until she was right next to it, then lifted the cloak just enough to drop it quickly over the stray parchment before Pettigrew noticed it. There was a slight rustling noise, but when the Creatures professor looked over fearfully, he didn't seem to see anything amiss.

He stuffed all the papers away into his newly-repaired bag and left at something close to a run, books encumbering him so much that he appeared not to bother locking the Library behind him. Sloppy, Rigel thought as she bent to pick up her prize and slip it into her pocket. She locked the door herself on her way out, and made her way quickly back to the Come and Go Room.

Once situated comfortably, she took out the scrap of notes that she'd claimed and swiftly perused it. There was a passage of some kind written out shakily at the top of the parchment. It looked like prose of some kind, or perhaps a poem. Underneath, and filling up the edges of every margin, was a collection of scribbled notes and half-formed ideas that were apparently Pettigrew's attempts to decipher the paragraph at the top. Wondering what had been so important for him to figure out, Rigel began to read the passage carefully.

If Dominion is desired, domination is required

~ere the moment be expired

To reach for selfsame power is to see Creation cower

~or to find oneself devoured.

The birds and beasts and flowers will conspire through the hours

~to contend these rising powers

So if supremacy you seek, look to reign beyond the weak

~else your Destiny be bleak

Master yourself; master the other,

Take control or be took by another

Keep Power alive, yet under control;

Dominion will answer, transforming the soul

Ascend and rule, but bear the cost

Beware what comes of power lost

She rubbed her eyes tiredly after reading it through twice. Well that wasn't cryptic at all, she thought sourly. She'd always found riddles incredibly annoying. She preferred less oblique means of communication, herself. She could start with the structure, though—there was something about the rhyme scheme that she thought was important. She looked tiredly over the passage, noting the two juxtaposed meter systems and counting the lines in each. Four lines of tripled rhymes followed by three rhyming couplets. Seven rhyming units total—a number of power, the Arithmancy student in her noted. Where had she heard about magical prose? Sometime talking to Pansy, she thought, wracking her mind for the memory. Her blonde friend had mentioned the importance of rhyming schemes in relation to one of her homework assignments. It hadn't been an assignment she shared with Rigel, which meant it was for one of her other extracurricular classes. But which one? Divination or Care of Magical Creatures?

After a sleepy attempt to recall the details of the brief conversation, she remembered where she was and asked the Room politely for a book on the technical aspects of magical poems and prose. An incredibly dense tome landed in her lap with a cloud of dust that sent her into a brief sneezing fit.

Rigel paged through the book to the chapter that dealt with identifying pieces of magical literature by their structure. She skipped over the sections on identifying spells, chants, vows, summonings, and various other rituals, eventually finding a section on divination that looked promising.

It was a prophecy, she groaned in belated realization, or something very close to one. It followed exactly the pattern said by the book to be favored by centaurean foretellers. According to the short paragraph the author offered on the seven-part rhyme scheme, it wasn't a true prediction of the future—more a prophetic collection of knowledge pertaining to an unknown subject. Centaurs weren't as reliable as human Seers when it came to predicting specific moments or events, but they could read general information on a broad range of topics from the stars. Still…where had Pettigrew found such a passage? As far as Rigel knew, centaurs rarely gave prophetic advice to wizards, and, unlike human Seers, almost never consented to their predictions being recorded. Even the book she had open on her knees referenced the rhyming structure as an oral pattern of conveyance.

The bed in the corner of the room was calling to her, but she knew she should at least make an attempt to figure the passage out before going to bed. It would only keep her awake if she didn't. It was definitely about the Dominion Jewel; aside from the fact that she'd taken it from Pettigrew, who couldn't be researching anything else, the word Dominion was capitalized on the paper.

Wait…if it was a centaur foretelling, then how would there be capitalized words? Were they arbitrary, or a true reflection of the inflection given by the original speaker? Rigel supposed ruefully she had no way of knowing, so she would take the capitals as important on faith, for now.

Scanning the verses for any other obvious conclusions, she grimaced slightly. There was a lot of mention of controlling things and dominating and mastering and reigning…that didn't bode well. Neither did the ominous warnings about being devoured and the explicit mention of cost. In her experience any magic that referenced sacrifice so blatantly was either powerful, dangerous, or a potent combination of both.

All right, let's take it line by line, she thought with resignation. Why couldn't Pettigrew have accidentally dropped a passage with very explicit directions on how to neutralize the jewel's power, or maybe a map to where he was hiding it?

The part about desiring Dominion seemed clear enough—it was introducing the requirements for using the jewel. Domination being necessary wasn't entirely surprising, though she had to wonder if Pettigrew met that qualification at all. The 'moment be expired' part was promising, too—if there was some kind of time limit, then maybe Pettigrew wouldn't be able to gain the power he sought before it was reached. He had looked pretty panicked for time while going through Library books.

Creation in capitalized form probably just meant 'everything,' she supposed, and she didn't like the dichotomy the second line seemed to be setting up. Make everything cower before you or end up devoured yourself? What an awful set of alternatives. The 'birds, beasts, and flowers' part was obvious—even Pettigrew hade made a note in the margins about how the creatures around Hogwarts had reacted to its use. So they, at least, recognized the power the jewel offered as a negative thing. That in itself should dissuade anyone from trying to use it, Rigel thought. Magical creatures rarely agreed upon anything, and that was when they involved themselves outside of their own communities in the first place.

The 'so' in the line directly after that worried her, though. It seemed to indicate a continuation of the line before it, which would put the birds, beasts, and flowers in direct juxtaposition to the 'weak.' What did that mean? That one should only reign over strong magical creatures? Or that it would not be enough to reign over weak things? She supposed it would bely the whole 'dominion' idea if the wielder settled for using it on petty things, but why would that be important enough to include in the verse?

'Master yourself; master the other,' she read again. But was that sequential or conditional? Which were you supposed to do first? Take control or have it taken by another—that seemed like a warning that if you didn't use the jewel someone else might. What a power-hungry, paranoid thing to worry about.

She had no idea what keeping power alive meant, nor why that mention of power in particular was capitalized. As far as she knew you couldn't 'kill' power. The next line about the jewel actually transforming the soul of the one who used it was equally ominous. That made it sound like the jewel had a deep effect on the one who used it. The last couplet wasn't any better—bearing the cost was in line with what she knew about truly powerful magic, but she would have thought the warning would be about the dangers and responsibilities that come with power, not about what might happen if you lost the power.

There was so much vagueness about power and control in different forms. It almost seemed like a general warning against being weak—without any concrete information on how to actually use the jewel. Judging by the disjointed, frustrated notes all over the page, that fact had been infuriating Pettigrew to no end.

Her brain was protesting violently in the form of a headache that throbbed in time with her heartbeat, so Rigel set the parchment carefully aside and decided to call it a night. She could pour over it more tomorrow, for all the good it would do her. She wasn't any closer to getting the proof she needed. How nice it would have been if Pettigrew put his name in the upper-right corner of all his notes like Theo did. Chuckling a bit at the image of the beady-eyed man carefully signing all his incriminating research notes, Rigel drifted off into a deep, bone-weary sleep.

With Hermione's recent and rather persistent habit of considering looks, leading questions, and expectant expressions, Archie had seen this confrontation coming for a while. He'd been dreading it, fully aware that she'd somehow become suspicious of something, but unable to redirect her conclusions without being able to figure out what she thought she knew.

Nothing he'd imagined in all his panicked scenarios had prepared him for this, however.

They were outside at their usual spot, and Archie was sure that if he hadn't already been sitting on the grass beneath their shady tree, he would have fallen over in shock. "You…come again?"

"I said I know, Harry," Hermione said, somehow looking both apologetic and impatient at once. "I know you're a girl."

"I'm…not," Archie tried, weakly. Her accusation, while false and somewhat humorous, still betrayed a dangerous amount of knowledge—how could she have come to that conclusion without knowing something?

Hermione sighed, and managed to summon a very disappointed look that Archie was pretty sure they only taught people with small children. "I've known for months. I've been waiting for you to tell me, but I realized you weren't ever going to, so…so I'm telling you now."

"Months?" Archie croaked. "How, uh, exactly did you come to this conclusion?"

"My parents got me a subscription to the Daily Prophet for Christmas," Hermione said, gazing pityingly at him, as though he ought to have guessed how she knew. "I saw the article they did on the gala the Sow Party hosted. It said that someone had almost died there, and then mentioned that your dad was head of the Minister's security detail. I was perplexed, because it went on to say that Auror Potter's own daughter was one of the two people who saved the life of the man who was attacked. I was so confused, Harry, because I knew you had a little sister but you'd never mentioned any other siblings." Hermione was rambling now, the words spilling out quickly and almost pleadingly. "I went to the British Ministry and tried to look up some information about your dad, thinking maybe he had a child from a previous marriage you hadn't told me about, only they don't let citizens access Ministry personnel records, apparently, so I had to go to through the individual genealogy records kept by the Ministry's Department of Magical Heritage –did you know your family is in the Book of Gold?" The last was said with a demanding glare, which Archie was too distracted to cower appropriately before.

"Yes," he said, swallowing roughly. "Those records aren't always updated correctly, though—"

"Don't bother," Hermione huffed. "Even after I saw your entry written as Harriett Potter in the Book of Gold, I wasn't entirely certain. So I went to the Bureau of Magical Land Management and talked my way into looking at the estate records by saying I was doing very important research about the conservation of folded space for Wizarding Wildlife."

"You shouldn't lie to Ministry officials," Archie croaked.

"Don't you dare talk to me about lying right now, Harry," Hermione hissed. "Guess who the Potter Estate is currently entailed to? The Heiress Harriett Potter, eldest daughter to the current Lord." She folded her arms triumphantly and waited with raised eyebrows for him to collect his thoughts.

It wasn't a disaster. She hadn't accused him of anything awful, yet, like being someone else entirely. So she knew Harry was a girl. Harry was a girl, and it wasn't like that was really a secret—back home, anyway. Looking at her pouting lips, Archie suspected Hermione was more concerned with the idea that he'd been lying to her for two and a half years than with wondering why.

"That's very impressive deducing," Archie offered, smiling in a transparent attempt to lighten the air between them.

Hermione's face only darkened. "You lied to me, Harry. To everyone here. Do you know how stupid I felt once I'd figured it out?"

"You're not stupid," Archie exclaimed, feeling suddenly awful.

"I know that," Hermione snapped, "And yet I somehow missed all the signs leading up to this. How your letters were always addressed to Harriett, how you had to explain to even the teachers at the beginning of first year that your dad was just playing a joke on them—but he wasn't, this whole time. You were the one playing the joke."

"It wasn't a joke," he said quietly.

"And how you never invited me over to meet your family or let me stay to meet them at the airport, even though you've met mine half a dozen times," Hermione went on, working herself up into a real rant. He supposed she'd been bottling it in for a while. "And how you flirt outrageously with everyone you meet because you're overcompensating for the fact that you're not really a boy."

Archie didn't suppose she was in the mood to hear that that was a genuine part of his personality.

"Were you ever going to tell me?" Hermione asked, her eyes slightly wet with suppressed hurt. Archie had never felt more a cad, but he didn't know how he could fix things without jeopardizing everything he and Harry had been working for. If it was just his dream…maybe he could give it up for Hermione's friendship and understanding. Harry's dreams were everything to her, though. He could never betray their ruse like that. Not even for his best friend. Somehow, he would have to improvise and hope that Hermione was as wonderful as he thought she was.

"I didn't want you to think of me like that," Archie said after some quick thinking. The only way out of this was to invoke Hermione's sense of compassion. "If I told you I was a girl, pretending to be a boy, you'd always treat me as some kind of imposter, instead of understanding who I really am."

"You…" Hermione's concentration was beautiful as she tried to follow the trail he was laying down. "You don't identify as a girl?"

"It's always been a struggle for me to feel like I belonged in my own skin," Archie said, trying to squash the feeling of incredibly guilt he felt at misleading her like this. "I thought, coming here, it would be like a fresh start. I could be the person I want to be, instead of who I was born." That much, at least, was true. And Harry was a bit of a tomboy, so he wasn't stretching reality too much.

"Don't you think it would be better to come to terms with yourself, rather than try and suppress parts of it?" Hermione asked, frowning concernedly now. That was good, he told himself. If she was worried about him she would be less likely to think up more sinister reasons he might have for hiding his gender.

"I've been working on it," he lied. Time to set some groundwork—and wouldn't Harry be proud? She was always telling him to think ahead. "Maybe one day I can go back to being a girl. For now, though…I'm more comfortable like this. Does it really bother you so much?"

"It bothers me that you lied about it," Hermione said, eyes narrowed. He could tell most of her anger had bled away once she felt she had an adequate explanation, though. "Have you even talked with your parents about it?"

"Not…exactly," Archie grimaced. That would certainly be awkward.

"Well you should," Hermione said firmly. "It's not healthy to bottle things up like this. I'm sure your parents would understand and work through it with you—this is actually very common, you know. I've read about it in several reputable psychology books."

"Of course you have," Archie said, smiling fondly.

"I must say, I didn't consider that you might actually feel more comfortable this way," Hermione said, frowning. "I should have thought of it. I was thinking maybe you'd done it as a big joke, or maybe as some sort of attempt to avoid sexist discrimination in the future—I know you've mentioned there's some unfairness in certain Wizarding industries still—and I was prepared to lecture you sternly on how wrong it is to avoid the issue yourself while everyone else in your situation is still subjected to unfairness, because you have to fight for change, of course, but…well, I'm glad that wasn't it," Hermione finished, smiling sheepishly.

Archie kept a bland expression on his face through force of will, but he could feel his insides curling up in shame. Hermione's assessment had been, once again, too close for comfort. He could only imagine how angry and disappointed she would be if she knew that he was doing exactly what she'd feared—and worse, because the issue he and Harry were skirting was blood prejudice, which Hermione already felt very strongly about fighting against.

It amazed him, how mature she was. The idea that their duplicity tacitly endorsed the unfair system they were circumventing in the first place would have never occurred to Archie without someone pointing it out, but of course it was far too late to do anything about it now. He would just have to look for other ways to atone, if he could. Perhaps once he was himself again, he could use what influence the Blacks had left to bolster Hermione's campaign.

"If I may ask," Hermione said after a moment, "How…how do you look like a boy? I can't see the girl in you even now that I know to look for it. Is that natural? Is this why you made me steal all the Polyjuice in first year? I still never saw you taking any. If it is natural, what are you going to do in a few years when you fill out and it'll be obvious to anyone—"

"Take a breath, 'Mione," Archie said, lips quirking a bit. If she was already starting to think of how he'd hide his gender in the future, then it looked like she was planning to stay friends after all. He wasn't sure he should tell her much more, at first, but then realized that if they were going to be friends till they graduated, it would be very suspicious to Hermione if he never started looking like a girl. "I…have to swear you to secrecy, Hermione," he said, lips tightening.

"Yeah, okay." Hermione rolled her eyes.

"I'm serious," Archie said. He held her gaze for a long second, to make sure she understood how earnest he was. "I won't make you swear a binding oath—"

"As if I would agree to something so reckless—"

"But you must promise me solemnly to never tell anyone what I'm about to tell you," he concluded.

Hermione bit her lip. "I suppose…you're not really hurting anyone…" Her expression revealed the furious debate taking place inside her head, but in the end she sighed gustily. "Fine, but after this you are not getting rid of me, Harriett Potter. We are in this together."

"Nothing would please me more," Archie said, smiling widely.

"Then… I promise not to tell anyone what you tell me about pretending to be a boy. I won't even tell anyone that you are pretending, if you don't want—though I maintain that you should talk to your parents about this," Hermione said.

"Noted," Archie said dryly. He gathered his courage, then said, "I'm a metamorph. It means I can—"

"I know what it is," Hermione breathed, eyes widening. "That's so rare, Harry! I read it was only common to a couple of Wizarding families."

"It runs in the Black line," Archie told her, "And my grandmother was a Black. I haven't told anyone, though—not my family, not anyone. But it's how I live as a boy."

"So…this isn't what you really look like?" Hermione asked, looking perturbed.

"Not really," Archie said wryly. She really had no idea.

"Hmm," she said, taking it in slowly. "It's almost a fateful coincidence that you would harbor such confusion about your inner self and then be given the means to manipulate your outer self, don't you think? Have there been studies of other metamorphmagi? Maybe the feeling uncomfortable in your skin thing is a side-effect of the ability, a natural adaptation of the brain, perhaps, or…well, I suppose I could look into it."

Archie was amazed, as always, at the way Hermione's brain worked.

"Just so you know, you could have told me sooner," Hermione said, tilting her head at him admonishingly. "My family happens to be very progressive."

"I'll keep that in mind," Archie laughed, fully relaxing at last. Everything was going to be okay. His relief lasted until he realized that Harry would have to be informed of this development. He could feel the blood draining from his face immediately. She was not going to like this. And somehow, he was certain, it would end up being his fault.

Chapter 13

Rigel wasn't sure why she'd thought that obtaining a prophecy on the subject of the Jewel would herald some progress on her understanding of the artifact; it hadn't seemed to do Pettigrew much good, if his continued late-night bumbling through the library was any indication. She'd had to give up following him around the narrow stacks about the third week in March—it was just too depressing. She reasoned that as long as he was in the library, he wasn't up to anything more nefarious than incompetent research methodology. It would serve her time better to begin her own research on the subject, she thought, and from then on she spent the time Pettigrew sweated over crumbling Dark Arts books deep in the history section, sure that the answer to the mysterious artifact lay in the past, not in pursuit of other, equally vague methods of dominion, as Pettigrew seemed to believe.

There just had to be some record of such a powerful artifact—if humans could be counted on to do one thing through the annals of history, it was to take advantage of dubious avenues of power. She believed absolutely that power attracted attention, and so she was far from surprised to find a series of oblique references to an artifact like the jewel in the oldest of historical records available. The trouble with ancient history, she found, was that truth was rarely separated from myth, and an accurate recounting often played second fiddle to an interesting story. Each new source she found seemed increasingly removed from the rigors of credentials that she was accustomed to in her usual research.

One particularly ambiguous account concerned the pharaoh Amenhotep I, who, according to one historian, had lived a modest life tending to his mother until he suddenly conspired to kill his two older brothers and ascend to the throne unopposed. Once in power, he waged war on surrounding nations with a tenacity that granted him the epithets "bull who conquers the lands" and "he who inspires great terror." His rule was apparently so awe-inducing that after his demise he was deified with cult-like fervor. This was not altogether unusual for ancient pharaohs, who didn't do much to keep their magical abilities from the eyes of their mostly muggle subjects, but the historian whose account Rigel was perusing argued that Amenhotep's success was owed to his having been in possession of the Dominion Jewel.

Part of his evidence for this came from the order given by Hatshepsut fifty years later to demolish Amenhotep's mortuary complex. The Egyptian queen's personal scribe noted later that all involved in the complex's dismantling were unceremoniously executed halfway through the project without recorded cause.

Such hasty and unceremonious a mass execution was not typical of Hatshepsut's reign, the historian wrote. All evidence points to something powerful and dangerous being there unearthed, and subsequently guarded with great jealousy. It may not be too presumptuous to note, the author added, that Hatshepsut's reign, while not as violently war-oriented as many others, was characterized by an unusual and almost obsessive ambition to remake the face of the natural world in the queen's image. Hatshepsut's unprecedented (and nearly inconceivable) archeological feats might thus be cast in a more sinister light…

Rigel's eyes unfocused on a yawn, and she paused in her reading to take a peek in Pettigrew's direction. He was slumped over a table not far from the Restricted Section, looking close to sleep.

Rigel shut the book and replaced it on the shelf quietly, resigning herself to another night of wasted effort. Every possible account of the jewel was the same—someone previously ordinary (in terms of Wizarding kings, at any rate) reportedly obtained the stone just prior to going on a power-fueled bender. How many of those stories were possible and how many simply some historian's attempt to make sense of a ruler's sudden change in personality? She had no way of knowing. There didn't seem to be much consistency in the way in which the jewel helped one achieve power, either. Some reported acquirers gained unheard of military prowess, while others gained a sudden power over the natural world, or were all at once able to subjugate large groups of creatures or muggles or even other wizards. How could one jewel give someone so diverse a power? And why, if it could give power over literally everything, didn't all of its so-called possessors become masters of everything? The stories consistently compartmentalized the kind of power each jewel-bearer exercised. That made no sense, as far as she could tell. It would be like someone making a philosopher's stone and only turning things to gold with it, never producing the elixir of life.

It's probably all nonsense anyway, she thought to herself despondently. No one who actually had contact with such an artifact would risk writing something down about it. Unless they were incredibly thick, she added, watching Pettigrew furiously scribble notes all across a piece of parchment with no apparent care that they might fall into the wrong hands.

Then again, the jewel seemed to draw megalomaniacs—or at least create them, she allowed. Ego-driven people who obsessed over power probably rarely considered that another might gain that power in their stead through a careless mistake. She didn't want the power, but what if Pettigrew dropped his notes when she wasn't around to pick them up? Who knew what sort of person might come across them?

She shook her head, well aware that she was now being paranoid. They were at Hogwarts, after all, not some evil villain's secret base. If a student saw a piece of parchment with mysterious notes scribbled all over it they'd probably throw it straight in the trash. She had yet to meet a student who could stomach any more studying than passing his or her exams required.

By the way the Creatures professor was nodding, it wouldn't be long before he packed it up for the night, so she didn't bother picking another book to read. Instead she watched the little man thoughtfully from under her cloak, wondering what had possessed this person to take possession of the jewel in the first place. He didn't seem the domineering type, nor the power-hungry. Someone who truly lusted for power wouldn't be wasting their time in a library trying to research how to correctly use the jewel—they'd be out using it, and damn the consequences. She wasn't sure Pettigrew had used the jewel at all since the disaster on Halloween, and she liked to think it was because he hadn't meant to cause such a clamor.

The fact that he was persisting in digging deeper into the mystery didn't reflect well on him, but she couldn't entirely blame him. That prophecy hadn't been particularly forgiving. All that stuff about taking control or having it taken, bearing the cost and bewareing the consequence of losing control—or was it power? She was too tired to recall. Was 'bewareing' even a word?

In the end, the sum of all she read on the subject seemed to be that the jewel was very dangerous. History would likely have been better off without it.

She slept a full eleven hours when she finally got back to the Come and Go Room, and woke just in time to pick up where one of her previous selves had left off on Saturday after lunch.

She rejoined her friends in the common room just as Draco and Pansy broke off to change for their Dueling Club meeting. Theo and Millicent had come once or twice, but neither seemed particularly devoted to developing the skill, and Blaise had flatly refused to even attempt it, claiming physical exertion to be the least diverting thing he could think of.

They met up with several of their housemates who now attended the club religiously, including Rookwood and Rosier, the latter of whom was wearing one of the hideously expensive 'toiling robes' that he'd commissioned over the winter break. As far as Rigel could tell, it was a glorified sweat-proof smock, but she had seem him receive some very admiring comments from others in the club, so she had to conclude that she simply knew nothing about fashion.

They arrived at their usual spot by the lake to find numerous members of other Houses already warming up, and while she and Pansy began stretching, Draco set about in an approving fashion to supervise the newer members who hadn't quite got a hang of the regimen yet.

"He's really come into his own," Pansy commented, mid-bend.

"He's a natural leader," Rigel agreed.

"Naturally bossy, you mean," Pansy smirked.

"I think direction is only considered bossy when it's unsolicited," Rigel remarked. "It doesn't hurt that he knows exactly which direction is the right one every time, either."

Draco had made leaps and strides with his gift of late. He could read others' emotions faster and more accurately, now, and made unapologetic use of this knowledge when dealing with his club members. Others thought it uncanny how the young snake could always tell who was confused but pretending not to be because of pride and who was growing annoyed and wished to be left alone for a while. Rigel could see the confidence her friend was gaining in what had previously been the most troublesome area of his life, however, and was proud of him for coming so far in so short a time.

When it came time to pair everyone up, Draco hesitated upon assigning Rigel a partner. "You've pretty much surpassed everyone young enough to reasonably pair you with," Draco admitted, looking resigned. "If I pair you with a seventh year from the Dueling class, it will be taken as an insult. Especially if you win, which I wouldn't put past you at this point. You're a bloody natural."

She wasn't, she knew, but there was no way to explain her rapid progress in the subject to Draco. She spent long hours perfecting what her friend taught her from Remus' class, as well as going over what she remembered of Leo's lessons from winter break. It did feel a bit like cheating, but she reasoned that she needed those hours of exercise the balance the time-turned hours she spent hunched over a book or scroll.

"Would you be averse to pairing with Neville?" Draco asked after a short pause.

"Not at all," Rigel said. Neville had come quite far since they started the club meetings. He still cast relatively slowly, but he was becoming harder to predict as experience gave him a measure of creativity.

"He needs to work on shielding between offensive spells," Draco told her, "So try to use wide-area spells he can't dodge."

"Will do," she said, saluting in the irreverent way that she knew her friend detested, just to see him lose his serious composure for a moment as he rolled his eyes at her.

She found Neville, and the two of them claimed a section of grass as their own. The air filled with the sounds of enthusiastically cast magic and she lost herself easily to the familiar rhythm of a one-on-one duel. It had grown from the exercise of a necessary skill to a very enjoyable practice over the year. When she worked with Leo, she could feel the intensity in every movement, and the idea that what she learned could save her life one day was never far from her mind. Here, though, she practiced with those who had never seen magic used to systematically attempt to harm another. To them, it was more like a game, an exhibition skill that they might one day be called upon to demonstrate in competition, but which no one anticipated using in earnest. The last Wizarding war to involve Great Britain was beyond living memory. Grindelwald's campaigns were a page in the history book much like the goblin wars, to those here.

After several engaging but ultimately unchallenging duels, she and Neville cooled off in the shade and took turns pointing out which of the other members was using the most interesting combinations that afternoon.

"Hey Neville," she said after a time, "My dad mentioned something over the break I thought was curious."

"About me?" Neville looked bewildered. "I don't think we've met."

"That's what's odd," Rigel said, "He seemed to think we'd had a play date at some point while we were younger, but I can't remember ever meeting you before Hogwarts."

Neville furrowed his brows. "I don't remember that either. I did think it odd, though," he offered abruptly, "I mean, my mum is really close with your cousin Harriett's mum, and you're really close with Miss Potter, so I did sort of wonder why we hadn't ever…met. I just figured your family wasn't too social, maybe. My family isn't that social, really, but I met Ron a bunch of times before we started school, since our dads worked at the Ministry together."

"Dad acted really odd when I said I didn't remember, too," Rigel said, an ominous feeling in her heart for reasons she didn't quite understand. "He tried to brush it off as his mistake, but something about it didn't sit right with me."

"I'm getting an uncomfortable feeling, but I don't know why," Neville said hesitantly, "Like there's something important I'm supposed to know but don't."

"Yes!" Rigel said, breathing deeply. "That's it exactly. What does it mean?"

"That we should let it go and pretend that this conversation never happened?" Neville suggested weakly. "I'm getting a very strong 'stop thinking about this' vibe."

"Doesn't that make you want to know what's causing it?" Rigel said.

"Not really," Neville said, frowning, "It makes me feel like I'm about to break an oath I don't remember taking, and that is scary enough that I'd rather live in ignorance."

Rigel didn't think that was very Gryffindor of him, but she couldn't exactly say so. She would have to work out the answer to this most troubling revelation on her own, she supposed. "We can talk about something else," she offered. She didn't think Neville had anything else to tell her, in any case.

The mystery of the play-date that wasn't hovered in the back of her mind, troubling her sleep late into the night when all other thoughts had been quieted. It sent her delving into tomes on memory, on bindings of magic that might affect the mind, and drove her to write a long letter to Archie trying to articulate the feeling of foreboding that crept upon her at every attempt to recall something that probably hadn't happened, and couldn't possibly be important if it had. She turned it over unhappily: that is, until something much more immediate occurred to redirect her attention.

She had half-hoped her talk with Snape would be enough for him to let the subject of her magic lie for a while, but before she'd even thought about how she was going to go about doing something she wasn't sure was possible, the Potions master forestalled her from leaving his office one evening to inquire just how her magic control was coming along.

"Not at all," she said, quite blunt. "If I try to use even the simplest of spells without the suppressor it floods my wand until something explodes."

"Have you been practicing?" Snape demanded.

"Not really," Rigel frowned. "I assumed someone might disapprove of me exploding things."

"Do not take a tone you may regret, Mr. Black," Snape drawled. He looked entirely disgruntled.

"Sorry, Sir." She dropped her eyes in brief submission, then said, "Is that all?"

"It is not all," Snape sneered, "Not if you haven't made any progress. You gave me your word in this, recall. I am not above taking this over your head if I must."

"You promised not to tell my family, if you recall," Rigel said, fighting to maintain politeness.

"I do not break my promises," Snape hissed, visibly affronted.

"Neither do I," Rigel said, not actually sure at this point if that was true. "I'll work on it. I need more time."

She took her leave abruptly, sure that he would have more to say if she gave him the chance. She knew what she'd promised; she just didn't see any point in pushing it. It's not like they were starting free brewing tomorrow. Snape said himself it would be next year sometime. She could work on it over the summer, if she really had to, when she didn't have a dozen other distractions.

She had never known her Head of House to make an idle threat, but it somehow still caught her completely flat-footed when he requested she meet him in a disused classroom close to his office one Sunday morning soon after that. They never met on Sundays, as Snape usually reserved that day for marking and preparatory work for his classes. The location was odd, too, and if she'd received the message any other way than straight from the professor's mouth she might have been suspicious.

When she saw the wizard Snape had brought with him, she could only think that she ought to have been suspicious after all. Lord Riddle, in all his richly tailored glory, stood calmly in the center of the empty room, as though he often spent his time lying in wait for unsuspecting third-years. She resisted the urge to run a hand nervously through her hair, instead closing the door gently behind her and turning to her Head of House with questioning eyes. She was entirely content to ignore the well-dressed elephant in the room—forever, if she had to.

"Am I early?" she asked, despite knowing full well there was no plausible reason for Snape to be meeting with Riddle in the same place he'd asked to meet her unless her day was about to go very downhill.

"You are perfectly on time, as well you should be," Snape said, beckoning her to step forward to where the two men waited. "You are acquainted with Lord Riddle, are you not?"

"Tangentially," she said, completely confused as to what Riddle wanted with her—for surely that was the only explanation for Snape setting up a meeting on their behalf.

"Our acquaintance is not so peripheral as that, Mr. Black," Riddle said. He was eyeing her speculatively, which perplexed her, as she believed Riddle had already taken her measure and found her to be a simple, if terribly unlucky, child.

"If you say so, Mr. Riddle," she allowed, feeling petty amusement as Riddle's brow ticked with displeasure at hearing the lack of title. He was no doubt accustomed to more respect from his Slytherins, but she would hold her respect until she knew what he wanted. If he intended to go back on their deal, she would have to find a way to dissuade him.

"He's less polite than I remember," Riddle said mildly, giving Snape a chiding glance. "Your influence, no doubt."

"The boy is remarkably headstrong, for one who knows so little of the world," Snape said, keeping his eyes on Rigel as he spoke, that she might see exactly how annoyed she'd made him lately.

"Thus the need for my interference," Riddle said, chuckling softly.

"What interference is that, Mr. Riddle?" Rigel asked, wary at receiving their combined focus.

"You have not told him why I am here," Riddle observed.

"I believe he would have come less readily were he to be forewarned of my intentions," Snape said, voice wry.

"This is an ambush," Rigel concluded suddenly. "Why?"

"You have not kept your word—" Snape began.

"My magic again?" Rigel bit off a sharp sigh. "I told you I need time, Professor."

"I do not believe you," Snape said. "You have dug your heels in against learning to control your magic from the start. It is clear that if you are not made to do it, you will see no progress."

Rigel had nothing to say to that, as it was, she had to admit quietly, the truth. Still, she didn't like being cornered. "What has this to do with Mr. Riddle? Is this your way of forcing my hand—revealing me to those whose interest I sought to avoid, so that my reasons for avoiding the issue become null? What's next? Are you going to take me to Dumbledore's office and parade me before him as well?"

"Watch your tongue, Rigel," Snape growled. He seemed to be saying it more for Riddle's sake than for any want of her respect in that moment. Snape's face was laced with understanding, and she forced herself not to be angry by focusing on the evidence that he was not trying to bring her many plans to ruin. "I have not betrayed you. I brought Lord Riddle here to help you. He has the experience you need to guide you in this."

"Indeed," Riddle cut in. "I was young once. I remember the feeling, the sudden influx of power that came, almost over night, like a blessing from the world. It can be intimidating, at times, the knowledge that you are destined for great things, but it is not something to be ignored—embrace it! This power was meant for you, Mr. Black. Once you accept that, all these doubts will disappear." He accompanied the last with a wave of his hand that was entirely dismissive of her 'doubts.'

"With all due respect, Sir, I don't think that's true," Rigel said, thoroughly unimpressed.

"That is because you are inexperienced in the ways of the world," Riddle sneered. "You know nothing yet of the incredible opportunity that power brings."

"Those aren't the sort of opportunities I'm looking for," Rigel said, attempting to diplomatically convey that she did not, in fact, aspire to be like Riddle in any way.

"Then you are a fool, Rigel Black," Riddle said. "Unfortunately for you, a fool is not something we can afford to abide." She didn't like the sound of that at all, and fought briefly with the impulse to step back toward the door.

"Lord Riddle, perhaps—" Snape attempted to cut in, but was silenced by an imperious hand.

"No, Severus. The boy is being unconscionably narrow-sighted. This is not about you, Mr. Black," Riddle said sternly. "Slytherin needs strong wizards to represent it—the more the better. The Black Family needs a powerful Heir to steer it back in the proper direction. The politics of this cannot be ignored. You must learn quickly, and take your place at the helm of this new generation, for the good of our world."

She could see Snape wincing from the corner of her eye, and it occurred to her that this was not what he'd anticipated in inviting Riddle here. Her Head of House must know that this was exactly what Rigel did not want to hear. If anything could have solidified her suspicion that powerful magic attracted attention and trouble, this was it. With the cat out of the bag, so to speak, what was she to do now?

Riddle was saying something else, something about power being the ultimate decider in everything, but all Rigel could think was—did the politician really think her so stupid that she might believe he had some altruistic compassion for the House of Slytherin itself, or the Black Family in particular? It was painfully obvious he meant the SOW Party needed her power, needed to shift the balance toward Dark politics once more. Did he think because she was a friend to his sycophants' heirs that she would toe the line politically and socially as well? Had she given him that impression somehow?

"So if you will not think of yourself, of the doors and avenues that open before the command of true power, then think of others—of your House and your Family," Riddle concluded, smiling in a way that she was sure had won him many favors in the past.

"It is others I think of when I choose not to use all my magic," Rigel said, knowing that someone like Riddle was not likely to understand, but also knowing that it was the only truth she could give him. "Their safety. The integrity of their relationships with me. My magic would put these things in jeopardy, if it could. I will not risk attempting to use it for something as abstract as political gain."

Riddle's face darkened, and there was a shadow of the boy that she had met in the Chamber of Secrets staring out at her suddenly. "Your obstinance leaves me no choice, Black."

"It is not your choice, Sir," she said, wary.

"Magic belongs to the world, Mr. Black," Riddle said, a sinister smirk that she did not trust at all tucked into his cheek.

Rigel frowned, wondering why Riddle thought that he spoke for the world. As she attempted to reiterate her refusal, however, Riddle's wand was in his hand and she felt a violent tug on both her gloves. They flew across the room and into Riddle's hand before she could so much as make a fist in protest. She fisted her hands afterwards, though, glaring at Riddle and taking several steps backward in open refusal.

Another twitch of Riddle's wand and her basilisk scale ring grew loose and slippery, wiggling its way off her finger of its own accord. Even as she tried to hold it with her other hand, it jerked away and finally broke free to join her gloves in Riddle's hand. He looked down at the ring curiously. "Basilisk scale. Pretty, but not what we're after, is it?" His wand moved but the suppressor on her finger didn't budge. After Snape had threatened to make her take it off, she'd had Binny make extra certain it could not be taken off by anyone but herself. No doubt the house-elf magic was putting up an unexpected fight against Riddle's summons.

"Well-warded little thing, isn't it?" Riddle said, too casually. His unconcerned tone made her half-afraid he would simply cut off her entire finger. When his wand moved again, however, the ring still didn't move. Instead, it burned. Gasping, Rigel clutched her hand in pain and surprise. It felt like her ring had somehow been made molten, so hot it grew, and yet to her eyes the ring appeared unchanged. Was the spell on the ring or on her hand? Or on her mind? She couldn't focus past the agonizing searing. Her hand was twitching uncontrollably in thwarted instinct, trying and failing to remove itself from the object of its torture.

"Stop it," she panted, tears swimming to her eyes as her brain fought against the incoming sensory signals.

"It will stop when you remove it," Riddle said, voice still casual.

"Lord Riddle, this is still Dumbledore's school," Snape said sharply. She thanked him for his attempt even as she cursed him for being too beholden to Riddle to demand that he cease for her sake.

"He will notice nothing amiss," Riddle snapped. "Take the ring off, Black."

"I can't," she tried, a last, vain attempt to dissuade him. "It's spelled to be irremovable."

"You lie," Riddle said. He was plainly amused. "Fine attempt, but I can read you even without an aura. Take it off, or I will set your boots on fire."

Rigel liked her boots. Also, the pain in her hand was starting to grow mind numbing, and she realized she was fighting a losing battle. Slowly, in deference to her pride and fury, she worked the ring off her hand and slipped it into her pocket with the most annoyed scowl she could muster. She wasn't about to hand it over—the politician would probably refuse to return it on principle, even after he got whatever it was he wanted.

She wanted to continue to glare at Riddle, but her magic seized all of her attention in the next moment. It had noticed it was free. A riot occurred beneath her naval, and power, thick and furious, stormed through her with the grace of an ogre tumbling down a hill. It ran too hot in her veins, snaking through any available outlet to pour out into the air around her like air into a vacuum. The weight of it gathering around her pressed her head and shoulders down and her arms inward to curl about her ribcage protectively. It felt as though she were being squeezed on all sides. She imagined this was what being hugged by a giant who was trying to kill you would be like.

"Not so uneager after all, are you?" she heard Riddle say. Her head shot up to retort angrily that it wasn't her doing, but as her attention shifted so did her magic's attention. It swept away from her in a wave that had her pulling in deep gulps of air as the pressure around her eased. Riddle snarled in surprise, however, as the magic was suddenly upon him, pushing and tugging in equal measures at his previously immaculate hair and clothes. "That's quite enough, Mr. Black," he said firmly, his fingers tightening on his wand as he flexed his own magic to gain breathing room.

"It isn't me," Rigel snapped, her hands shaking as the magic continued to pour out of her in a rampage of freedom claimed at last. "I told you I can't control it."

"And so it happens to harass me, the object of your ire, rather than Master Snape?" Riddle shook his head in a superior way. "I don't think so. This is your doing, whether you know it or not. Now you must take control consciously."

Rigel, anger and trepidation warring in equal measure within her, attempted to call her magic back coaxingly. Please, she tried, Come back here. Settle down. The magic drew back from Riddle immediately, but it did not return docilely to her side. It turned on her with a vengeance, coursing through the air with irrepressible speed and violence, making her the center of a displeased tornado of magic. She reached out toward it gamely, a grim expression of determination on her face. She had to get it under control. Her hand had barely left her side before it was swatted back with a malevolent lash of power.

There was a raised welt on the back of her hand where she'd been struck. She stared at it for a moment in disbelief. This wasn't the magic she knew. Normally it was only unruly in use. She had never been unable to suppress it—just unable to control it once it manifested. This…it was as though the magic had at last rejected her authority completely. It no longer deigned to even be contained within her.

"Control it!" Riddle said above the sound of air slashing about her.

"I can't," Rigel gritted out. "Haven't you heard anything I've said?"

"When you believe you can't, then of course you can't," Riddle scoffed.

"People keep saying that," Rigel snapped, utterly sick of people telling her the only problem was her own perception. "Only saying 'believe in yourself' is nonsense that doesn't actually help."

"True enough," Riddle allowed, still openly amused at her expense. She hoped his perfect teeth all fell out during one of his speeches. "Start with a focus, then. Attend all your will toward one thing, one feeling, one instinct. Even if it is destructive, try and force the magic to destroy the thing you choose."

"I don't want to destroy," Rigel said, face tight.

"It is easier to begin that way," Riddle said, mockingly patient. "Once you can control the more…passionate aspects of power, the technical applications will follow. Now, choose something to direct its attention to—not me, if you please—and will it. It will answer."

"How?" she asked, trying to calm her mind by breathing very slowly.

"Your wand, of course," Riddle said. His arms were crossed and he gazed at her as one would a child refusing to eat its vegetables.

Harry took out her wand, which had been busy burning a hole in her pocket in response to the nearness of her magic, and pointed it at a desk on the far side of the room, well away from Professor Snape. Riddle could get stuffed with splinters for all she cared. Her magic, perhaps drawn to the wand as electricity to a good conductor, swirled around her hand impatiently, building there until her entire forearm struggled against the currents. She hesitated on incanting the Bombardment Hex, having no way to aim reliably with her arm shaking all over the place, but the intention had scarcely entered her mind before her wand was suddenly alive with magic pouring through it. It shot out of her core as though she'd pulled the cork form a champagne bottle after shaking it vigorously, and the magic in the air around her joined it readily, merging with the spell and transforming it visibly as it flew through the air.

The magic, which resembled more closely a miniature cyclone than any spell she'd ever seen, impacted one of the pushed-aside desks and…devoured it. There was no other way to put it. The faded wood turned black upon contact with the magic, then began to dissolve as though exposed to acid, or particularly fast-working termites. In the space of a few seconds, there was nothing left of it, not even a pile of ash on the floor where it had been.

"What spell was that?" Riddle asked, the kind of awe in his voice that musicians reserved for works of Beethoven.

"Bombarda," she said, rubbing her now-sore wand arm.

Riddle frowned. "That was nothing like a Bombarda."

"My magic does what it wants," Rigel grumbled. Said magic had returned to her and was now whistling sharply in her left ear like a spoiled child, begging for another sweet. Irritably, she attempted to quell it once more, picturing it receding back into her core and laying dormant. Immediately, the wind around her picked up and sent her stumbling sideways. Okay, okay, she capitulated, raising her hands to her face to protect it as the wind took on an edge that cut through her robes in several places. When it had calmed marginally to a stern wind, she examined the rips with deep resignation. "Sirius is going to be displeased. He just had these tailored," she muttered morosely. If she asked for new ones, he'd send her Archie-sized robes and she'd have to fix the hem herself.

"Again," Riddle said decisively. "Continue focusing the destructive tendencies in your magic until you can rein it in reliably."

Rigel frowned. "I don't think it's a good idea to encourage my magic's 'destructive tendencies.' It's only going to teach it bad habits."

"That is not how magic works," Riddle said, a snide curl to his lip.

"Magic is highly impressionable," she argued.

"Children's magic is impressionable," Riddle shot back, "As is wild magic. A fully fledged wizard's is not."

She opened her mouth again, but Snape, closer now but still far enough that his robes barely stirred in the breeze of her magic, broke in at last. "Rigel, you must listen to Lord Riddle. He knows what he is doing. He dealt with this very issue himself, once."

Riddle was full on smirking as he said, "I never let my magic grow so unruly, but yes, the theory will be much the same. Now, do it again."

Seeing that she was outgunned, Rigel gracelessly jabbed her wand at a different desk and sent her magic toward it with a great mental push. The desk turned into a bust of Riddle's smiling face, then imploded.

"Very amusing," Riddle said, looking anything but. "Try it again."

Sighing, Rigel rallied her mental fortitude. This was going to be a long morning. It didn't take much time to destroy all the desks in the room, thus necessitating the men to begin conjuring targets for her magic's wrath. Snape stuck with simple pieces of furniture and the occasional straw dummy, but Riddle was especially creative. His targets inevitably took the shape of delicate china vases, stained-glass windowpanes, golden mirrors, and once an elaborate replica of Hogwarts itself done in crystal. When he conjured a live bunny, Rigel's temper, frayed thin from a pounding headache and constant struggling against the unruly tide of her magic, simply snapped. She transfigured the bunny into a viper without even pausing to think about it, sending it snapping at Riddle's ankles with a thoroughly vexed slash of her wand.

Riddle vanished the snake with a wide smile and began to clap, slowly and very patronizingly. "Well done, Mr. Black."

Realizing that her magic had obeyed an impulse that was not entirely destructive, Rigel reined in her ire and took a slow breath. She surveyed her magic for a long moment, noting that while it still encircled her in a steady current, she felt much less like she stood in the eye of a hurricane. Now it was as though she was a planet, rings of magic orbiting her body rhythmically, but not threateningly.

"See how much easier it is to control, now?" Riddle said, smiling superiorly down at her.

"I could have told you that expending a large amount of my magic makes it easier to control," Rigel said, giving an unimpressed eyebrow flick. "It is, after all, the point of the suppresser I wear. Take a large part of it away, and it isn't hard to control at all. Your way works too, but it seems idiotic to destroy a classroom every time I want to pass a Transfiguration quiz, don't you think?"

"What is idiotic," Riddle said in a low voice, coming within arm's reach of Rigel and seeming completely unaffected by the wind that buffeted his face, "is thinking that I will be intimidated by this power as others are. You would do well to set a respectful tone to your tongue before I silence it, boy."

"I respectfully do not see the practicality of such a violent method of control, Mr. Riddle," Rigel said. She refused to be intimidated by the man just because everyone else was.

"You will see when you want to see," Riddle said, eyes sliding over hers in a way that reminded her she was looking at a man rumored to be an incredibly subtle Legilimens. "Control takes time. It also required a good deal of practice. You have let it go too long, with rather predictable results. It will take dedicated attention to prune the wildness from your magic now that it has taken root."

Rigel resented the implication that her unruly magic was her own fault—it had always been that way…hadn't it? She couldn't remember why she thought so, but she was sure it wasn't something she'd caused by wearing the suppressor alone. The problems had started before that.

"That is not to say you lack potential," Riddle went on, a calculating glint now hardening his eyes. "You may yet be useful, Mr. Black, if you but stretch out your hands to the world around you. Your magic will lead you to extraordinary places, but you must first grasp the reins. I can show you how. Let me tutor you personally during your summer holiday. With my help, you could do great things."

Rigel was frozen in speechless disbelief for a long moment. Had he just…offered to mentor her? She glanced at Snape to see what he made of Riddle's unexpected suggestion, but her professor's gaze, while wide with something like shock, held neither approval nor censure. She swallowed soundlessly and scrambled for an answer that would not offend the man.

"That is very generous of you, Sir," she said, hoping he didn't pick up on how her magic became more agitated with her unease. "I must decline, however. I've made other arrangements for the summer. Also I…do not seek the sort of greatness you could help me achieve."

"Do not try my patience with this naïve insistence that power is not something you desire," Riddle said softly, a dangerous edge to his voice. "Power is a matter of necessity. It is practical to develop every talent Fate gives you."

"Even so, I do have other plans," Rigel said, making an attempt at firmness. "I'm sorry, but I will develop the rest of the control I need on my own. Thank you very much for your help today, Lord Riddle. I am in your debt."

Riddle's face was closed tight with anger, and he turned from her without another word. "Talk some sense into your student, Severus," he hissed, tossing her gloves and her other ring to the Potions master on his way out the door. "I'll be in your office."

The door shut behind him and Snape turned to her with an entirely resigned expression. "You would have me tell him no, I take it?"

Rigel grimaced a bit in sympathy, but nodded. "Sorry, Professor. I really can't agree to that, though."

"I'm not sure what he was thinking, even offering," Snape muttered. With an annoyed snort, he got out his wand and began setting the classroom to rights. "Mr. Black," he said after a minute of conjuring new desks, "I feel I should tell you…this was not entirely what I intended, in bringing Lord Riddle here today."

"I know," Rigel said quickly. It was hard to be mad at Snape for doing what he thought was best for her—especially when Riddle had so effectively drawn her ire in his direction. "I understand that you were trying to help me. I just…I hate that everything to do with my magic is so violent and destructive. Without the suppressor, I can't do anything without it blowing up in my face, and then I'm told the answer is to be so destructive that I burn through power like Draco at a tart festival—" Snape snorted in amusement, but Rigel ignored him, well into her rant now, "—and it seems so pointless when I could just wear the suppressor and not have to blow anything up, and what's the point of having all that extra magic if the only thing it's good for is mass destruction anyway?"

She shoved her hand into her pocket and took out the suppressor ring, flinching slightly as her magic picked up around her and began oscillating wildly back and forth, making her stumble a bit as she struggled to get the ring back on her finger without dropping it. When she tried pushing it on, however, a pressure built up around her finger that blocked it, like a hundred miniscule gusts of wind all rushing around her finger madly. It burned terribly where the friction from the wind scraped against the tender skin left by Riddle's earlier attempt to remove the ring, and she whimpered in a way she knew was pathetic at the renewed pain.

"I can't even get this stupid thing on," she whispered, blinking back moisture from her eyes. She would not cry in front of her Head of House like a child. She was just so frustrated by it all. She wanted to crawl into a dark hole and stay there for a week or two. She'd rather do anything but deal with her magic for a single moment longer. "I'm so sick of this," she said tiredly.

Pale, spindly fingers covered her own, stopping her attempt at forcing the ring any further. Rigel relaxed, glad that one thing, at least, had been taken out of her hands. As she ceased trying to put the suppressor on, the pressure of her magic eased, confused by the sudden lack of direction in her mind, no doubt. In the wake of that ebb, Snape slid the ring onto her finger swiftly, not giving her magic any time to react. She felt the roar of her power as it sank into her skin and seeped back into her core; echoes of anger rang in her bones, and she trembled, knowing somehow that the next time she released it, it would be worse.

"Thank you," she said, mouth a bit stiff in the aftermath of such a long, emotionally trying morning. "Sorry I snapped at you before, about bringing Riddle here. Does Dumbledore know too, now, though?"

"I cannot speak to what the headmaster does or does not know," Snape said, handing over her gloves with the ring of scale and stepping back a pace to put some distance between them once more. "Lord Riddle had some business with the headmaster today in regards to an event they are cooperating to organize in the coming months. He stopped by to see me in my office, as he usually does on the rare occasion he visits the school, and we had a very long and involved discussion on the merits of regulating the migration patterns of certain magical species of birds." At Rigel's small smile, Snape cleared his throat uncomfortably. "When Lord Riddle told me of his visit, I admit I thought it opportune. It was clear to me that you needed motivation of some kind to take control of your magic completely. I…believed you might relate to another who had dealt with the same sort of problem. It was not my intention to corner you, though I see now how it may have appeared. I merely wished you to understand that your situation is not unique."

As that was probably the closest Snape could get to saying, 'I wanted you to know you aren't alone,' Rigel was touched. Any lingering resentment she felt at his highhandedness melted away, and she summoned the most grateful, reassuring smile she was able. "Thanks, Professor. I'll…work on my magic, all right? If only to prevent you summoning Lord Riddle on me again." She hitched up her mouth on one side at the last, to let him know she was joking, and that he was already forgiven.

"See that you do," Snape said shortly. His gruff tone was utterly belied by the spots of color high on his cheeks. "If that is all, I must go make a very powerful man extremely unhappy."

"Good luck," Rigel said, grinning a bit, "I hear they bite."

"Only when provoked," Snape sneered. He left the classroom and turned in the direction of his office, while Rigel turned toward the kitchens. She was going to eat a bar of chocolate the size of her head, then think about everything that had just happened. Then she was going to sleep. Possibly for years.

How long had it been since his plans last resulted in unmitigated disaster? He pondered this in wry self-deprecation as he parted ways with his student. It been some time, he noted, since he misread a situation so egregiously. No. Not the situation. Riddle. Lips pressed into a thin line of displeasure, he was in no mood to find the man lounging behind his desk as he entered the room. Riddle did not bother to stand as Severus entered, so Severus conjured an intimidating armchair and sank into it with a scowl.

"Could you have been any more confrontational?" Severus asked, very interested to know why Riddle had completely disregarded his advice and suggestions for dealing with Rigel.

"I could have cut out his tongue for his insolence," Riddle said, the smallest of smiles playing in the corner of one cheek. It relaxed Severus minutely to know that the man was not as angry as he had seemed. Why put on a show for the boy's benefit? Did he think he could scare Rigel Black into submission? The child had killed a basilisk, for Salazar's sake.

"I requested your assistance in this matter so that you could calm the boy's fears," Severus said, forcing patience into his words. "You were to make the magic seem normal, not terrorize him and then draw out its destructive energies—do not think I missed that little manipulation, Lord Riddle."

"It isn't normal," Riddle scoffed, "Nor should it be treated as such. It is extraordinary. He will be extraordinary, if he ever gets his head on straight."

"And riling him up is supposed to help straighten him out, is it? You were feeding the restlessness in his magic," he said angrily. "What is going to happen when the energy you mingled with his is absorbed by his core?"

"Rigel Black could use a little more restlessness," Riddle informed him. "It will give him drive."

"Or drive him mad," Severus snapped.

"I didn't give him that much." Riddle was openly restraining an eye-roll. "Just a little nudge."

"In the wrong direction," Severus seethed. "Could you not see the trouble he already has with it? The magic is so detached from his will that it was physically injuring the boy. Making his magic wilder is only going to make it harder for him to control. That is the precise converse of what I asked you to do."

"I know what I am doing, Severus," Riddle said, a warning in his tone that Severus easily ignored.

"Whatever you are doing is irrelevant to my point," he spat. "That is my student. I decide what is best for him, not you. You overstep your bounds, Lord Riddle."

"My bounds?" Riddle clutched both armrests and leaned forward on a hiss. "Do not ssseek to inssstruct me on my limitsss, Ssseverusss." It was as close to Parseltongue as Riddle could come while still being intelligible, and it was always a sign of grave danger, but Severus was not finished.

"You hold dominion over me, not the child," he said, nostrils flaring with rage. "I stood by as you tormented him physically and emotionally in the vain belief that you had a purpose that served his best interests, but that is the last time I will do so."

"Your lack of understanding does not reflect upon my methods' validity," Riddle said.

"I understand the result well enough," Severus said. His eyes narrowed to catch Riddle's next expression. "His magic was so wild at the end that he could not re-don his suppressor. He nearly broke a finger trying."

The fleeting surprise that flickered in Riddle's eyes was the only thing that saved the man from the full infliction of Severus' ire. "That is impossible. Magic is not intelligent in the way you are implying."

"That's what I used to say about Rigel's magic," Severus said flatly. "It seems I shall be reconsidering that opinion. You would do well to reconsider your approach with him, as well. At this moment it is unlikely he will willingly come within ten feet of you. Somehow I doubt that was your intention."

Riddle scowled. "Cease, Severus, your point is made. I will consider your words. I must reject your assumption that the boy is yours alone to influence, however. Our plans may require his allegiance—and not just to you."

"Prepare to be disappointed," Severus said, cynically amused. "You know very little of Rigel, it seems, if you think he will be swayed to any political agenda. The boy cares nothing for politics."

"Do not sound so proud, Severus," Riddle admonished slyly. "You once felt similarly, did you not? Look at you now. A Party man, unless I am very much mistaken."

"Our circumstances are not the same." Severus felt an old bitterness churning like acid in his gut. "Rigel has strong familial ties, much stronger than the ties of friendship he has forged in Slytherin." Even as he said it, Severus was not so sure of the truth in that. Many things contradicted that idea: the strange social dissembling between Rigel and his father, the singular academic interests that isolated him still further, the distance between the depth of his talent and his family's ability to even comprehend it.

"New ties can easily replace old ones," Riddle said, leaning back now to look across the desk from beneath lowered eyelids. "You could be a father figure, if you but put forth the appropriate effort, Severus." Severus immediately squashed the ambiguous feelings that bloomed at such words said aloud, but not before Riddle sensed them. "You'd make a good role model for the boy, Severus. You deserve such a child to teach, to foster and mold as though he were your own son."

Damn the man's cunning. He never failed to root out the most vulnerable parts of a person, no matter how well concealed. "The boy does not look to adults for personal guidance," he said after a long moment, ignoring the sting of his own words. "That is why you will find it so difficult to manipulate him to your side. He seeks only academic appreciation; no other acclaim even mildly interests him."

"Hence the need to motivate him through necessity," Riddle said, tapping a finger on the desk pointedly. "If he thinks he can avoid an issue, he will, is this not so? I have noticed that trait in conversations with the boy; always he sidesteps when he senses the approach of confrontation—except, of course, when he is motivated by a principle greater than himself." The older man seemed to be talking almost to himself, now, and Severus did not disturb him—if Riddle wished to speak aloud his plans, the better for Severus. "Perhaps that is the leverage I need. If he will not strive for himself, perhaps he can be made to strive for another…"

Riddle lapsed into a pensive silence, and Severus knew better than to interrupt him. Riddle's thoughts were precious, and those who intruded upon them learned swiftly of the cost they incurred.

"That girl," Riddle spoke again, this time glancing in Severus' direction to let him know the question was not rhetorical. "The Potter girl—Black is close to her, is he not?"

"Extremely," Severus agreed. "They were raised as siblings, and appear to esteem one another before most others, for whatever reason. You think to use the girl to motivate him?" He could not articulate how he felt about that idea. It would depend on the nature of the motivation, he supposed.

"Perhaps," Riddle said vaguely, clearly still in the process of generating plans. "There is something…off about the combination of the two. I haven't grasped the exact trigger, but many things incite my suspicions. They look remarkably alike, and yet I have heard no rumors of infidelity or conspiracy regarding either the Potters or the late Lady Black. Then there is their dovetailing academic interests. What fostered such intellectual tendencies in a family of brash-headed Gryffindors? Something doesn't add up."

"There is a rumor," Severus offered, his lip curling at the distaste he felt in relating gossip of any kind. Riddle was the sort to demand any and all information pertinent to a discussion implicitly, however, no matter the seeming triviality of it. "Regulus related it to me in a desire to know if I found any merit in its claims. There is a belief that the boy possesses some sort of passive metamorphic ability that has affected his physical development somehow."

"I have never heard of such a thing." Riddle frowned.

"Nor I," Severus agreed, inclining his head. "And yet they do look uncannily alike. His father is apparently of the opinion that Rigel's close bond with his cousin brought out an unconscious desire to identify with her. It would explain why they have similar interests, and, if there is any truth in the metamorphic talent, why they appear as twins despite having different parents."

"Have you seen evidence to support this theory?" Riddle asked.

Severus hesitated. When Riddle caught the pause and lifted a single, demanding eyebrow, he was forced to say, "I thought I noticed his features blurring once. When I looked again, however, they were as they always are. It may have been a trick of the light—or a simple muscle contortion; he was ill at the time."

"Or the illness may have caused the magic to slip for an instant," Riddle mused. "You checked him for Polyjuice?"

"Every day for a week," Severus snorted, still annoyed at that erroneous suspicion. It had been a colossal waste of time, coming up with flimsy pretexts for keeping Rigel under his watch longer than an hour successively.

"Normally I would dismiss a claim like this—magic does not behave in such a way," Riddle said, frowning. "To even suggest that one's magic might accidentally, unconsciously, yet consistently enact a physical change for years—one that evolves over time, no less—is preposterous. And yet…apparently Rigel Black is rewriting the rules of magic before our eyes." There was no small amount of frustration in Riddle's expression, and Severus felt some small measure of satisfaction at the sight of it. Welcome, he wanted to say, to the club.

"If this is the case, then the boy has an unnatural dependency on this halfblood girl," Riddle added, now looking sharply displeased. "He will have to be broken of that connection if he is to move forward."

Severus could not suppress the scowl that moved his features at those blunt words of portent.

Riddle merely smiled at his disapproval. "Weren't you better off, Severus, once it was all said and done? Surely you don't regret the doors that opened once that one swung closed behind you?"

Severus drew his best sneer to the fore. "Life's choices are absolute. There is no room for regret in the well-organized mind."

"So noncommittal, Severus," Riddle complained, smiling fully now. "Will I ever know the depths of your soul?"

"Find an easier soul to plumb," Severus suggested sharply.

"Oh, I intend to," Riddle said, drawing himself up a bit straighter. An unconscious attempt to intimidate whatever he was thinking about, Severus had guessed from experience. "Where is the rat?"

Now they came to Riddle's true purpose in coming to Hogwarts, Severus recognized. The pretense of meeting with Dumbledore was just that; Riddle had all summer to plan his little tournament. He wanted Pettigrew dealt with now.

"He will be at the noon meal," Severus assured him.

"Good." Riddle's eyes flashed. "I want him to see my face and know that he is not so untouchable here in Dumbledore's castle as he thinks."

"The headmaster will notice if you curse the man," Severus reminded him. At times Riddle's thirst for vengeance overrode his otherwise careful scheming.

"I don't need to curse him." Riddle smirked. "He is a scurrying rodent. When he recognizes my ire in the flesh he will crawl back of his own accord like the sniveling coward he is. He has only lasted so long in this rebellion because he is removed from the reality of his transgression. How easy it is for the mouse to laugh at the snake while it sleeps safe in its den. When the snake comes to call, the mouse laughs no longer. Pettigrew's spinelessness will reveal itself shortly, Severus. He will be back at my side before the month is out."

Severus was not so sure. He did not know Pettigrew well, thank Merlin, but what he had observed over the past months did not mesh with what he thought he knew of the man. Something had changed him. He stood straighter as he walked, made eye contact in the hallways with Severus when before he would have scurried in the opposite direction at his approach.

Perhaps sensing his doubt, Riddle said sharply, "If he does not repent, my next visit will not be so lenient. He is fortunate that I do not wish to cause a scene at present. It is not beyond my political capital to do so, however. Tell him that, won't you, Severus?"

"I will attempt to convey the depth of your bereavement at his departure, My Lord," Severus drawled.

"Your sense of humor knows no wisdom, Severus," Riddle sighed.

"That is why you recruited me, I believe," Severus reminded him.

"It is why I allow you to berate me, at any rate," Riddle said, resignation in every syllable.

"Criticism is healthy," Severus told him.

"Is that what you tell your students?" Riddle asked, amused.

"Some more often than others," Severus snorted.

Riddle stood with a fluid grace that had made more than one person accuse him of vampiric inclinations. "Come, let us adjourn to the Great Hall. I have a rodent to intimidate and you have a student to check on."

Severus scowled as he followed Riddle out of the office. He had no intention of seeking out Rigel at lunch like an overprotective parent after his child's first day of school. When they entered the Hall and he didn't see Rigel seated at the Slytherin table, he told himself firmly that he was not worried. He steadfastly ignored Riddle's annoyingly knowing smile to the contrary. The man was too nosy for Severus' patience. He would be well rid of him that afternoon.

He hadn't expected to see him here, of all places. There was a part of him that thought he should be alarmed by this unexpected occurrence, but most of him was strangely calm. Unaffected. Uninterested. He knew if he thought about it that this was unusual. He would have been afraid, he knows, not long ago, but that feeling was a lifetime away. It didn't belong to him anymore.

He knew it was the Jewel, giving him power, courage. It focused his mind on what was important, and Tom Riddle wasn't important anymore. What was important…? The Jewel. The Jewel was important. His mind turned away from the man sending daggers through his eyes from just a few seats down the table. His vision narrowed to the prophecy. Why hadn't he made a copy? He could remember much of it, from poring obsessively over each line for weeks after he'd forced the centaur to tell him what it knew—the Jewel was good at forcing creatures to obey him. He almost never lost control anymore. He'd turned two acromantula from their intention to make a meal of him the other night. His progress was impressive. The satisfaction filled him up, making the food he mechanically swallowed almost irrelevant to his hunger. Then dissatisfaction, stronger and more biting, gnawed at him. He still hadn't unlocked its full powers. The wyrm still resisted…

A debilitating depression gripped him, sending his fork stabbing into his potato with something like frustrated rage. After a moment, the feeling passed, and he was able to focus his thoughts again. The prophecy. The prophecy was the key. It said he had to prove his right to dominion by dominating others. He was trying. He could subjugate most of the creatures in the forest, now. It wasn't enough, though. He had to 'reign beyond the weak' or something…what else could he try? What would prove him worthy? He had to take control of something powerful. Just dominating magical creatures clearly wasn't enough. 'Master the other' it had said. Maybe…maybe he was supposed to master someone else, not something else. Another wizard…?

The feeling of greed was swift, rushing into his veins eagerly. That was the Jewel, he knew. He could feel it burning in his pocket, even through the mokeskin pouch he kept it in to avoid having it summoned or stolen from his person. He began to smile down at his plate. If the Jewel liked that idea, then he must be on the right track. His smile faded once more as he looked around himself and wondered how he was to accomplish such a thing. He was in no position of power. Those ancient pharaohs had it easy—they could boss their slaves around all day and no one would bat an eye. Who could Peter control?

He looked speculatively up and down the staff table. He had wizards in plenty, but…the likes of Albus Dumbledore? Tom Riddle? Severus Snape? Filius Flitwick? Who was he kidding? The depression swallowed him violently, weighing on his shoulders like a boulder. What a hopeless task. His eyes lit on his old friend, Remus. The sandy-haired man ate sedately, but he knew that was a façade. Peter would be a fool to try subjugating a werewolf. It was a shame, for his old friend was trusting, even now. He might have been able to convince him…convince him…of what? He had something to tell Remus. Something important, a warning…he shook his head. Focus. Find a wizard to control.

His frustration ate at him. Anyone with enough magic to qualify as 'beyond weak' would not be controlled by him. He may have to start small. Like with the creatures. Work his way up. Yes. Not all wizards were on the level of Albus Dumbledore, after all. He could start with a woman. Not McGonagall, obviously, but someone easy to fool. A weak woman, or…a child, even. His eyes lit greedily on the expanse of students chattering boisterously there below him. It was so obvious! Their innocent faces were like beacons to his desperation. It would not be so difficult. He only had to decide which one…

When March dwindled to a close, Rigel welcomed April with mixed feelings. On the one hand, everything about the term so far had been exhausting. She was starting to feel the toll of the time-turner daily. She couldn't quite bring herself to stop using it so frequently—it was addicting, in a way, knowing that she had so much more time than everyone else. She knew it was borrowed time—she was aging, even if no one else would be able to tell. It would be a relief, as well as a shame, when the device was taken away from her for the summer. On the other hand, she was learning so much, and progressing so quickly in her dueling, even without being able to use most of the tricks Leo had taught her. The coming of April meant only two months left at Hogwarts. It meant only two more months with her friends. It also meant she had two months to get useful information on what Pettigrew was doing with the jewel—something more than circumstantial conjecture and one cryptic poem.

The big things lurked in the background, however, largely detached from the day-to-day life that she considered 'real.' As she sat in the Gryffindor common room going over Transfiguration theory with Percy, she didn't feel at all connected to the version of herself the Map said was studying in the Room of Requirement, nor to the version that she'd glimpsed walking toward the library at roughly the same time she had been going to dinner. The real version of her—the one that interacted with others, the one who walked without an invisibility cloak and whose whereabouts were kept track of—lived a simple life. She spent time with her friends, studied, ate, and slept. Today, she listened to Percy pontificate on the half-life of semi-permanent Transfigurations.

"So it's really dependent on the material you start with, as much as it is the amount of power that goes into the spell," Percy was saying, gesturing with his quill to a table full of example figures for various materials.

"These numbers are directly proportionate to a material's magical coefficient," Rigel said suddenly, bending closer. "Look, the half-life of walnut is one third that of cypress—because the magical coefficient of cypress is one third that of walnut!"

"The what?" Percy asked, alarmed. "That isn't in any of my review sheets. Is that NEWT material?"

He looked ready to burst a vein, so Rigel said quickly, "It's an Alchemy term, not Transfigurations." NEWT students were growing increasingly touchy, with exams coming up in a matter of weeks.

"What do you know about Alchemy?" Percy asked, settling down visibly and adjusting his glasses calmly as though he hadn't almost taken her head off. "I did know it was related to Transfiguration, but I've never heard them compared mathematically."

"I read about it in my spare time," Rigel said, carefully casual. "In Alchemy, you have to calculate the amount of magic needed to change however many units of the starting material into however many units of the ending material. It's all about balancing materials and magic. Alchemists have worked out standard coefficients for measuring the amount of magic needed to transform materials. They describe how resistant a certain material is to transformation. This sounds like the same thing, only in reverse. How long a material stays Transfigured in a Semi-permanent Transfiguration is inversely related to how resistant the material is. The more resistant it is, the shorter the spell lasts, right?"

"Yes, that's one of the principles," Percy said. "So you're saying the rate that the magic wears off is always a perfect inverse of its magical coefficient? That's very interesting. I wonder how long it took to standardize the math like that. It would be fascinating to read a history of the development of the two fields…" He broke off with a sigh. "I don't have time, though. So much reviewing to do…"

"I'll look for some books in the library, and then tell you which one is the best so you can read it over the summer," Rigel offered.

"You don't have to—"

"I'm interested too," Rigel said firmly. "And I have tons of free time."

"Apparently," Percy said, looking jealous for a moment. "Well, anyway. Where were we?"

"You were about to tell me how being in a magically saturated environment can affect something's half-life," Rigel said.

"Right." Percy cleared his throat. "Well—"

"No one cares!"

Percy scowled across the room at where Fred and George were racing down the stairwell that led up to their dorm room. The both had gigantic hats on their heads. Fred's read, "I'm the Birthday Boy!" while George's said, "No, I Am!"

"You don't even know what we're talking about," Percy rolled his eyes.

"I know you were about to talk," Fred said, plopping down on the table with his legs crossed a moment later.

"My notes," Percy groaned, pushing Fred until he leaned far enough that the Head Boy could rescue his crumpled parchment. "Why do you always do this?"

"Ah-ah-ah," George shook his finger admonishingly as he came to rest one hip against the table on Rigel's other side. "It's our birthday, Perce. You're not allowed to be mad at us."

"You two turned my favorite quill into a hamster on my birthday," Percy said.

"That was a birthday present," George said, blinking.

"Obviously," Fred added with a grin.

"Speaking of which!" Rigel cut in, smiling widely, "I brought your presents with me." She dug into her bag quickly and produced two handsomely wrapped boxes, one green and purple for Fred and one orange and blue for George.

They took them almost gingerly, exchanging surreptitious glances. "What did you get us, then?" George asked, oh-so-casually.

"It's a surprise," she said sweetly. "Why don't you open them?"

"We can open them later," Fred said, laughing nervously.

"But I want to see you open them," Rigel frowned, affecting a sad sort of disappointment. "Don't you like them? I Transfigured the wrapping paper myself."

With pained grimaces, the twins began examining each box carefully. "Looking for traps?" Percy asked, snorting incredulously.

"Well…" George eyed her suspiciously. "Our pup does owe us a prank. And today is April Fool's Day. And it's our birthday. It's pretty much the golden opportunity for revenge."

Fred nodded in agreement, peeling a corner of the paper back on his box and tensing dramatically, as though waiting for a bomb to go off.

"Would I do that to my two favorite tricksters on their birthday?" Rigel asked, one hand placed over her heart in acute dismay.

"I hope so," Percy muttered, smirking a bit.

"We should probably get it over with," George sighed.

"We do deserve it," Fred said, in a tone that would have suited a soldier marching off to war in defense of his homeland.

They ripped back the paper as one and…nothing happened. They stared in confusion down at two identical, completely nondescript cardboard boxes. Exchanging another long look, they each took hold of a flap and pulled, wincing, outward. The boxes opened and a plethora of sweets spilled out rather anticlimactically onto the table.

"Uh…" Fred pawed through his box quickly, noting the wide range of assortment. "Thanks, Rigel."

"Some of them I got at Hogsmeade," she said, pointing them out, "But some of them I baked myself in the kitchens, see?"

George pulled out a bag of fudge with a most nervous expression. "Looks good, Rigel. Thanks."

"Try a piece," Rigel encouraged them, smiling. "It's really good. You like chocolate, right?"

"They love chocolate fudge," Percy said helpfully, grinning along, "Why, at Yule they ate a half a pound each!"

"I, um, had a big dinner," George said warily.

"Me too," Fred said, smiling apologetically. "We'll have some later."

She pulled out The Look. Eyes wide, mouth trembling slightly, she blinked once. "You…don't like it, do you?" She bit the smallest corner of her lip. "It's okay. You…you don't have to eat it. Give it away, I don't mind." She looked down into her lap as though she simply could not bear to look them in the eye as she said it. "I'm sorry. I didn't mean to gross you out. You probably think a potions maker can't bake anything that doesn't taste like slugs."

"We'll have some!" George said desperately, clapping a hand on her shoulder. "Really. We just wanted to save it for later—greedy, that's us, right Fred?"

"Right," Fred gulped. When Rigel looked up she saw him gazing resignedly at the fudge. "Can't wait."

"Oh, good!" Rigel smiled brightly, clapping her hands twice just to see the twins flinch.

They slumped in defeat and each took a chocolate square from their bags. They held them up and gave a 'cheers'-ing motion that bumped the pieces together before tilting their heads back and swallowing the fudge as though knocking back a vial of Skele-gro. They both froze, eyes closed, as a few seconds stretched into a minute, then a minute more. Eventually, they gazed at one another with relieved confusion, then looked at Rigel suspiciously.

"How was it?" Rigel asked, still smiling.

"Ah, pretty good, I think," George said, scratching his head with a slight frown.

"You ate it too fast to tell?" Rigel laughed. "Well, have another piece. Maybe this one will be more memorable."

The twins paled at her words, and shuddered minutely. The suspense appeared to be actually killing them. "We'll eat the rest later," George choked out after a silent inner struggle. "It was greattoseeyouRigelbye!" He ran off toward the dorms with his box of sweets, Fred fast behind him.

"Happy birthday!" she called, waving exaggeratedly after them.

When Percy stopped laughing, he said, "What's really wrong with the sweets?"

"Nothing at all," Rigel said loftily.

"Nothing…?" Percy shook his head, "Really? You know they're going up to the secret lab they think I don't know about to test them extensively, don't you?"

"Then I guess the joke's on them for being so suspicious," Rigel said, smirking a bit.

"That's…pretty funny, actually," Percy said, smirking back. "They'll agonize over this all night. It's a good way to get them back for that Valentine's Day thing."

"Oh, this isn't my revenge," Rigel said, affecting a surprised tone. "Oh, no. My vengeance can wait until they've driven themselves positively mad with suspense. When they start seeing shadows around every corner, when they start questioning if any of it is real or if it's just their paranoia—that's when they won't see me coming."

"Mother always said to beware a Slytherin's revenge," Percy said, looking uneasy, yet impressed.

"She should have said to beware a Marauder's revenge," Rigel said. "It comes ever so creatively."

"I think I'll take care not to stand too close to my younger brothers for a while," Percy remarked, smiling a bit unsurely.

"See that you do." Rigel smiled back.

With the first week in April came yet another Ministry-mandated psychological evaluation. Snape seemed entirely jaded with the process at this point, running through the questions rapidly and without much interest. When they finished the final question, Snape sat back with a satisfied nod.

"This is very good, Rigel," Snape said. She blinked at the use of her first name, which she didn't often hear from her Head of House. "Most students who have been afforded this privilege do not do half as well. Many end up running themselves ragged trying to keep track of everything, and almost all have to deal with increasingly suspicious classmates by this point. Yet you say you haven't been spotted even once somewhere you weren't supposed to be. It is impressive—if worrying, considering that it means your skill at sneaking about it is much greater than I am comfortable with as your Head of House."

She smiled at the wry joke. "What can I say? My classmates are quite unobservant." Also, she had an Invisibility Cloak and the Marauder's Map, which made avoiding the problems that came up for other students granted the use of a time-turner rather easy.

"So it would seem." Snape shook his head disapprovingly. "I shall have to remedy that, if my Slytherins are to be worthy of the name."

"Don't think too badly of them," Rigel said, smirking a bit, "We can't all be paragons of this noble House. It would be unfair to hold them to my standards of Slytherinness."

"Would it now?" Snape asked, sardonic.

"Oh yes," Rigel said sadly. "They'd have to be able to cure incurable sicknesses, slay basilisks, take twelve classes at once while winning the hearts of the people, and talk to snakes."

"Is that all?" Snape raised an eyebrow. "Two Gryffindor feats, one hallmark of Ravenclaw, one ambition worthy of a Hufflepuff, and a single genetic accident to mark your true House. I can't say I'm impressed."

"You haven't heard about my stunning good looks," Rigel said seriously. "I can melt a heart at ten paces."

"Another genetic happenstance," Snape said dismissively. "Your father had looks, for all the good it did him."

Amazed at such a casual, barely contemptuous mention of Sirius, she eagerly continued the banter. "He did land Mum. She was an amazing witch."

After a slightly uncomfortable pause, Snape lifted his chin at her. "Is that your plan, then? Use your looks to attract a mate and then—what? Bask in your self-proclaimed Slytherinness?"

Rigel wrinkled her nose. "What an awful picture." After a laugh, she said, "No, I'm actually hoping everyone forgets about all that nonsense. It's such rubbish, what people say about me."

Snape looked ready to refute that statement, but instead he continued playing along. Someone must have put him in a good mood that evening. "And how will you catch your intended prey if you give up all your remarkable Slytherinness and good looks?" He sneered at the phrase 'good looks' as though it meant 'acute maculopapular dermatitis.'

Rigel shook her head on a self-deprecating chuckle. "I don't have to land anyone—I already have, didn't you know?"

"What?" Snape's eyebrows drew together sharply. "What are you talking about, Rigel?"

Rigel blinked. She didn't know why Snape sounded so serious all of a sudden. She thought they'd been joking around. "I just meant I'm engaged to Harry, that's all. I thought everyone knew."

"You are engaged to your cousin?" Snape sounded completely incredulous. "I thought Black dispensed with that sort of thing? Does he want your children to come out like Bellatrix?"

Rigel's eyebrows rose at that blunt implication. "Our relation is relatively distant," she said after a moment. It's not so unusual."

"It seems entirely premature," Snape said, sneering slightly in his disapproval. She wondered why it mattered to him who she married.

"We've known each other our whole lives," Rigel attempted to explain. "It's not like I don't know Harry."

"Your cousin is all you know," Snape said. "You cling to her like a security blanket."

"I what?" Rigel let out an incredulous laugh. "What gave you that idea?"

"You think the world of her, do not deny it," Snape said sternly. "You two do everything together or for one another, you look like each other, and now you want to marry one another? It's absurd. Whatever gave you the idea that you should tie yourself to the first person you can stand? Just because you know one another well does not mean you are well suited. There is an entire world of people who can show you different perspectives and give you new ideas. It is ridiculous to deny yourself even the possibility of discovering something new about yourself simply for the sake of convenience."

"It's really not like that," Rigel backpedaled, very confused at how this conversation had gotten so weird.

"Whose idea was this?" Snape demanded. "Your father's? Is he really so eager to merge his and Potter's lineages that he would force—"

"No!" Rigel exclaimed, "It's nothing like that, Professor, really. It's just—it's a formality at this point, that's all. I'm not being forced into anything, and neither is Harry."

Snape scoffed. "Harriett Potter should be so fortunate as th—" he paused suddenly, eyes narrowed in thought. "That's it, isn't it? The engagement is a ploy your family has come up with for her sake." His eyes flashed in the most potent of rage. "How dare they use you as some kind of shield against the realities of Potter's choice in bride. Your future is not a birthday cake, to be given out in shares to whoever comes sniffing—"

"Professor!" Rigel raised her voice sharply, realizing he was working himself into a fury. "Please calm down." At his silent glare, she smiled reassuringly. "Thank you for being concerned, but it is misplaced in this case. My future is not in any danger of being, um, eaten by party guests…or whatever that metaphor at the end was. Honestly. I'm sorry I brought it up. It's not important, and it doesn't matter to me at all one way or another. So…you don't have to get mad on my behalf, okay?"

"Someone should," Snape growled.

"I appreciate it," Rigel said again. "I just don't think it's necessary at this point. If I ever feel like my love life is being unduly infringed upon, I shall inform you immediately." They stared at one another for a long moment, and both seemed to realize how ridiculous that sounded. Snape looked away with a snort, and Rigel let out a breathless laugh. "Wow. That was cheesy," she said. "Sorry."

"It is I who should apologize," Snape said, unusually magnanimous. He had seemed nicer, somehow, since that morning with Riddle. Maybe he thought he had to make it up to her. Rigel almost preferred the stern taskmaster she was accustomed to, though. He at least wasn't confusing.

"Let's forget this conversation even happened," Rigel said. "I have to get back before curfew. See you tomorrow, Professor."

"Good evening, Mr. Black," Snape said, sounding more defeated than dismissive.

She left his office wondering if it wasn't Snape who needed the psych evaluation. He had definitely been off, lately. At least around her.

Once she was a fair distance away, she got out the Map and searched for a particular dot. If she wasn't mistaken, it would be somewhere around the Quidditch pitch…there. Still in the stands, as usual. Flint was incredibly predictable, at least in regards to his post-practice routine. Draco was on his way toward the Slytherin common room, so she took the long way through the dungeons to avoid him. He would have questions if he saw her heading away from the common room at this time of night.

After dodging a couple of prefects who had begun patrolling early, Rigel slipped out of the front doors and hurried through the chilly night down to the pitch. Flint was halfway up the stands, scribbling away on a roll of parchment. He looked up as her boots echoed on the stairs, relaxing a bit when he recognized her.

"Come to harass me about spending too much time on Quidditch and not enough on NEWT prep?" he asked lazily, still writing. "You can forget it. Pansy already gave me an earful."

Rigel chuckled. "She usually knows what's best for people. I've actually come to take some of that NEWT prep off your hands, though. Do you have this week's assignments?"

"With me?" Flint asked, looking incredulous. After a pause in which Rigel raised her eyebrows expectantly, he barked out a laugh. "Yeah, I've got them. I usually mail them after practice. No witnesses this late."

"How do you get past the prefects?" she asked, curious.

"I glare at them until they go away," Flint grunted. "Unless it's that walking rulebook Weasley. Him I have to hex."

She favored him with an unimpressed look. "The assignments, Flint?"

He dug deep into one of his pockets and pulled out a wrinkled packet. "That's all of them."

"Good," she said vaguely, paging through them.

"Rigel," Flint said, his tone making her look up. "I mean that's all of them. Ever."

She blinked. "Ever? But…it's only April."

He smirked. "From here on out it's just test-prep for seventh-years. There's some out-of-class work, but it's stuff I actually need to do."

"You're going to do test-prep work?" she wondered if she'd crossed into a parallel dimension recently.

Flint glared at her, and she could see why the prefects avoided him. "I have to get top marks if I want a job that pays enough to support my mother."

Oh. That was…very responsible of him, actually. "How is she?" she asked.

He thought about it for a moment before answering. "She writes more often, now. I think she likes working, and living alone. She seems almost at peace. I have you to thank for that."

"I was glad to help," Rigel said smiling a bit. "Let me know if she mentions anything she needs. I can get hold of Harry any time."

"You've done enough," Flint said gruffly. "Our debts are nearly met. Soon you'll be finished with all of this. Relieved?"

"I suppose," she said, musing. "I don't mind the learning. It has been a very educating experience. I feel almost as though I've done the last three years here already. I'm going to be very bored come fifth year."

"You'll find something to do," Flint scoffed. "Probably read the whole damn library by the time you graduate." She had a brief fantasy of doing just that, and smiled. "Meanwhile, I'll have to keep your ridiculous secret for the rest of my life," Flint complained, rolling his neck as though it pained him at the idea of keeping up his end of the bargain.

Rigel found it hard to be sympathetic. "I'm sure not doing anything will be terribly difficult for you," she said, heavily sarcastic. "Try not to strain anything while you keep your mouth shut."

"It's touching that you've grown to care so much about my wellbeing these three years," Flint remarked.

"Almost as touching as you actually applying yourself to make a better life for your dear, sweet mum," Rigel shot back.

"Watch it," Flint growled.

"Oh, it's too late to intimidate me," Rigel said, "I already know your secret. You toil deep into the night, reading frantically by the light of a single candle, lit by the strength of your love—" Flint took a swing at her, which she ducked, laughing. "You've spent too long on a broom, Flint," she said, clicking her tongue softly. "You're slow on the ground."

"You'll be in the ground if you don't scram before I remember that you haven't done the last of my essays yet," Flint threatened. She waved off his words with a small smile, making her way down the stands once more. "Wait," he called after her suddenly, "How do you avoid the prefects?"

"They avoid me," she called back.

"Brat!" she heard him bark down at her.

"Grump!" she shot over her shoulder.

She honestly couldn't remember why she'd ever been afraid of Flint. He was just a ticked off ogre living in a teenage boy's body. Her face grimaced at that mental image. She supposed on second thought that did sound pretty terrifying. The papers in her pocket rustled as she hurried across the lawn. Soon she'd be pretty much rid of him. It would almost be sad, she thought, when she no longer had Flint's work to keep her so much busier than her peers. She'd been doing his essays since almost the day she started at Hogwarts. They were as much a part of her school experience as moving staircases, at this point.

Perhaps she'd see if Archie would send her his essay topics next year—it might be interesting to compare the styles of schooling, since AIM was considered a progressive, relatively modern institution, while Hogwarts was one of the last bastions of neoclassical Wizarding education.

Lost in plans for the future, she fingered her time-turner eagerly. If she went back just a couple of days, she could probably finish all of Flint's essays by the end of the week. Then she'd be done forever. The next couple of months suddenly seemed full of possibility.

By mid-April the nights were finally warm enough that she didn't need her heaviest cloak to go walking by the forest. Her lessons with Madam Pomfrey were coming along apace. There were very few kinds of physical trauma she couldn't Heal, and the matron had promised her that if she kept up her studies over the summer they could start on ailments caused by jinxes, hexes, curses, and other forms of magic. Pomfrey told her that one of the advantages of learning at Hogwarts was the profusion of such injuries—she'd have plenty to practice on, once she got the basics down.

As was now usual for her nighttime strolls, Treeslider found her within minutes of her entering the tree line. She heard his hissing song through the underbrush as he approached, irrepressibly cheerful.

"Juiccy moussse coming sssoon, nicce and fat, not too chewy," he sang sibilantly. She could tell if she listened very carefully that his little chant rhymed in his language, but her Parseltongue ability sort of jumbled the translation in her head until it sounded like English—silly English, at that.

"Over here," she called out into the trees.

"I know, I know," the boomslang snake hissed back, "I sssmell you."

He came shooting out from a nearby bush and coiled happily around her feet. His green scales flexed adroitly as he climbed her boot, head swaying eagerly toward the pocket she'd stowed the mouse in. "Hungry?" she laughed, fishing the wrapped treat out and holding it up by the tail for his perusal. "I'm afraid I only found a little one thisss night." The mouse was substantial, of course, thick and fresh, but Treeslider had high standards in his food.

"It isss pitiful," the snake agreed mournfully, an eager look in his bulging eyes that gave lie to his disapproval. "I know you did your bessst, Ssspeaker."

"Your approval meansss much," she said. She didn't bother with an eye roll, as she was fairly certain it would be lost on the reptile. "Have you ssseen any animalsss in need of help tonight?"

The snake swayed silently for a moment. "If I have not ssseen any, do I ssstill get the moussse?"

Rigel smiled. "Asss long asss you tell the truth."

The snake made a parody of a nod by bobbing its head. Had he learned that from her or had he always done that? She couldn't remember. "I have ssseen nothing. I ssswear."

"That'sss odd," she said, tilting her head. She'd always been able to find at least one injured animal with Treeslider's help.

"It isss becaussse there are no predatorsss on thisss ssside of the foressst anymore," Treeslider said, eyes fixed only on the mouse.

"None?" Rigel frowned. "That doesssn't make sssenssse."

"It isss sssensssible for them," Treeslider said uninterestedly, "Bad thingsss have been happening to the biggessst, baddessst creaturesss in thessse partsss."

"What kind of thingsss?" she asked.

"Sssome have been found ssslain," Treeslider said, writhing a little uneasily now. "Ssstrong onesss, like the ssspidersss, sssometimesss. Sssome have lossst their witsss, and wander, aimlesssss, without themssselvesss. Sssome, like the horsssemen, jussst left without warning. No one knowsss why."

Rigel dropped the mouse for the snake to devour while she pondered his words. Not many things were big enough to kill an acromantula, and centaurs were not easily run out of their own territory, even a part of it. As to the report of creatures being robbed of their faculties completely…that was worrying. Could it be Pettigrew's doing? She hated to automatically blame him for what could be an unrelated mystery, but she had seen him go into the forest numerous times. She hadn't ever been able to follow him past the edge of the Map, but she had seen him stumble out looking a bit worse for wear on a few occasions.

It seemed a senseless thing, killing creatures in the forest for sport. The centaur's portent hadn't said anything about slaying spiders, as far as she could decipher. It seemed more about controlling great power. She supposed something so vague could be interpreted in a variety of ways, but if Pettigrew thought he needed to kill things to gain power that was undeniably very bad. The other things, though…how would he scare the centaurs away? Did it have something to do with the prophecy he'd somehow gotten a copy of? Perhaps he'd angered them, or threatened them with the jewel somehow. The jewel…could it be responsible for taking away the minds of otherwise sentient creatures? What would be the point of such a power? The more she learned about the Dominion Jewel the more she wondered who on earth would countenance creating something so obviously ill advised.

She was jarred from her thoughts as Treeslider began trembling suddenly on the ground at her feet. Crouching down, she looked over him in concern, but could see nothing obviously the matter. "Indigessstion?" she asked, a bit amused.

"Do not insssult me, Ssspeaker," Treeslider complained, still shaking. "There isss a feeling. It comesss ssso frequently thessse daysss."

"Where doesss it hurt?" she asked, peering down at him.

"Not a feeling of pain," the snake hissed. "It isss a feeling of fear."

"Where does it come from?" Rigel asked, stroking the snake's head soothingly. "From a thought? A memory?"

"Elsssewhere," the snake said, shaking its head agitatedly. "It comesss to the foressst from elsssewhere. It doesssn't belong. The foressst hatesss it."

"But what isss it?" she pressed.

"I don't know," Treeslider said, sending a snake-glare into the trees. "But I wisssh it would leave."

"Isss it in the foressst now?" Rigel asked, looking the direction he was, "Can you sssenssse it?"

"Over there," the snake said irritably, jabbing his shaking tail in the direction of his glare.

In her head the cadence, memorized painstakingly over days of study, rang out unsummoned. The birds and beasts and flowers will conspire through the hours to contend these rising powers. Could it be? She dove into her bag and pulled out the Marauder's Map, scanning it breathlessly. The last she'd checked, Pettigrew had been in his quarters, pacing swiftly back and forth between his rooms. As her eyes devoured the parchment, she realized with dismay that the man was nowhere on the Map. That could only mean he had slipped past her and gone deep into the forest while she'd been walking.

Rigel set off determinedly into the dark, resolved to figure out just what Pettigrew was doing once and for all. If he was killing creatures or wiping their minds somehow, then he needed to be turned over to the authorities at once. Studying a mysterious artifact was one thing. Even accidentally causing a huge ruckus on Halloween that put people's lives in danger didn't condemn him completely. Torturing sentient beings, however, most certainly crossed a line. She couldn't in good conscience wait any longer for the man to come to his senses if things were the way Treeslider intimated.

Treeslider hissed in annoyance, trailing clumsily through the leaves in her wake. "What are you doing, Ssspeaker? Don't go that way. You do not want to encounter that one! He issss not one to ssspeak before roasssting hisss visssitors!"

Rigel slowed her jog, turning with alarm to say, "What? Roasssting?"

Before Treeslider could answer, she heard a roar, plain as day, if rather distant, echo through the trees behind her. What on earth…? As far as she knew, the Forbidden Forest didn't have any animals that roared so loudly within its borders. Had a family of manticores moved in recently?

She rushed toward the sound, knowing as she did so that this was incredibly idiotic. She could hear Snape's voice in head telling her to go back and get a teacher, but really, what professor would just jump up and follow her into the depths of the Forbidden Forest on her word? And how would she explain that she knew Pettigrew was in there because she had a magic map that violated about a dozen rules of privacy in the code of ethics? And what if they came too late? Something big and loud sounded very angry. She didn't know what she'd be able to do if it was a manticore, but she knew what she couldn't do: nothing.

She left Treeslider behind as she sprinted toward the roars, which got louder much quicker than she'd anticipated. It sounded as if the sound was a long way off, until all of a sudden it was right in front of her, as though she'd crossed an invisible barrier that had been muddling the sound. She pushed through a densely growing copse of trees and stumbled to a stop abruptly at the scene on the other side.

Pettigrew was indeed standing on one side of the clearing, but her numb brain nearly overlooked him in its preoccupation with the other occupant. There was a dragon in the forest. There was a Dragon. In the forest. She fell back against the tree behind her, clutching at the bark with shaking fingers. She didn't know enough about dragons to identify the breed, but it dwarfed the clearing with its wingspan, and its clawed limbs dug great swathes of dirt from the forest floor as it roared its rage to the sky. She gazed open-mouthed at the enormous grey-scaled reptile, and all she could think for one hysterical moment was why couldn't it have been manticores?

She drew two deep breaths and forced her thoughts into a linear and useful direction. How did it get here? Her brain made the leap easily—it was one of the escaped dragons that had been running loose since the winter holidays. Why would it come to Hogwarts? She didn't know. Hunger? Had the dragon been killing the acromantula for food? No, focus, why would it stay here? How could it, with no one noticing? It looked like it would be as tall as the trees if it straightened to its full height…oh. She narrowed her eyes at the dragon, now calm enough to take in the enormous metal shackles that hung from its neck and forepaws. Chains ran between them and down into the earth. There was no telling how deep they were embedded, but it had to be at least a hundred feet to keep a dragon grounded.

Why would anyone want to keep a dragon in the Forbidden Forest? Her eyes moved to the other figure in the clearing. Pettigrew stood to one side of the enormous beast, holding something high in his hand, as though warding the creature off. Neither the man nor the dragon had noticed her entrance, each focused entirely on the other in an obvious battle of wills.

She huddled against the tree, in no hurry to jump in the middle of this particular scenario until she knew exactly what was going on. The dragon made a sudden movement with its neck, a sort of horse cough-sneeze that made it shake its head violently. A tendril of smoke escaped its nostrils, but nothing more. It was trying to use its flame, she realized, but something was preventing it. Pettigrew appeared to be panting harshly, his arms trembling even though the red jewel he held could not possibly be very heavy at all. He must be doing something to the dragon with it, she surmised. Pettigrew took a step forward, still holding the jewel between himself and the reptile like a shield—or maybe a sword, from how the dragon flinched back, pawing the ground in agitation.

Pettigrew continued to step forward, pushing the dragon back until it reached the far end of the clearing. With its back against the thick trees and its shackles at the end of their chains, the dragon growled and whined, dropping its head in a cringing motion that didn't seem very dragon-like at all. Before long, Pettigrew stood triumphantly over the dragon's nose, breathing hard but standing tall. In his flush of success, he relaxed his hold on the jewel, lowering it ever so slightly.

In the blink of an eye, the dragon struck. Its talon slashed through the air and caught Pettigrew's leg with a spray of blood. He sprawled to the ground, and the dragon seized immediately on the moment to sink its teeth into the man's arm, raised instinctively to protect his face. The reptile shook its head back and forth like a dog with a bit of rope, flinging Pettigrew across the clearing like a rag doll.

It then surged forward, and Rigel realized Pettigrew, now lying prostrate on the ground, was not yet out of the range that the dragon's shackles allowed. Springing into motion, she grabbed for her wand and shot a summoning charm at his prone form, managing to get him clear of the dragon's teeth just in time. Unfortunately, the reptile's attention then shifted rather predictably to the thing protecting its prey—her.

Rigel had the absurd urge to smile and hold out her hands non-threateningly. Unfortunately, she didn't think a dragon was likely to respond to something that worked on a suspicious dog. The dragon snorted threateningly at her, and a thick funnel of black smoke filled the air between them. The beast seemed to realize at the same time she did that it was able to use its fire now that Pettigrew wasn't suppressing it with the jewel. Her eyes widened as the dragon inhaled deeply, a glint in its snake-like eyes that Rigel recognized as Treeslider's I-am-about-to-eat-this-mouse-look.

"We're the mice," she said breathlessly, frozen before the vision of her impending death. Many ideas raced through her mind in that half-moment. Dodge to the side or roll out of the way—except a dragon's flame was meters wide and she could never get the speed on foot to outrun it. Use the protective potion, she had several doses in her bag—except there was no time to locate one and complete the circle before she was cinders. Try and use the jewel the way Pettigrew had—except she had no idea how it worked. Even as all this ran through her mind, a paralyzing fear turned the blood in her veins to slush. Her airways felt clogged and her mind felt like a blind man grasping and clutching at thin air at he fell from a cliff he'd never seen coming.

She didn't notice her fingers moving, had no awareness that her hands were coming together behind her back, stripping the gloves smoothly away, nor that her jade ring loosened and fell to the dirt even as the dragon's belly turned the glowing red of a newly lit furnace. The next thing she knew for certain was the blast of power that exploded from her chest, throwing her physically backwards into a tree even as it raced in the other direction toward the source of her fear.

The flames met something intangible halfway across the clearing, a pressure that swallowed them into nonexistence as though all the oxygen in its path had been sucked mercilessly away. The dragon ceased its fiery breath much sooner than Rigel would have thought, if she could have thought of anything beyond the numb shock that had subverted her usual neurological pathways. It coughed and hacked pitifully, looking as angry and confused as its reptilian features would allow. Rigel felt the magic come back to her like a blow to the head, sending the world tilting drunkenly as her vision swam and reality became a hard thing to focus on past the rush of energy setting her nerve endings randomly alight.

"What…how…" Pettigrew was attempting to push himself off the ground, looking from her to the dragon with pained confusion. He paled at the sight of the furious reptile. It roared at him defiantly, and he flinched back against the ground violently. "I don't…what's happening…no, no, no," he chanted, shaking his head as though throwing off a terrible memory. His gaze was drawn to the blood-red jewel still clasped in one hand, and he began to tremble, shaking his hand frantically as though trying to shake it away from him, even as his fingers clutched it ever tighter.

"Don't move around so much," Rigel said distractedly, her eyes still mostly on the creature across the clearing. "You'll make your injuries worse."

"My what?" Pettigrew looked entirely confused, until he looked down at his body with a shocked gasp. She wondered how he hadn't noticed getting slashed open by a dragon, but maybe the trauma of being thrown fifty feet had affected his memory. "Oh…oh Merlin…" He attempted to staunch the bleeding on his leg and arm, the latter of which looked like it had be dislocated from its socket. He only had one hand, though: the one attached to the mangled arm, which he could barely move, as the other refused to let go of the jewel. He was starting to hyperventilate and probably about to go into shock, so Rigel attempted to snap him out of it.

"Professor," she said sharply.

"Who, me?" Pettigrew blinked helplessly up at her. "Yes?"

"We have to get out of here," she said, thinking quickly. There was no way Pettigrew could walk on that leg. She shot her wand into the air, intending to shoot red sparks above their location. Instead, her magic shot out a cacophony of light and sound that looked like a firework display shot at close range above the tree line. The dragon let out a roar that was almost a squeal, rubbing its nose to the dirt in acute distress at the loud noise. "Way to piss it off," she groaned at her magic in frustration.

"What?" Pettigrew whimpered.

"Not you," she snapped. She took a deep breath. She had to calm down. She dug through her bag to find one of her protection potions. She was pretty sure it wouldn't hold up against a dragon, as the shield it was based on certainly wouldn't have, but it was better than nothing. She hoped someone had seen that light show. She hoped they could last until help came. "Can you stop it from flaming, Professor?" she asked. She didn't want to encourage him to use the jewel, but if the alternative was dying…well, she really didn't want to die before she at least invented a potion to cure spattergroit or something.

"I…no, no I can't," he said, shaking his head back and forth quickly, even as he looked at the jewel with something like terrified hunger. She didn't know if he was disheartened by his recent failure or trying to somehow pretend he didn't know what she was talking about, but either way it seemed he would be of no help. Swallowing her contempt, she completed the protection circle, shoved a Blood-Replenishing Potion into Pettigrew's good hand, and turned to face the dragon herself.

Normally she would make a better attempt to see to his injuries, but at the moment her magic was everywhere except in her control. It filled the clearing with wind that changed direction every other second, giving the entire clearing a surreal feeling that made it hard to concentrate on the gritty reality of the danger before her. The dragon seemed to be biding its time before it tried roasting her again—and why hadn't she stopped to let Treeslider explain that there was a dragon in the woods before she rushed ahead?

There was no guarantee help was coming. She needed to think faster. What did she know about dragons? Not a lot, except that in the stories Ron told about his brother Charlie they were a lot bigger. It was also a bit more docile than she might have expected. It had been at least five minutes since it sent fire their way. Had Pettigrew damaged its flame-maker somehow? Or maybe…she thought back to every little comment Ron had thrown out in their conversations. It wasn't a fully-grown dragon at all. It—it was an adolescent dragon, she realized. That's why it was so small, compared to what she'd heard of adult dragons. That was why it needed so long between jets of fire, too—it hadn't developed that ability fully, yet.

She looked over the creature in a new light, taking in the spindly legs and tapered torso. It looked sick, she thought. How long had it been here? It was probably starving, if most of the animals had left this part of the forest and it couldn't move beyond this clearing. No wonder it was so angry. The creature was probably severely weakened and nearing desperate straits in regard to its own survival. She wondered if it had ever been out on its own before it escaped the reserve. It had probably been born and bred in captivity.

She shook her head sharply and marshaled her defenses as smoke began seeping from the reptile's nostrils once more. This was no time to be feeling sorry for something that could bite her in half without trying. She pulled on her magic insistently, hoping beyond hope that it would come to her defense again. Between it and her protective potion, they might just survive.

As the fire raced toward them across the clearing, she heard Pettigrew squeak in terror from the ground beside her before his body twisted in the corner of her vision and then—disappeared. She tore her gaze from the flames jettisoning toward her in sheer disbelief. Had he just Disapparated? No, there was a small rat curled on the ground where he'd just lain, bleeding out from wounds on two of its limbs, a deep red jewel almost as big as its body on the ground next to it. Idiot, was all she could think, even as her eyes darted back to the more pressing matter of fire blooming into white-hot doom before her protective barrier. He was going to die if he stayed transformed with injuries like that. And a rat would burn to death faster than a human, anyway.

The flames were so close she could feel the hair on her head trying hard to catch fire. They didn't penetrate the shield, though, and whether that was because her magic lent a helping hand or because the protective potion was strong enough to stand up to an immature dragon's flame, she didn't know. As the dragon roared its frustration to the sky, she thought it was time to take things on the offensive while she could. Not many spells could penetrate a dragon's thick hide, but she could attack it peripherally, she thought. If its reaction to the firework display her magic had put on was anything to go by, it had sensitive hearing. That strength was about to become a weakness.

Mentally apologizing to the beast, she cast a Wailing Charm with as much power as she dared. It wasn't as powerful as a Caterwauling Charm, but she didn't know how to cast one of those. It didn't matter, in the end. Her magic took the Wailing Charm and magnified it so effectively that she lost hearing entirely as her eardrums burst with a ringing pain that sent her to her knees. She frantically gasped out a Muffliato, but couldn't hear to know if she'd been successful or not. She didn't even notice she had been screaming until her throat began to hurt.

The only saving grace was that the dragon was affected just as badly, if not worse, than she was. She watched through the tears that filled half her vision as the reptile thrashed and writhed wildly in its bindings. She mouthed apologies to no one in particular, forcing herself to keep looking at the poor beast, knowing that its pain was her fault. The shackles were beginning to cut into its skin, scales fracturing in various places where the dragon lashed mindlessly against the metal. Its mouth was open wide, and she knew if her ears weren't filled with blood they would be filled with its guttural cries.

As she watched, the strain on the thick iron links finally became too much and one shackle blew apart in a spray of metal. The dragon noticed something different amidst the pain that drove it, and struggled all the harder against the other chains. She wondered if she shouldn't just release it. It was awful, locking the thing up like that. Reason intruded, however. Where would it go? What if it hurt someone else? What if it ate all the goats in Hogsmeade or something? An image of a thousand goats bleating from the inside of a dragon's belly drifted across her mind before she refocused it forcibly.

Her choice was taken as the other shackles gave way at last. With scarcely a moment's pause, the dragon shot off the ground and exploded out of the trees, wheeling away into the night. She realized in immediate retrospect that it would want to get as far away from the insanely loud noise as possible. That was good. It would lick its wounds somewhere and she could tell…tell someone about it. Sometime.

She was too dizzy to stand, so she crawled unsteadily toward where the rat lay several paces away. It was unconscious, probably because of the extent of its injuries. She poked it gently, but insistently, until it began to stir. She had to tumble backwards as Pettigrew retook his human form without warning, clutching at his own ears, which she guessed from the blood leaking out had probably also been ruptured.

"Sorry," she mouthed. He didn't appear to notice, focused only on his own injuries—and, of course, the jewel, which he snatched up from the ground and stuffed in his pocket with a guilty desperation that she found a bit sad, considering the situation.

She took out the antidote to the protection potion, not sure what would happen if she tried using her magic to make a ward-disruptor. She'd probably electrocute them both. Once free of the circle, she made her way, clumsily and very slowly, back to where she'd been standing before her ring had come off. How had that happened, anyway? Had she unconsciously known what to do? More likely her magic had taken advantage of the mental absence caused by her terror, she thought darkly.

She found her gloves fairly easily and shoved them in her pocket. Now where did that ring land? The ground swam in and out of focus too fast for her to see effectively. She knelt and began shifting her hands through the grass. After a moment, the bent position of her head became too much for her stomach, and she lost her dinner, just barely remembering to turn her head to the side so that she didn't throw up right where she was looking for her ring. Digging through a pile of her own puke was probably the first thing on the list of things she didn't want to do right now. Second was falling unconscious before she got her magic back under control. The thought of it raging around free while she wasn't there to attempt to corral it was sickening.

She coughed out the last of the bile in her stomach and got back to searching. Eventually her fingers found it, barely visible in the green grass of the clearing. She paused before grasping it fully, remembering what happened last time. She focused all her attention on a tree on the other side of the clearing, channeling anger, fear, anything she could pull from the dredges of her emotions, strung out though they were. Her magic perked up like a hungry dog at the sudden intensity of the emotions she let pour over her. She felt its intention shift, and the wind started to divert itself away from her. It seemed curious at first, not sure why the tree was important. She supposed she wasn't manufacturing emotions sincerely enough. She imagined the tree infested with flesh-eating slugs, focused all her attention on the disgust she felt at the idea. Her magic roared as it recognized the challenge.

It swept across the clearing eagerly, zeroing in on the tree Rigel was making the center of every prominent thought, even as her fingers twitched toward the jade ring—which she was not thinking about! Her magic shuddered to a sudden halt, its attention evolving violently midway to the tree. Cursing, she abandoned the pretense and grabbed for the ring as fast as she could, shoving it onto her finger so hard she jammed the knuckle. The pure, unadulterated rage that coursed through her as the magic was forcefully reabsorbed into her skin left her newly nauseated. She gagged and dry heaved for several minutes before she felt stable again. Or, as stable as someone with no balance in their inner ear could feel.

She took a moment to curse her bad luck at being in such a predicament, and her own stupidity for rushing into such a situation, and Riddle in particular simply because she didn't believe all that demolition in the classroom had helped her magic at all. If anything, it was more powerful and even harder to control, now.

She would gather her strength for a moment, then figure out a way to get her and Pettigrew back to the castle. She felt a sudden rush of heat behind her that made the hairs on the back of her neck stand up. She spun on her knees, gasping at the way the world whirled on the wrong axis. Had the dragon come back? How hadn't she noticed it landing? Was it going to—?

Rigel blinked at the sight before her. It was a phoenix, not a dragon, and attached to its tail feathers was the headmaster himself, looking serious indeed as he surveyed the clearing. His sharp eyes took in Pettigrew lying in a pool of blood, Rigel sitting next to a puddle of her own vomit, the shackles on the other side of the clearing, the scorch marks on the ground where the vegetation had been razed, and the remains of the protection circle she'd broken. He strode forward swiftly, saying something she couldn't hear.

She pointed to her ears carefully, almost poking herself in the eye in her dizziness. "I can't hear," she said, probably too loudly. "There was a dragon. I ruptured our ears running it off. Professor Pettigrew needs a Healer." The headmaster looked both concerned and incredibly perplexed. She supposed some of that might have come out garbled.

Nevertheless, the headmaster moved without delay. He stepped forward to grasp Pettigrew's uninjured arm gently, then the two men and Fawkes disappeared in a flash of fire. A bit of the tension in her relaxed. The headmaster would send someone for her. She was going to be okay. Even as she thought that, Dumbledore was back, this time with a hand held out for her. With a weak smile, she took it, and then warmth and heat enveloped her. When she opened her eyes, it was to the blinding white of the Hospital Wing.

Madam Pomfrey had her hands on Rigel's head almost before she had registered where she was. She could see the matron's mouth moving, but it was many minutes before she could hear the tirade the older woman was heaping on her ears.

"—kind of reckless, ridiculously thickheaded nonsense is it to cast a Wailing Charm so loud it breaks half the castle windows? You're lucky there's anything left of your eardrum to repair!" she seethed, her wand jabbing Rigel in the ear pointedly with every other word. She was pretty sure that wasn't part of the healing process.

"I'm sorry," she muttered, "It's not like I had any choice. There was a bloody dragon chained up in the Forbidden Forest!"

"And just what were you doing in the Forbidden Forest, young man?" Pomfrey demanded, glaring.

Headmaster Dumbledore chose that moment to cut in. "I would appreciate an explanation to that as well, Mr. Black."

Right. Of course he would. Because being almost fried by a dragon wasn't enough for Fate. She had to get detention, too.

"I was walking near the edge of the woods when this snake I know told me that someone in the forest was in trouble," she invented, sticking just close enough to the truth that Dumbledore wouldn't be able to tell she lied unless he employed some serious Legilimency. "I did think about getting a teacher, but I thought it would be better to respond quickly. I followed the sound of roaring and found a dragon in one of the forest clearings. Professor Pettigrew was trying to fight it off, but he got hurt, so I stepped in to get him out of harm's way. It…got complicated after that. Basically I made a really loud noise and the dragon broke free of the shackles and flew off. You should probably send someone looking for it. It's probably injured and angry, but also desperately hungry if I had to guess, so they should probably bring it a goat or something. Do dragons eat goats?"

"He's delirious," Pomfrey sighed, "Goats and dragons. What nonsense."

"Hmm," Dumbledore said, stroking his beard slowly. "It seems Professor Pettigrew is fortunate to have such a quick-thinking rescuer. You may want to go easy on the noise charms next time, though."

"Next time!" The nurse glared daggers at the headmaster. "There will be no next time if he wants to be treated in this infirmary."

"Teach me how to repair eardrums and I'll do it myself next time," Rigel said, smiling fondly up at the prickly woman.

"You won't either," Pomfrey snapped. "You're not patching yourself up while I'm around."

"Whatever you say, Madam Pomfrey." She grinned, watching the matron's eyes narrow as she realized she'd been tricked.

"Bed rest," the nurse growled. "Overnight. Now."

"Yes, ma'am," Rigel said, settling back into the bed she'd been laid up on.

Dumbledore gave her one last, penetrating look before nodding farewell and requesting Madam Pomfrey fetch him when Pettigrew woke up from his Healing-induced sleep. As Pomfrey shut off the lights to the ward, Rigel slipped gratefully into oblivion. In the morning she would figure out the rest of it—what to do now that she knew Pettigrew was using the jewel for ill, how to explain to Pansy that she'd managed to piss off a dragon since they last spoke, and how to justify to herself the idiotic choices she'd made over the last few hours. Her last thought before falling asleep was that for once she hadn't used the time turner when she should have. If she'd used it right when she realized there was something wrong in the forest, she could have gone back and gotten help before any of it even happened.

That was one mistake she swore she would not make again.

When she woke next, the Hospital Wing was as silent as a graveyard. The windows let in the barest of moonlight, and she wondered if she'd been asleep a few hours or a whole day. She slipped out from the blankets, shivering slightly as the cold tile met her bare feet. She didn't know who had taken her shoes off, but it relieved her to note that nothing else on her person had been removed, save her bag, which hung from the chair by her bed.

She brushed past the curtain quietly, aware that there might be another sleeping nearby. A bed two down from hers with the curtains drawn tightly around it confirmed her suspicion. Pettigrew was still recovering from his injuries, too, then. She stood there for a moment in the semi-darkness, thinking. After all she knew now, there was nothing else she could do. It didn't seem right, but it was definitely the course of action that made the most sense.

She crept closer to Pettigrew's bed and slid back the curtain slowly. He was terribly still, his breathing even, but relatively shallow. She supposed the Healing had probably taken a lot out of him; he wasn't exactly in the peak of physical condition to begin with. On the chair beside him was his coat, stained with blood and grass and scorch marks. She kept her breathing soft and moved toward it. Inside one of the pockets would be the jewel, unattended for probably the first time since Pettigrew had come across it.

Resolved, she began rifling through the pockets carefully, sending glances over at Pettigrew's sleeping form every so often to be sure he lay undisturbed. She found no trace of the jewel, until she came to a small, mokeskin pouch in the innermost pocket. She clenched her fist around it, feeling nothing within but knowing that an undetectable extension charm was likely at work. She gritted her teeth with a feeling of defeat. Everyone knew mokeskin pouches could only be opened by their owners. Even if she took the pouch, it would disappear from her hands the moment it sensed it was getting too far from its master's reach. They were incredibly rare, but she had to admit it was the perfect place for Pettigrew to keep the jewel. Until he took it out himself, if could quite literally not be taken from him.

As she was putting the pouch back, she heard a low groan break through Pettigrew's lips. She froze, but her mind was getting used to thinking quickly. She took the coat in both hands and draped it over Pettigrew's supine form just a moment before his eyes opened, unfocused until they zeroed in on her embarrassed smile.

"Sorry," she said. "You were shivering so hard the bed frame rattled. I thought maybe you were cold."

"I was?" Pettigrew struggled to sit up, wincing and moaning at the stiffness in his hurt limbs. He caught sight of the coat and clutched it with his good hand. "Yes. Thank you." His eyes darted between her and the coat frantically, and she knew he was wondering if she was telling the truth.

"Well, I'm glad you're okay," she said, backing away a bit. "That was a close call, huh? I mean, with the dragon and all. Heh."

"Yes," he said, licking his lower lip nervously. "I…did they ask you what happened? What did you say?"

She couldn't help but think he really ought to work on his subtlety, if he was going to play such dangerous games. "Oh, yeah," she said, outwardly nonchalant. "I told them how I heard the roaring and went running toward it. I tried to help when I saw you were being attacked. Guess I made things worse, though, huh? Sorry about bursting your eardrums like that. I misjudged the power of my noise spell." She laughed sheepishly. "Say, what were you doing in the forest, anyway? Pretty bad luck to run into a dragon like that."

She couldn't let on that she thought he'd been the one to tie the dragon up like that. Now that she could think clearly without fearing for her life, it seemed likely that Pettigrew had been practicing his mastery of the jewel on the dragon—and any other creatures he happened to come across, if Treeslider could be believed.

"I…was tending to some of the creatures," he squeaked out after a suspiciously long pause. "I am the Care of Magical Creatures professor, after all. I was as surprised as anyone to find a dragon in that clearing. It just attacked me! I could have been killed!"

Anyone who came across it could have been killed, she thought irritably. It was just so irresponsible. "Well, good thing Dumbledore rescued us, then," she said, affecting a yawn. "I'm going back to bed. Get well soon, Professor."

She trotted back to her own bed and closed her eyes, pretending to a tiredness she didn't feel. Had he bought her act? There was no way to be sure. She would have to keep her distance for the next couple of weeks, until he relaxed his guard.

Madam Pomfrey was an eagle-eyed old bird, and extremely watchful when it came to things she considered 'in her nest,' but Rigel was able to slip past her with the help of the time-turner and her Invisibility Cloak. She'd be back before the matron even missed her, and in the meantime she had a job to do.

The Owlery was loud and crowded with birds, but she blocked all that out as she scribbled a brief note that, she hoped, would be enough to put an end to this jewel nonsense once and for all.

To: Aurors searching for the Dominion Jewel

Peter Pettigrew, employed at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, seen attempting to control creatures in the Forbidden Forest with a blood-red stone.

-A very concerned citizen

Chapter 14

Rigel wasn't in the Hospital Wing for very long, but her stay wasn't short enough to get out of explaining to her friends exactly what had put her there. She attempted to shrug off their concern with a vague, "I got sick, that's all," but Pansy and Draco knew her too well, it seemed.

"You suddenly got sick on the same night something in the forest created a wave of sound so strong it shattered most of the windows on that side of the castle?" Draco asked, pausing in putting pepper on his eggs to gesture to where one side of the Great Hall was warded off temporarily to prevent students from messing with the broken glass until architects were brought in to fix them.

"Yes," Rigel said, pursing her lips.

"So I guess Blaise was wrong when he said you were probably down by the forest when it happened," Pansy said, examining her nails casually.

Rigel aimed a slow, betrayed look at Blaise, who shrugged beneath her accusing gaze and said, "I only deduced that it was likely, considering how frequently you go walking down there in the evenings. The odds of you getting into an unrelated accident at the same time all those windows broke are lower than the odds of you being directly involved in whatever happened."

"You wouldn't say that if it were someone else," she complained.

"No one else has luck like you do, Rigel." Blaise smirked. "The odds on you are one of a kind."

"So you were involved," Pansy pressed, looking disappointed. "Rigel, what have we said about—"

"It doesn't matter," Rigel sighed. "It's over now, so what's the point in making you worried over something that already happened? Yes, I was walking by the forest last night. I was close enough to whatever made the noise that it ruptured my eardrums and I had to go to the nurse to have it fixed. Do you feel better now that you know?"

Pansy sniffed and looked away, but Draco said, "Yes, we do. Thank you."

She shook her head in amusement and got back to her breakfast. Her friends were equally endearing and ridiculous, sometimes.

"Do you know what happened to Professor Pettigrew, then?" Theo asked, pointing his knife up at the Head Table. "He's missing this morning and I heard his classes have been canceled."

"He was in the Hospital Wing when I was there," she said honestly. "I guess he ran into some trouble in the forest. Maybe he broke the windows."

Theo was content to debate the likelihood of that with Millicent and Blaise for the rest of breakfast, leaving Rigel to eat her porridge in peace.

"You know we're just worried about you, right, Rigel?" Pansy asked as they were finishing up. "I know we've seen a lot more of you this year, but it still feels like you're a bit distant, somehow. You can talk to us, if you need to."

Rigel smiled with quiet gratitude, but knew that she couldn't, in fact, talk about this with her friends. So many powerful people wanted to get their hands on this jewel. Riddle and the SOW Party wanted it as badly as the goblins did. If she told her friends everything that was happening, they'd be tempted to tell their parents where the jewel was and what it did. Rigel was wary of even telling Dumbledore about the jewel—she didn't think anyone should have such a thing. The best thing was to tell the Auror Department. They would make the right decision on what to do with it. Or at least, they would do what was legally right, which was more than she could presume about any of the other parties. Maybe they'd send it to the Department of Mysteries and let them tinker curiously with it for all eternity. Anything but hand it over to one of the leaders in the political quasi-war that had quietly taken over their world.

"Thanks, Pansy," she said, placing her napkin on the table slowly. "I'm not even thinking about it anymore, though. I'm more worried about the upcoming exams. Professor Snape hasn't told me what he wants to do for my individual Potions final, but it's sure to be grueling, knowing him."

"I'm certain you'll do just fine," Pansy said, still looking a bit concerned, but transitioning topics gracefully nonetheless. "Professor Snape knows your level, after all. He won't make it impossible."

"You say that like you don't know his expectations at all," Rigel grinned.

"He only has such high expectations because you keep meeting them, Rigel," Pansy said admonishingly.

"I'll have to do better at being a disappointment in the future, then," she said wryly.

"Or you could just resign yourself to people thinking highly of you," Draco drawled. "Oh, wait, I forgot who I was talking to for a moment there."

"What's that?" Rigel cupped a hand to her ear curiously. "I can't hear anything over the swelling in my head. Is that you, Draco? You look so small from up here."

"Shut it." Draco nudged Rigel with an amused grin. "Let's get going, before we're late to class."

They filed out of the Great Hall and the day went on, as most days do, in complete normalcy.

A few weeks passed, April bloomed into May, and the days seemed to grow shorter as examinations grew closer. The OWL and NEWT students could be seen traveling in packs, shooting information back and forth aloud in frantic, ever-quavering undertones. The Quidditch season was officially ended, with Slytherin once again in possession of the Quidditch Cup. The House Cup would be theirs, too, if no one messed up royally between now and the end of the year.

Pettigrew was teaching once more, but his extracurricular movements had changed quite a bit since the night he almost became dragon food. The portly professor no longer went to the library at all. He didn't spend long hours pacing in his rooms as he used to, either. He was almost nightly in the forest, and Rigel perpetually attempted to work up the nerve to go out and see what he was doing. She couldn't bring herself to do it, though. She didn't want to go back into that forest ever, if she could help it.

It felt like a betrayal of her principles, sitting in the castle and watching Pettigrew's dot drop off the edge of the Map every evening. He was probably torturing some creature or other and she was doing nothing to stop it. What good would she do, though, wandering through the forest and getting caught up in whatever incredibly foolish thing he was attempting? The dragon had been more than enough hint that she was in over her head, thank you very much. Every day she waited for Aurors to come through the Entrance Hall and demand to know Pettigrew's whereabouts. Every day she was disappointed. Didn't they read their mail at the DMLE?

How long could she afford to wait before taking more drastic measures? Until he got control over a giant and squashed half the school? Until Riddle got his hands on the jewel and changed his mind about being a politician after all and went on to rule the world? Until Pettigrew got himself eaten by a lethifold? Actually, she thought darkly, that might solve a lot of problems all at once. As long as the jewel got eaten, too.

She shook her head and picked up her pace, knowing she had to hurry if she wanted to get to her Magical Theory class on time. She would wait a few days more. The Aurors were probably just taking the time to marshal their case against the man. They would come before the week was out.

Just when she had started to think Pettigrew had forgotten all about her presence that night in the woods, reality intruded and reminded her that power never went unnoticed. Not even by half-dead half-wits who, in her opinion, ought to have had other things on their minds at the time.

She was up late in the common room, going over their Charms notes one last time before bed with Draco and Pansy, when Rosier and Rookwood dropped by their table on their way through. Rigel looked at Rosier expectantly, as he almost never let a chance to say something pithy pass him by, but the golden-eyed boy was quiet, deferring, unusually, to Rookwood as they approached.

"Sorry to disturb your studying," Rookwood said, his low voice rumbling in the air between them. "I have a matter I think Rigel needs to hear."

Rigel straightened from her textbook and blinked inquisitively at the upperclassman. "What is it?"

"Are you acquainted with Professor Pettigrew?" Rookwood asked, eyes deep and searching.

"Not well," she said carefully. "Why?"

"He held me after class today to ask about you," Rookwood told her, a slight frown on his face. "I suppose he heard we were friendly."

"You can say 'friends,'" Rigel smiled slightly.

"Friends, then," Rookwood smiled ever so slightly back. "Pettigrew asked after you, in any case. Said he was an old friend of your parents and was disappointed not to have you in his class. Wanted to know how you were doing, lately. I found it odd, so I thought I'd mention it."

Rigel swallowed thickly. That was… not good. She had played as dumb as a rock after the whole dragon thing. Was he still suspicious? Or just wondering if she'd told anyone what she'd seen?

"Pettigrew asked me about you, too," Pansy said suddenly, eyes sharp. "I didn't think to mention it, because it was in passing, but that's a little strange."

"What did he ask you?" Rigel asked, clenching a fist under the table in nervous anticipation.

"Nothing that made any sense," Pansy said, frowning. "He asked how you were doing in classes and if I thought you were a good wizard. I said I wouldn't be friends with you if you weren't. It was supposed to be a joke, but I don't think he got it."

"Hmm," Rigel said, noncommittally. Her mind was racing. What was Pettigrew looking for? Evidence that she was clever enough to figure out his game?

"Do you know him at all, Rigel?" Draco asked, likely picking up on her unease. "Why is he asking questions about you? You said you only saw him that one time in the Hospital Wing. Did you talk?"

"Not really," Rigel prevaricated. "He is an old friend of my family, so maybe…he's just curious about his friend's son. I'm sure it's nothing."

"Keep away from him," Rookwood advised unexpectedly. "I didn't like the look in his eye. He's up to something."

"If you say so," Rigel said, now a little disturbed. She would have to make extra certain he never caught her watching his movements. Lately, she kept such a distance that there was no way he could have—unless he guessed that Sirius had given his son the Marauder's Map. She blanched, fighting to keep a normal look on her face even as Draco glanced sharply at her. If Pettigrew deduced that, he would have every reason to suspect she knew more than she should. "I'm not in his class," she forced herself to say calmly. "I can't see how we'd cross paths anyway."

Rookwood didn't look entirely reassured, but he and Rosier bid them goodnight all the same. After they left, Draco put down his quill. "You're afraid of this Pettigrew fellow," he said. "Why, if you don't know him?"

"I…" What could she say? "I wonder if he might hold a grudge against me, because of the way he fell out with my dad and uncles. It was before the Marauder joke line made it big, so it's possible he resents not sharing in the success of that venture, which he was technically a part of when it started, I think."

"Oh," Draco said, relaxing a bit. "You think he might be like that Lee Jordan fellow, right? You wouldn't think people would get so worked up over pranking supplies, honestly. Whatever happened to Jordan anyway? Did they catch him after the gala?"

"He ran," Rigel said, having heard the story from her dad before coming back from break. "His father had no idea where he'd gone and, after questioning, it was determined that Jordan Sr. wasn't involved in the assassination attempt on Ogden. Lee was the one behind it, but they haven't tracked him down yet. He'll run out of places to hide, eventually."

"Well, I'm sure Pettigrew won't turn out like that," Pansy said reasonably. "He's a bit strange, and getting stranger as the weeks pass, but he doesn't seem like the type to hold violent grudges. He can barely remember who's turned in their homework and who hasn't. I'm half afraid he'll just assign everyone a random grade at the end of the term."

As Draco reassured Pansy that it was worth studying anyway, Rigel lost herself in worry. Pettigrew had moved at least some of his attention onto her. That didn't bode well. On the one hand, it might detract from the time he focused on the jewel. On the other, it was one more person paying attention to her now. This year really hadn't been a success on the lay-low-o-meter.

Late one evening after brewing in her lab, Rigel stopped by the kitchens on her way to the Come and Go Room. She was absolutely famished. Her usual seat was waiting for her already, and she was beginning to wonder if the house-elves knew about her time-turner. They never seemed surprised that she ate sometimes three full meals in the kitchens with them, despite the fact that she was fairly sure students weren't supposed to eat outside of the Great Hall.

Maybe they'd been informed to cater to the increase in calories she'd found use of the time-turner caused her to crave. Even if she were using the time-turner more judiciously, she thought she'd have to add at least one meal a day to keep herself appropriately fueled. In any case, she hadn't yet got up the nerve to ask. If they didn't know about the time-turner, that would constitute a willful breaking of one of the more stringent of the Department of Mysteries' rules.

Binny was there at her side moments after she sat down, launching into a story about one of the laundry elves who mixed the uniforms for the Gryffindor and Hufflepuff teams into the same load and turned both a lurid orange. "He is being new," Binny giggled in French. "He is not fitting in very well, but I is thinking him funny."

"He sounds entertaining," Rigel said, smiling. She poked a piece of chicken around her plate half-heartedly. Even after all this time, she still hadn't developed a taste for meat. "I hope the others aren't being too hard on him."

"He is being recently dismissed from his family," Binny said, quieter now. "We is understanding."

She nodded distractedly. "That's good."

Binny nudged her with a toe under the table when she lapsed into silence. "Is something being wrong?" She had switched back to English and was using her wide eyes to solemnly intimidate her into answering.

Rigel was ready to brush off the elf's concern, used to not talking about her problems, but something in Binny's earnest gaze made her pause. Why not, really? Who would Binny tell? She never saw anyone besides the Weasley twins down here, and even they were rare visitors. Unlike her friends and Professor Snape, Binny had absolutely no stake in any of this mess. She was also extremely respectful of people's privacy. Binny wouldn't ask pointed questions or try to pry out any more information than Rigel was willing to give.

She smiled at the elf a bit tentatively. "Are you sure you want to know?"

"I is giving very good advice," Binny told her firmly.

"Well," Rigel said slowly, not sure quite where to begin. "Do you remember me telling you about the difficulties I was having with my magic before? Back when we first met?"

Binny nodded quickly, ears flapping. "You is thinking your magic isn't listening to you, but I is telling you that you is not listening to it."

Rigel blinked. "Yes, that's right. You have a great memory, Binny."

"All house-elves is having good memories." Binny sniffed. "It is being necessary for us."

"Makes sense," she said. "Well, I thought I had gotten my magic under control, but this year it sort of broke loose again over the summer—"

"On Young Sir's birthday," Binny said knowingly. "You is being thirteen, now, yes?"

"That's right," Rigel said again, amazed at the elf's perceptiveness. "It grew out of my control again, so I got this ring made to suppress the excess, so I could manage it more easily."

Binny shot the gloves on her hands a nasty look. "That is being a bad idea, Young Sir."

"Just Rigel is fine," Rigel said, frowning. "And yeah, that's what people keep saying. I thought they just didn't approve of me wasting my potential, so I didn't listen, because it's none of their business what I do with my magic, really, but I'm starting to think it isn't a good idea for other reasons."

"It isn't being healthy," Binny said sternly. "It is being like binding ears."

"Like what?" she asked, not having heard such an expression before.

Binny grew very grave. "In old times, it is being the practice to bind the ears of house-elves when they is born. Some wizards is thinking the elves is looking sweeter with little ears all tucked away, but it is hurting baby elves and stunting growth of ears forever. When ears isn't growing properly, they isn't working properly, and elves is being less effective servants, so eventually the tradition is dying out. Young Sir's magic is needing room to grow. Binding magic is being like binding ears—silly and hurtful."

"It doesn't hurt," Rigel protested weakly. Was such a comparison really the case?

"It isn't hurting you," Binny admonished. "You is being like old wizard masters. Your magic is being like baby elf. It is being hurt and you is not noticing, because you is thinking you is knowing better."

Rigel winced. "Is that why the magic is angry with me? I thought it didn't like being kept under control. Am I really hurting it? Can magic feel things like that?"

"I is not knowing," Binny said slowly. "But I is knowing this: wizards is not being given magic they is not being able to control. Nature is knowing what is best. You is meant to be trusting nature, trusting your magic, and trusting yourself. If you is not trusting it, it is not trusting you."

It was hard to trust something that liked to destroy things as much as her magic did. Binny may as well ask her to trust a rabid animal. And she wasn't just trusting it with her own safety—she was trusting it with the safety of everyone around her. She would sooner put an actual rabid dog into her baby sister's cot than rely blindly on the faith that her magic, more powerful than could possibly be natural, wouldn't turn on her will without warning.

"Nature doesn't always know what it's doing," Rigel said eventually. "Sometimes accidents of nature happen and they're no good for the species as a whole. I'm one of them."

"Nature isn't making accidents," Binny argued. "It is carefully preparing and planning all through time. Sometimes it is trying something special. It is being a test, not an accident, and nature is giving the answers, too. You is just needing to look."

Rigel smiled a bit at the elf's wise tone. "How do you know?"

"Everyone is knowing this, deep down," Binny said, giving her an odd look. "Maybe wizards is forgetting, but they is knowing if they is remembering."

She worked through that sentence in her head for a moment. Was she talking about cultural knowledge or instinct? "Were you born knowing this?"

Binny shook her head. "It is being obvious, if you is paying attention." The elf struggled for words visibly before saying, "You is comparing wizards to Muggles, yes?"

"Okay," she said, tilting her head, "on what terms?"

Binny tapped her head. "Smarts. You is coming to Hogwarts when you is eleven. Is you knowing any muggles at eleven?"

"Just my…er, my cousin's cousin," she said, thinking of the brief interactions she'd had with the Dursley family.

"Is this Muggle being like you?" Binny asked. "I is not talking about magic. I is talking about brains. Is he being smart like you? Is he thinking like you?"

"Well, no," Rigel said, frowning, "But he isn't a good example of Muggles in general when it comes to brains."

"You is thinking that, but I is guessing he is being average," Binny said, wagging her finger. "Muggles is not having magic from birth. They is not growing up with great power being at their fingers. They is not needing to be smart until later. Magical children is needing brains sooner. They is needing not to be killing themselves before they is learning, yes?"

"You're saying magical children develop at a faster rate mentally than their Muggle counterparts?" Rigel thought this over with interest. It was a very compelling theory, biologically speaking.

"On average," Binny prevaricated. "Yes. Nature is knowing that wizards is having more dangerous childhood, so nature is making wizards smarter sooner, so wizards is living to make more wizards."

Binny was talking about an evolutionary mechanism in terms of a sentient being of nature, Rigel realized. When pared down to the theory itself, she had to admit it made a certain amount of sense. The idea that magic would have no effect on a child's development would be harder to swallow, she realized. A magical child lived with the magic constantly, even from its time in the womb. It probably did do something to the brain. Was it an effect of the magic itself or of the body's adaptation to the magic, though? Did the magic make its host smarter so that it would be better utilized or did the host grow smarter by necessity of dealing with the magic? She was now desperately curious about the answer.

She would write Archie, she decided. He could talk to his friend Hermione and ask whether she had felt significantly more developed than her peers before joining the Wizarding world. She had never considered her peers' level of maturity unusual, but she supposed she wouldn't notice something like that, ensconced as she was among people like her.

"When do Muggles catch up?" she wondered aloud.

Binny shrugged, "I is not knowing so much about Muggles. I is guessing once they is being on their own."

Sometime around the age a wizard would finish school, then, she presumed. Interesting. She couldn't imagine the catastrophe it would be if wizards didn't gain a measure of maturity until well into their teens. There would probably be a lot of dead teens, she realized with morbid interest.

"The point is being," Binny said pointedly, pulling her back from her thoughts, "that nature is giving wizards what they is needing to deal with the magic they is having. Same as house-elves is being given good memories for the things they is needing to be doing. Thestrals is being given wings for flying and grindylows is being given gills for swimming. Young wizards is being given strong wills for controlling strong magic. It is being obvious, yes?"

It seemed obvious when put in so simple a light, Rigel had to admit. She didn't feel very strong-willed, though. A thestral could see easily whether or not it had wings before it tried to fly. Was she supposed to jump off a metaphorical cliff and just hope for the best?

"You is getting there soon," Binny said comfortingly, patting her arm. "You is only needing to be patient. Nature is not rushing things. Wizards is. And you is needing to stop binding your magic, before it is being too late, Young Sir."

"Just Rigel, Binny," she reminded the elf. After a moment she added, "Thanks. I'll think about it."

She would think about it, she promised herself. If even house-elves were telling her she was being an idiot, then maybe it was time to start listening. She would work on it this summer, once everything was settled and she had the space to experiment without hurting anyone. She would wean herself off of the suppressor, too. Somehow.

She checked the path to the Come and Go Room on the Map once she left the kitchens. She had been extra careful about not getting caught using her time-turner of late. She was in the home stretch and she didn't want any mistakes at this juncture to ruin her perfect record and jeopardize her chances of getting to use it next year, too.

While perusing the Map, she spotted two dots creeping slowly through a corridor on the fifth floor that made her stop and smile slowly. She had been waiting a while for her chance, watching the Map idly for the perfect moment, and it had finally arrived. The Weasley twins were out after curfew, all alone, and they were about to rue the day they challenged Rigel Black.

She took a teacher tracker out of her bag. She'd been saving it for this occasion. She activated the tracker and slipped it into her pocket, taking out the corresponding map to make sure it was working. The two dots overlapped exactly in the center. Perfect. She tucked the parchment away and took out the Marauder's Map instead. She needed to plot her course carefully. There was another version of herself on the Map, and she kept her distance until she saw her other self meet up with the twins. Once all three dots had converged, she began walking slowly but surely in their direction, herding them like sheep in the direction they needed to go. The three dots traveled together for a while, until Rigel's other dot broke in one direction while the twins went another way. Perfect. She waited a good five minutes just to be sure, then took out her time-turner and turned back several hours. It would take a while to set everything up.

A good amount of time later, everything was finally in place. It would be the most epic experience of their little lives, she thought maniacally. By the time the previous version of herself had left the kitchens, Rigel was heading across the fifth floor on an interception course. She destroyed the teacher tracker in her pocket, leaving the only dot on the radar map the one carried by her previous self. A few minutes later, she heard the sound of two footsteps coming around a corner ahead of her. She stopped and turned her back to their approach, making a show of fretting over the piece of parchment in her hand.

She heard their footsteps stop abruptly and whirled, gasping, only to relax when she 'recognized' them. "Oh, it's you two," she said.

"Rigel?" Fred grinned. "What are you doing out at this time of night?"

"Said the pot to the kettle," Rigel snorted.

"George and I have important business," George told her.

"Yeah, me too," Rigel smiled. "Got to get back to it, actually…" She looked down at the parchment again with a prominent frown. "I've got to go. Night."

She began walking away, then stopped, biting her lip. "You guys…aren't going that way, are you?" she asked, gesturing back the way she'd come.

"We are. Why?" Fred asked, frowning at her.

Rigel grimaced. "Don't go that way. Filch is coming."

"How do you know?" George wanted to know. He looked a bit suspicious.

Rigel clutched the parchment as though reluctant, then made a show of caving. "Okay, look. I put a teacher tracker on Filch's lantern. See? This is us, at the center, and that's him." She showed them the dot moving steadily in their direction. "Judging by the distance, he's about two corridors over, but he's been moving systematically through the fifth floor in this direction. You have to come with me if you want to avoid him."

"Smart," Fred said, leaning forward interestedly. "We've tagged his robes before, but it seems a pain to do it every day. He always carries the same lantern though….we really should have thought of that, Freddie."

"Speak for yourself, Georgie," George said with a smirk. "I like the thrill of the chase."

"I'm not sure Gryffindor's hourglass can afford your adrenaline rush," Rigel said, referring to how Gryffindor was in last place for the House Cup.

"At least we can't afford the unpopularity that would result," George admitted. "All right, lead the way."

Rigel took them down a series of side corridors that would circumvent 'Filch,' only to groan aloud in dismay a few minutes later. "He's circling around! Quick, this way." She made to head up a set of stairs one corridor over, but the twins paused, exchanging a glance.

"Actually, we've got it from here," Fred said, smiling. "Thanks for the tip, but we'll go our own way."

She pretended to look confused, then shrugged as though it didn't bother her what they did. "All right. Good luck." She set off up the stairs while the twins took a path that would lead them to a little-known secret passageway that jumped the sixth floor entirely and came out close to Gryffindor Tower. It was the perfect choice for them to avoid Filch and get back to their common room quickly. The route Rigel had tried to take them on was the long way round, after all.

They obviously assumed she didn't know about that particular passage. Poor, innocent little lions. They should know by now not to underestimate their enemy's cunning.

"That was close," Fred whispered as they eased the false door away from the dark passage it concealed. "Good thing Pup warned us."

"Nice of him," George agreed. "Then again, we rule-breakers have to stick together. We'd have done the same for him."

"If we'd thought of it," Fred said. He was still clearly annoyed that they hadn't tagged Filch's lantern. It was an obvious move, in retrospect.

"What do you think he was up to?" George asked as they carefully closed the wall behind them. He didn't bother with a light, as they knew this passage by heart.

"Smelled like the kitchens," Fred noted, taking the lead.

"The kitchens aren't on the fifth floor," George said. "He must have been on his way back down from somewhere higher. The Owlery, maybe?"

"Odd time of night to mail a letter," Fred said. "Maybe he was meeting someone for a little risqué romance."

"If Rigel is seeing someone, I'll eat every one of those seriously suspicious sweets he gave us," George said. Honestly, Rigel with a secret rendezvous? Not likely. The boy barely looked at other people without prompting.

"It's a little worrying that we haven't found anything wrong with them yet," Fred agreed. "Almost like there is nothing wrong with them. Which means—"

Whatever it meant, George never got to hear. The next thing out of his brother's mouth was a shout of surprise. There was a whoosh of displaced air as Fred stumbled forward in the darkness and hit the ground with a splat. Wait, a splat?

"Fred," he said worriedly, groping the air before him blindly. His feet caught in something ropey and he only had time for a surprised "Woah!" before he hit the ground, too.

It was wet. He spluttered and jerked his head back from what felt like at least three inches of…something. It wasn't water—too thick. It smelled like syrup of some kind, but why would there be a huge puddle of syrup in the passage? And what was that he'd tripped on? He rolled over, grimacing as the syrup coated his back, and sat up, fumbling for his wand in the dark. Fred got there first and conjured a light that had them both wincing as their eyes readjusted suddenly.

His twin was as covered in the sticky stuff as he was. On closer inspection, it appeared to be strawberry jam. "What on earth…?"

"Gross," Fred chuckled. "What happened here? Peeves?"

"Didn't know he knew about this passage," George said, looking around. The floor had jam spread all over it, several inches deep and at least as far as their light reached.

"He probably knows all of them by now," Fred reasoned, licking one finger curiously. "Come on, let's get through this mess and clean up on the other side. It looks like it goes all the way through."

George thought about suggesting they double back, rather than walk through a whole corridor of jam. Then he remembered why they'd taken the passage in the first place. The last thing he wanted to do was run into the caretaker while inexplicably covered in strawberry jelly. That was sure to land them a double dose of detention.

As they stood and began moving forward once more, grimacing at the squelching of jam under their boots, a sudden draft of cold air wafted past them, and in its wake came an eerily echoing voice.

"You…" it whispered, seeming to wind its way directly into George's ear. "You…"

"What is that?" Fred stopped walking abruptly. "Do you hear that?"

George nodded, squinting into the darkness of the corridor ahead. He couldn't see anyone or anything. "A ghost?"

"Don't recognize the voice," Fred said, frowning.

"You…" There it was again. Louder, this time. "You have angered the gods…"

"Okay I'm officially creeped out," Fred said. "Let's get out of here."

They moved forward again quickly, peering around them warily.

"The pranking gods," a voice whispered harshly in his ear, just before all hell broke loose.

Fred tripped over something invisible and went down again. George stopped abruptly to avoid the same fate, but a sudden push from behind sent him careening forward with a little scream that did not sound at all girlish.

He attempted to catch his balance, but the jam was suddenly thinner, slipperier, and he went sliding onto his butt with another splat. Fred was way ahead of him, for some reason, carrying the light with him. Before he could call out for him to wait, George realized he was beginning to slide forward. What the—?

It was then he noticed the floor was sloping downwards before him. But how? This passage was uphill! There was no time to work out the improbable physics, as he was quickly sliding down the passage at a speed he was entirely uncomfortable with. As he caught up with Fred, the light from his twin's wand picked up something huge and white blocking the tunnel before them. They were going to smack right into it! It was too late to slow their out-of-control slide. They let out matching cries of dismay and George tried in vain to at least protect his face before they—

Slid with an anti-climactic smoosh into a wall made entirely of marshmallow fluff. It killed their momentum, and he and Fred blinked slowly at one another behind what looked like masks of sticky cotton.

"What…just happened?" Fred asked, sounding a bit numb.

It began to rain chocolate syrup from the ceiling over where they sat. The thick, stick liquid dribbled almost insultingly gently onto their heads, sticking everywhere to the marshmallow and jam combo they were sporting.

"Some booby-trapped this entire passage," George said, filled with the utmost disbelief. He struggled to stand, feeling like some sort of swamp monster, covered in sweet-smelling goo like some sort of demented birthday cake.

"And we walked right into it," Fred complained. "What are the odds? And who would trap a secret passageway so elaborately? There's no way of knowing who'd fall victim to it, and you wouldn't be around to see it…anyway…wait. You don't think…?"

Catching on to his twin's train of thought easily, George shook his head (with difficulty, on account of the pile of red and white and brown glop on his head). "Rigel probably doesn't even know about this passage. And there's no way he'd have time to set this up—it was five minutes after we left him! And how would he know which passage we'd take anyway? It was our idea to come this way to avoid Filch."

"…was it?" Fred asked, struggling to his feet as well. "I mean…maybe he tricked us."

"There's just no way…" he said before trailing off in thought. Rigel was clever. But still…there was no way he could have pulled this off. Too many variables would have been at play.

"Let's just get out of here and worry about who did this to us later," Fred decided.

They began wading forward once more. The passage was still going downhill. Which was impossible. George was starting to feel like he was in the middle of a very surreal dream. They finally reached the end of the passage, a red door with a large, brass handle that George was sure he had never seen before. "This isn't right," he said, exchanging a nervous look with Fred. "The passage ends in a tapestry."

Fred grimaced, glancing back up the way they'd come. "You want to climb back through it all?"

Not a chance in hell. George grasped the knob resignedly and turned. It exploded into gold confetti. He opened his mouth on a groan and immediately regretted it as the golden bits filled his mouth. They were sprinkles, he realized after a moment of trying to scrape them off his tongue. Golden sprinkles. He pushed the door open with annoyed force, but wasn't fast enough to avoid the bucket of something that upturned itself over the doorway as they stumbled out into the corridor. He froze, slowly looking over at Fred in disbelief. His twin was smeared red and white and brown from head to toe with gold sprinkles in a layer over it all. Littered in his hair and stuck to his shoulders were little red balls that he recognized after a moment as de-stemmed cherries.

Fred started to laugh, pointing at George, who no doubt looked similarly ridiculous. He choked out, "A cherry…hahaha…on top…haha. Get it?"

"A cherry…" George had to snort at the sheer cheek of it. "Where's the ice cream, then?"

Like magic, the door across the corridor from them creaked open and out walked one Rigel Black, licking a three-scoop cone of soft serve with so much casualness that George couldn't stop the laughter that escaped him.

"You rang?" the boy drawled, giving a long, exaggerated lick.

"You," Fred groaned, pointing a goopy finger dramatically. "I knew it. But how, Rigel? How?"

Rigel unhurriedly put a hand into her shoulder bag and pulled out a camera. Before they could react, she snapped a picture of their gaping expressions. "This one is going in the Book of Glory."

George had no idea what that was, but it didn't sound good. They had more important things to worry about, though. "Seriously, Rigel, how did you do that?" he asked, utterly bewildered.

"How did I get all the booby-traps to work in smooth synchronization?" Rigel clarified, tilting his head infuriatingly. "How did I know where you'd be tonight? Or how did I make taking that passage seem like your own idea?

"All of it," Fred said. George didn't need to see his face to know he was dying of curiosity. Fred hated not knowing something.

"As to the first," Rigel said, pausing to lick his ice cream. "Immense patience and planning. As to the others—well, I'm psychic."

George had to sigh at their own foolishness. How could they have trusted Rigel for even a second? They'd been so sure his revenge was in the sweets somewhere. Talk about serving it cold, he thought, eyeing the ice cream in Rigel's hand with ironic appreciation. "How did you make the passage seem like it was going downhill?" he asked after a moment. That part didn't make any sense.

Rigel smirked. "That secret passage you two always take doubles as a passage to the third floor, if you press the right stone on your way through. I changed its destination before you got there."

What? What? How could he know that? They'd been taking that passage for years and they didn't know that. Was this the power of a true Marauder? What a legacy. He couldn't help a moment of envy. What other secrets about the castle was their pup privy to?

"I'd show you which stone it is, but I don't fancy getting my favorite boots dirty tonight," Rigel said, yawning widely. "Well, I'm for bed. Good luck getting back to that tower of yours. Filch probably isn't on the fifth floor anymore—if he ever was." Rigel chuckled to himself as he walked off into the darkness slowly.

"We were duped from the start," Fred admitted, sighing. "He never even had a tracker on Filch.

"He's an evil genius," George agreed. They had their work cut out for them, if they were going to top it. They would, though. Their pride as pranksters was on the line. They would just have to work harder. The summer would be upon them soon and they would spend the time wisely. Some of their preliminary products were nearly ready for testing, he recalled with a grin. When they came back next year, Rigel wouldn't know what hit him.

Before that, though, they had to get back to the common room. After cleaning up, he grimaced. Leaving a trail of jam-covered footprints behind them would be an excellent way to get caught and they had to at least deny Rigel that satisfaction.

That Friday evening, she walked with calm steps toward her Head of House's office, for once not looking over her shoulder or worrying about whether anyone caught sight of her. She was not doing anything surreptitious, for the first time in what felt like awhile. She was as prepared as she could be for the upcoming final exams, was nearly finished with Archie's syllabus for the semester, and, after turning in her last set of assignments for Snape, was planning on spending the weekend relaxing. Well, probably not the whole weekend, she mentally amended. Maybe just Saturday.

Unusually, there weren't a handful of other versions of her running around that night, as she was, frankly, running out of things to do. She had brewed so many potions that Krait was complaining about overstock and she'd long since read and reread all of her textbooks. Pettigrew had been almost completely unsuspicious the last couple of weeks. He wandered around the castle a lot, but she hadn't seen him return to the forest for maybe ten days. He seemed to be dialing back work with the jewel, which she could only be hopeful about. If he wanted to spend hours waking in circles, that was fine with her. She had stopped tailing him around the castle after the first time. All he ever did was lurk through the corridors aimlessly.

What would she do this weekend? She could work on her Occlumency, but she was stymied on her work with the construct. The frustration ate away at her concentration, so she kept that project on hold for the moment. She had a stack of books on the roots of mathematical transfigurations, in any case, that she was rather looking forward to reading.

The dungeons were quiet, which was not uncommon, as they were large and sprawling, with so many routes to go through that the Slytherin students rarely met one another in the passages. She heard no footsteps behind her and saw no shadow looming on the walls before her. The only evidence that she wasn't alone in the damp corridor was the barest whisper of a spell that came just moments before her wand abandoned her pocket with a sharp twist.

Rigel whirled to face her attacker and could not find it in her to feign surprise at the sight of Peter Pettigrew holding her wand tightly in his fist. In his other hand was the jewel, shining with an unnatural light.

"Professor," she said, voice even. "May I have my wand back?"

"You won't need it," he said. The usual squeak in his voice was absent, even as his beady eyes darted this way and that in manic nervousness.

The passage they were in wasn't long. There was a turn maybe twenty feet behind her. If she could make it around the corner before he got a spell off, she could throw on her Invisibility Cloak and escape. When Pettigrew took a single step toward her, she made her move. Turning on the ball of her foot, she sprinted down the corridor as fast as she could. Six steps, seven—she was almost there when something like a heat wave enveloped her from behind. Her legs were abruptly trapped in molasses, struggling to move, and the air around her shimmered in a hazy, mirage-like furnace. Sweat broke out from every part of her. Her lungs tightened and shriveled like dried prunes. She gasped in air and fought to turn her head to see Pettigrew coming up the corridor after her, step by slow step, brandishing the jewel before him and squinting against the light it was putting off.

He held it higher, coming within arms reach of her frozen form. The world was starting to develop a surreal quality and she blinked rapidly against the red-orange film that crawled across her eyes. Her mind was floating in the heat, sluggish, sloth-like, and confused. What was she doing? What….what was important? There was a tickle in her brain, behind the heat that seared the frayed edges of her concentration. She reacted on instinct, knowing the feeling of something invading her mind all too well to remain docile, despite every form-driven thought telling her to stop doing anything at all.

Her fist lashed free of the magic holding it, bloodying Pettigrew's nose and jerking her into the realization that the heat wave was in her mind, not in reality. It was the jewel, attempting to subvert her will. She gritted her teeth and pushed back against it mentally, not physically, giving it everything she had. Pettigrew, clutching his nose with the hand not holding the jewel—and what had he done with her wand?—didn't see her break completely free of the compulsion until she'd kicked him in the stomach and followed him to the floor. Her elbow slammed down toward his throat, but fire bathed her mind without warning and she rolled instinctively to the side, clutching her ears as though she could put out the flames between them with her bare hands.

There was hardly room for anything in her head that wasn't pain, but the word "Incarcerous" registered above the white-hot mindlessness. Leo favored that spell heavily in their spars, telling her over and over it was the go-to method for thieves, murderers, rapists, and all sorts of miscellaneous evildoers to neutralize a mark. Her elbow braced itself at an angle automatically, even as the ropes encircled her shoulder to knee and squeezed. Her joint protested even louder than the fire in her head, groaning as the ropes continued to tighten until the spell was satisfied that it had found the limits of its victim's form.

The weakness of the Incarcerous Spell, Leo had lectured, was its non-lethal nature. It wasn't intended to squeeze a person to death, so it only tightened until it registered that the target was compressed as much as could be accomplished without breaking anything. That meant that if you could convince the spell you were bigger than you were, you could break free once it had settled into shape.

She fought against the jewel's influence with everything she had while the binding spell solidified into place. She needed her senses for this next part. When she felt the ropes begin to harden, she collapsed her bent elbow, using the split-second of loose slack to slip her right arm between the coils and grab for the golden chain around her neck. Just one turn and this would all be over.

Her fist found the little hourglass at once, digits fumbling over the sides for the dial. That was when it slipped from her between her fingers—not, not slipped, flew. It jerked away from her grasp, clipping her in the ear as it whizzed over her shoulder and landed, to her horror, in Pettigrew's outstretched hand. The blood running down her neck from where the outer edge of her ear had been torn open was easy to ignore in her shock and dismay. How had he…the Notice-Me-Not Charm was no good if she drew attention to it, she realized. He'd simply summoned it away when he saw her go for it. And why would there not be anti-summoning wards on a time-turner? In her frustration, she wasted precious seconds cursing her own stupidity and the Ministry's incompetence. The next Incarcerous came before she could brace her free arm against it. Not that Pettigrew would have let her use the same trick twice, she thought dully.

She opened her mouth to scream, acutely aware that her choices in methods of resistance were dwindling. A hastily conjured gag caught her mid-yell. She glared over it at her attacker, who stood, panting around a broken nose, glaring right back. Pettigrew opened his fist slowly, looking down to examine the golden thing he'd caught within it, and she took that second to look down at the ropes frantically. Her right hand was bound close to her face, but the suppressor ring was on her left hand, making an attempt to pull it off with her teeth rather moot. She felt like crying. The one time she wanted to take off her suppressor and unleash her wandless magic capabilities, she couldn't. The irony felt like a slap from the universe.

"What is this?" he muttered, turning the time-turner over in his hands. She hoped he fumbled the dial and sent himself back hours into time. That would let her escape the same as if she'd used it herself. "This…it can't be…" He sounded awed and breathless. Not a good sign. "How did you get one of these?" She grunted somewhat sarcastically from behind her gag, but he only smiled at her, suddenly calm once more. "It is Fate. It knew I needed more time to figure this out. Now… I have all the time I need."

Rigel shuddered with trepidation at those words. What was he going to do? What had she done, letting him get his hands on that? She calmed herself by remembering that the time-turner only went back a week. What could he possibly do to the time stream in seven days? It wasn't the end of the world. When she got out of this mess, she would go to Snape, and he would inform the Department of Mysteries and they would send a team to take it back. Yes. There were still ways to fix this. He wasn't supreme overlord of a new world order yet.

While she was thinking, Pettigrew had been marshaling himself as well. An egg yolk running down her neck let her know that she'd been Disillusioned. Pettigrew shimmered out of sight a moment later and she felt a chain draping itself around her neck. No, she panicked, throwing her head to the side as much as her bonds would allow. Her skull cracked into Pettigrew's with a sharp pain, but it wasn't enough to stop him turning the dial. She could feel the sensation of time-travel coming on and wondered desperately how far back they were going as the world began to fade away. She thought she saw a figure in black robes come around the corner into their passageway just before they melted temporally out of existence, but she couldn't be sure. It didn't matter now. Whenever they were going, that person would be long gone. She was beyond the reach of the present, for now.

After kicking her vindictively for nearly cracking open his skull, Pettigrew had cast a quick Tempus to orient himself. "A week," the squat man said. "Only a week." He sounded displeased, but Rigel could not believe her ears. Had he seriously just turned the dial as far as it would go without knowing how far that was? What if she'd had a more powerful time-turner? What if it had taken them back months?

He levitated her out of the dungeons carefully. She wondered a bit hysterically if they would pass the version of her that had been on her way to hand in last week's assignments at this time on Friday evening, but Pettigrew was careful to take the least used of avenues toward the Entrance Hall.

He took her quickly across the lawn, making a beeline toward the last place in the world Rigel wanted to be taken. They were headed for the Forbidden Forest. Was he going to kill and bury her, then make his escape a full week before anyone noticed either of them missing? It was clever, if getting rid of her was the goal. He'd accosted her before he knew of the time-turner, though, so he must have had some escape plan that didn't rely on having a lot of time. At least, that was what she assumed.

Pettigrew took off the Disillusionment Charm once they were far enough into the trees that no one was going to see him heading off with her. He traipsed through the forest with the ease of familiarity, seeming to know exactly where he was going. Rigel kept her eyes peeled, trying to memorize their general route so that she could find her way back, once she escaped. And she would escape. She just had to be patient for now. Everyone made mistakes, eventually. She refused to believe that Pettigrew would prove a more effective kidnapper than Tom Riddle Jr.

Her every faculty was bent toward formulating as many escape plans as she could think up, while she still had the wherewithal to think of anything at all. She knew the odds that he wouldn't use the jewel on her again were extremely low. It was hard to concentrate, though, with Pettigrew's constant, mind-numbing mumbling. He apparently considered himself 'home-free' already.

"No one will even notice you're missing," he muttered, obviously pleased. "And my alibi is air-tight. No one will suspect until it's too late. Even then, they won't look for me. It will be a mystery." He paused in walking for a moment to gaze down at the golden device in his hand with naked lust. "Think of all I could accomplish with endless time."

She could certainly relate to that sentiment, but surely it had never sounded so sinister in her head. She had to wonder if Pettigrew knew how time-turners actually worked—about the rules and limits. Maybe he would destabilize his core by trying to use it too many times at once. It would serve him right, she thought. Just who did he think he was, kidnapping her?

As they moved deeper into the forest, she couldn't help but worry. If she had been trapped in time a week ago—from the perspective of her most current self, at least—then that meant she hadn't been freed in that week, because if she had, then something would have happened in the regular time stream, like Pettigrew being arrested. Was she really going to be trapped a whole week? No, she calmed herself. That wasn't certain. Maybe she'd been rescued quickly and they'd kept it quiet to keep the time stream intact. Her first thought was they better not have let me get kidnapped just to preserve the integrity of other people's temporal reality. Then she realized that all of that was wishful thinking, anyway. No one would even know she was missing until Friday evening at the very earliest. There would be no reason to look for her, before that, and a week was a long time. Hadn't her father said once that most kidnapping cases were decided one way or another in the first two days? Either the victim was found or they were dead.

She shook off those morbid thoughts. She would escape.

Rigel had to wonder why she hadn't noticed herself going missing—that is, why she hadn't seen Pettigrew taking a version of herself into the forest at this time last week—this week—no—ugh never mind. She supposed whatever versions of herself there were at the moment simply weren't looking at the Map. One was in Snape's office, she recalled, and another brewing in her lab…she thought. It was increasingly hard to remember.

It didn't matter, anyway. She didn't remember noticing herself getting dragged into the forest, which meant she wouldn't notice this time around either. They finally stopped moving as Pettigrew stepped into a clearing surrounded by thick-trunked trees that must have been a least a couple of miles from the school. It was well off the edge of the Marauder's Map.

Pettigrew dropped his levitation charm unceremoniously, letting her fall to the soft dirt with an irritated grunt. She wiggled until she could roll enough to see what he was doing. If he was going to kill her, she wanted to see it coming. He held the jewel aloft, pointing its energy toward—the ground. Confused, she squinted through the darkness. What was he doing? The earth began to tremble at his feet, churning almost as if it were liquid in some way. It parted before the jewel, creating an opening that expanded slowly until it was large enough for a person to drop comfortably through.

Thus, it was somewhat unsurprising when she was nudged to the lip of the hole and pushed in. The predictability didn't make it hurt any less, she discovered as she hit a dirt floor six feet down. She landed on her left side, the dirt sending a pulsing throb resonating through her hip and shoulder. That was rather petty, she thought, considering he was perfectly capable of levitating her down. Far be it from her to try to impress manners on her accoster, however.

Pettigrew joined her underground a moment later and it was short work after that for him to use the jewel's power to close the hole in the ceiling once more. It was pitch dark until Pettigrew lit a single lantern. Its light barely reached the edges of the dug out cavern, which stretched about fifteen feet across its diameter, from what she could tell. The edges of the room sloped downwards in a dome, giving the entire cavern the feeling of being inside a very small circus tent. It smelled of earth and damp musk and appeared to be entirely empty, with no distinguishing features beyond the lantern that hung by a wooden peg pushed into the dirt wall and a pile of animal carcasses on the other side, all of which looked fresh.

"I prepared this place weeks ago," Pettigrew said, his voice distorted by his still-broken nose. "Ever since it became clear to me what I had to do. I had my creatures working on it by moonlight. They were not so eager, at first, but I persuaded them to my way of thinking. Do you like it?"

She wondered why he would ask such an inane question, but there was a vaguely disoriented look in his eyes that made her question whether he even knew what he was saying.

"I can make all sorts of creatures do my bidding, after so much practice. I can make them mine, such that they do not even remember a time when they had wills of their own," Pettigrew said. He stood looking down at the jewel, the time-turner now tucked away in a pocket, no doubt. There was desperation in his gaze, only tempered by the disorientation that made him look more helpless than hungry. "Even the rocks and plants bend to do my bidding, now. The natural world moves at my command. And yet…it's not enough."

The last was said with a growl, in which she heard a year's worth of frustration. His whole body shook briefly, before settling once more. He stretched his neck almost casually. "I knew, after you saw me that night with the jewel, that it had to be you. Fate chose you for me. Brought you to me to show me the path I must take, revealed me to you to force my hand. I built this prison for you, you know. I waited and waited for the right time, looked and looked until I caught you walking alone. And it's almost complete…"

Rigel didn't like the sound of that, or anything else that had happened so far, come to that. All those nights she'd seen him going back into the forest after the dragon debacle: this is what he'd been doing? All the time she'd been unknowingly witnessing the construction of her own cage? And the time she'd followed him around the castle he'd been looking for her?

Pettigrew looked over at the pile of dead animals—nifflers, she thought, following his gaze with a sickened clench of her stomach. "Perfect," he said, beginning to smile. "Just what I need." He said that as if he wasn't the one who put them there, as if they were a gift from some higher power. She was starting to realize just how far from sane Pettigrew was at this point.

He moved to where the dead animals lay and picked one up by its tail, causing the blood from its wounds to drip onto the dirt floor grotesquely. He tucked the jewel away into his coat and used his now-empty palm to catch the blood. It pooled sluggishly across his fingers. He dropped the niffler carelessly and walked to a seemingly arbitrary section of dirt wall, where he began smearing the blood carefully, drawing something with great concentration. She shuddered to think what he could be intending; blood magic was rarely benign.

When the symbol was complete, it lit with an iridescent glow that didn't come from the blood itself. Lines of magic shot out from what she belatedly realized was a rune to connect to dozens of other points all over the cavern, forming a matrix that covered the walls, ceiling, and floor. It was a ward, that much was obvious, but the pattern of runic placement indicated a protective barrier of some kind. Was he hoping to keep out anyone who might come to her rescue?

"It took ages to find the right ward," Pettigrew said, turning back to face her once the rune sequence, now completed, sank invisibly into the dirt once more. "It had to be something unbreakable, to keep you here no matter what. I had no intention of spending the rest of my life down her, however. So I got a little…creative."

He approached her and took her chin between his blood-covered fingers. She fought against her stomach's reaction to the smell as he turned her head forcibly toward the lantern. "Do you see that?" She blinked at the light, wondering what she was supposed to make of it. "That," he repeated, shaking her head a little and pointing with his other hand to a spot below the lantern that she hadn't noticed until now. It was a small hole, no more than six inches across, which sat at the base of the wall. "That is the only way in or out of this cave, now. Can you fit in there?" He moved her head back and forth in the parody of a shake with his hand. "Well I can." He turned into a rat and back to a man so fast his body was one continuous blur.

Rigel stared at the tiny hole with dawning alarm. He'd sealed them off…completely? How could she escape through that? It was impossible, unless she could figure out a way to take the ward down. Maybe he would leave her alone at some point and she could make an attempt to find the ward's weak spot. Very few designs lacked something that could be exploited. She refused to give up hope. Not yet.

"Your father thought it was so funny," Pettigrew sneered. "Peter the rat. Wormtail. But it got me this, didn't it?" He fished the jewel from his pocket and held it toward her. She flinched, but he wasn't using it. Just showing it off to her. "My master sent me into the tomb because no one else could do it. I crept through air pockets and drainage canals no wizard could ever fit through, ones the Egyptians didn't bother booby-trapping, they were so small. I carried my destiny out with my wormy tail, didn't I? So who's laughing now?" He barked out a long and bitterly triumphant laugh, in case there was any doubt.

"Well?" he demanded suddenly. "Why aren't you laughing?"

The gag vanished from within her mouth, sending pain shooting through her stiff jaw as it suddenly snapped closed. She tasted blood where her teeth had come down on her tongue and spat it out onto the dirt floor with a grimace.

"Now, now, don't go desecrating this place." Pettigrew wagged a finger at her slowly. "You're going to be here a long time. The longest of time, actually. Did you know the ancient pharaohs spent ages touring their burial complexes before they died? It was a matter of grave importance, their final resting place. You should try to come to terms with your tomb while you can. Not many wizards these days get such a chance."

"I'm…not going to let you kill me," she said, coughing a bit.

"That's the spirit," Pettigrew said. He seemed entirely detached. "In any case, I don't have to kill you. I just have to leave you here, once I've taken your magic."

So he was too cowardly to kill her himself. That was fine with her. She would start planning a way out now, then, and wait for the moment he left her alone. "How can you take my magic?" Rigel asked, not really wanting to know. The first rule of being kidnapped was keep the other person talking, though, and so she would, despite the way Pettigrew's whole demeanor was giving her the creeps. "It's bound to me."

"The jewel can do anything," he said surely. "I am Fated to, in any case. 'Take control or be took by another.' 'Master the other.' It is the only way to succeed."

"It also said 'keep power alive,'" Rigel said suddenly, deciding that keeping cards off the table wasn't going to help her at this point.

"How do you know that?" Pettigrew dove for her, grabbing her shoulder in one hand and thrusting the jewel in her face with the other. "What do you know of this?"

"I saw that piece of paper you dropped," she told him. "I read it. It definitely said you should keep me alive."

"Only until I control your power." Pettigrew frowned. "Don't try to trick me. I know what I'm doing." He stepped back and looked down at her. She was lying in what was possibly the most uncomfortable position on earth, bound with two layers of thick ropes that were cutting off circulation just about everywhere, one hand pressed against her side while the other was bound close across her chest. "I should take more precautions. I don't trust you."

"The feeling is mutual," she bit out.

Pettigrew reached into his coat's expanded pocket mechanically and pulled out a very familiar bag. It was hers. She supposed he'd picked it up from the corridor after binding her. Clever, to not leave any evidence behind. Her eyes must have lit up at the sight of the shoulder bag, for Pettigrew chuckled a bit cruelly. "You want it? Come take it." He held the bag out to her in one hand, the jewel clenched tightly in the other. She didn't see why he bothered with his nonsensical jokes. She glared up at him from where she was restrained. To her utter shock, the ropes around her slackened, and feeling, sharp and painful and beautiful, raced back to her extremities.

She rolled immediately to her feet, ignoring the tingling needles that were jabbing numbness away everywhere they advanced. She lunged for the bag and hooked it away from him swiftly. Before she could make a proper retreat to the other end of the cavern, roiling heat erupted around her and drove her to her knees, panting. The world was a desert and she was dying slowly, baked and sizzling before the might of a thousand suns.

A cool breeze swept across her face. Open the bag. The what? She turned her head toward the feeling. Please, please, come back. Open the bag. The bag? What, this? Her attention turned slowly, sluggishly toward the thing in her lap. What was she doing? What was important? Open the bag. Her fingers floated toward the clasp, deftly undoing it and peering dumbly into the reinforced fabric. Take out the potion. The what? The potion. Which one? Confusion tried to assert itself, but the desert wind blew it back. It didn't matter. What didn't matter? What was she doing? The potion.

A picture came into her mind. There was a dragon, and a skinny boy with dark hair was pouring something onto the ground in a circle. Recognition lit somewhere inside her and her hand moved unconsciously into the bag, rooting around automatically until the correct vial came to her fingers. She pulled it out dazedly, blinking at it. There was something important about this. What was it?

Give it here. She held out her hand, but then retracted it sharply. Something was wrong. What was wrong? Nothing. Give it here. Something. Give it here. Her head hurt. It didn't feel good anymore. Why had it felt good, again?

The potion was snatched from her hand and she snapped out of it, gasping for air in the wake of such utter deprivation of herself. How did it do that? She hadn't known anything. She hadn't remembered who she was or—or anything. It was the most terrifying thing she'd ever experienced. She shook off the aftereffects with difficulty, grasping for a linear thought amidst the senselessness that had taken hold. She looked up to see Pettigrew standing a good distance away from her, shoulder bag back in his hands and an empty vial in the other.

She stood, as though in a dream, and stumbled forward on pain-filled legs. She hit an invisible wall before she'd made it two steps. She leaned against it, mind haltingly whirling. She looked down. There was a line of potion on the floor and it circled back around to…to enclose her completely. The Protection Potion. He'd used it when she was disoriented. She was trapped. No, she wasn't, she realized. She struggled to keep a smile off of her face. She could break the ward easily with a ward-disrupter. As soon as Pettigrew left her unattended she would take off her suppressor, then—then what, exactly?

If she got out of the barrier without electrocuting herself with her unsuppressed magic, then what? She was still trapped underground until she found a way around the ward Pettigrew had set up. She backed away from the side of the round barrier that Pettigrew stood beyond, sitting down in the middle and pulling her knees into her chest slowly. What should she do? She stared out at Pettigrew and he stared back. She felt like a caged animal, put on display for someone's amusement.

"I'd never seen this potion before that night in the forest," Pettigrew said, almost conversationally. "It held up against dragon fire, though. It ought to hold you without much trouble."

Don't count on it, she promised silently.

Pettigrew cast a Tempus and read the result. It was deep into Friday night. How long had she struggled with the jewel? It had felt like minutes—could it really have been hours? Pettigrew did look exhausted, she noticed. He pulled out a wand—his, not hers—and conjured a basic pallet to sleep on. He laid himself down, shifted fitfully for several minutes, and finally turned away from her accusing eyes completely. He slept facing the wall, and Rigel debated for nearly half an hour over what she ought to do.

She could take off her suppressor and break free of the barrier, then attempt to break the ward—but wards were not like shields. They couldn't be broken with brute force alone. The runes that fed the design fueled it with power outside of the magic used to cast the ward. It drew strength from the air around it, from the ground it was anchored to, and so on. Her magic probably wouldn't be able to just bust through it, unless it had been cast improperly.

Then there was the fact that the barrier would not break quietly and she would lose the element of surprise the instant she was free. As long as he had the jewel, he could turn her will against her at any time. If he merely restrained her physically with it, she thought she could fight it off. She recognized the feeling, now. If he attacked her mind, though…well, she didn't know how she could fight without the idea of resistance to even remind her that she ought to be fighting. Retrospectively, it had been like losing her conscious self completely. Did she want that to happen when her magic was free? She shuddered. Definitely not. It would kill her for him if left to roam without a will opposing it, like as not. She would wait, then. There would be an opportune moment. Eventually.

She resigned herself to getting some sleep. If he was going to be well rested for whatever came next, then so was she. It was all she could do, at this point, to improve her odds.

His dreams swam around him in circles, just out of reach. They mocked him. He knew he had to catch them, but didn't know how. When he woke, he wasn't any clearer on what he was to do. He had brought the boy here. The Jewel had been happy; he'd felt its pleasure wafting through him as he bent the child's will toward his commands. Now, though, it only felt empty. Cold. Distant. His mind was washed in confusion. He'd been so full of purpose, hadn't he? What was he to do now? Why didn't the Jewel respond to him? It was supposed to guide him now that he had control over the boy, the 'other' that the Jewel had led him to. It was supposed to transform him, giving him power beyond his dreams. Had he run out of time? No, he couldn't have. He controlled time, too, now. It bent to his will. So why didn't the Jewel? He didn't understand.

He sat up and looked across the cavern to where the boy now slept. He supposed he hadn't met the requirements for controlling the boy, yet. He needed to control his magic. He didn't know what was so important about this child's magic in particular. It was powerful, he'd seen, but immature. The boy didn't control it well. Was that why? Was he meant to control it instead? How?

It doesn't matter how, he thought staunchly, making his way to stand before the barrier. He would control it. He refused to fail.

The boy looked small, curled up in sleep. Why did it have to be Sirius' boy? His old friend would never forgive him…he shook off the thought before it gripped him fully. He didn't care what Sirius thought anymore. He didn't care about any of them. He was the one who had moved on to better things while they were still making their little toys.

He held the stone up to the barrier, then paused. What was he doing, really? This wasn't a dragon. It was a person. A child. His fingers shook. Was this what he had come to? Killing children for power? The Jewel perked up at the thought of power. Not killing, he corrected himself slowly. Just…controlling. The stone in his hand thrummed soothingly. Once he had the boy's magic under his control, the Jewel would give its full allegiance to him. That's what the prophecy said. If Dominion is desired, domination is required. He had to. Anyway, it was too late to turn back. The boy had seen too much and knew too much. He had to be dealt with. It was just economical to make his demise useful, wasn't it?

He nodded slowly, the fog clearing from his mind. It must have been a dream. He was waking, now. His thoughts were sharp again. Get control. That was important. And he would be important. Just like his old master had always promised. Peter would thank him, one day, for leading him to the Jewel. He felt a flicker of guilt. Hadn't he meant to give the Jewel to that man? A shudder of rejection flowed through him. Give it away? Never. Why give the world to another when it's already in my hands?

He was so close. He just needed to focus a little longer. How many creatures had he already bent to his will? Too many to count. One more would be easy. He would subjugate the boy's power and make it his own. With all that magic at his command, the Jewel would be persuaded fully to his side. It would grant him all the power he could imagine and he would be unstoppable. He just had to do this one thing.

Just one more thing, and then the universe would unfold before him. Greatness beckoned. He raised his fist once more. The Jewel glowed. The boy screamed.

She woke in flames. It wasn't the heat of a desert pressing on her from without, this time. The fire was inside of her and it wanted out. She was screaming, but that was immaterial to the pain. It felt as if something was being pulled from her soul but had got trapped by her skin on its way through. There was no thought, only agony, for immeasurable time.

When the pain receded, she came back to herself slowly, almost uncertainly. Did she want to know? In the end, the answer was yes, of course she wanted to know. She opened her eyes, finding her vision blurred and painful. It was possible she'd damaged something in her delicate eye tissue screaming. She was still inside the barrier and Pettigrew was looking at her with alarmed bewilderment. His beady eyes flicked from the stone in his hand to her and back again, utterly nonplussed.

"What…did you do?" she asked, her voice raw.

"I…it wasn't supposed to hurt that much," Pettigrew stuttered.

She prodded her brain into coming up with an answer that made sense. What had he been trying to do with the jewel? Oh, she grew into the realization slowly. He must have tried to take her magic. Unsuccessfully. She could still feel it like fire in her veins. Why hadn't it worked? She thought carefully. Something had resisted the jewel's ability to draw out her magic. The only answer that made sense was…the suppressor? It didn't suppress all her magic, of course, but her magic was still bound together as one entity. Part of it was simply stifled. If the jewel was unable to take the free part without taking the bound part as well, it would explain the failure. And the pain.

On the bright side, the suppressor was extremely effective. She'd have to recommend Frein to her friends. A hysterical giggle left her lips. She stifled it quickly, but not before Pettigrew took a half-step back uncertainly.

"Why didn't it work?" he asked. She didn't know if he was talking to himself or actually asking her, but she figured it was a good opportunity.

"It's impossible," she told him, making up what she thought was a plausible falsehood. "You can't take another wizard's magic. It's bound to me—you're going to kill me if you try, and that violates the prophecy."

"Shut up!" Pettigrew began pacing back and forth before the barrier. "That's not right. I've done this before, with creatures. I can use their powers as my own, once I control them. How do you think I got that prophecy in the first place, you stupid child?"

She had to concede that he was probably right. If he'd done it before, then the jewel must have some way of superseding the bond between one's magic and one's will. Still, he didn't seem entirely sure of himself. She could probably still divert him, if she stepped carefully. "It's probably different with wizards," she said, trying to be convincingly firm despite her slur. "I mean, humans and creatures aren't the same at all. Isn't our magic greater? I bet the bond between a human and his magic is much stronger. Maybe the jewel can't break it."

"Maybe I need to try harder," Pettigrew said quietly.

She scarcely had time to regret how quickly that had backfired before her world narrowed to the existence of pain alone. As she wasn't taken by surprise, she was slightly more aware this time as the magic in her core flooded through her forcefully, searching desperately for a way out. She didn't know how the jewel had managed to awaken her magic's will, as normally the ring didn't allow it to do anything while it was repressed. She did know that the push and pull between the jewel and her suppressor was going to slowly tear her apart from the inside out.

As the torment persisted, Rigel lost all sense of herself in the tide of pain that blossomed and receded and peaked again in a cycle of contention that ceased to have either beginning or end.

At some point, consciousness stopped being possible, and she fell away from reality, into dreams about drowning in a lake of fire. When the torture ended for her body, her mind dragged her far beneath the riptide of thought. She slept there at the bottom of the ocean of her mind, hoping she never resurfaced.

She did, of course, some time later, to spasms of pain in every limb and a throb in her neck where she'd probably strained something thrashing. She knew, medically, what to expect if this continued. It was with a detached sense of shame that she acknowledge the evidence of her bowel control having deserted her at some point. She forced herself to take things in a practical lens. This solved the problem of her modesty, and losing her dignity now meant it wouldn't be something she had to fight for later.

She didn't see Pettigrew anywhere in the cavern. With a groan, she pushed herself up and noticed with mixed feelings that the barrier around her had faded. Had it been more than twelve hours already? She forced herself to stretch every muscle painstakingly until she could move more or less at human levels of coordination. She stood and crossed the cavern carefully, eyes on the discarded shoulder bag by Pettigrew's abandoned sleeping mat.

She sank to the ground beside it, pulling it open and taking things out as fast as her twitching fingers would allow, looking for anything that would help her survive. There was a canister left over from her run on Friday morning. She uncapped it with an eagerness that would have embarrassed her at any other time. There was maybe a third of the bottle of water left inside. She drained it greedily, pausing only afterwards to wonder if she should have saved a little for later. She put the empty container aside and continued looking. Her potions kit was broken open. She must have done it while under the jewel's control, or maybe Pettigrew had been going through her things.

Any panic she may have felt at that was squashed quickly. She meticulously began cataloging the contents of the bag. Was there anything that he could have found to use against her? She didn't keep the letters Archie sent her after reading them and there were no new ones in her bag that she could recall. Her work for Flint was long finished, with nothing incriminating left. She had a potion for menstrual cramps in her potions kit, but she doubted Pettigrew would recognize it. Even if he did, she had a lot of potions in her kit, many of which made no sense for a thirteen-year-old boy to carry, such as the ones she brewed for Krait.

In fact…she dug quickly through the extended compartments until she found a Pain Relief Potion. Perfect. She downed it immediately and thought about taking another, but in the end decided to save the other doses. There was no guarantee she wouldn't need them. She went through the rest of her bag carefully. Aside from textbooks on subjects she wasn't officially taking, which would be moot to disguise since Pettigrew already knew she had a time-turner, there wasn't anything besides her Invisibility Cloak and maybe the Marauder's Map that she didn't want Pettigrew to find.

Rigel considered her options. She could hide under the Invisibility Cloak. Then, when he came back, he might assume she'd escaped and…what? Leave, probably, which left her still trapped with no way out. She tucked the Invisibility Cloak away into an extended compartment and then stacked books on top of it, so that it was marginally hidden from casual perusal. The Map she put into her own pocket. She also filled the pockets of her outer robe with all the potions that might be useful. Vials of Pain Relief Potion along with those of Nutrient Potion, Blood-Replenishing Potion, Invigoration Draught, Pepper-up Potion, Numbing Potion, and even Gasnik's Gastric Solution, in case she went hungry for a while and needed to dull the ache.

She considered pouring out the rest of the vials of her Protection Potion, but thought better of it and merely added the vials of the antidote to her pockets instead. That way, she'd have a way out of the barrier and Pettigrew would have a sense of security, however false. If she didn't leave him some of the Protection Potion, he'd probably find another way to contain her, she reasoned. One she couldn't counter.

Rigel carried her outer robe back to where she'd slept, in the center of the room, and folded it carefully as though she'd been using it as a pillow. Hopefully, he wouldn't think to check it for anything hidden when he returned. She took a moment to wonder where he'd gone, then decided she didn't care. She would use the time given to her gratefully. It was time to examine those wards.

Pettigrew returned not long after she'd searched the entire cavern end to end for her wand. She'd found nothing, which she supposed wasn't surprising. He probably had it on him, along with the jewel. She'd attempted to dig a hole in the dirt wall, something that would have been easy, were there not magic involved. The ward sprang up in the way of every attempt to penetrate its boundary.

She took to hitting the walls with a rock she found and watching the patterns of runes that appeared around the room until she thought she had them all memorized. She was paging through her Ancient Runes textbook in hopes of identifying one of the runes that she wasn't familiar with when she heard a soft scrabbling coming from the hole Pettigrew had indicated as the only way in and out of the cavern.

Rigel hurried to replace the book and take up a position flat against the wall near the tiny entrance. If Pettigrew didn't know that the barrier should have faded by now, she could take him by surprise. A rat scrambled awkwardly through the hole, a small rope between its teeth. It tugged a small sack behind it slowly—an easy target. Her foot shot out with all the strength she could put behind it, catching the rat square in the underbelly and sending it careening into the dirt wall across the room. She leapt after it, but Pettigrew retook human form before she got close enough to try knocking the rodent out. He was disheveled and crumpled into a defensive ball, but he had enough wherewithal to grasp the jewel and send her reeling back before its power.

"Don't. Come. Any. Closer." Pettigrew's breathing was so ragged he was barely comprehensible, but the jewel's will made the command very clear as it rooted her feet to the dirt. Rigel fought against the oppressive heat, glaring down at her captor as she struggled to throw off the mental compulsion. She hadn't expected that to work, but she'd got unexpectedly close to turning the tables. To have that taken away was infuriating.

Pettigrew reached blindly with his free hand into the pouch that lay beside him. He pulled out a loaf of bread and Rigel's mouth began watering mindlessly. She swallowed against it, even as she eyed the bread with undisguised longing. It had been almost a full day since she'd eaten and she was not accustomed to hunger in the slightest. "You want this? I'll feed you, if you do as I say."

She tilted her head wordlessly. She was not above bargaining for sustenance, in these circumstances.

"Food and water, if you go quietly into the barrier," he said.

"You have to feed me anyway, if you want to keep me alive," she said.

"And you'll be forced into the barrier anyway if I use this jewel," Pettigrew growled.

She wondered why he didn't simply use it, then, but realized after a moment he was probably trying to save his strength for conquering her magic. She would save her strength, too, then. "Deal," she said, retreating slowly toward where her outer robe lay.

Pettigrew scurried over to her bag, which she'd left lying open, if only to prevent him using the jewel on her again to reopen it. She was getting sick of that thing enslaving her to this pathetic man's whims. Pettigrew pulled a potion out and, as he approached her to pour it on the ground, she couldn't quite contain a sneer.

"That's a Deflating Draft," she told him flatly. "Going to ease your swollen head?"

"Shut up," Pettigrew hissed, throwing the potion in a fit of anger and letting the vial smash against the wall. What a waste, she thought, annoyed. Pettigrew stomped back to the bag and dug about inside it until he pulled out a potion he was apparently satisfied with. She wondered how someone who didn't even bother checking the labels on potions vials had engineered so effective a prison. Was it dumb luck? Or was he marginally intelligent when he bothered to concentrate on something in earnest?

He cast the barrier around her, almost forgetting to toss half the loaf of bread and a canteen of water to her before sealing it completely. She wolfed down the bread and sipped lightly at the water, stowing the rest next to her cloak almost protectively, like a dragon guarding a pile of gold.

When the food was gone and Pettigrew rose from his pallet to face her across the barrier once more, she knew that the truce, whatever it had been, was over. She moved as far from the precious glass vials tucked into her 'pillow' as she could, telling herself with trepidation that bracing for the pain would only make it worse.

It was worse, in any case. Her nerve endings, or whatever parts of her brain the magic was pressing against trying to get out, were still sore and they flared with a vengeance when the jewel tried once again to force the power out of her. The suppressor held firm, but amidst of sea of suffering it was hard to muster gratitude for that.

When it stopped again and Pettigrew took to his pacing, Rigel pushed herself to her knees and fought a tumultuous battle with her stomach. She was not going to loose the bread she'd just put into it. Her mind felt scrambled, thoughts going in all directions in a desperate attempt to find a way that led away from the pain. She could take the suppressor off. She could just take it off and all of this pain would stop. She knew that. She stared down at her gloved fingers, barely visible through the tears and snot that dripped between her eyes and nose and got tangled in the sweat-soaked fringe clinging to her forehead.

Something hard in her gut protested this, though. Despite the pain, despite the utter senselessness that threatened to wipe her mind of any coherence at all, she was still Rigel Black and there were some things that Rigel Black could not do. She forced her mind away from the present, sending it back to one year earlier. Do you remember? Remember the Chamber? She had been willing to die to keep the unstable construct from controlling her magic. She could not be less willing to endure mere physical pain to keep Pettigrew from the same. Consistency was important. She didn't remember why, exactly, but it was.

She held onto this knowledge. It was not anything as strong as a mantra and it did not soothe the pain in any way. It held her to herself, though, and when the pain began again, it was the only thing left that mattered.

Eventually, Pettigrew gave up. She could dimly hear him railing aloud in anger and frustration, but the words were a garbled mess to her ears. He brain was having trouble doing the interpretation thing, at the moment. She closed her eyes for a long minute and woke to find it quiet. Pettigrew was asleep across the cavern and she knew she should being doing something—taking advantage of his guard being down to do—something. She couldn't move, though. She couldn't even find the strength to crawl to her robes, even though she knew there were potions there that would take the pain away. It devastated her to be so close to relief, but unable to close the distance. She lost the fight for consciousness again and collapsed within herself.

She didn't know what time it was when she awoke. She wasn't even sure what day it was. Sunday? The lantern in the cavern was her only light source and it burned day and night, not giving much clue as to how much time was passing. Pettigrew wasn't there, but the barrier was down. Perhaps he'd gone for food again. She hoped so. She was terribly hungry once more and the small amount of Nutrient Potion she drank did nothing to fill her stomach.

It took her quite a while to master herself enough to stand, but when she had the strength, she limped to her bag and settled into scouring her Runes book. She had to figure out a way out of here. Nearly an hour later, she found a piece of the puzzle. The rune she hadn't recognized wasn't drawn in her textbook, but it was described in general terms under the section of non-human runic adaptations.

One species in particular is known for their extensive and creative appropriation of Wizarding runic systems for their own gain. Goblins have long since devised ways of using runes in place of wands to direct and channel natural magic to achieve their ends. The complex warding system that protects the thousands of vaults at Gringotts is an excellent example of goblin-designed and forged runic anchors. Over the years, goblins have also developed a runic alphabet that is particular to their language, with symbols for many complex ideas that our own languages don't have words to capture succinctly. Recognizable by their square, almost seal-like nature, such runes are notoriously difficult for wizards to counter, and were put to devastating use in the goblin wars of the sixteenth century in particular—

"What are you doing?"

Rigel twisted with a gasp to find Pettigrew standing over her, burlap sack in one hand and jewel held warily in the other. How hadn't she heard him come back? As he dropped the bag and stepped toward her threateningly, she noted the lack of sound accompanying his movements and realized that he had cast a Silencing Charm to prevent her ambushing him again. Rigel tried to push the book away surreptitiously into her bag, but he caught sight of the title before she could.

"Trying to find a way out?" Pettigrew actually laughed. "This is a goblin ward. They used it for wizard prisoners of war, a long time ago. It excludes humans in particular from crossing the ward without a creature's assistance. You can't get out unless I take you out. And no one can get in unless I help them in. It's no perfect, of course. The goblins stopped using it so much when wizards figured out an Animagus could slip through it and help the prisoners escape. I don't think you're an Animagus, though, are you?"

He laughed again at the shadow of defeat that crossed her face. She wouldn't be able to escape on her own, if he told the truth. Not without dismantling the entire ward system. That could take weeks, though, without the runes that unlocked the sequence. She didn't know any goblin runes. What was she going to do now? She doubted Pettigrew would be so kind as to escort her out in his rat form—and through what door, anyway? The passage that led away from the cavern was too small. She had briefly considered trying to somehow brew a Shrinking Solution with what she had in her Potions kit. She had no cauldron, and it wasn't meant to be used on living things anyway, but it had been a slim ray of hope. That possibility vanished with the knowledge that even a tiny human wouldn't actually be able to walk through the wards.

Pettigrew bent to retrieve a bag of peanuts and two bananas from his burlap sack. "Don't look so glum," he said, smirking at the despair in her eyes. "Look what I brought you. It's all yours if you go back to the ring."

She stood shakily, eyeing the jewel in his hand consideringly. Could she knock it away before he used it on her? Probably not, she admitted, with the current state of her muscles. She would not be quick enough. She hobbled slowly back to her circle, feeling much like a circus elephant rewarded for performing a trick when the bag of peanuts landed in her soiled lap.

Pettigrew looked entirely pleased at her docility, at least. He had no way of knowing that it cost her nothing to agree to a prison she could break out of anytime. She ate half the peanuts—cursing and biting back tears as her spasming fingers made the task infinitely more frustrating—and one banana. No sense in counting on the man's generosity continuing, after all. He waited impatiently for her to finish—wary of making her choke to death accidentally, no doubt.

As she set the food she was saving aside, she tried to reason with him again. "It's fruitless, you know. Maybe you've misinterpreted the prophecy. You should try to get power another way. Or leave England while you still can. Now is a good time to escape, actually. No one will notice you've gone for several more days."

"No," Pettigrew said, shuddering. "Nowhere is safe. They will come after the jewel no matter where I go. My old master… will not be forgiving, if it is he who finds me. I must master this power. If I can control other wizards…only then will I be safe again."

She wondered how it was that the idea of leaving the jewel and making a run for it by himself didn't even occur to him. Had the jewel really done so much for him? She thought it still seemed like more trouble than it was worth. She also thought he already could control other wizards, if his using it against her was any indication. The control was imperfect and she thought she would be able to fight it with enough time, but it was certainly enough to win advantage in a fair fight. Why wasn't it enough for Pettigrew? Was this the influence of the jewel? Or his own stubborn ambition?

He bent the jewel to taking her magic once more and this time Rigel found her mind centered in the pain, but intact. Was the jewel growing weaker, or was she growing better at being tortured? She had the faculties this time to think that withstanding torturous amounts of pain had not been on her list of things-to-get-good-at. She didn't know if cynicism in the face of pain was beneficial or detrimental to her mental health at this point. It didn't make her feel better, at any rate. She almost preferred the mindlessness of the last time. It didn't leave room for self-reflection and she didn't have to second-guess her own sanity, as it was already absent in the first place. She also hadn't noticed her bowels releasing last time. This time she did.

As Pettigrew's efforts faded into livid curses and whimpering pleas, Rigel rolled shakily onto her back, drawing in air slowly and shallowly.

"How are you doing this?" he demanded.

"It's not…me," she coughed. "Don't you think…I would make it stop, if I could?"

This argument stymied him for a moment, but a second later he was growling, "I know it is within the jewel's ability to do this. I've been researching all day and there's nothing that differentiates a wizard's magic from a creature's in that way."

"Look…again," she huffed, struggling upwards onto her elbows. The smell of her shame hit her nose and she raised her arm against it, grimacing.

Pettigrew took his wand out and spelled her clothes clean with a derisive sneer. She ignored him, rolling over to face the opposite wall. Her body was a trembling pile of uselessness at the moment. She needed rest. She had to keep her strength up.

She tried to ignore the little voice in her head that suggested she was acting tougher than she was to stave off the deep sense of despair that crept over her with each passing hour. The voice got louder, however, the longer she lied to herself. It was becoming increasingly clear that escape was a very narrow window, receding into the distance and getting smaller all the time.

He rose on Monday with panic in every fiber of his being. His failure overwhelmed him, making it harder and harder to focus on the task. Why did the Jewel keep failing? Was it him? No, he was doing everything right. It was the boy. Somehow the boy was keeping his magic locked away beyond his reach. But how?

He would find out. Somewhere in the vast library at Hogwarts there were answers. He calmed himself, patting the pocket where he kept his time-turner reassuringly. He had time to figure it out. The boy would not thwart him forever. Already, he should be losing strength. The herbs he'd been straining into the boy's water should see to that. They would weaken his resolve, slow his mind. Sooner or later he would give into despair and doubt, and his resistance would crumble completely.

In the meantime, he would figure out what about that child in particular was thwarting his Jewel. He slipped out of the cavern and into the forest in his rat form. When he reached the castle, he would Disillusion himself and make his way to the library. There wouldn't be anyone there, with classes in session. He slipped past his very own Creatures class on his way across the lawn. How strange this time-turner was. When he mastered the Jewel, he would turn his attention to unleashing its full potential as well.

He looked through book after book, trying to find something that would explain the magic's unheard-of resistance to the power of the Jewel. It was as if the magic was trapped, somehow… but what could do such a thing? Was it Occlumency? Some sort of trick? He didn't know. But he would find out.

Hours later, he despaired. There was nothing in the books about mind arts that would explain the inaccessibility of the boy's magic. He was so tired, so tired of trying. And for what? He was having trouble remembering. The world around him was growing heavy. So heavy…

He jolted awake to a prodding finger, whirling and nearly attacking the sandy-haired Ravenclaw student blinking back at him. "Um…Professor? It's almost breakfast. You don't want to miss it." The student smiled and walked away toward the library exit. Peter realized his Disillusionment Charm had faded away sometime after he'd fallen asleep. He gazed in panic at the window. He'd been gone all night! Oh, no. The boy. There was no way he could have escaped…right?

He hastened to get to the kitchens and collect the food he needed to keep the boy in line. There was no telling what he'd prepared for him with all the time alone he'd had. His ribs still hurt from that kick. He'd thought a child would be easy to control. Why was it all going so wrong?

When he crept silently into the pit, he expected to meet some sinister challenge and. as such was carrying the Jewel in his mouth, fairly certain he could still use it in his Animagus form if he had to. What he saw was…the boy, sleeping fitfully within the circle of the faded barrier. Why was he still sleeping? He had been gone so long. Was he faking? He reassumed his true form and stepped closer, wary of a trap.

No…he was just sleeping. Peter frowned down at the shaking child. He slept an unnaturally long time. Some of it could be from his time-turner use, Peter reasoned carefully. If he was awake longer in the day, maybe his habits had altered to keep him well rested. He shouldn't be sleeping all day, though. Unless…maybe the Jewel was doing more damage to the boy than Peter had thought. He'd certainly screamed a lot, but children were notoriously dramatic. Well, the boy was breathing, so he supposed it couldn't be doing too much injury. Whatever he was doing to resist the Jewel was probably just tiring him out.

The Jewel was an impatient presence at the back of his mind, giving him a headache that worsened the longer he went without making any progress. Pettigrew set the food and water inside the circle next to the boy and then cast a new barrier quickly. He had to get back to the library. He had to find the answer soon.

She opened her eyes once Pettigrew had left the cavern. She'd woken as he placed the bag of food beside her, but pretended to sleep. It had been nearly a full day since he left and now he was leaving again? She allowed herself a small smirk as she sat up. He must be having a hard time figuring out that she was wearing a suppressor. With luck, he'd give up soon. The smugness faded from her mind almost immediately. If he gave up, what would he do with her? Probably kill her immediately. Unless he was exceptionally good at Memory Charms. Even then…if she were evil, she had to admit she wouldn't take the chance of leaving her alive.

She wondered if he even was evil. He seemed very conflicted the whole time he threatened her. Why would someone so unsure of themselves try and do something so unequivocally dastardly, anyway? It was stupid. Someone like him should be an undersecretary somewhere, toadying his way into modest influence and letting other people do the thinking.

She opened the bag and began going through it. Water! She gulped half the canteen down immediately. She was beginning to live for the moments that water appeared before her. She'd tried to ration the food she had yesterday, but in the end had succumbed and eaten it all before going to sleep. Her stomach still rumbled and she promised herself she'd never take Hogwarts cooking for granted again. She pulled out three muffins and an apple from the bag. The apple she saved. The muffins she scarfed down with abandon. Her body needed the energy, she told herself. She suspected the truth of it just came down to the ache in her belly.

She spent a few hours going through her spell books for anything that might be helpful in ward dismantling. The problem was, wards were designed precisely so that they couldn't be dismantled from certain angles. For protective wards, like the kind put on houses, the ward could only really be taken down from the inside. To break it from the outside required unimaginable preparation and exact application of specific runic counters. The inverse was true for the kind of containment ward she was in. It would take skill she didn't have to figure out a way through. The longer she spent analyzing the problem, the more convinced she became that her only option was to overpower Pettigrew physically and wrest the time-turner away from him. If she could get back to a point in time before Pettigrew had activated the wards, she could blast her way out with magic.

The jewel was a problem. It could cripple her body before she got close enough to take Pettigrew down. If she could just find a way around it, she would be on her way to freedom.

Pettigrew was gone for hours and hours. It felt as though most of the day (or night, she wasn't sure anymore) had passed before he appeared again. She was caught off guard, having been attempting to scratch an identification rune into the wall in a bid to learn more about how the ward was constructed. His angry voice caused the rock in her hand to slip and her heart rate to skyrocket as she turned to see him bearing down on her.

"I finally figured it out," he said, looking entirely too manic to make any deduction, must less correct ones. He held the jewel in front of him like garlic held before a vampire and she found herself scrambling back before it, much to her disgust. "I know how you're doing it. You have a magic suppressor, don't you? This whole time, you've been wearing something that locked your magic up beyond my reach. Clever little beast, aren't you? Well. That ends tonight."

So it was nighttime, she thought in a distant part of her mind. That would make it…Tuesday evening? Three full days until anyone would notice her missing. She needed to stall longer, somehow.

Her herded her with the jewel back into her circle. He cast the Protective Potion around her again and she wondered how exactly he was planning on getting her suppressor off, now that he knew it was there. He clearly wasn't planning on taking it off of her physically—as if he could. It was irremovable to anyone but herself. She could outlast Pettigrew's determination. She was sure of it.

"Take the suppressor off," Pettigrew said, fists clenched in ire on the other side of the barrier.

She shook her head silently, waiting for his true attempt.

"I will take everything on you away, item by item, until I discover which it is," Pettigrew snarled.

She blanched, an icy fear that came from a place she rarely even acknowledged suddenly making itself known. He…wouldn't really… She took in his resolute expression. He would, she realized. And then he would know her secret, the one thing she wanted to protect above all else. She would have to—she cut off that thought ruthlessly. She did not have to do anything.

Her choices lay before her, crystal clear. She could take off her suppressor, surrendering her magic to the control of the jewel, and keep her secret. She could also hold onto her suppressor and resign herself to the uncovering of her deepest deception. The suppressor could not be taken off of her without her consent. As long as she hung onto it, even if all other articles of her clothing were stripped away, she would retain control of her magic. If she gave over the magic to Pettigrew's attempt to control it…he would probably kill her as soon as he had what he needed to fulfill the prophecy.

Would she die, then, to protect her secret? Would she take it to the grave? It was a moment of utter clarity for her. The answer was so immediate that she didn't have to even think about it long. No. She wouldn't. Not in these circumstances.

She folded her arms around herself protectively, but resolutely shook her head again. She would not take the suppressor off. Not even if it meant her secret was revealed. Some things, she discovered in that moment, were more important than her ruse.

Pettigrew growled in annoyance. She said, hoping against hope to dissuade him against all odds, "It can't be summoned. You'll be wasting your time. This whole thing is a waste of time."

"We'll see," he said, pulling out his wand. "Accio suppressor!"

She felt a brief, intense pain in the finger on her left hand, but did not react to it. The spell hadn't worked. She could see the wheels working in his head as he took in the barrier between them. How slowly they must turn, she thought scornfully.

After a time, he seemed to strike on an idea. The jewel shone brightly as he turned it toward her. The heat that enveloped her was entirely predictable and she was heartily sick of it.

Take off the suppressor. Her mind focused unnaturally on that one idea, even as another part of her swam angrily against the current in protest. Take the suppressor off now. He hands, apparently detached from her good sense, began moving outside of her consciousness. They stripped her left glove away and twitched toward the jade ring before she ground their movement to a halt through sheer, concentrated willpower. No! She refused to give in at this juncture when she'd endured so much to keep Pettigrew away from her magic. She clenched her fists and pulls her hands as far apart as she could, panting wildly at the strain even so simple a directive put on her mind. Take the suppressor off. The jewel hummed in her head insistently, but she was onto its game. She could fight it, she now knew.

"I…won't," she ground out between her teeth.

The pressure on her skull abruptly stopped. Pettigrew was gazing at her with considering eyes. "My control usually gets easier with each successive attempt. You seem to be getting better at resisting, somehow. It doesn't matter, though. Now I know your suppressor is one of those rings. If I can't make you take it off with the jewel, I will use other means to persuade you."

That was the only warning she got before pain invaded her senses and drove her to the dirt. What was he playing at? He knew he couldn't draw her magic out by force! He was using the pain to try and force her into giving in and taking the ring off. That—she didn't have the words. That he would sink to actual torture to get his way—! She didn't know why, but a part of her felt betrayed. Until now, it had seemed like Pettigrew felt he had to act the way he did, in order to achieve his ends. Now, though…he was torturing her to speed things along in lieu of any actual cunning or power. Well, screw that.

She rolled with the pain gamely. It was tearing up her body, this constant pressure on her magical coils, but she didn't care anymore. She was angry. Her magic could go boil itself for all she cared. Pettigrew and the jewel, too. She wouldn't give him the satisfaction. Not even if it crippled her.

She held onto consciousness much longer than she had previously, she thought. It wasn't a happy thought, but it gave her a certain grim satisfaction that she would not have recognized in herself just days ago. What was this place doing to her? There was no time to wonder in what form she might emerge, if she ever did escape. She was already slipping into the blackness of oblivion once more.

When she woke, it was to the feeling of someone fumbling eagerly with her left hand. She clenched it in silent denial, but it was pressed flat to the floor with the exception of the finger she wore her rings on. The basilisk ring was pulled off carelessly, then fingers slid for purchase on the ring of jade. Pettigrew cursed, the sound so close it sent air wafting against her neck. She tried to lift her head, but a rippling agony shot through her muscles each time she attempted to tense them.

"Why won't it move?" Pettigrew hissed.

"It's irremovable," she garbled, trying the same lie that hadn't worked on Riddle.

"No," Pettigrew seethed. "It can't be. I'll—I'll cut it off."

She clenched her teeth at that mental image. Should she just take it off? Her hands meant a lot to her. It wasn't her knife-wielding hand, but still…if he was going to cut her finger off then the suppressor would come off either way.

"No…wait. What's this?" Pettigrew's breathing picked up and his hand stroked over the jade band slowly. "This is…it's creature magic."

A pool of dread bled into her gut and her breath hitched abruptly. No. Surely he couldn't—

Pettigrew began to laugh gleefully. "This is too perfect. This whole time, the answer was right in front of me."

She squinted from the corner of her eye to see him holding the jewel close to her hand. The ring on her finger got hot all of a sudden. It hurt, but nothing like when Riddle had tried to force it off, and Riddle's attempt paled in relation to the pain she'd been introduced to in the last few days, in any case. This pain was a shadow of true pain. A blip on the radar of suffering. Pettigrew's gleeful muttering was far more devastating. "It is Fate, that it should come down to this. Creature magic is my purview. I'll have this off in a sec—" He paused abruptly. "No. That isn't—I have to be smarter." She felt him leave her side and heard his quick footsteps scraping through the dirt. She tried to get some response from her body while he was gone, but her muscles felt completely shredded. Just breathing hurt in places she hadn't known even had nerve endings.

She heard the now-familiar sound of a potion being poured onto the ground and intuited his plan. He was enclosing her in a barrier, now that he knew how to remove the suppressor. Once it left her finger, her magic would be unleashed and he didn't want to risk it getting at him before he could control it. He was almost annoyingly cautious. She supposed someone like him had to be, as opposed to someone like Riddle Jr., whose arrogance was in part a reflection of his faith in his own ability.

It seemed entirely unfair that the powers of the jewel could reach through the barrier while regular magic and physical things could not. Rigel supposed it was not the Protective Potion's fault. The shield it was based on must not have been designed to withstand mysteriously omnipotent artifacts. She would fix that, if she ever got the chance.

She tried to think of some way to stop Pettigrew from getting at her magic. She had run out of things to try, however. She had no more diversions or misdirections up her sleeve. When the suppressor began to heat once more, she clenched her eyes in true despair. There was nothing she could do. When the jade ring shattered, she braced herself for the storm.

At last. He could feel the power unfurling on the other side of the shield and it delighted him. He was finally succeeding. With this magic under his control, the prophecy would be fulfilled and the Jewel would fully bond with him. Then he would be unstoppable.

He bent the Jewel's power toward the barrier. He would make sure the magic was under control, first. Then he would soak it up into the Jewel like a sponge soaking up water. He felt the Jewel's happy thrum in response to his plan and smiled slowly. He was so close. All of his efforts were finally going to pay off.

CRACK.

He jumped backwards and stared, shocked, at the barrier. It had shuddered underneath the assault of the boy's magic. What was it doing? How was the boy controlling it without a wand? Once he drew it out of the boy, it should have been aimless. Dangerous, yes, but wild, like all the other creatures whose magic he'd taken. And yet his eyes told him frantically that the magic was coiling, marshaling itself, and aiming for the side of the barrier closest to him. As though it knew he was a threat. As though it were resisting with a modicum of intelligence.

Peter shook his head rapidly. That wasn't possible. It was the boy—he must have some kind of wandless magic capabilities that came out when his magic was released. He didn't waste time wondering why the boy had so much magic locked away in the first place. What did he care why the boy did anything? All that mattered was severing his unnatural control over the freed magic.

He readjusted the Jewel's target. Instead of attempting to soothe the magic, it would wrap itself around the boy. If Pettigrew could make him fall asleep, his will would be severed and the cohesion keeping the magic together would scatter. Go to sleep, he commanded. Go to sleep now. It should have been easy. The boy was obviously still weakened from his attempt to hold out against removing his suppressor. That, combined with the mind weakening herbs should have made him incredibly pliant. Instead, Peter felt a desperate scrabbling against the power of the Jewel, as though falling asleep were the scariest thing the boy had ever been made to do. Peter scowled and poured all of the power he could muster into the command. Go to sleep.

The boy resisted several long minutes before his body finally collapsed in unconsciousness. Peter felt a rush of triumph—until the barrier CRACK-ed loudly once more under the assault of the boy's magic. He stumbled back, utterly terrified. It shouldn't be possible. The boy was asleep—no one could use magic in their sleep. He desperately turned the Jewel back to the cloud of magic that hung menacingly suspended on the other side of a transparent—and worryingly flimsy, it seemed—shield.

His every attempt to wear the magic down with the Jewel was met with implacable defiance. The Jewel slid away from the magic like water over glass, utterly ineffectual. He could feel the Jewel itself becoming frustrated and he channeled that on top of his own desperation, unable to believe that this child's magic had a will that was stronger than the Dominion Jewel. It had subjugated nations. It had transformed the souls of countless unworthy wielders and raised them to from obscurity to prominence. It could not be thwarted by the wild energies of an underdeveloped fleshling—

Peter grasped his head with his free hand in sudden pain. Were those… were those his thoughts? He didn't think so. Was the Jewel…? He felt a rush of glee at his realization. It was bonding with him. It was finally recognizing him as its rightful master. It would come into his soul, now, and make him stronger, smarter, better looking, and—focus.

Yes. He had to get control of that magic. That was the most important thing. Together with the Jewel, they could not fail.

Except, they did. Over and over for hours until Pettigrew was quite sure the magic was some sort of preternatural force of nature that had been possessing the child somehow. The Jewel just couldn't get a grasp on it from any direction. Its power was jolted away at every angle by an untiring unruliness the likes of which Peter had never imagined. The first time he saw the protective barrier around the boy begin to crack, he could not quite fathom it. He had seen this shield deflect dragon fire, for Merlin's sake. He was barely able to get a second shield poured around the first before it shattered completely.

From then on, he ran through potion after potion, trying to keep a barrier between himself and the magic. There was not an endless supply of the potion, however. After pouring a vial onto the dirt and watching it smoke and fizzle uselessly, he realized he was out of the potion he needed completely. The final barrier began to flicker ominously each time the magic slammed against it and Peter admitted he could not go on in this way. Something would give, and he was certain it would be the shield.

Bitter and angry, he fled the cavern. The wards would keep the magic locked in until he came up with another plan. It seemed he had another unexpected hurdle to overcome. As he slunk through the small tunnel that led to the surface, he had to wonder if he shouldn't just find some other kid to control. This one was clearly too much for him. The Jewel gave a displeased jolt of magic that dug into his head painfully at the thought. It wanted that magic. And it would have it. He felt the certainty seep from the Jewel into himself, calming his mind and steadying his nerve. Yes. He would have that power. One way or another.

Rigel awoke slowly, wondering if she'd been transported to a far-off island. She could feel the breeze on her face. It smelled of salt. She must be close enough to see the ocean. If only she could open her eyes. They felt caked shut. Probably got some sand in them, she sighed. She started to stretch, then groaned as her every muscle protested. Why did her limbs feel like noodles? Had she been swimming too long? As if on cue, a cramp made itself known in her abdomen. She gasped, but breathing was difficult, too. Was she underwater? She struggled to open her eyes despite the gritty buildup keeping them closed.

She was met with dimly lit darkness and the sight of dirt all around her. She moaned in disappointment as reality crept back into her head, almost apologetically. Her magic was free, swirling restlessly around the little circle she was stuck in. Its movement had been the breeze she felt. The smell of salt was the crusted sweat all over her face. She couldn't breathe because her lungs were bruised from all the exertion they'd been through in the last few days. The pain in her abdomen wasn't a swimmer's cramp—it was ravenous hunger.

She had to sit up, she told her muscles firmly. They politely refused. She had to sit up, she told them. She needed the apple that was stashed under her robes—

The apple dropped onto her cheek and bounced onto the dirt beside her face. What…? She strained her eyes in the semi-darkness to see her magic hovering curiously above her. She laughed weakly, then winced at the pain that caused. "Great," she whispered hoarsely. "Now…can you lift it into my mouth?"

The apple twitched, then rolled from the dirt up the side of her face, coming to a stop on top of her lips. She opened her mouth and took a bite. Sloppy, yet effective, she thought with dark amusement. The magic obligingly held the apple in place until she'd eaten every bit that wasn't stem or seed.

Now a Pain Relief Potion, she thought hopefully. The clinking of a vial was music to her ears, and a moment later she was struggling not to choke as the liquid was poured down her throat. It took mere minutes to kick in and she was then able to override her muscles' complaints and sit up fully.

Pettigrew was nowhere to be seen. He couldn't have left more than twelve hours ago, or the barrier would have fallen, she reasoned, so she figured it was…Wednesday? Maybe? Two more days. She could hold out for two more days, surely. She didn't know how she expected anyone to find her, even once they noticed her missing, but she didn't want to discount the possibility just yet. There were a lot of people who would care if she disappeared…right? One of them would find a way. Sirius was an Animagus, even. He might be able to widen the tunnel enough to fit his shaggy dog form through. She just had to be patient.

She made her way to her pile of robes and took a quick inventory. There was a little bit of water left, which she polished off quickly. She downed a Nutrient Potion—her last one—and thought about taking another dose of Pain Relief, but reasoned she should save them.

Taking the potions was about the extent of what her energy reserves would allow her to physically accomplish. She sat, hunched over her lap and clutching her shoulders in opposite hands wearily. She lost track of time, there in the eye of her magic's lazy hurricane, trying not to think about anything, because every thought that led back to Pettigrew or her current situation was a thought that sent her magic buzzing angrily around her. Its anger and hate was a palpable thing and she hoped vaguely that Pettigrew had some sort of plan for when he came back. Her magic was ready to kill him.

Ignoring the sinister pleasure that coursed through her magic at that idle thought, she wondered if that wouldn't be a good thing. If her magic killed Pettigrew, she could take the time-turner from his corpse and turn back to before the wards were set on her prison, letting her escape. Despite her magic's excitement at that plan, something bothered Rigel about it. What was the matter with it?

Setting aside questions of morality, which she felt were entirely ambiguous at this stage from anyone's point of view, there was something about the idea of taking the time-turner and turning back to before Friday evening that sent an unconscious shiver of fear down her spine. What was it? It was like she was forgetting something she wasn't supposed to—

"No," she whispered aloud, shocked into voicing her denial by the force with which the despair suddenly hit her. No, no, no. She couldn't go back to before the wards were set. Why hadn't she remembered the first rule of time-turning? There could never be more than six versions of oneself in any given time. Tuesday, how many times had she done Tuesday morning? Three in the course of her normal class schedule, once brewing in the Room of Requirement, and once…once out running on the other side of the lake while everyone was in class. That was five times. It hadn't seemed reckless at the time. But now…Pettigrew had taken her back a full week, so she now had six selves existing simultaneously on Tuesday morning. If she went back again…well, she wasn't sure what would happen, but she was pretty sure the words 'crippled magically for life' had been tossed around while Snape was explaining it.

She felt tears well as the full realization of her doom came upon her. She couldn't use the time-turner to escape. It had been the last resort left to her that depended on her own impetus. All that remained was the hope that someone would come or Pettigrew would leave himself open to some manipulation that would get him to let her out.

She took deep, slow breaths for a long time, just focusing on getting through the next second, then the next, then the next. Once she was certain she wasn't going to fall apart, she turned her attention to modifying her immediate plans. Pettigrew could not die. He was one of the two tickets out she could come up with.

Her magic roared in fury at that resolution, denial in every drop. It slammed into her seated form and sent her bowling to the side. The winds grew sharp, cutting her exposed skin and ripping into her clothing mercilessly. Okay, she thought at it frantically, all right. She would not think of keeping Pettigrew alive, then. She would not think of him at all.

Her magic remained suspicious, so she began reciting the ingredients for a Befuddlement Draught in alphabetical order until it went back to circling their prison slowly, almost peacefully. She hoped it was enjoying its time free. Once she was out of here, she would be finding a way to remedy that. The magic growled. It was more of a feeling than a noise, but she ignored it all the same and stuck her tongue out at it for good measure.

They settled into an uneasy truce after that and she passed the time watching the Marauder's Map. She could see all of her other selves walking about the castle, innocently oblivious to what would befall them in a matter of days. She watched her friends go from class to class and tried to imagine their faces where the little dots were. She strained her memory to recall what they'd been talking about when one of her dots converged on one of theirs, and made up fanciful dialogue to substitute for the conversations that had been too short or inane to remember.

She watched them until her eyes slid in and out of focus dispiritedly. Pettigrew's dot was in the library, where it had been all day. Why hadn't she thought to keep track of him this way earlier? Her mind had not been as sharp as it usually was, throughout this entire trial. When her friends all converged in their beds, she assumed curfew had fallen up in the castle. Pettigrew's dot didn't look to be going anywhere, so she guessed he hadn't yet come up with a way to get what he wanted out of her magic.

Said magic perked up as her thoughts turned its way. The barrier had long since fallen and it had spent the day exploring the small cavern they were trapped in over and over. It didn't seem to have much luck with the wards, which didn't surprise her. They were designed to keep wizards in, and she didn't think the goblins would be careless enough to leave a loophole that allowed a wizard's magic to leave the containment by itself.

If she died in the cavern, perhaps her magic would be smart enough to latch itself onto an animal that wandered down the hole someday. Imagining a squirrel possessed by her demonic magic gave her a tiny amount of amusement, before she recalled that she was dead in that scenario.

She tucked the Map away and curled up on the dirt. She didn't want to sleep, since it meant leaving her magic largely unattended. It couldn't really do anything besides loom at the moment, though, and her body needed the rest. She had to keep herself together until Friday night. Her last thought before drifting off was two more days…

It was late in the day on Thursday when Pettigrew finally returned. He came in as a rat while Rigel was staring up at the ceiling listlessly. She didn't notice until his human self loomed suddenly over her. Even as her head tilted slightly to take in his determined expression, her magic struck from above and behind him, breaking like a wave against a rock.

She eyed the ward that shimmered into existence around the man curiously, but distantly. She was finding it difficult to focus her emotions into anything stronger than boredom. She was so tired, but she couldn't sleep. She was hungry, but the thought of choking down another potion on an empty stomach made her want to retch.

"Get up," Pettigrew said.

She blinked, slowly attempting to put some energy into her body. Her arms moved after much resistance, sliding under her slowly to prop her into a sitting position. Her legs were entirely uncooperative, though. She looked at him blankly, wondering what he wanted with her. It was her magic he cared about now, wasn't it?

He pulled out a bag and her vision narrowed alarmingly. Was there food inside? Water?

"I'll make a trade with you," Pettigrew said, ignoring for the moment the way her magic battered at whatever ward he's managed to erect around his person. Her mind tore itself away from wondering if he'd drawn the runes onto his clothes or onto his skin, refocusing on the bag with almost painful longing as he shook it to keep her attention. "You can have this, if you take an oath for me."

Her mind stuttered to a halt as her gut said No, rather forcefully. Wait, the hungry part of her whined. Let's hear it out.

"An oath to do what?" she croaked.

Pettigrew smirked. "An oath that you will not try to kill me."

She paused for a moment, thinking that over. "What makes you think I would try to kill you?" He gestured to the magic currently hammering away at his rune-powered armor. "That's not me," she said quietly. "I can't keep my magic from killing you."

Pettigrew sneered. "You'll forgive me if I do not believe you. You must be directing it somehow and even if you aren't, I want your word that you will not add your will to the magic's attempts."

"This won't help you," she said, frowning up at him. "Trust me. I kept my magic locked away for a reason and it had nothing to do with that jewel of yours. It's dangerous. And easily provoked. It will try to kill you without my help, if you keep angering it."

"As long as it is without your will, I can control it," Pettigrew said. That was what he'd come up with over the past day? Controlling her to control her magic? If her magic were controllable she would have done it already. Didn't he see that?

Her stomach growled and she forced her mind to consider the problem at hand. If she took an oath not to attempt to kill him, would her magic's actions be considered a violation of the oath? She supposed as long as she acted against her magic trying to kill him as best she could, that would constitute upholding it. She wanted Pettigrew alive, anyway, and she needed the food…it seemed like a positive scenario for her. Was she missing anything? It was so hard to think, lately. Her body's aches constantly distracted her mind and ideas that had once seemed very clear were becoming increasingly muddled.

"Your oath, or the food stops now," Pettigrew warned.

"The prophecy," she tried.

"It will take some time for you to starve," Pettigrew said, looking unconcerned. "I'm sure by then you'll be weak enough that your magic will have lost its forcefulness."

She didn't think the strength of her magic was related at all to the strength of her body, but if Pettigrew believed that, then he really would be willing to watch her slowly waste away. Should she….? Rigel didn't think any other choice would help her more. "All right," she said slowly. "I'll need my wand to swear—"

"Nice try," Pettigrew sneered. "I'll be doing the bonding." He pulled out his wand and stepped toward her. Rigel's magic collected near Pettigrew's wand like a hive of angry bees, but it could not get through the ward that seemed to cover Pettigrew from head to toe, flashing into existence each time her magic got within a foot of the squat man. She wondered where he was getting such effective rune systems. They didn't seem to fit with the bumbling image she had of the man, but she supposed it didn't take a genius to look up an array that someone else had designed and copy down the symbols. Anyway, she shouldn't disparage someone who had successfully beaten her into the dirt for nearly a week. It was an indirect insult to herself.

She eyed Pettigrew's wand, considering, but he kept it well back from her reach, and her muscles had not the strength to move at anything above a snail's pace, anyway. He clasped her hand and raised it to the proper position for her, then said, "Make the oath."

She gathered her thoughts and willed them with difficulty into coherent words. "I…" she paused. She could not say her name. She would do what she had when she swore the oath with Flint and merely refer to herself by intent. "…do hereby swear not to conspire with my magic to kill Peter Pettigrew, nor to make any attempt myself to end his life." She waited to see if he was satisfied and, after a long moment, he nodded and sealed the oath.

"So mote it be."

"So mote it be," she echoed. A golden thread wrapped around her wrist and disappeared, leaving no trace. It was done, for better or worse.

Pettigrew dropped the bag into her lap and she dug in eagerly. There was a single raw potato inside, and a canteen only half-filled with water. Her fists clenched angrily on the sides of the sack, but she pulled the contents out anyway. It was all she had.

Her magic, enraged at the disappointed bitterness that had engulfed her at the thought of eating raw potato, reacted rather predictably. It lashed at Pettigrew from every angle, engulfing his ward-protected form in a vortex of slashing winds.

"Stop it! You swore!" Pettigrew cried out fearfully.

Rigel didn't think her oath constituted a promise to keep her magic from reacting on her behalf, but just in case, she swiftly cleared her mind of anything related to Pettigrew or the potato, chanting the thirty-six uses of the Aloe Vera plant. Antifungal, antiviral, antibacterial, burns, constipation, stomach cramps, inflammation…

Her magic calmed marginally, but still hovered suspiciously over Pettigrew's head. "I can stop it from attacking you on my behalf, but I can't make it not react in its own defense," she warned him. "You'd better leave it alone, if you're so afraid of it."

"I'm not afraid," Pettigrew snapped. He had the jewel in his hand once more, however, and his thumb stroked over it in a way that was blatantly self-reassuring.

You should be, she thought. Her magic was as wild as she'd ever seen it and she suspected the only reason it hadn't done something more drastic by now was because it was marginally free to move about and exert its will, for once. As soon as Pettigrew succeeded at all in gaining a measure of control over it, the magic would probably show its true colors. She hoped dearly that Friday would come before he made any progress. Otherwise they were both in trouble. Just one day more…

The world was conspiring against him. Every step he took landed him two paces back. It wasn't fair! He'd done everything the Jewel told him to. He'd earned the power and yet it floated tantalizingly out of his reach. No matter what he did, the boy's magic resisted. He'd given himself a blinding headache trying to batter it into submission, but his desperation made no difference.

The Jewel was growing angry with him. Each new failure sent a backlash of pain resonating in his head that made it harder and harder to focus. The prophecy rang tauntingly in the back of his mind. 'Ere the moment be expired…'

He needed more time. Yes, that was all. He could figure it out, if he just had more time. Time. He had time, of course, what was he thinking? He would have to work quickly, of course, but then—no, he had no need to. This place…it could easily be made to accommodate his needs. And it had been! He smirked gleefully. The boy looked uneasy at the expression on his face. As well he should. He had great plans. First he would need a little help, but soon they would come to fruition. There was no turning back, now. The die was cast.

As Pettigrew inexplicably slipped out of the cavern on Thursday night, Rigel had to wonder what he was up to now. The last day had been an exercise in patience, on her part, at least. Keeping her mind continually occupied with things that didn't involve maiming Pettigrew had become more and more difficult the longer he provoked her magic with that blasted jewel of his. He either had no sense of self-preservation or he honestly thought he was going to be able to control her magic. Even watching him try, it had become clear to her early on that he wasn't making any headway at all. It was a little terrifying, actually, knowing that her magic had been able to shrug off so easily the powers of the Dominion Jewel, when she herself had been so quickly ensnared by it.

She supposed she ought to be grateful for her magic's implacable nature, for once. It was the only thing standing between her and Pettigrew deciding she'd lost her usefulness. The thought of Pettigrew leaving her to die riled her magic to a dull roar, so she quickly thought about something else. Like the fact that she needed to relieve her bladder before Pettigrew got back. Her body ached weakly in response to even the thought of moving far enough that she wouldn't be offended by the proximity of the waste.

Before she had mustered the strength to do anything about her body's pressing need, a very alarming invisible tug moved her in a kind of self-levitation several feet away. That was…convenient. Her freed magic was quite the unexpected boon, it seemed. When it wasn't lurking menacingly over her shoulder, that is. The magic slunk off toward the other end of the cavern, seemingly in response to her wry thought. She had to admit, it was almost like having company.

Pettigrew came back an hour or so after he left. When he reentered the cavern, however, he was not alone. There were five live nifflers following close behind him. They barely squeezed through the entrance hole and, once inside, they lined up like soldiers before their general, apparently awaiting Pettigrew's command.

"What are those for?" she asked, struggling to lift her head from the floor. She knew she ought to be stretching her muscles and working her way back to full movement, but it hurt too much to contemplate, so she just turned her head sideways from where she was lying and squinted at the nifflers in confusion.

"Don't you recognize them?" Pettigrew asked, sounding very excited about something.

She didn't know any nifflers personally, so she wasn't sure how he expected her to recognize them. The only ones she'd even seen recently were the dead…wait… She shifted her head slightly to take in the spot where there was a pile of dead nifflers. Oh. No. This was bad. If they were the same nifflers as had been dead on Friday evening, then… She looked at the five perky nifflers with a newfound sense of horror. How did their dead bodies get into the past? Surely Pettigrew wasn't going to…he wasn't going to go back another week, was he? She thought hard. What good would that do him, besides allowing him to plant the dead nifflers for his past self to use to finish up the rune sequence on the cavern?

He must realize he was running out of time before someone noticed her missing. How did he plan on getting more time to control her magic without… her there to…?

"No," she said, struggling against the pain to try desperately to sit up. Her muscles locked and seized and she growled in impotence. "You can't."

"Caught on, have you?" Pettigrew sneered. "You didn't think your imprisonment was nearly over, did you? I have as much time with you as it takes to—"

"You don't understand," she snapped, panting harshly as the effort it took her lungs to speak. "You can't take me back to the past again. There's a limit to how many times a person can turn back. You can't live a single moment more than six different times. It causes a resonance in the core that—"

"What are you talking about?" Pettigrew growled. "This plan is perfect. And anyway, I've already done it, don't you see? That's why the nifflers were left there. I finally figured it out—it's a sign. So I know what I have to do—or what I've done…" He looked very close to scratching his head in confusion, but shook it instead. "Look, I know what I'm doing. I have to take you back, to get more time with your magic. I don't even have to build a whole new prison because…well, you'll see."

"I'm telling you it isn't possible," she said, coughing as the strain on her voice became too great. "You…can't take me back. I've already done parts of this week six times."

"You're lying," Pettigrew snapped. "It isn't going to work."

"Please, I'm not," she begged. "You can go look it up in the library—it'll be in any book about time-travel, honest—"

"Oh, yes, go looking through the library again and in the meantime you'll wait patiently for someone to notice your absence and come and save you, is that it?" Pettigrew laughed. "I'm not going to ever allow you that chance. We'll turn back tonight and do the week again. If I need more time, we'll turn back another week, and another, until I find a way."

"I'm telling you I'll die," she said weakly.

"I know," Pettigrew said. He looked hesitant for a moment, then added, "I've known you were going to die for a while, actually. I can smell it."

She had no idea what he was talking about, but she knew she couldn't let him take her back in time. She struggled to sit up, gasping and crying at the knives that shot through every part of her as she did so. She needed to sit up. She had to move past the pain. There was no other choice.

As Pettigrew was coaxing the nifflers one by one into his burlap sack, Rigel was focusing all her attention on finding a way to stand, to get away from the man. She made it to her knees,and then, amazingly, felt an alien strength flooding into her muscles. Her magic was trying to help her, she realized. It sent air into her lungs even as the organs shuddered and stalled. It cleared the pain from her mind as she put first one foot beneath her, then the other. It steadied her legs when her knees threatened to buckle and it solidified her stomach muscles in anticipation of the coming fight. She would not let this happen.

When Pettigrew saw her standing, he gave her a pitying look. "You haven't the strength to fight anymore, boy."

Her trembling limbs agreed with him, but Rigel was stubborn. She would fight, because to do otherwise was to concede to death willingly.

Pettigrew stepped forward slowly and she sank into a trembling crouch. He dropped the sack from his left hand and took his right out of his pocket. To her surprise, she didn't see a wand or the jewel in his other hand. It was curled into a fist. Could he really be so arrogant? She opened her eyes wide and focused entirely on the way Pettigrew's body shifted back and forth uncertainly. He was not an experienced fighter, from the look of his stance. She was in no shape to be tussling with anyone, but if her magic would keep her propped up, she could last long enough to knock him out, maybe. The oath prevented her from killing him, but she could at least destroy the time-turner.

She ignored the doubtful voice in the back of her head that said she couldn't have destroyed the time-turner if there was a pile of niffler carcasses in the cavern when she'd arrived. Not unless she had escaped and then requested that a Ministry official kill some nifflers and plant them at a certain time to protect the time stream.

There was no more time for doubts, though, as Pettigrew made his move. His fist shot forward toward her and she had no trouble at all dodging to the left, the strength from her magic lending her a speed that she considered acceptable in the circumstances. His fist flew past her ear and she thrust her own toward his solar plexus. She connected solidly, pulling a gasp from Pettigrew as he retracted his fist instinctively. On its way back toward him, however, the fist opened and a spray of dark powder caught her square in the nose and eyes.

Sleeping Dust, was all she had time to comprehend before the world went black.

She awoke feeling surprisingly good—not good, she amended, but better than she had in a while. How long had she been asleep? Her mind went back to the last thing she remembered and her blood ran cold. She sat up swiftly and looked around her. She was still in the cavern. She frantically looked to where the pile of nifflers had sat—there. She slumped in relief. They were still there. Then she hadn't been taken back in—wait. There were only four. Where was—

A sickening squeal followed by an ugly squelch had her turning slowly to the other side of the room. Pettigrew held the last niffler by the tail and his wand had just perforated its guts from groin to liver.

She glared at the Animagus as he tossed the last carcass carelessly into the pile. How infuriating that he would act so casual about killing things. She supposed she shouldn't be surprised. He'd just killed her, after all. She started to shake as it sank in that she was truly finished. Come Tuesday morning, there would be seven of her in existence. Her core would resonate wildly and, if a regular wizard could expect to be crippled or maimed by the experience, she could only imagine what the resonance of a core as big as hers would cause. She imagined being split into a thousand different pieces and cringed. What an awful way to go. She wondered how much time she had left.

"How long…" She couldn't complete the sentence; instead she coughed through her disused throat uncontrollably.

"You've been asleep almost an entire day," Pettigrew told her, wiping his knife off slowly. "It's Friday afternoon. You missed my nifflers' excellent work. Oh, well. I suppose you'll get to see if firsthand, won't you?"

He gestured to a spot a few feet away, where there was a good-sized hole in the dirt floor of the cavern. But where did it go? Why would he bother digging a hole underneath the hole they were already in? Her mind caught up a moment later. They were about to overlap their own time stream, of course. She and Peter would show up in the cavern Friday evening, which meant the two of them couldn't also be there, obviously. He was going to move her to a lower chamber of the same prison. He must have had the nifflers building it all day.

She moved forward to look down the hole with a grimace. It was much smaller than this cavern. Her gaze flicked to her folded robes, pockets stuffed with what was left of her useful potions stash. She needed to take that with her. Even if she only lived another three days, she could at least make them comfortable days. No one deserved to die in pain.

She looked around the cavern for her magic and found it unexpectedly settled near the dirt roof, rather docile. Had it calmed down while she was asleep? Was it running out of steam? A rumbling feeling of disagreement rolled through her. It was waiting. For what?

"It's been quite well-behaved," Pettigrew told her, smirking triumphantly. "That Sleeping Dust really did the trick. Too bad your family will never know how useful I found their little joke product." He laughed at the irony of her attempt being thwarted by a Marauder product in particular, then looked up at where her magic hovered like an overgrown bat. "I've let it be and its strength seems to be waning. Soon, it will be easy to control. First, we must move locations, though."

She ignored him as he went about the room, erasing all signs of their having been there. She had to marvel at how different the cavern looked, just one week earlier. She had forgotten how smooth the floor had been before so many Protection Potions had been pored on it. The whole cavern smelled cleaner, which she supposed reflected the lack of a week's worth of waste buildup. She wished she could say the same about herself. She stank royally and her teeth were so fuzzy she thought they might be growing a winter coat.

"Feeling nostalgic?" Pettigrew asked, rather cruelly. "Enjoy your last look around. You won't see it again."

"You seem pretty sure," Rigel said, her voice empty.

"I am," Pettigrew said flatly. He beckoned her forward toward the hole. She pondered whether she wanted to go quietly or not. She felt like resisting on principle, at this point, but she also wanted to keep her stash of potion vials. In the end, she decided it wasn't worth the fight. She gathered her robes into her arms slowly, as though reluctant. Really, she was just hiding the faint sound of clinking. She came to the edge of the hole and looked down. It wasn't more than four feet down. She wouldn't even be able to stand up in the lower cavern, it seemed. She hesitated at the edge, really not wanting to go down there, but a push from Pettigrew solved her reticence. Belatedly, she realized that the wards must have been modified sometime while she was asleep so that they stretched far enough down to cover the lower level. Otherwise, she could never have passed through the floors without being accompanied by Pettigrew in his Animagus form. When was this guy going to make a mistake? she thought with utter frustration as she fell.

She dropped to her knees and moved out of the way before Pettigrew could toss the lantern on top of her. Instead of that, he tossed her bag down, which she just managed to catch before it hit the ground. She clutched it to her, backing away as far as she could. It wasn't far. The entire hole seemed to be ten feet across. When Pettigrew jumped into the hole without the lantern, she frowned until she realized with dismay that the lantern had been in the upper chamber when they'd first arrived. They couldn't take it with them.

Pettigrew closed the ceiling behind them with the jewel, its light the only thing distinguishing the space around them. She had to wonder what exactly his plan consisted of, at this point. As far as she could tell, he had brought no provisions. She spotted a hole close to where she was sitting and supposed he must have created an alternate exit for himself from this lower chamber. Was he planning on doing something similar to the week before, leaving every day or so and gathering sustenance? That would get old quickly, she thought—then again, she probably wouldn't be around the whole week, this time.

"The last few days I've wondered where the smell was coming from," Pettigrew said casually as he took out his wand. "I thought it was just you, at first. It wasn't until I realized I was going to build this room that I recognized the scent as death." Her breath caught in her throat as he turned to her with cold eyes. "You're going to die here. Haven't you noticed the rotting garbage smell at all over your own stench? That was you, I'm afraid."

It couldn't be. Her stomach rebelled in protest. She'd been smelling…her own corpse? That was beyond twisted. She watched in horror as Pettigrew set up a Secrecy Charm. She didn't know why he bothered, as no one would hear them fifteen feet below ground, but then she realized that it was so the versions of themselves that would shortly be above them wouldn't hear anything. And they wouldn't be able to hear them, either. It was so creepy to think of two parallel versions of herself existing so close, with one having no idea of the tragic future that awaited her. She felt an acute sympathy for the her of one week ago. She'd been so sure that if she was patient enough and clever enough she could get out of anything. How ridiculous. In the end, her greatest ruse had been one of self-deception.

What did she think, that just because Riddle Jr. had been arrogant and careless that every villain was so? That just because Pettigrew wasn't impressive meant he wasn't dangerous? Wasn't ruthless? How foolish she'd been. And all the time she'd been thinking he was the fool. She wondered morbidly if it was the destabilization of her core on Tuesday that killed her, or if Pettigrew wrangled control of her magic before then and did her in himself. She'd noticed his hesitation and reluctance fading away over the past week. He was coming into this whole 'evildoer' thing. He'd probably have no compunction about killing her himself, at this point.

He certainly seemed to be in no hurry, as he curled into a ball to sleep on the other side of the small hole. She knew how endless time could seem, when you held its lever in your hand. She thought he was putting an awful lot of faith in his personal ward, however. Wards that weren't tied to an anchor of nature didn't typically last very long. She figured he had a few days at best until the runes were corrupted by being exposed all the time. And that was without her magic hammering away at it.

She supposed it didn't matter. Her magic hadn't been doing any hammering lately. She looked up at it, curled in the dome of the new ceiling, and wondered if it had given up. A thrumming negation went through her bones, but that was all the answer she received. She settled down into a kind of detached depression. She didn't really want to sleep. Not if she only had a few more days left to live. What did she want to do? Cure lycanthropy, maybe. She wondered if she thought about it for three days straight if she could come up with a new idea. Then she closed her eyes in new despair.

Even if she cured lycanthropy in her mind, what would she do with her new idea? Scratch it into the dirt? No one would find it. All her ideas would die with her. It would be better not to try, than to risk getting a stroke of brilliance only to die with the knowledge that it would never be realized.

She heard soft snores fill the small cavern and had to think wryly that that was just the icing on the bloody cake. In the moment between that thought and the next snore, her tiny world exploded into chaos.

She was blown back into the wall as her magic descended like a bird of prey without warning. She couldn't see anything in the darkness, but she could feel the incredible wake of the jet stream even at its peripheries. Pettigrew cried out in surprise at being woken by such a battering and a moment later the jewel glowed with light as Pettigrew attempted belatedly to fight back against the sudden assault.

He was pinned to the ground, she realized, amazed. The force of the magic coming down on him was so strong that it was keeping her pressed back against the dirt. How powerful the concentrated propulsion must be. She could see Pettigrew struggling against the current, trying to move out of the way or even lift his hand with the jewel against the magic. He couldn't, though, and the longer he stayed splayed on the dirt like some kind of rare insect on a collector's board, the more amazed she became. Where was her magic getting this power? Had it been biding its time, growing stronger? She didn't put that kind of strategy past her magic, exactly, but she couldn't help but wonder if the influx of freedom was affecting it. It also seemed rather clever to wait until Pettigrew was asleep to launch a counterattack. Her magic was many things, but patient? Not the magic she knew.

Sparks of magic began to fly from where Pettigrew was pressed to the floor and her eyes widened as she realized what she was seeing. The ward Pettigrew had constructed around his person was being forcefully ground against the ward around the chamber that ran through the floor beneath him. The magic in each ward was attempting to neutralize the other and, even before it happened, she could predict the result: the lesser ward would give—in this case, the one around Pettigrew.

It was brilliant. She was terrified and impressed all at once. Was it a coincidence or had her magic come up with that strategy on its own? Caught up in her speculation, she almost didn't recall the oath that she'd made. Should she do something? It was clear from the amount of malevolence coming from her magic what would happen when Pettigrew's personal ward fell. She wasn't breaking the letter of the oath by doing nothing, unless the magic interpreted her silence as allowance or encouragement to do as it pleased. She grimaced. Perhaps she would have to do something after all.

She almost didn't want to. She felt a curious ennui that had been tightening its hold on her ever since she realized that her death was a very likely possibility. What did it matter if the oath turned on her for breaking it, at this point?

Pettigrew's cry of pain and fear moved something within her that she hadn't known still existed, after everything that happened. Even if death awaited her, even if the oath didn't technically require her to come to Pettigrew's defense, she was still Rigel Black. Sitting silently while her magic killed someone was not something she could do, no matter the circumstances that preceded it or those that would follow. She was better than that, even now.

Her body, while much recovered either from her magic's assistance in her stand against Pettigrew or the long stasis that had followed, was not up to the task of physically rescuing Pettigrew from her magic's wrath. She could not control it with mere willpower, either, at this point—she felt drained, emotionally and mentally, and probably wouldn't succeed in controlling a wounded puppy in her current state.

There was something else, though, that she might be able to do.

It had come to her at some point in the past few days, the slow, steady growth of an idea that she'd tucked carefully away from conscious thought, just in case she needed a last resort against her magic's complete separation.

Rigel sank backwards into her own mind, swimming mentally away from reality with relief that was tempered by the knowledge of what she needed to do. The last time she'd seen her magic, it had looked different to her mental senses: visibly changed by the suppressor she had worn. In reality, the ring was only a physical manifestation of the runic configuration that locked her magic away. What could be done physically could be done mentally, in the realm of magic. She thought, with the proper application of Occlumency, she might be able to replicate the effects of the suppressor on the sun in her space room. She could build a cage, perhaps, or some other sort of mental barrier that would have the same result as the physical barrier the ring had created. In theory, at least. And why did it always seem to come down to that? She really ought to experiment more before she was caught in do-or-die scenarios. Or do-and-die, in this case.

Her mindscape was bright. She knew it was the artificial, sourceless light of her own imagination, but after so many days in near-darkness it was like finding religion. The mountain appeared just as it had when she'd left it last, snowy and still. She flitted into the mountainside cave and noted distractedly the construct that sat in an armchair with blank eyes, an empty shell that she hadn't ever been able to fill. Another project that would go unfinished.

The tunnels under the trapdoor were warm. No, she noticed with a slow frown. They were hot. She began walking faster, now concerned that all was not right in her mental sphere. Temperature wasn't logically consistent in a mental world. Unless one specifically constructed the likeness of the sensation, the mind would be devoid of that sense. She could think of only one thing that might produce true heat in a mindscape—magic.

The door to her space room looked innocuous, but some premonition snagged her attention as she touched the doorknob. There was a sudden shock of energy, like the shot of heat that might be felt in the knob of a door that separated one from a house fire. She couldn't run the other way, though. This was her mind. If there was something wrong, she wanted to know what it was.

She flung open the door to a conflagration. In the center, where the sun of her magic should have been rotating, there was a massive tornado of fire. It swept all the orbs in the room around it in a frantic tailspin, and everywhere flames lashed out and licked at the edges of the room. At the opening of the door, the entire scene seemed to contract in surprise before expanding at a rate that flung her back into the passage with the force if its approach. She stumbled backwards and turned on her heels, sprinting back up the corridor with speed born of desperation. What was that? Her magic had completely broken from its regular mold. There was barely a cohesive shape remaining to the firestorm that she'd witnessed in that room. Had it really run so utterly wild since being set free at last by the breaking of her suppressor?

She jumped the rungs up into her potions lab frantically, flames licking at her heels, and slammed the trapdoor shut behind her to buy herself a little time. What now? she thought. Her plan was completely moot. The fire would consume her if she even tried to contain it. All she could do was slow its progress—

Even that thought was interrupted by the roiling appearance of fire spreading out from beneath the area rug that covered the trap door. She noticed with confusion that the fire wasn't burning anything. The rug remained completely unaffected. It was simply spreading, much as the sleeping sickness had. Would the spread of her magic in such a way also correspond to the loss of control of her body? She hoped not. She stuck a toe nervously in the direction of the closest crawling ember, only to jerk her leg back with a hiss as the magic burnt her. So she was not as immune as her mindscape was. She supposed that made sense. There was no point in her magic destroying the mental landscape—its target was herself, the consciousness that represented the will that had suppressed it for so long, in one form or another.

As her potions lab became infested with fire across every surface, she retreated onto the mountain. Maybe the snow would slow the fire down.

It didn't.

Ice melted away before the unstoppable march of fire. Step by step it chased her further up the mountain, until she finally looked up to find it sliding down the mountain top toward her as well, having crested the other side of the peak to encircle her. With the diameter of snow between her and her magic evaporating beneath her feet, Rigel slowly sat down and put her head in her hands in utter defeat.

So, this is the end. Burned to death in my own mind by my own magic. I didn't see that coming, so at least it was unpredictable. She let out a harsh laugh at the idea that an element of surprise somehow brought some quality of interest to her death. She slammed her fist angrily against the mountain beneath her. What kind of contest did she think she was winning—what is that?

She looked down at where her fist had landed on something that didn't feel like rock at all. It was squishy and black. A leftover piece of the Sleeping Sickness? No, it wasn't that. It was a small orb, half-buried in the rock and still dripping from the snow that had melted away to reveal it. Distracted from her impending doom, she dug her fingers around the sphere and pried it loose. It looked like a memory orb, but it was pure black. She'd never seen one that color, and what was it doing out here, anyway? All her memories were in the space room. She was sure she'd never even seen this one before…

She pulled it closer to her face, trying to make out the memory within. Usually she could tell which one an orb contained by peering into it, but this one seemed to be completely opaque. She shook it a little, wondering if somehow the memory had become congealed by being left under the snow for so long. Instantly, the mindscape around her faded away. She had triggered the memory, she realized as her vision cleared. She looked around, curious. All thoughts of the fire raging out of control in her mind or the magic equally out of control in the cavern faded away as she was immersed in the past.

She stepped out of fog and into the receiving room at Grimmauld Place. There were several adults standing around the room, easily recognizable despite their younger appearances. Sirius was there with Diana, whom she almost didn't recognize. It felt like so long since she'd last seen the beautiful witch, faded and wan, in St. Mungo's disease ward. The couple stood along with James, Lily, and Alice Longbottom. She looked around for herself, knowing that the memory could only have been in her mind if it was hers.

She found herself on the other side of the room, with little black pigtails that she could recall clearly telling her mother she would never wear again on her seventh birthday. She would be six, then, or slightly younger. Archie was squatting on the floor next to her, his chubby fingers drawing a terribly unfortunate picture of a griffin in the dust. His imaginary friend, she remembered dimly. He'd named it something ridiculous, like Finny, and for years had required a seat at every meal to be saved for the invisible griffin, who only ate raisins and whole sticks of butter.

Leaning close to the picture, nodding interestedly with each disproportionately added feature, was a child who, upon closer inspection, she gathered to be Neville Longbottom. He was cheerful-looking and gap-toothed, and he asserted himself quickly by adding a sword and shield to the picture, laughing. "It's the Sword of Griffin-dor, see?"

"He needs a bad guy," young Harry said, poking her own finger into the dust. "To fight."

She watched as her six-year-old self drew a monster with a plethora of teeth. The Floo going off didn't disturb the children, but it caused her to look around in time to see Mrs. Longbottom taking her leave. She had dropped Neville off to play, then. Her vague suspicions confirmed, she watched eagerly to see what would happen next. She had no memory of this day and she desperately wanted to know why.

Sirius called over to the children. "Why don't you all run along and play upstairs in Archie's room?"

Archie and Harry jumped up immediately, Neville only a short beat behind. They raced out of the room and up the narrow staircase. When they got to Archie's room, they slowed to a stop. "We could play vampires and werewolves," Neville suggested, looking between them uncertainly as neither Harry nor Archie made any move to go into the room.

"We don't play that," Archie said, frowning. They hadn't, because Remus' condition was never hidden from them, even at a young age.

"Let's play in the attic," Harry said, smiling slowly as Archie continued to frown.

"We're not allowed…" He drew out the objection in a considering way. He always did that, she remembered, and they always played in the attic anyway.

"What's in the attic?" Neville asked, looking excited.

"Monsters," Harry whispered dramatically.

Neville giggled. "Let's go see!"

Archie finally grinned. "Yeah, let's go. Dad won't check on us for awhile."

They traipsed up another couple of stories, winding through the maze-like house until they came to the door that led up to the attic where Sirius and Diana stored all the old things they didn't want to leave lying about, but also didn't feel right getting rid of. She remembered playing there many times as a child. It was full of old crotchety portraits, forgotten pieces of Black Family memorabilia, and furniture that no longer fit in the rest of the house.

She and Archie had treated it like their own private clubhouse, when they were little. She didn't see what was so unusual about them taking Neville up there. What had happened that was worth forgetting about? And how had she forgotten in the first place?

She watched little Archie try the door and huff, "It's locked." She expected them to turn around and find something else to do—it was what they'd always done when Sirius remembered to renew the locking charm on the attic door. Instead, her younger self stepped forward with a smile.

"No problem," Harry said, reaching forward with her hand. She didn't touch the door, but she scrunched her face into a frown and glared at it for a long moment. To her amazement, the door swung open before her six-year-old self's smug smile. She'd never done that…had she?

"Woah, cool!" Neville said, clapping enthusiastically.

"Come on, show off," Archie laughed, leading the way up the attic stairs. They filed into the attic and Neville gaped appreciatively at the piles of random things scattered in every direction.

"There's so much stuff," he said, eyes wide. "What should we play?"

"Dress up!" Harry said at once. It had been her favorite game. She rushed across the attic to a trunk that sat on an old end table. Throwing it open, the young girl pulled out a long, black cloak with purple fur around the collar. She draped it around her in a pool of silk, lifting her chin haughtily and saying, "I am the great dragon-rider, Targof! I will fly to the moon!"

Archie pulled a hat off a nearby coatrack and flicked the feather out of his face with a grin. "Oh yeah? Well I'm Baniby the Beast Tamer! Uh, Neville, who are you going to be?"

Neville searched the room quickly and grabbed a large golden sheet off the painting behind him. "I am Merlin! My magic cloak of gold protects me from all evil!"

Archie frowned. "You can't be Merlin. Then you'd always win."

"Not if I'm Morgana!" Harry shouted, pointing her finger dramatically at Neville, who looked quite ridiculous swathed in a giant gold toga. "I will defeat you, Merlin, and Camelot will be mine at last! Haha!"

They played in this vein for a long while, each new character becoming more outlandish than the last. She watched them with a frown, still not seeing anything unusual about this memory. It was almost touchingly innocent, in fact.

Eventually the play dissolved into a spirited conversation about what they were going to be when they grew up. "I'll be a Knight of Gryffindor!" Neville cried, brandishing an imaginary wand. "I'll zap my enemies away and be the strongest wizard in all the land."

"What if they sneak up behind you?" Harry said slyly, climbing onto a table and jumping at Neville from above. "Attack!"

Neville leapt aside, pointing his imaginary wand in her direction. "Die, evil wizard!"

Harry pretended to get stunned, stiffening and falling backwards dramatically. She watched in horror as her younger self swooned directly into the path of a ceremonial sword set precariously on a stack of dining room chairs.

Her younger self was not impaled, however. An invisible force caught her just before she hit the pointed tip, pushing her gently back to her feet so smoothly that her younger self giggled and went right back to playing, not noticing anything odd, apparently.

What was going on? Her magic hadn't been that way. She didn't remember anything like the benevolent watchfulness she had just seen.

"This is fun," Neville said after a little bit, breathing heavily and plopping down to rest. "Are you guys gonna be in Gryffindor when you're grown up, too? We should be friends forever."

"Yeah!" Archie said, grinning ear to ear. "We can be just like our dads were—the Marauders return! Right, Harry?"

Harry nodded so fast her pigtails bounced. Then she paused. "What if I'm in Ravenclaw? Is that okay?"

"Of course," Archie said, laughing. "Maybe I'll be in Ravenclaw, too."

"No, you have to be in Gryffindor with me," Neville said, frowning.

Archie looked torn. "Well—"

"Oh, do shut up," a sharp voice cut across their conversation.

"Who's there?" Neville asked, looking frightened. "Is it a monster?"

"It's just a dumb portrait," Archie said, folding his arms. "We must have woke one up."

"We have portraits at my house, too!" Neville said. His fear had gone as quickly as it had come. "They remind me to do stuff sometimes, like tie my shoes or make my bed, and my great-great-great-great aunt Minnie tells me where Papa hides the crisps."

"These ones are mean," Harry whispered, unsuccessfully trying to keep her voice down.

"Yeah, and some say things to Harry that are really rude," Archie agreed.

"Where is it?" Neville said, frowning fiercely. Archie pointed at the portrait Neville had uncovered earlier. She moved through the memory to take a closer look, but she didn't recognize the portrait as one of the ones, like Walburga, who used to yell at her. Neville marched right up to the painting and stuck his finger out angrily. "Don't you be mean to Harry. If you don't have nice things to say, then you shouldn't say anything, that's what Papa says."

She smiled at the future Gryffindor's swift defense. Her younger self just looked worriedly between Neville and the painting. The man depicted had long, dark brown hair and a close-trimmed beard. He sneered at Neville without restraint, drawling. "How the House of Longbottom has fallen."

"Be quiet!" Harry said. "We'll cover you back up if you don't."

"Go ahead," the painting sneered. "Anything would be preferable to watching the utter desecration of the House of Black. Children running wild. Halfblood whelps polluting the air with their obscene naivety."

"I'm not a…a whelp," Harry said quietly. She wondered if she'd even known what that word meant, at that age.

"You are an impertinent fool," the portrait said, painted eyes cold. "And worse, you're an ignorant, impertinent fool."

"Am not," Harry whispered, bright green eyes beginning to fill with tears.

"You speak of attending Hogwarts with your little friends as though they allow your kind to disgrace those halls," the portrait snapped.

"They—they do," Archie piped up, uncertainly. "Uncle Remus went and he wasn't…um…fullblood."

"Yeah!" Neville said, nodding fiercely. "Everyone can go to Hogwarts. You just have to be really good and eat all your vegit-bles."

"Haven't you heard?" The portrait smirked. "Those days are over. How sad that the Heir to the House of Black is less informed than the paintings on his walls." The long-haired man began to laugh darkly, louder and louder.

"Shut up!" Harry shouted, her little fists in tiny balls. "I am too gonna go to Hogwarts."

"You will never set so much as a toe inside the wards, halfblood." The portrait's face twisted in disgust.

"You're a liar," Harry growled. "I can do whatever I want." At the last word, flames engulfed the painting without warning, sending Archie and Neville skipping backwards with shouts of alarm. Little Harry stared angrily at the portrait, watching it burn. It screamed and Harry only glared at it harder. "You're just a stupid painting," the young girl muttered. "I don't have to listen to you."

Archie and Neville ran to hide behind a nearby stack of boxes, both whimpering and looking terrified.

"Stop! Stop it, please," the painting begged, even as oil and canvas melted and twisted together.

"I don't want to," Harry said, her lower lip trembling. She watched solemnly as the rest of the painting was engulfed. Its subject's cries gradually faded as the painting crumbled to ashes, and Harry turned wet eyes to look for her friends. A few leftover embers from her magic jumped from the pile of ash to her hands and traveled up her shoulders in a parody of a hug. It made her look like she was aflame.

She watched her younger self peer about in confusion, wondering where Archie and Neville had gone, and was utterly speechless. How had such a thing happened? Was it real?

Young Harry called out, "Hello? Where'd you go?"

"Is it gone?" Neville's voice was small and timid, nothing like the boisterous fearlessness he'd shown just minutes earlier.

"Yeah, the portrait is all gone," Harry said.

"No, the fire," Neville whispered, peeking out from behind the box.

"Huh?" Harry looked down at the flames that had settled into a warm glow about her shoulders.

"AH!" Neville ducked back into hiding, "Make it go away!"

Harry frowned, looking at herself in confusion. "I…I don't know how."

Archie crept out from behind his box slowly. He eyed the ashes on the floor with a low moan. "Oh, no. We're gonna be in so much trouble."

"We can sweep them up," Harry suggested, yawning a little. She wondered if the potent use of magic had tired her younger self out.

"No, we hafta tell," Neville said, darting from the box to stand behind Archie, eyeing Harry with obvious fear. "When there's a fire you hafta tell a grown up."

She watched her younger self's eyes go wide with panic. "We can't tell!"

"Maybe we should," Archie said, biting his lip.

"No!" Harry said loudly. The magic on her shoulders moved restlessly and Neville squeaked, dipping his head behind Archie's shoulders. Even Archie looked a little scared.

She moved to her younger self's side and placed a phantom hand on the little girl's shoulder. The emotions that flooded her were heartbreaking. She was confused, scared, tired, and hurt. She didn't like how Archie was looking at her. She didn't want to tell. What if Mummy looked at her like that? What if Daddy did, too? Shame made her tremble hard and start to cry. Why did she get so angry? Archie said mean things sometimes, but she never got mad like that at him. It wasn't fair. She didn't mean to.

Archie held out a calming hand, even as the little boy swallowed hard. "It's okay, Harry. Dad won't be too mad. He doesn't like these paintings."

"You can't tell," Harry said desperately. "I—I won't let you."

The magic moved before any of them could react. It swept Archie and Neville up into a glowing fog. Both boys slumped, their eyes closing slowly as their bodies fell to the floor. Harry gasped and ran forward, shaking their shoulders frantically. "Oh, no, no, no. Wake up. Wake up."

The little girl started to cry, fat tears falling to collect under her chin. She watched her cry, finally starting to understand the nature of the memory. She found herself waiting with bated breath for the little boys to wake up, even though she knew they both ended up just fine.

Not long after, Sirius came hurrying into the attic with a worried expression. "Archie? Harry?"

"Over here," Harry said, sniffling. "They won't wake up."

She had never seen Sirius's face so white. He fell to his knees beside his son and checked his pulse frantically. After a long moment he sucked in air and sat back on his ankles, running a hand through his hair. "They're sleeping, Harry. It's okay."

"Really?" Hope came back to Harry's eyes. "They're okay?"

"Yes," Sirius said, now eyeing her sternly. "How many times do I have to tell you two not to play up here? It's incredibly dangerous. I don't even know everything that's up here. You could come into contact with anything."

"I'm sorry," Harry began to cry again. "I didn't mean to. I didn't mean to hurt anyone."

"Oh, Harry, it's not your fault," Sirius said, looking immediately regretful. "I just want you lot to be safe. Run and get Aunty Diana, okay? I'll stay with the boys."

Harry nodded and raced from the room and the memory faded. Everything dissolved into fog, then reformed in a darkened corridor. She spotted her younger self standing silently in the shadows before a cracked doorway. The light inside the room illuminated Sirius talking quietly with Neville's parents.

"How is he feeling?" Sirius was asking, voice tight with concern.

"He seems just fine," Alice said. It was clear she was attempting to be reassuring while confused herself. "He doesn't remember what happened, though."

"Nether does Archie," Sirius said. "He woke up just fine, but can't recall most of the day. I asked Harry what happened, but she didn't want to talk about it. I think whatever happened scared her pretty bad." Sirius blew out a breath. "There's all kind of junk in there. They could have come across anything from sleeping powder to a cursed cummerbund. I don't even know how they got up there. I just renewed the locking charm this morning. I'm so sorry, Alice, Frank. I should have been watching them more closely."

"Neville is a very curious child," Frank Longbottom said, smiling ruefully. "He gets into scrapes all the time. It wasn't your fault. We'll keep a close eye on him, but I don't think there was any real damage done, whatever it was."

"Still…" Sirius trailed off with a frown. "I'll let you know if I find out what it was. Whatever did it needs to be taken out of this house, before it hurts someone else."

Harry smothered a gasp and ran back down the corridor with fear and self-loathing written all over her face.

The scene dissolved and solidified in Archie's room. By the light of a night light she could see Archie sprawled on a pile of blankets on the floor, snoring. Her younger self was lying awake beside him. They must have decided to have a sleepover that night.

Tears dripped silently into the pillow beneath her as Harry stared up at the ceiling with wide, solemn eyes. A stirring of wind brushed against her cheek, ruffling her hair in an almost caressing breeze. Harry bit her lip and shook her head sharply. "Go away," she whispered, her voice choked with sadness.

The wind picked up restlessly around her and Archie stirred slightly in his sleep. "No, go away," Harry hissed into the dark. "Go away and don't come back!"

The wind fell still and Archie sat up with a befuddled, "Wha—?" He looked around and saw Harry awake. "What's wrong?" he asked blearily.

"Nothing," Harry said, turning over so that her tearstained face was hidden. "Nothing's wrong. Go to sleep, Archie."

She knelt down by her six-year-old self's curled up form and patted her head helplessly. At the brief touch, the emotions running through the child blasted through her. Sorrow and shame mixed together with fear of what her family would think if they found out. She wished the day hadn't happened. She just wanted to forget, and she wanted it to never happen again.

The memory stuttered to a halt and Rigel opened her eyes to an alien landscape. The wintery snow of her cold mountain was gone and in its place a lake of golden fire bathed the rock and warmed the air. She took in a deep breath and wiped the tears from her avatar's face. The fire around her had ceased expanding, having claimed every inch of physical territory that her mind would allow. It licked at the mountainside beneath her feet, but she felt no pain. She felt entirely calm, for the first time in a long while.

She understood, now, what she'd been so afraid of all this time. She wasn't afraid of her magic. She was afraid of her own anger. Afraid and ashamed of herself for something that had, in retrospect, been a simple case of overzealous accidental magic. The feeling of dread that crept inside her at the very idea of her magic being more powerful than she liked had stemmed from an infected memory that had festered, like a sore, beneath the skin of her consciousness for all these years.

It relaxed her, to finally know that fear and be able to confront it, to see it for what it was. She could see, now, that it was a child's fear, grown larger and more important than it was by an aura of mystery and a lack of understanding. She was afraid of what other people would think of her, and of her magic, and that was okay. It didn't mean she had to be afraid of herself. She was not a scared little girl anymore. She had grown a lot since then. She was not going to go to her death pale and frightened, a rabbit before a wolf. She refused to let an old memory make a coward of her for a single minute more.

She summoned every ounce of determination she possessed. It was hard. She was tired and drained emotionally. She wanted to curl up and sleep. Instead, she forced herself to remember other memories. She brought to mind the stubbornness and gumption that had brought a halfblood girl to Hogwarts. She thought of her determination to study under Master Snape, of all the bitter sacrifices she made along the way—her relationship with her parents, her appearance, her chance to be recognized by Professor Snape on her own terms, and more. She focused on the fortitude that brought her through obstacles like a basilisk, and on the everyday perseverance it took to lie, over and over, to the people she loved and respected the most.

All of this she drew into her consciousness, like a tree sapping strength from the earth. She channeled it, determined that now, for once and for all, her magic would bow to her—not to her will, a fickle, fleeting, changeable thing, but to her principles. Her magic would bow not to her desires, but to everything she stood for and believed in. To her ironclad character traits. To the part of her that refused to let her magic kill even the man who had imprisoned and tormented her.

You will not hurt anyone else, she thought with all the fierceness in her heart. You will not disobey me. You will act in a way deserving of the power you represent. Starting now, you will be held to the standards to which I hold myself. Irrevocably. Forever.

The fire slid away before her avatar, as krill before a whale. She threw a hand imperiously away from her and the magic was thrown from her mountain in a single swift movement, a blanket cast off after a long sleep. She banished it back into the inner reaches of her mind, following, unhurried, behind its retreat. When she reached the space room, she took in the newly compressed sun, burning brightly and flexing a bit defiantly, as she approached. She sunk her hands into the fire unhesitatingly.

"I'm sorry for how I've been acting," she told it seriously. "But I'm not afraid of you anymore. So you have to act differently, too, now."

The warmth that came emanating from the sun wasn't entirely forgiving, but it was welcoming. She smiled, just a tiny bit regretful. Imagine how much happier she might have been, if she had been wiser sooner.

She whispered a soft goodbye, then let her mindscape slip away and crawled her way back, however reluctantly, to her physical body. She would have liked to stay there, in the peace of her mind, but there was reality to be faced. And she was finally ready to face it.

He could feel the inevitability of his struggle. He felt it in his bones, crushed beneath the weight of a magic he was only now re-estimating. He felt it in his heart, worn thin and flinching by all he had given to this task—this impossible, doomed task. The Jewel was silent and cold in his hand. It had assisted him, at first, but as the tide of magic was proven stronger than Pettigrew's ability to fight it off, the support of the Jewel had waned.

He supposed that was all he needed to know that he had failed. He couldn't fulfill the prophecy after all. His great plans would come to nothing. When the energies of the Jewel turned against him, taking strength instead of giving it, he mustered no surprise. He felt nothing but bitter resignation. Even his despair was gone and he had to wonder how much of that desperation had been the Jewel, pushing him forward on a path he could neither see nor understand.

At least, he thought faintly as he caught sight of the unconscious boy by the light of the treacherous Jewel, I did not kill the boy after all. He would at least die without that sin on his soul. He knew the boy didn't have much hope of getting rescued, but, he thought, he hadn't directly killed him. That would count for something. Wouldn't it?

No answer came to him as his life force poured out, sucked greedily away by the very artifact that had promised his victory and engineered his defeat. What an ambiguous thing, power had turned out to be.